<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile Payments on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/mobile-payments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile Payments on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/mobile-payments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Celebrates One Year: Five Key Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-celebrates-one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-celebrates-one-year/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is celebrating its first birthday on Tuesday. The Mukesh Ambani-led mobile and internet service provider, which was commercially launched on September 5, 2016, keeps unleashing a plethora of offers, which have changed the landscape of the Indian telecom sector. As Jio sparked off an intense price war among the debt-ridden domestic telecom industry, its attractive offers have made key rivals like Bharti Airtel, Idea Cellular, Vodafone and even Mukesh’s younger brother Anil Ambani owned-Reliance Communications up the ante in terms of data and call offerings to retain customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSNL Expects To Start 5G Service Trials By March 2018</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-expects-to-start-5g-service-trials-by-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-expects-to-start-5g-service-trials-by-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>The state-owned telecom firm BSNL expects to start field trial of 5G services by the end of this financial year, company&amp;rsquo;s chairman and MD Anupam Shrivastava said today.
&amp;ldquo;We had interaction with Nokia last week (on 5G). Next we are going to present about our requirements after which field trail concept is there. It should start before the end of this financial year,&amp;rdquo; Shrivastava told reporters today.
The state-run firm has started discussion with Larsen &amp;amp; Toubro and HP for end devices that will be required for 5G services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Attack Could Affect 143 Million Americans: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/equifax-hacked-massive-data-breach-could-affect-143-million-americans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/equifax-hacked-massive-data-breach-could-affect-143-million-americans/</guid>
      <description>US-based credit reporting agency Equifax Inc announced on Friday that hackers had gained access to the company&amp;rsquo;s data, potentially impacting approximately 143 million US consumers.
Hackers exploited a vulnerability in the company&amp;rsquo;s website application from mid-May through July and gained access to consumer information including names, Social Security numbers, birth dates, addresses and in some instances, driver&amp;rsquo;s license numbers, the agency said in a statement.
The breach also included credit card numbers of approximately 209,000 consumers and certain dispute documents with personal identifying information of approximately 182,000 consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI- Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</guid>
      <description>HomeIndustry Banking financeFee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI
State Bank of India (SBI) on Wednesday waived charges on all money transfers of less than Rs 1,000 made through the Immediate Payment System (IMPS) channel, in a bid “to promote small ticket size transactions”.
By: FE Bureau | Mumbai | Updated: July 13, 2017 5:02 AM imps, sbi, state bank of india, sbi news, sbi latest news, imps transaction fee SBI’s decision to waive charges on some IMPS transactions may have been the result of more than a nudge from the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Issuing New-Look And Tamper-Proof PAN Cards</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-issuing-new-look-and-tamper-proof-pan-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-issuing-new-look-and-tamper-proof-pan-cards/</guid>
      <description>The Government is issuing newly designed PAN (Permanent Account Number) cards that have added security features to make them tamper-proof and with contents written in both Hindi and English, a senior Income-Tax Department official said today.
The distribution of new-look PAN cards, being printed by NSDL and UTIITSL (UTI Infrastructure Technology and Services Ltd), started since January 1. The cards are being issued to new applicants but existing ones can only apply for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car insurance: How to get extra cover during monsoon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/car-insurance-how-to-get-extra-cover-during-monsoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/car-insurance-how-to-get-extra-cover-during-monsoon/</guid>
      <description>Is there any special monsoon motor insurance cover available in the market? – Anuj Bansal
For new vehicles up to a certain
number of years, add-on covers like Engine Protect and Return To Invoice is advisable to opt for. These add-on covers are annual contracts and not restricted to a particular season. Engine Protect will indemnify the owner for engine related damages caused to the vehicle due to water ingression in the engine while driving the vehicle in accumulated flood waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New internet, mobile banking Charges</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/neft-charges-rtgs-charges-by-sbi-set-to-be-cut-but-applicable-only-on-internet-mobile-banking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/neft-charges-rtgs-charges-by-sbi-set-to-be-cut-but-applicable-only-on-internet-mobile-banking/</guid>
      <description>A day after it waived charges on Immediate Payment System (IMPS) transactions of up to Rs 1,000, State Bank of India (SBI) on Thursday lowered transaction charges on transfers made through the National Electronic Funds Transfer (NEFT) and Real Time Gross Settlement (RTGS) channels. NEFT transactions of up to Rs 10,000 will now attract a charge of Rs 1, transactions between Rs 1,001 and Rs 1 lakh will be charged at Rs 2, those between Rs 1 lakh and Rs 2 lakh will be charged Rs 3, while transactions involving higher amounts will be charged Rs 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSNL To Offer Ultra Fast 1,000 Mbps Broadband Services</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-to-offer-ultra-fast-1-000-mbps-broadband-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-to-offer-ultra-fast-1-000-mbps-broadband-services/</guid>
      <description>Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today launched a next generation optical fibre-based technology on BSNL network that will enable the state-run firm to provide broadband connection with download speed of up to 1,000 mbps.
Bharat Sanchar Nigam Ltd at present offers broadband facility with top download speed of 100 megabit per second on its fibre-to-the-home network.
&amp;ldquo;BSNL has successfully implemented a major project of NG-OTH technology in 44 cities covering state capitals and major cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government imposes 10% customs duty on chargers and adapters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-imposes-10-customs-duty-on-chargers-and-adapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-imposes-10-customs-duty-on-chargers-and-adapters/</guid>
      <description>NEW DELHI: The government has imposed a 10% basic customs duty (BCD) on imported chargers and adapters, while exempting parts or raw material used for making these products out of the duty ambit. The move reinstates an advantage that local manufactures had before the introduction of GST.
The industry welcomed the move, saying the step would provide stimulus to local manufacturing and take care of a loophole in rules that allowed for the import of chargers or adapters without paying any duty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How safe is your Aadhaar data and what security measures are taken by UIDAI: Here’s all you need to know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-safe-is-your-aadhaar-data-and-what-security-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-safe-is-your-aadhaar-data-and-what-security-measures/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number is a 12-digit random number issued by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) to the residents of India after satisfying the verification process laid down by it. The Aadhaar number is a proof of identity and does not confer any right of citizenship or domicile. Aadhaar has become very important now keeping in view the fact that the number has been made compulsory by the government for many financial transactions as well as a host of social schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>