<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile Payments on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/mobile-payments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile Payments on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/mobile-payments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Celebrates One Year: Five Key Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-celebrates-one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-celebrates-one-year/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is celebrating its first birthday on Tuesday. The Mukesh Ambani-led mobile and internet service provider, which was commercially launched on September 5, 2016, keeps unleashing a plethora of offers, which have changed the landscape of the Indian telecom sector. As Jio sparked off an intense price war among the debt-ridden domestic telecom industry, its attractive offers have made key rivals like Bharti Airtel, Idea Cellular, Vodafone and even Mukesh’s younger brother Anil Ambani owned-Reliance Communications up the ante in terms of data and call offerings to retain customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSNL Expects To Start 5G Service Trials By March 2018</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-expects-to-start-5g-service-trials-by-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-expects-to-start-5g-service-trials-by-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>The state-owned telecom firm BSNL expects to start field trial of 5G services by the end of this financial year, company&amp;rsquo;s chairman and MD Anupam Shrivastava said today.
&amp;ldquo;We had interaction with Nokia last week (on 5G). Next we are going to present about our requirements after which field trail concept is there. It should start before the end of this financial year,&amp;rdquo; Shrivastava told reporters today.
The state-run firm has started discussion with Larsen &amp;amp; Toubro and HP for end devices that will be required for 5G services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Attack Could Affect 143 Million Americans: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/equifax-hacked-massive-data-breach-could-affect-143-million-americans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/equifax-hacked-massive-data-breach-could-affect-143-million-americans/</guid>
      <description>US-based credit reporting agency Equifax Inc announced on Friday that hackers had gained access to the company&amp;rsquo;s data, potentially impacting approximately 143 million US consumers.
Hackers exploited a vulnerability in the company&amp;rsquo;s website application from mid-May through July and gained access to consumer information including names, Social Security numbers, birth dates, addresses and in some instances, driver&amp;rsquo;s license numbers, the agency said in a statement.
The breach also included credit card numbers of approximately 209,000 consumers and certain dispute documents with personal identifying information of approximately 182,000 consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI- Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</guid>
      <description>HomeIndustry Banking financeFee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI
State Bank of India (SBI) on Wednesday waived charges on all money transfers of less than Rs 1,000 made through the Immediate Payment System (IMPS) channel, in a bid “to promote small ticket size transactions”.
By: FE Bureau | Mumbai | Updated: July 13, 2017 5:02 AM imps, sbi, state bank of india, sbi news, sbi latest news, imps transaction fee SBI’s decision to waive charges on some IMPS transactions may have been the result of more than a nudge from the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Issuing New-Look And Tamper-Proof PAN Cards</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-issuing-new-look-and-tamper-proof-pan-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-issuing-new-look-and-tamper-proof-pan-cards/</guid>
      <description>The Government is issuing newly designed PAN (Permanent Account Number) cards that have added security features to make them tamper-proof and with contents written in both Hindi and English, a senior Income-Tax Department official said today.
The distribution of new-look PAN cards, being printed by NSDL and UTIITSL (UTI Infrastructure Technology and Services Ltd), started since January 1. The cards are being issued to new applicants but existing ones can only apply for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car insurance: How to get extra cover during monsoon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/car-insurance-how-to-get-extra-cover-during-monsoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/car-insurance-how-to-get-extra-cover-during-monsoon/</guid>
      <description>Is there any special monsoon motor insurance cover available in the market? – Anuj Bansal
For new vehicles up to a certain
number of years, add-on covers like Engine Protect and Return To Invoice is advisable to opt for. These add-on covers are annual contracts and not restricted to a particular season. Engine Protect will indemnify the owner for engine related damages caused to the vehicle due to water ingression in the engine while driving the vehicle in accumulated flood waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New internet, mobile banking Charges</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/neft-charges-rtgs-charges-by-sbi-set-to-be-cut-but-applicable-only-on-internet-mobile-banking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/neft-charges-rtgs-charges-by-sbi-set-to-be-cut-but-applicable-only-on-internet-mobile-banking/</guid>
      <description>A day after it waived charges on Immediate Payment System (IMPS) transactions of up to Rs 1,000, State Bank of India (SBI) on Thursday lowered transaction charges on transfers made through the National Electronic Funds Transfer (NEFT) and Real Time Gross Settlement (RTGS) channels. NEFT transactions of up to Rs 10,000 will now attract a charge of Rs 1, transactions between Rs 1,001 and Rs 1 lakh will be charged at Rs 2, those between Rs 1 lakh and Rs 2 lakh will be charged Rs 3, while transactions involving higher amounts will be charged Rs 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSNL To Offer Ultra Fast 1,000 Mbps Broadband Services</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-to-offer-ultra-fast-1-000-mbps-broadband-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-to-offer-ultra-fast-1-000-mbps-broadband-services/</guid>
      <description>Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today launched a next generation optical fibre-based technology on BSNL network that will enable the state-run firm to provide broadband connection with download speed of up to 1,000 mbps.
Bharat Sanchar Nigam Ltd at present offers broadband facility with top download speed of 100 megabit per second on its fibre-to-the-home network.
&amp;ldquo;BSNL has successfully implemented a major project of NG-OTH technology in 44 cities covering state capitals and major cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government imposes 10% customs duty on chargers and adapters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-imposes-10-customs-duty-on-chargers-and-adapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-imposes-10-customs-duty-on-chargers-and-adapters/</guid>
      <description>NEW DELHI: The government has imposed a 10% basic customs duty (BCD) on imported chargers and adapters, while exempting parts or raw material used for making these products out of the duty ambit. The move reinstates an advantage that local manufactures had before the introduction of GST.
The industry welcomed the move, saying the step would provide stimulus to local manufacturing and take care of a loophole in rules that allowed for the import of chargers or adapters without paying any duty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How safe is your Aadhaar data and what security measures are taken by UIDAI: Here’s all you need to know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-safe-is-your-aadhaar-data-and-what-security-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-safe-is-your-aadhaar-data-and-what-security-measures/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number is a 12-digit random number issued by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) to the residents of India after satisfying the verification process laid down by it. The Aadhaar number is a proof of identity and does not confer any right of citizenship or domicile. Aadhaar has become very important now keeping in view the fact that the number has been made compulsory by the government for many financial transactions as well as a host of social schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No GST On Second Hand Goods If Sold Cheaper</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-gst-on-second-hand-goods-if-sold-cheaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-gst-on-second-hand-goods-if-sold-cheaper/</guid>
      <description>The buying and selling of second hand goods will not attract Goods and Services Tax (GST) if sold at a price cheaper than the purchase price, the government said on Saturday.
HIGHLIGHTS
 The clarification comes after doubts regarding the Margin Scheme It can be availed by any registered person dealing in second hand goods Dealers of old and used empty bottles are also included  Rule 32(5) of the Central Goods and Services Tax (CGST) Rules, 2017, provides that where a taxable supply is provided by a person dealing in buying and selling of second hand goods or used goods as such or after such minor processing which does not change the nature of the goods and where no input tax credit has been availed on the purchase of such goods, the value of supply shall be the difference between the selling price and the purchase price and where the value of such supply is negative, it shall be ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI Pushes For Currency Security Features To Be Made In India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-pushes-for-currency-security-features-to-be-made-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-pushes-for-currency-security-features-to-be-made-in-india/</guid>
      <description>In a big &amp;lsquo;Make in India&amp;rsquo; push, the Reserve Bank today came out with fresh tender for currency security features, mandating that the supplier set up the manufacturing unit in the country within two years and gradually increase the local content.
RBI cancelled two tenders issued earlier for supply of security features and fibre for currency notes in order to incorporate &amp;lsquo;Make in India&amp;rsquo; as an essential requirement. The bid document is for supply of different types of security threads, colour-shifting ink, foil patch, security fibre, paper based taggant, ink based taggant, advanced watermark and micro perforation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Railways Launches Mobile App That Does More Than Just Booking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-launches-mobile-app-that-does-more-than-just-booking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-launches-mobile-app-that-does-more-than-just-booking/</guid>
      <description>The Railways today launched an integrated mobile application to cater to various passenger requirements, including ticket booking, inquiry, on-board cleaning and ordering meal on a single platform.
The app &amp;ndash; Rail SAARTHI &amp;ndash; was launched here by Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu.
Currently there are multiple mobile app by the Railways. To use different services, users need to search and download each application separately.
In order to provide better customer experience, there was a need for an integrated application which could give a single window interface for these services, Prabhu said after launching the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suresh Prabhu Launches India&#39;s First Solar Powered Train, Says 24 More To Come</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launches-indias-first-solar-powered-train-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launches-indias-first-solar-powered-train-says/</guid>
      <description>Railway Minister Suresh Prabhakar Prabhu on Friday said more solar-powered coaches will be inducted in the railway&amp;rsquo;s fleet.
&amp;ldquo;Indian Railways is committed for environment conservation and use of cleaner fuels,&amp;rdquo; Prabhu said at an event here.
&amp;ldquo;Indian Railways is trying to increase use of non-conventional sources of energy. More solar-powered trains may be inducted in future.&amp;rdquo;
The minister spoke at an event to launch the first 1,600 HP DEMU train with solar-powered coaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Department Seeks Explanation From Another 5.56 Lakh For Demonetisation Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-another-5-56-lakh-under-operation-clean-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-another-5-56-lakh-under-operation-clean-money/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department has identified another 5.56 lakh individuals whose tax profiles are found inconsistent with the money deposited by them post demonetisation.
In the second phase of &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo; launched in April with an aim to detect black money generation post demonetisation, the I-T department has used information received under the Statement of Financial Transactions (SFT) from banks to identify additional cases.
&amp;ldquo;These are persons whose tax profiles were found to be inconsistent with the cash deposits made by them during the demonetisation period,&amp;rdquo; a finance ministry statement said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 30 Aadhaar Deadline Not To Be Extended, Government Tells Top Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</guid>
      <description>Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of the Unique Identity programme Aadhaar are pending in the Supreme Court.
There is &amp;ldquo;no question&amp;rdquo; of extending the June 30 deadline for making Aadhaar mandatory for availing benefits of various social welfare schemes, the centre today told the Supreme Court.
Attorney General Mukul Rohatgi told the top court that the idea behind making Aadhaar mandatory for welfare schemes was that the benefit should not go to &amp;ldquo;ghosts&amp;rdquo; as was noticed in schemes like the public distribution system (PDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How railway insurance has become a boon for many</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</guid>
      <description>When the Railway Ministry introduced an optional Indian railway travel insurance scheme for e-ticketing passengers in September 2016, the move was welcomed. But little did we know how useful the policy would become soon after. Given the recent spate of train accidents that have left many passengers injured and caused several deaths, the insurance scheme has come as a boon for many.
The policy can be bought by passengers when booking tickets online from the IRCTC website or through the mobile app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks vs e-wallets: Who is winning in cashless India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>When two of the biggest banks in the country resist wallets from fintech start-ups, you know a few things are simmering. First, SBI disallowed its net banking users to top up third party wallets and next, ICICI blocked transactions on PhonePe, a Flipkart managed wallet that was launched in partnership with YES Bank – PhonePe allows users to link bank accounts to the smartphone through the National Payments Corporation of India’s encrypted software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Can Be Saved If Exemption Limit Is Doubled</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-tax-can-you-save-if-exemption-limit-is-doubled-to-rs-5-lakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-tax-can-you-save-if-exemption-limit-is-doubled-to-rs-5-lakh/</guid>
      <description>Ahead of the Budget presentation on February 1, expectations are rising that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley could offer more income tax sops than he has in the past.
Ahead of the Budget presentation on February 1, expectations are rising that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley could offer more income tax sops than he has in the past. Rajesh Baheti, MD of Crosseas Capital Services, says Mr Jaitley is unlikely to tinker much with the indirect taxes (excise duties) in the Budget as government has set July 1 date for rolling out the goods and services tax (GST) regime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To negate Reliance Jio&#39;s threat, Vodafone may join hands with Idea</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/negate-reliance-jios-threat-vodafone-may-join-hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/negate-reliance-jios-threat-vodafone-may-join-hands/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone Group Plc doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much of a choice but to accelerate consolidation moves in India — likely with Idea Cellular with whom it is in talks — as the UK telecom major tries to counter Reliance Jio Infocomm in a key market where it has been struggling to ward off value erosion, add customers and grow revenue market share (RMS).
Vodafone India, the No. 2 telco, and third ranked Idea are reckoned to be in merger talks, people aware of the matter told ET, with latest discussions locked over who will have operational control of the merged entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre pushes for fingerprint money transactions through Aadhaar Pay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-pushes-fingerprint-money-transactions-aadhaar-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-pushes-fingerprint-money-transactions-aadhaar-pay/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar Pay is the merchant version of the already in use Aadhaar-enabled payment system It works on any android-based phone, with an attached finger biometric device Andhra Bank, IDFC Bank, IndusInd Bank, State Bank of India and Syndicate Bank have gone live over Aadhaar Pay  Keen to push digital payments among the poor and illiterate in rural areas of the country, the government is pushing to popularise Aadhaar Pay which ensures financial transactions by just using fingerprint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPCI has no jurisdiction over us: PhonePe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-no-jurisdiction-us-phonepe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-no-jurisdiction-us-phonepe/</guid>
      <description>The Flipkart-owned payments app PhonePe’s co-founder &amp;amp; CEO Sameer Nigam has said that the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) had no legal jurisdiction to `direct’ his company or Flipkart to do anything.
Bengaluru:The ongoing tussle between India’s largest private sector bank ICICI Bank and payments startup PhonePe isn’t showing signs of abating.
The Flipkart-owned payments app PhonePe’s co-founder &amp;amp; CEO Sameer Nigam has said that the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) had no legal jurisdiction to `direct’ his company or Flipkart to do anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweeping reforms in Civil Supplies Dept: EPOS machines in all 16,560 FP shops soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sweeping-reforms-civil-supplies-dept-epos-machines-16560-fp-shops-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sweeping-reforms-civil-supplies-dept-epos-machines-16560-fp-shops-soon/</guid>
      <description>As directed by the Union government and also at the behest of the State Government, the Civil Supplies department has opened its doors for sweeping reforms with the implementation of Electronic Point of Sale (EPOS) Unit system throughout the State. Now EPOS machines are provided with advanced features and at a low price too.
A committee under the guidance of CGG with C.V. Anand, Civil Supplies Commisioner, as Chairman has been formed to finalize the tenders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>70% Of Notes To Be Remonetised By February-End: SBI Research</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-of-notes-to-be-remonetised-by-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-of-notes-to-be-remonetised-by-february/</guid>
      <description>Roughly 70 million pieces of notes of different denominations are being printed per day at the printing press. This translates into around 1.8 billion pieces per month, said the SBI Research report, released on Friday.
At the Reserve Bank of India&amp;rsquo;s current printing press capacity, 70 per cent of the notes will be remonetised and &amp;ldquo;normalcy will return most likely&amp;rdquo; by the end of February, according to a report by SBI Research, the economic research arm of State Bank of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar number could be made compulsory for I-T returns in budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-number-made-compulsory-t-returns-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-number-made-compulsory-t-returns-budget/</guid>
      <description>The Business Standard has reported that the government is planning to insist on Aadhaar numbers for all those filing ncome tax (I-T) returns from the upcoming financial year.
The paper reports sources in the government as saying that “relevant amendments to the Income Tax Act, 1961, in this Budget are under ‘active discussion’ to ensure mandatory linkage of tax returns to Aadhaar numbers”.
The report comes on the back of other measures to increase vigilance on the flow of money from and to accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Employees Union Threaten Nation-Wide Strike On February 7</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/section-of-bank-employees-threaten-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/section-of-bank-employees-threaten-nation/</guid>
      <description>Unions are also demanding publishing names of individuals who have defaulted in paying loans of Rs 1 crore and above so that stringent measures could be taken to recover bad loans.
A section of bank trade unions have threatened to go on a day-long nation-wide strike on February 7 to press various demands including complete removal of restrictions imposed during demonetisation period and safeguarding the autonomy of the Reserve Bank of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customers Can Cancel Rail Tickets Booked Through Point-Of-Sale Machines</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-can-cancel-rail-tickets-booked-through-point-of-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-can-cancel-rail-tickets-booked-through-point-of-sale/</guid>
      <description>The Railway Ministry today spelt out the procedure for cancelling tickets booked through Point of Sale (PoS) machines as it prepares to install 10,000 of them across ticket reservation counters in a bid to encourage cashless transactions following demonetisation.
In case of tickets booked through SBI PoS machines at a reservation counter, a customer can approach a counter and cancel his ticket. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to swipe his card again for cancellation as the refund will be credited directly to his or her bank account within 7 days, according to a statement issued by the Railway Ministry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital payment firms hope for tax benefits in Union Budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payment-firms-hope-tax-benefits-union-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payment-firms-hope-tax-benefits-union-budget/</guid>
      <description>They have also requested for extension of the import duty waiver on PoS terminals for card payments beyond March 31 as it expects the demand for such terminals to go up.
If demonetisation got ‘Acche Din’ for digital payment companies, further tax incentives and rewards are things these entities are hoping for in the upcoming Union Budget to ensure customers stick to digital payments instruments and don’t migrate back to cash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes Ban: Tax Department Gets Over Rs 300 Crore Declarations Under PMGKY</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/notes-ban-tax-department-gets-over-rs-300-crore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/notes-ban-tax-department-gets-over-rs-300-crore/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax department has received confirmations for over Rs 300 crore declarations from across the country till now as part of the ongoing black money window called the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), brought out by the government post demonetisation.
Officials said I-T department offices across the country have got a number of small to big declarations in this regard after the taxman launched a large number of search, survey, seizure and electronic database analysis operations to check stash funds hoarded or generated post the November 8, 2016 notes ban.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI Working On Plan To Reduce Online Charges: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-working-on-plan-to-reduce-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-working-on-plan-to-reduce-online/</guid>
      <description>The Reserve Bank of India is working on a plan to reduce online transaction costs as it tries to encourage more digital banking, two parliamentary panel members quoted central bank governor Urjit Patel as saying on Friday.
&amp;ldquo;We are working on a mechanism to bring down transaction costs,&amp;rdquo; one member of the public accounts committee quoted Mr Patel as saying. &amp;ldquo;We are speaking to all stakeholders.&amp;rdquo;
Mr Patel met the panel to answer questions about the November 8 abolition of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes, or 86 per cent of the currency then in circulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDA&#39;s New Housing Scheme Likely To Be Launched In February</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ddas-new-housing-scheme-likely-to-be-launched-in-feburary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ddas-new-housing-scheme-likely-to-be-launched-in-feburary/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi Development Authority&amp;rsquo;s new Housing Scheme with 12,000 flats on offer is now likely to be launched next month, with the delay being blamed on &amp;ldquo;lack&amp;rdquo; of basic infrastructure in &amp;ldquo;few pockets&amp;rdquo; falling under the scheme. The scheme was earlier expected to be launched around January 26.
&amp;ldquo;We had a January target but people were reeling under the immediate impact of demonetisation and so bank transactions were getting difficult to come buy,&amp;rdquo; a source said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Clears Rs 45,000 Crore Loan To Food Corporation Of India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-clears-rs-45-000-crore-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-clears-rs-45-000-crore-loan/</guid>
      <description>The Cabinet meeting headed by Prime Minister Narendra Modi also approved providing one-time loan of Rs 45,000 crore from NSSF to FCI to meet its food subsidy requirements.
The government on Wednesday approved Rs 45,000 crore loan to FCI out of National Small Savings Fund, while exempting most of the states and UTs from mandatory investment norms with regard to funds collected under the NSSF scheme.
The Cabinet decision to exempt states barring four, Arunachal Pradesh, Delhi, Kerala and Madhya Pradesh, from NSSF investments from April 1, 2016 will help them raise cheaper funds from the market and reduce interest outgo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mehbooba launches J&amp;K Bank’s mobile app</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mehbooba-launches-jk-banks-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mehbooba-launches-jk-banks-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>Chief Minister Mehbooba Mufti on Tuesday launched the mobile app and AEPS (Aadhaar Enabled Payment System) of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir Bank.
The mobile application has been specifically designed to cater to the needs of the customers of the state. The inauguration was part of the ‘Digi Dhan Mela’ held here.
Digi Dhan is an initiative of the Central government which enables direct interface between consumers and merchants to undertake real time digital transactions through the Digi Dhan Bazaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing Of Budget 2017 Documents To Start Today With &#39;Halwa&#39; Ceremony</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/printing-of-budget-2017-document-to-start-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/printing-of-budget-2017-document-to-start-today/</guid>
      <description>The process of printing documents for the Budget 2017-18 will start today with the ritual &amp;ldquo;Halwa Ceremony &amp;ldquo;. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley will participate in &amp;ldquo;Halwa Ceremony&amp;rdquo; today marking the beginning of printing of Budget documents.
As part of the ritual, which has continued for long, &amp;lsquo;Halwa&amp;rsquo; is prepared in a big &amp;lsquo;kadhai&amp;rsquo; and served to the entire staff in the ministry.
FM @arunjaitley to participate in Halwa Ceremony today marking the beginning of printing of documents which are part of Union Budget 2017-18</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecom Sector To Create 2 Million Jobs This Year: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-sector-to-create-2-million-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-sector-to-create-2-million-jobs/</guid>
      <description>The sector requires skills in areas such as IoT, mobility solutions, telecom infrastructure, network architectures, sales amongst others.
The telecom sector is expected to create two million jobs this year, thanks to increased data penetration and entry of new service providers, says a report. The entry of new service providers, the government&amp;rsquo;s initiatives like &amp;lsquo;Make in India&amp;rsquo; and thrust on mobile economy will also add to the buoyancy in the sector, it said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vodafone Counters Jio, Airtel With 4 Times More Data In SuperNet 4G Pack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-counters-jio-airtel-with-4-times-more-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-counters-jio-airtel-with-4-times-more-data/</guid>
      <description>The battle that began with the launch of Reliance Jio4G services in September last year is getting fiercer by the day. Telecom companies like Airtel, idea, and Vodafone are launching new plans to take on Reliance Jio which is offering free 1GB data everyday till March 31, 2017.
Here are the details of 4G data tariffs being offered by different companies
Vodafone
Vodafone customers who purchase a 1GB data pack at Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arun Jaitley Says July 1 Rollout Of GST &#39;More Realistic&#39;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/july-1-rollout-of-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/july-1-rollout-of-gst/</guid>
      <description>The new levy is hailed as India&amp;rsquo;s biggest tax overhaul since independence in 1947, and is expected to transform Asia&amp;rsquo;s third largest economy into a single market for the first time.
India&amp;rsquo;s new nationwide sales tax is now expected to be rolled out from July after Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Monday managed to break a three-month long deadlock on who would administer the tax.
The long-awaited Goods and Services Tax (GST) was earlier proposed to come into effect from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDS Disclosures Valid If Taxes Realised By December 5: Taxman</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-ids-disclosures-valid-if-taxes-realised-by-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-ids-disclosures-valid-if-taxes-realised-by-december/</guid>
      <description>In an instruction to principal commissioners, the income tax department has asked them to condone the delay in payment of first installment which has arisen due to &amp;ldquo;genuine technical difficulties&amp;rdquo;.
In a minor relaxation to IDS tax payment rules, the Income Tax Department has said disclosures under the scheme will be considered valid even if the tax amount has been realised by December 5.
The first installment of taxes was to be paid by November 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon, Aadhaar Card To Be Integrated With BHIM App For Easier Payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-aadhaar-card-integrated-bhim-app-easier-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-aadhaar-card-integrated-bhim-app-easier-payments/</guid>
      <description>Another step towards making Aadhaar the focal point for all transactions.
The government is set to link the Aadhaar card to the newly launched BHIM app for making e-payments through mobile devices. An update to the BHIM app will integrate the user’s Aadhar number with it, enabling payments to be made easily and seamlessly.
As reported in the Times of India, there will be no need for bank registration or biometric authentication if a user logs into the app with her or his Aadhaar number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State’s first Digi Dhan Mela gets good response</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/states-first-digi-dhan-mela-gets-good-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/states-first-digi-dhan-mela-gets-good-response/</guid>
      <description>The first Digi Dhan Mela in the state held in Bengaluru on Monday received a good response with the young and the old seeking information on various modes of digital transactions.
The mela is being held in various cities by the Centre in association with state governments to popularise digital transactions and it was Bengaluru’s turn on Monday.
The day-long mela had around 50 stalls. Various banks displayed and also registered customers for digital transaction schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICICI Blocking Flipkart’s PhonePe on UPI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-blocking-flipkarts-phonepe-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-blocking-flipkarts-phonepe-up/</guid>
      <description>ICICI has been blocking PhonePe since Friday UPI is supposed to be fully interoperable ICICI says it’s blocking the app due to security concerns  Although one of the big selling points of the Unified Payments Interface (UPI) has been that it is interoperable unlike mobile wallets, it appears that ICICI Bank has been blocking the @ybl virtual payment addresses (VPAs) that Yes Bank and PhonePe (Flipkart’s UPI app) use, since Friday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI Raises ATM Withdrawal Limits From Rs 4,500 To Rs 10,000 Per Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-raises-atm-withdrawal-limits-from-rs-4-500-to-rs-10-000-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-raises-atm-withdrawal-limits-from-rs-4-500-to-rs-10-000-per-day/</guid>
      <description>For current account holders, the cash withdrawal limit has been enhanced from the existing limit of Rs 50,000 per week to Rs 1,00,000 per week and it extends to overdraft and cash credit accounts also
TheReserve Bank of India ( RBI) has raised the cash withdrawal limits from ATMs in the country. Consumers will now be able to withdraw Rs 10,000 per day from their savings bank accounts through ATMs as against the previous limit of Rs 4,500 per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI to roll out Aadhaar Pay for merchants to enable cashless transactions without a smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-roll-aadhaar-pay-merchants-enable-cashless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-roll-aadhaar-pay-merchants-enable-cashless/</guid>
      <description>Unique Identification Authority of India has indicated that it will be rolling out Aadhaar Pay app for merchants in the coming weeks. The program has been running as a pilot project in fair-price shops in Andhra Pradesh, according to a report in The Economic Times. The app will be based on Aadhaar-enabled payment system (AEPS) which is already being used by micro ATMs across the country.
The application is being developed by UIDAI in collaboration with TCS, and is available to banks to integrate with their applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>