<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile Payments on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/mobile-payments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile Payments on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/mobile-payments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>June 30 Aadhaar Deadline Not To Be Extended, Government Tells Top Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</guid>
      <description>Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of the Unique Identity programme Aadhaar are pending in the Supreme Court.
There is &amp;ldquo;no question&amp;rdquo; of extending the June 30 deadline for making Aadhaar mandatory for availing benefits of various social welfare schemes, the centre today told the Supreme Court.
Attorney General Mukul Rohatgi told the top court that the idea behind making Aadhaar mandatory for welfare schemes was that the benefit should not go to &amp;ldquo;ghosts&amp;rdquo; as was noticed in schemes like the public distribution system (PDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How railway insurance has become a boon for many</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</guid>
      <description>When the Railway Ministry introduced an optional Indian railway travel insurance scheme for e-ticketing passengers in September 2016, the move was welcomed. But little did we know how useful the policy would become soon after. Given the recent spate of train accidents that have left many passengers injured and caused several deaths, the insurance scheme has come as a boon for many.
The policy can be bought by passengers when booking tickets online from the IRCTC website or through the mobile app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks vs e-wallets: Who is winning in cashless India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>When two of the biggest banks in the country resist wallets from fintech start-ups, you know a few things are simmering. First, SBI disallowed its net banking users to top up third party wallets and next, ICICI blocked transactions on PhonePe, a Flipkart managed wallet that was launched in partnership with YES Bank – PhonePe allows users to link bank accounts to the smartphone through the National Payments Corporation of India’s encrypted software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Can Be Saved If Exemption Limit Is Doubled</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-tax-can-you-save-if-exemption-limit-is-doubled-to-rs-5-lakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-tax-can-you-save-if-exemption-limit-is-doubled-to-rs-5-lakh/</guid>
      <description>Ahead of the Budget presentation on February 1, expectations are rising that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley could offer more income tax sops than he has in the past.
Ahead of the Budget presentation on February 1, expectations are rising that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley could offer more income tax sops than he has in the past. Rajesh Baheti, MD of Crosseas Capital Services, says Mr Jaitley is unlikely to tinker much with the indirect taxes (excise duties) in the Budget as government has set July 1 date for rolling out the goods and services tax (GST) regime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To negate Reliance Jio&#39;s threat, Vodafone may join hands with Idea</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/negate-reliance-jios-threat-vodafone-may-join-hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/negate-reliance-jios-threat-vodafone-may-join-hands/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone Group Plc doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much of a choice but to accelerate consolidation moves in India — likely with Idea Cellular with whom it is in talks — as the UK telecom major tries to counter Reliance Jio Infocomm in a key market where it has been struggling to ward off value erosion, add customers and grow revenue market share (RMS).
Vodafone India, the No. 2 telco, and third ranked Idea are reckoned to be in merger talks, people aware of the matter told ET, with latest discussions locked over who will have operational control of the merged entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre pushes for fingerprint money transactions through Aadhaar Pay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-pushes-fingerprint-money-transactions-aadhaar-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-pushes-fingerprint-money-transactions-aadhaar-pay/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar Pay is the merchant version of the already in use Aadhaar-enabled payment system It works on any android-based phone, with an attached finger biometric device Andhra Bank, IDFC Bank, IndusInd Bank, State Bank of India and Syndicate Bank have gone live over Aadhaar Pay  Keen to push digital payments among the poor and illiterate in rural areas of the country, the government is pushing to popularise Aadhaar Pay which ensures financial transactions by just using fingerprint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPCI has no jurisdiction over us: PhonePe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-no-jurisdiction-us-phonepe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-no-jurisdiction-us-phonepe/</guid>
      <description>The Flipkart-owned payments app PhonePe’s co-founder &amp;amp; CEO Sameer Nigam has said that the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) had no legal jurisdiction to `direct’ his company or Flipkart to do anything.
Bengaluru:The ongoing tussle between India’s largest private sector bank ICICI Bank and payments startup PhonePe isn’t showing signs of abating.
The Flipkart-owned payments app PhonePe’s co-founder &amp;amp; CEO Sameer Nigam has said that the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) had no legal jurisdiction to `direct’ his company or Flipkart to do anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweeping reforms in Civil Supplies Dept: EPOS machines in all 16,560 FP shops soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sweeping-reforms-civil-supplies-dept-epos-machines-16560-fp-shops-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sweeping-reforms-civil-supplies-dept-epos-machines-16560-fp-shops-soon/</guid>
      <description>As directed by the Union government and also at the behest of the State Government, the Civil Supplies department has opened its doors for sweeping reforms with the implementation of Electronic Point of Sale (EPOS) Unit system throughout the State. Now EPOS machines are provided with advanced features and at a low price too.
A committee under the guidance of CGG with C.V. Anand, Civil Supplies Commisioner, as Chairman has been formed to finalize the tenders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>70% Of Notes To Be Remonetised By February-End: SBI Research</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-of-notes-to-be-remonetised-by-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-of-notes-to-be-remonetised-by-february/</guid>
      <description>Roughly 70 million pieces of notes of different denominations are being printed per day at the printing press. This translates into around 1.8 billion pieces per month, said the SBI Research report, released on Friday.
At the Reserve Bank of India&amp;rsquo;s current printing press capacity, 70 per cent of the notes will be remonetised and &amp;ldquo;normalcy will return most likely&amp;rdquo; by the end of February, according to a report by SBI Research, the economic research arm of State Bank of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Issuing New-Look And Tamper-Proof PAN Cards</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-issuing-new-look-and-tamper-proof-pan-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-issuing-new-look-and-tamper-proof-pan-cards/</guid>
      <description>The Government is issuing newly designed PAN (Permanent Account Number) cards that have added security features to make them tamper-proof and with contents written in both Hindi and English, a senior Income-Tax Department official said today.
The distribution of new-look PAN cards, being printed by NSDL and UTIITSL (UTI Infrastructure Technology and Services Ltd), started since January 1. The cards are being issued to new applicants but existing ones can only apply for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar number could be made compulsory for I-T returns in budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-number-made-compulsory-t-returns-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-number-made-compulsory-t-returns-budget/</guid>
      <description>The Business Standard has reported that the government is planning to insist on Aadhaar numbers for all those filing ncome tax (I-T) returns from the upcoming financial year.
The paper reports sources in the government as saying that “relevant amendments to the Income Tax Act, 1961, in this Budget are under ‘active discussion’ to ensure mandatory linkage of tax returns to Aadhaar numbers”.
The report comes on the back of other measures to increase vigilance on the flow of money from and to accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Employees Union Threaten Nation-Wide Strike On February 7</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/section-of-bank-employees-threaten-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/section-of-bank-employees-threaten-nation/</guid>
      <description>Unions are also demanding publishing names of individuals who have defaulted in paying loans of Rs 1 crore and above so that stringent measures could be taken to recover bad loans.
A section of bank trade unions have threatened to go on a day-long nation-wide strike on February 7 to press various demands including complete removal of restrictions imposed during demonetisation period and safeguarding the autonomy of the Reserve Bank of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customers Can Cancel Rail Tickets Booked Through Point-Of-Sale Machines</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-can-cancel-rail-tickets-booked-through-point-of-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-can-cancel-rail-tickets-booked-through-point-of-sale/</guid>
      <description>The Railway Ministry today spelt out the procedure for cancelling tickets booked through Point of Sale (PoS) machines as it prepares to install 10,000 of them across ticket reservation counters in a bid to encourage cashless transactions following demonetisation.
In case of tickets booked through SBI PoS machines at a reservation counter, a customer can approach a counter and cancel his ticket. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to swipe his card again for cancellation as the refund will be credited directly to his or her bank account within 7 days, according to a statement issued by the Railway Ministry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital payment firms hope for tax benefits in Union Budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payment-firms-hope-tax-benefits-union-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payment-firms-hope-tax-benefits-union-budget/</guid>
      <description>They have also requested for extension of the import duty waiver on PoS terminals for card payments beyond March 31 as it expects the demand for such terminals to go up.
If demonetisation got ‘Acche Din’ for digital payment companies, further tax incentives and rewards are things these entities are hoping for in the upcoming Union Budget to ensure customers stick to digital payments instruments and don’t migrate back to cash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes Ban: Tax Department Gets Over Rs 300 Crore Declarations Under PMGKY</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/notes-ban-tax-department-gets-over-rs-300-crore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/notes-ban-tax-department-gets-over-rs-300-crore/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax department has received confirmations for over Rs 300 crore declarations from across the country till now as part of the ongoing black money window called the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), brought out by the government post demonetisation.
Officials said I-T department offices across the country have got a number of small to big declarations in this regard after the taxman launched a large number of search, survey, seizure and electronic database analysis operations to check stash funds hoarded or generated post the November 8, 2016 notes ban.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI Working On Plan To Reduce Online Charges: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-working-on-plan-to-reduce-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-working-on-plan-to-reduce-online/</guid>
      <description>The Reserve Bank of India is working on a plan to reduce online transaction costs as it tries to encourage more digital banking, two parliamentary panel members quoted central bank governor Urjit Patel as saying on Friday.
&amp;ldquo;We are working on a mechanism to bring down transaction costs,&amp;rdquo; one member of the public accounts committee quoted Mr Patel as saying. &amp;ldquo;We are speaking to all stakeholders.&amp;rdquo;
Mr Patel met the panel to answer questions about the November 8 abolition of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes, or 86 per cent of the currency then in circulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDA&#39;s New Housing Scheme Likely To Be Launched In February</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ddas-new-housing-scheme-likely-to-be-launched-in-feburary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ddas-new-housing-scheme-likely-to-be-launched-in-feburary/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi Development Authority&amp;rsquo;s new Housing Scheme with 12,000 flats on offer is now likely to be launched next month, with the delay being blamed on &amp;ldquo;lack&amp;rdquo; of basic infrastructure in &amp;ldquo;few pockets&amp;rdquo; falling under the scheme. The scheme was earlier expected to be launched around January 26.
&amp;ldquo;We had a January target but people were reeling under the immediate impact of demonetisation and so bank transactions were getting difficult to come buy,&amp;rdquo; a source said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Clears Rs 45,000 Crore Loan To Food Corporation Of India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-clears-rs-45-000-crore-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-clears-rs-45-000-crore-loan/</guid>
      <description>The Cabinet meeting headed by Prime Minister Narendra Modi also approved providing one-time loan of Rs 45,000 crore from NSSF to FCI to meet its food subsidy requirements.
The government on Wednesday approved Rs 45,000 crore loan to FCI out of National Small Savings Fund, while exempting most of the states and UTs from mandatory investment norms with regard to funds collected under the NSSF scheme.
The Cabinet decision to exempt states barring four, Arunachal Pradesh, Delhi, Kerala and Madhya Pradesh, from NSSF investments from April 1, 2016 will help them raise cheaper funds from the market and reduce interest outgo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mehbooba launches J&amp;K Bank’s mobile app</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mehbooba-launches-jk-banks-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mehbooba-launches-jk-banks-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>Chief Minister Mehbooba Mufti on Tuesday launched the mobile app and AEPS (Aadhaar Enabled Payment System) of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir Bank.
The mobile application has been specifically designed to cater to the needs of the customers of the state. The inauguration was part of the ‘Digi Dhan Mela’ held here.
Digi Dhan is an initiative of the Central government which enables direct interface between consumers and merchants to undertake real time digital transactions through the Digi Dhan Bazaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing Of Budget 2017 Documents To Start Today With &#39;Halwa&#39; Ceremony</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/printing-of-budget-2017-document-to-start-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/printing-of-budget-2017-document-to-start-today/</guid>
      <description>The process of printing documents for the Budget 2017-18 will start today with the ritual &amp;ldquo;Halwa Ceremony &amp;ldquo;. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley will participate in &amp;ldquo;Halwa Ceremony&amp;rdquo; today marking the beginning of printing of Budget documents.
As part of the ritual, which has continued for long, &amp;lsquo;Halwa&amp;rsquo; is prepared in a big &amp;lsquo;kadhai&amp;rsquo; and served to the entire staff in the ministry.
FM @arunjaitley to participate in Halwa Ceremony today marking the beginning of printing of documents which are part of Union Budget 2017-18</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>