<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/mobile-payments/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/mobile-payments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>June 30 Aadhaar Deadline Not To Be Extended, Government Tells Top Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of the Unique Identity programme Aadhaar are pending in the Supreme Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is &amp;ldquo;no question&amp;rdquo; of extending the June 30 deadline for making Aadhaar mandatory for availing benefits of various social welfare schemes, the centre today told the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General Mukul Rohatgi told the top court that the idea behind making Aadhaar mandatory for welfare schemes was that the benefit should not go to &amp;ldquo;ghosts&amp;rdquo; as was noticed in schemes like the public distribution system (PDS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also raised preliminary objection to the plea seeking interim relief and challenging various notifications issued by the centre and told a bench, comprising Justices A M Khanwilkar and Navin Sinha, that this matter should be listed for hearing before a five-judge constitution bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Rohatgi said that earlier, some pleas seeking identical interim reliefs were also filed and those matters were pending before the top court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bench said it would be appropriate to hear all these pleas seeking interim relief together to &amp;ldquo;avoid multiplicity&amp;rdquo; and fixed the matter for hearing on June 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the bench was considering whether to list the matter for hearing during the summer vacation, senior advocate Shyam Divan, appearing for the petitioner, said there was urgency involved in it and if the matter was not heard before June 30, &amp;ldquo;the other way was if they (centre) extend the deadline&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;There is no question of that,&amp;rdquo; Mr Rohatgi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Aadhaar are pending in the top court and would be heard by a five-judge constitution bench, which is yet to be set up by the Chief Justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Supreme Court had passed a slew of orders asking the government and its agencies not to make Aadhaar mandatory for extending benefits of their welfare schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top court, however, had allowed the Centre to seek Aadhaar card voluntarily from citizens for extending benefits of schemes like LPG subsidy, Jan Dhan scheme and Public Distribution System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How railway insurance has become a boon for many</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the Railway Ministry introduced an optional Indian railway travel insurance scheme for e-ticketing passengers in September 2016, the move was welcomed. But little did we know how useful the policy would become soon after. Given the recent spate of train accidents that have left many passengers injured and caused several deaths, the insurance scheme has come as a boon for many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy can be bought by passengers when booking tickets online from the IRCTC website or through the mobile app. Earlier, the cost of this policy was 92 paise per passenger for an insurance cover of Rs 10 lakh in cases of demise or permanent disability. However, Dipankar Acharya, Country Head-Affinity and Strategic Relationships, Royal Sundaram General Insurance, points out, “From 10 December 2016 the cost of premium for this policy is subsidised by the railways so passengers don’t have to pay anything. Everyone should opt for this insurance policy while travelling by railways.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy is valid from the time of departure of train to the time of arrival of train at the destination. If an accident occurs during the journey, the injured passenger or the nominee of the deceased passenger will get the claim amount. If an insured passenger is injured, and it causes their demise within 12 months of the accident, their nominee can also claim Rs 10 lakh as per insurance policy. In case of injuries, passenger can claim hospitalisation expenses up to Rs 2 lakh which includes room rent for hospital, medicines, diagnostic test, nursing charges, ICU charges, operation theatre charges, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the exclusions under this policy are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intentional self-injury, suicide or attempted suicide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim in instances wherein ticket was booked by the Insured, but they did not board the train, irrespective of whether the train ticket was cancelled or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim in instances where the ticket was booked but wasn’t confirmed, but the passenger still boarded the train.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any medical treatment which was not medically necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has tied up with three general insurance companies - ICICI Lombard, Royal Sundaram and Shriram General Insurance - for policy issuance. Once you book the tickets, you will receive the policy details on your registered mobile number and mentioned email ID. The next important step is to update the name of your nominee on the insurance company’s website before travelling. “The benefit of appointing a nominee is that it helps to settle the claim quickly in the wake of unfortunate train accidents. If a nominee is not appointed, the process of claim settlement much longer, since legal heir certificate has to be produced,” says Acharya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a claim, the insured or nominee must submit a report of the railway authority confirming the accident of the train, a claim form, medical reports, death or disability certificate, ID proof, and NEFT details and a cancelled cheque to the insurance company. After the submission, the claim is settled within 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Easing the burden&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The insured passenger or nominee can claim the following amounts.&lt;/em&gt;
*On death: Rs 10 lakh
*On permanent total disability: Rs 10 lakh
*On permanent partial disability: Rs 7.5 lakh
*Hospitalisation expenses for injury: Rs 2 lakh
*Transportation of mortal remains: Rs 10,000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks vs e-wallets: Who is winning in cashless India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When two of the biggest banks in the country resist wallets from fintech start-ups, you know a few things are simmering. First, SBI disallowed its net banking users to top up third party wallets and next, ICICI blocked transactions on PhonePe, a Flipkart managed wallet that was launched in partnership with YES Bank – PhonePe allows users to link bank accounts to the smartphone through the National Payments Corporation of India’s encrypted software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While SBI cited security concerns, ICICI said PhonePe was “following restrictive practices allowing users to make payments with only its UPI handle which is in contravention to the UPI guidelines of interoperability…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While security concerns could be real, there is more to it than meets the eye. There is an imminent threat from fintech start-ups to the Indian financial services industry as we see growing disintermediation in mobile payments, financial product comparison/aggregation, lending, and remittances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report by consulting firm Zinnov released mid-2016, investments in the fintech sector crossed $1.3 billion.  Mobile wallet start-ups have received the most funding – they have been using this capital to both aggressively market as well as improve the ease of using their technology. Compared to say a Paytm, SBI’s wallet ‘SBI Buddy’ and ICICI’s ‘Pockets’ have much less brand recall. These privately funded start-ups are now threatening the banks from three sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, banks are worried about relationship with their customers being upended. Banks had failed to notice India’s demographic shift; the young did not want complicated KYC norms even for small transactions such as mobile recharges. They love the app economy and the convenience it provides. Wallets stepped in to provide a better payments experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was a slipping market scenario for traditional banks.  The banking industry’s business model majorly centres around retail as well as corporate lending and not small value transactions. However, according to some estimates, the payments market is a mammoth $500 billion opportunity today when domestic and international remittances, government, utility bills as well as merchant payments are included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New payment categories have come into being as well — taxi payments were always in cash a couple of years ago. Today, tech savvy customers are paying their maid or a driver through money transfers. Many more new categories could emerge.  If these start-ups, armed with private equity money, were to garner a major share of this pie, it would be more than an opportunity lost for traditional banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third threat, and a more serious one, is about data. What happens when users start trusting payment companies? The fallout of such a scenario – where both trust and transactions move to wallet companies – would reflect in a bank’s visibility of customer data or their behaviour patterns. That, in turn, would reduce a bank’s ability to cross sell or up sell other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may, in fact, become reliant on wallet companies for such data. Payment companies, for instance, will be in a better position to judge the credit worthiness of many retail customers the banks are after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, the margins of many banks could slip due to competition. As smart phones become more affordable and pervasive, experts see fintech start-ups scale massively. And if traditional banks don’t align their cost structures with current realities — especially the public sector ones — they can find themselves in a quagmire with only “restrictive practices” as aid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Can Be Saved If Exemption Limit Is Doubled</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-tax-can-you-save-if-exemption-limit-is-doubled-to-rs-5-lakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-tax-can-you-save-if-exemption-limit-is-doubled-to-rs-5-lakh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ahead of the Budget presentation on February 1, expectations are rising that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley could offer more income tax sops than he has in the past.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the Budget presentation on February 1, expectations are rising that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley could offer more income tax sops than he has in the past. Rajesh Baheti, MD of Crosseas Capital Services, says Mr Jaitley is unlikely to tinker much with the indirect taxes (excise duties) in the Budget as government has set July 1 date for rolling out the goods and services tax (GST) regime. So individual income tax and corporate tax would be the focus of this year&amp;rsquo;s Budget, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides that Budget 2017 has a lot of expectations riding on it, especially post-demonetisation. &amp;ldquo;The common man is expecting some relief in the form of reduced tax rates or enhanced tax slabs to soothe the discomfort caused by the demonetisation drive,&amp;rdquo; said Amarpal Chadha, a tax partner at EY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shuddhasattwa Ghosh, a tax partner at EY, says though the income tax rates may not be tinkered with, some realignment of slab rates is expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Ghosh says the threshold limit could be raised to Rs 5 lakh. According to the current income tax laws, for individuals below 60 years of age, income up to Rs 2.5 lakh is not taxed. Income between Rs 2.5 lakh and Rs 5 lakh is taxed at 10 cent; between Rs 5 lakh and Rs 10 lakh at 20 per cent, and beyond Rs 10 lakh at 30 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Ghosh of EY says the new 10 per cent tax bracket could be for income between Rs 5 lakh and Rs 7.5 lakh and the 20 per cent for between 7.5 lakh and Rs 10 lakh. The 30 per cent tax bracket could remain unchanged for income above Rs 10 lakh, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming a person with total income of Rs 8 lakh and saves Rs 1.5 lakh under Section 80C and gets deduction of Rs 50,000 towards house rent, he/she has to pay income tax of Rs 45,000 (excluding cess.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the exemption limit is raised to Rs 5 lakh and income between Rs 5 lakh and 7.5 lakh is taxed at 10 per cent, the same person will have to pay a tax of Rs 10,000 (excluding cess), assuming that he/she saves Rs 1.5 lakh under Section 80C and gets deduction of Rs 50,000 towards house rent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if a person earns Rs 15 lakh and saves Rs 1.5 lakh under Section 80C and gets a tax deduction of Rs 1 lakh on rent paid, the tax liability comes to Rs 2 lakh. If the exemption limit is hiked to Rs 5 lakh and income between Rs 5 lakh and Rs 7.5 lakh is taxed at 10 per cent and Rs 7.5 lakh to Rs 10 lakh is taxed at 20 per cent and beyond Rs 10 lakh at 30 per cent, the tax liability of the will be come down to Rs 1.5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Home Loan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDFC Chief Economist Indranil Pan said that the government could also provide higher income tax exemptions on housing loans to boost the property sector which has suffered in the wake of demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report from real estate consultant Knight Frank said property sales volume in top cities falling to a 6-year low in the wake of demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporate Tax Expectations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley in his second Budget speech in February 2015 had announced reducing the corporate tax rate from 30 per cent to 25 per cent over a period of time. In a survey by Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu India LLP, commissioned on budget expectations of India Inc, 53 per cent of the respondents expect the corporate tax rate to be reduced this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rahul Garg of PwC believes that the government could reduce corporate tax rate by 1 percentage point to 29 per cent in this Budget.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To negate Reliance Jio&#39;s threat, Vodafone may join hands with Idea</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/negate-reliance-jios-threat-vodafone-may-join-hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/negate-reliance-jios-threat-vodafone-may-join-hands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vodafone Group Plc doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much of a choice but to accelerate consolidation moves in India — likely with Idea Cellular with whom it is in talks — as the UK telecom major tries to counter Reliance Jio Infocomm in a key market where it has been struggling to ward off value erosion, add customers and grow revenue market share (RMS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India, the No. 2 telco, and third ranked Idea are reckoned to be in merger talks, people aware of the matter told ET, with latest discussions locked over who will have operational control of the merged entity. If the two decide to merge, the new entity will be the largest telco in India by revenue and subscribers, replacing Bharti Airtel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent reports suggested Vodafone could also be open to a consolidation with Jio, but the latter has denied it, saying it is focusing on organic growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industry insiders expect a Vodafone and Idea consolidation to be the more likely option. Any such move though will face regulatory hurdles associated with spectrum caps and significant market power in terms of combined customer base and RMS, but these, they say, can be dealt with as the companies will have a year to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;INDUS TOWERS STAKE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ex-Bharti Airtel CEO Sanjay Kapoor said the big challenge for Vodafone and Idea would be &amp;ldquo;how they take a call with Bharti Airtel on the future control of Indus Towers&amp;rdquo;, especially since the combined entity would become the majority 58% shareholder of India’s biggest tower company, reducing Bharti to a minority shareholder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharti and Vodafone are equal stakeholders in Indus with 42% holdings each, while Idea owns the remaining 16%. Bharti’s Indus stake is routed through tower arm Bharti Infratel. Airtel is also looking to pare stake in Infratel, which only complicates the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea&amp;rsquo;s stake in Indus is routed through subsidiary, Aditya Birla Telecom (ABTL). Since US private equity firm Providence Equity Partners reportedly has stakes in both Idea and ABTL, it effectively owns 5% of Indus, with Idea&amp;rsquo;s real ownership at 11%. Accordingly, the net Idea-Vodafone combined holding in Indus is 53%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another senior executive agreed &amp;ldquo;control of Indus&amp;rdquo; would be critical for Vodafone and influence the pace of the merger with Idea, since a substantial part of the value of the British carrier&amp;rsquo;s India operation is reckoned to stem from its Indus stake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BLEEDING FROM JIO&amp;rsquo;S ENTRY&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India&amp;rsquo;s financial woes have lately been exacerbated by the bruising impact of Jio&amp;rsquo;s free voice and data services launched last September that will continue till end of March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mix of its recent £4.4 billion write-down, its till now modest on ground 4G spectrum footprint reflected in slower customer adds, and continuing price cuts in response to Jio&amp;rsquo;s free services have further hit revenues and profits, which have all contributed to the consolidation overtures.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/image-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The impact of Jio&amp;rsquo;s free services has already dealt a body blow to Bharti Airtel, which reported a 55% fall in its third quarter net profit to Rs 504 crore, its worst in four years, amid a first ever on-year revenue drop too. But Vodafone India and Idea are expected to perform a lot worse, with some analysts estimating Idea to report its first ever net loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone though said it is fast expanding its 4G footprint and is well placed to take on the new player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consolidation talks have pushed Idea&amp;rsquo;s stock price higher in recent times with returns on its scrip at 9.3% over the past month, ahead of Airtel&amp;rsquo;s 8.7%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At press time, neither Vodafone nor Idea confirmed their merger talks. However, in response to ET&amp;rsquo;s detailed queries, a Vodafone India spokesman said the company remained &amp;ldquo;committed to investing and continuing to grow its businesses in India” and that it had &amp;ldquo;successfully launched 4G services across all 17 circles planned and is on course to make it available across 2,400 towns by March 2017&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONSOLIDATION ONLY OPTION?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An analyst at IIFL said M&amp;amp;A appears to be the only option left for Vodafone, which has been struggling with RMS relatively flat at 23% for the last 14-15 quarters, a view seconded by Jaideep Ghosh, partner &amp;amp; COO (management consulting) at KPMG India, who noted that Vodafone is &amp;ldquo;a late entrant&amp;rdquo; in 4G.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kapoor feels blending Vodafone and Idea&amp;rsquo;s distinct corporate ecosystems to derive the targeted synergies towards a healthier bottomline would be the other key challenge for both companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another top industry executive said Vodafone and Idea may not find it too tough to rejig customer numbers to within requisite post-merger limits by weeding out dormant subscribers by reclassifying active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said any potential RMS breaches (beyond 50%) will also get rebalanced in a year, post merger, once Jio starts generating RMS, which would reduce the RMS of Vodafone and Idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s telecom merger and acquisition rules require a merged entity to hold up to 25% of total assigned spectrum and up to 50% in a specific band. This apart, the rules entail a merged entity&amp;rsquo;s combined customer market share and RMS does not exceed 50%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brokerage CLSA said a potential Vodafone-Idea combine would breach requisite spectrum caps in five circles but industry veteran and ex-VSNL chairman, BK Syngal said this can easily be overcome if Vodafone and Idea surrender excess spectrum to the government.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre pushes for fingerprint money transactions through Aadhaar Pay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-pushes-fingerprint-money-transactions-aadhaar-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-pushes-fingerprint-money-transactions-aadhaar-pay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aadhaar Pay is the merchant version of the already in use Aadhaar-enabled payment system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It works on any android-based phone, with an attached finger biometric device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andhra Bank, IDFC Bank, IndusInd Bank, State Bank of India and Syndicate Bank have gone live over Aadhaar Pay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keen to push digital payments among the poor and illiterate in rural areas of the country, the government is pushing to popularise Aadhaar Pay which ensures financial transactions by just using fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay, which is merchant version of the already in use Aadhaar-enabled payment system (AEPS), will become an alternative for all online and card transactions which require password and PIN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app facilitates merchants to take cashless payments from a customer who is only required to give his Aadhaar number, name of the bank (from where the money is to be deducted) and finger print for authentication. Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) CEO AB Pandey said Aadhaar Pay works on any android-based phone, even a low cost one, with an attached finger biometric device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This ensures digital transactions which are cardless, PINless… There is no need of smartphone for the customers,” he added. In order to popularise the use of Aadhaar Pay among merchants, the government has asked banks to enrol 30-40 merchants per branch so that they are able to take cashless payments from customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present five banks — Andhra Bank, IDFC Bank, IndusInd Bank, State Bank of India and Syndicate Bank — have gone live over Aadhaar Pay and several banks are in the process of launching pilots on the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior official said the plan is to identify Aadhaar Pay transactions separately and to incentivise merchants for long-term sustainability and scalability of the system. As it needs a biometric device costing about Rs 2,000, the government is also working on an incentive model so that cost of the device is amortised over time and the merchants are encouraged to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rejecting security concerns over AEPS, the UIDAI CEO said transactions using Aadhaar Pay are much more secure than any other digital mode of transaction, both in terms of technology and process. Besides the merchant using the app being enrolled in the bank and the customer’s bank account linked to Aadhaar, he said the biometric data get encrypted leaving little scope for any misuse. “Fingerprints can’t be copied as it get encrypted. Even if any merchant or customer tries to misuse the fingerprints, he will be caught immediately as the location of merchants using the app is known to the bank,” he explained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AEPS platform, launched in December 2012, enabled people to carry out banking transactions over hand-held devices (micro ATM) using the Aadhaar number and fingerprints. The Andhra Pradesh government has launched cashless payments at most of the fair price shops (FPS) and Gujarat, in partnership with CSC e-governance, has launched cashless payments using AEPS platform at over 3,000 fair price shops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPCI has no jurisdiction over us: PhonePe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-no-jurisdiction-us-phonepe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-no-jurisdiction-us-phonepe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Flipkart-owned payments app PhonePe’s co-founder &amp;amp; CEO Sameer Nigam has said that the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) had no legal jurisdiction to `direct’ his company or Flipkart to do anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bengaluru:The ongoing tussle between India’s largest private sector bank ICICI Bank and payments startup PhonePe isn’t showing signs of abating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Flipkart-owned payments app PhonePe’s co-founder &amp;amp; CEO Sameer Nigam has said that the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) had no legal jurisdiction to `direct’ his company or Flipkart to do anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nigam’s comments come after NPCI, an umbrella organisation for all retail payment systems in India, said last Friday that PhonePe should comply with its guidelines before ICICI Bank would allow its customers to register on the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last one week, ICICI Bank and PhonePe have been engaged in a public wrangle after the bank blocked its accountholders from registering with PhonePe for digital payments through the Unified Payment Interface (UPI) platform. PhonePe had partnered with private sector lender Yes Bank to go live on UPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a blog post on Sunday , Nigam said: “NPCI can direct its member banks. PhonePe is Yes Bank’s client, not NPCI’s client. Flipkart is PhonePe’s client–definitely not NPCI’s.We have no direct agreements with NPCI.“ For now, PhonePe has disabled payments through UPI platform on Flipkart’s Android app temporarily, it said on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nigam also countered ICICI Bank’s arguments on interoperability and data security concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweeping reforms in Civil Supplies Dept: EPOS machines in all 16,560 FP shops soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sweeping-reforms-civil-supplies-dept-epos-machines-16560-fp-shops-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sweeping-reforms-civil-supplies-dept-epos-machines-16560-fp-shops-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As directed by the Union government and also at the behest of the State Government, the Civil Supplies department has opened its doors for sweeping reforms with the implementation of Electronic Point of Sale (EPOS) Unit system throughout the State. Now EPOS machines are provided with advanced features and at a low price too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A committee under the guidance of CGG with C.V. Anand, Civil Supplies Commisioner, as Chairman has been formed to finalize the tenders. The Secretaries of Finance and IT depts., MD of APTS, Director of NIC, Hyderabad CRO were included as members in it. Consequently the committee started the tender process in August 2016 and completed its task within five months. Sandip Kumar Sultania, Finance Secretary, V. Prem Chand, APTC Managing Director and other members of the Committee also participated in the last meeting held on Saturday night and finalized the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messrs Oasys Cybernetics Pvt Ltd, has won the tender by quoting a lowest rental of Rs 1,499 per month per unit. The other two companies quoted Rs 1,548 and Rs 1,775 respectively. The committee saved Rs 3 crores per year to the exchequer by finalizing the tender purely on transparent methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the occasion, C.V. Anand explained about the changes made in the system. Now EPOS units are already in vogue in the FPSs of Greater Hyderabad for the implementation of PDS. These machines recognise the finger prints of the beneficiaries. Now Iris Scanner, Electronic weighing machine, swiping Aadhaar Enabled System (AEPAS), audio/voice features are the added facilities, explained C V Anand. As per the initiative of the Govt of India to conduct banking operations also through FPSs, micro ATMs would be positioned suitably and the dealer of FPS would hereafter work as Business Correspondent for banking operations in addition to his existing PDS responsibilities, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AEPS system: To make avail of this system, every card holder should have a bank account. While entering Aadhaar Number into the records after the distribution of essential commodities, the dealer also enters the bank account number of the beneficiary. This enables the dealer to get payment of the bill directly from the account of the card holder for the items purchased by the beneficiary. After the implementation of this system, the Department of Civil Supplies, would certainly take a lead in the State, in Cashless Transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPOS units would be installed in all the 16,560 FPSs in the entire State. The department would bear the total burden of Rs 1,499 per unit per month. Already in twin cities, the department was paying a rental of Rs 1650 per unit which is operating on biometric (finger print) technology. As the bidding process is conducted now at national level in transparent manner, the department has saved Rs 151 on each machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Union Minister for Consumer Affairs, Food and Public Distribution Ram Vilas Paswan held a meeting in New Delhi on January 19 with all the Commissioners of State-level Civil Supplies Departments and directed them to implement the cashless transactions through their network by the end of next March. While clarifying the firm determination of the Centre on Cashless transactions, the Minister had clarified to all the food Secretaries that in case of failure, some sort of cut would be imposed in the Central subsidy from April 15. He also informed the meeting that Rs 17 should be paid to the dealer of the FPS for every quintal, if he procured the EPOS unit on his own. He said he Union Government would pay half of that amount and the rest should be borne by the State Governments. As the Telangana government was arranging the machines on rental basis, the Central subsidy of Rs 8.50 would directly be credited to the State Treasury, Anand said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the biometric process, often problems are cropping up whenever the finger prints are hazy. So to get over it, IRIS is introduced and similarly voice over system would be of much help to the rural folk and particularly so to the illiterate, he explained. On the whole, with the introduction of EPOS in all the 16560 FPSs, every year approximately 15- 20% would be saved to the exchequer, which means an amount of Rs.750-800 crores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To curb irregularities in FPSs, EPOS machines have already been introduced in 1545 FPSs spread in the 9 circles of Hyderabad and 3 circles of RR Dists from last March onwards. These are bio metric machines and function on the basis of Aadhaar Number. So far, Rs 190 crores have been saved after the introduction of this system, the Commissioner added. EPOS helps in removing the irregularities in PDS, in ensuring that the benefits reach the card holder in full, in monitoring the accurate stock position in Fair Price shops at any given time etc, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>70% Of Notes To Be Remonetised By February-End: SBI Research</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-of-notes-to-be-remonetised-by-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-of-notes-to-be-remonetised-by-february/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roughly 70 million pieces of notes of different denominations are being printed per day at the printing press. This translates into around 1.8 billion pieces per month, said the SBI Research report, released on Friday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Reserve Bank of India&amp;rsquo;s current printing press capacity, 70 per cent of the notes will be remonetised and &amp;ldquo;normalcy will return most likely&amp;rdquo; by the end of February, according to a report by SBI Research, the economic research arm of State Bank of India. The report also noted, quoting Reserve Bank of India data, that Rs 7 lakh crore of new currency has been supplied till January 13, 2016, adding that &amp;ldquo;printing of new notes is going on at a pace keeping in mind the less cash future and not the past and we welcome this new normal&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roughly 70 million pieces of notes of different denominations are being printed per day at the printing press. This translates into around 1.8 billion pieces per month, said the SBI Research report, released on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is highly unlikely that RBI has only printed Rs 500 notes in entirety&amp;rdquo; given the current printing press capacity, due to the printing capacity of &amp;ldquo;less than 2 billion pieces a month, it seems going by the data&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hence, RBI has most likely also printed notes of varied smaller denominations as well as printing Rs 2000 notes, so as to optimise the printing capacity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we go by this trend, we are still maintaining that 70% of the notes will be remonetized by Feb-end,&amp;rdquo; the report said, adding, &amp;ldquo;Hence normalcy will return most likely by Feb-end.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The banking behemoth also welcomed the pace of printing of new currency notes. &amp;ldquo;To sum up, printing of new notes is going on at a pace keeping in mind the less cash future and not the past and we welcome this new normal. The future belongs to money as a medium of exchange and not as a store of value!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI also estimated newly supplied currency by February-end to be worth Rs 10.2 lakh crore. It also projected 62-72 per cent of total new currency in circulation by the end of February, as percentage of extinguished currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, a parliamentary panel member quoted RBI Governor Urjit Patel as saying the central bank has injected Rs 9.2 lakh crore worth of new currency notes into the banking system to help replace the notes banned on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Patel met the panel on finance to answer questions about the demonetisation move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government on November 8 last year announced demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes, or 86 per cent of the currency then in circulation, to flush out black money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About Rs 15.4 lakh crore worth of the notes were removed from circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Issuing New-Look And Tamper-Proof PAN Cards</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-issuing-new-look-and-tamper-proof-pan-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-issuing-new-look-and-tamper-proof-pan-cards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Government is issuing newly designed PAN &lt;em&gt;(Permanent Account Number)&lt;/em&gt; cards that have added security features to make them tamper-proof and with contents written in both Hindi and English, a senior Income-Tax Department official said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distribution of new-look PAN cards, being printed by NSDL and UTIITSL (UTI Infrastructure Technology and Services Ltd), started since January 1. The cards are being issued to new applicants but existing ones can only apply for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The distribution of new PAN cards kicked off on January 1. However, these are only for the fresh lot of PAN card applicants,&amp;rdquo; the official told PTI here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have automated the data and made the PAN cards error-free,&amp;rdquo; he said, adding, &amp;ldquo;In case existing cardholders apply for a fresh PAN card, they will be issued the newly designed cards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping in view the Rajbhasha policy of the Government, we have made fixed contents of the new PAN cards bilingual in which the headers are in English and Hindi, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government has added a new feature to the card, known as Quick Response Code, which will help in verification process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code will help in providing all details of the cardholder in one go as when the document is produced before any authority. Hence, no room will be left for the cardholder to either tamper or give any kind of wrong information relating to the card, the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PAN cards are mandatory for any transaction above Rs 2 lakh and for a lot of other activities like opening of a bank account and as identity proof. There are currently more than 25 crore PAN cardholders in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Government estimate, every year 2.5 crore people across the country apply for PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar number could be made compulsory for I-T returns in budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-number-made-compulsory-t-returns-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-number-made-compulsory-t-returns-budget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Business Standard has reported that the government is planning to insist on Aadhaar numbers for all those filing ncome tax (I-T) returns from the upcoming financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper reports sources in the government as saying that “relevant amendments to the Income Tax Act, 1961, in this Budget are under ‘active discussion’ to ensure mandatory linkage of tax returns to Aadhaar numbers”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report comes on the back of other measures to increase vigilance on the flow of money from and to accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has now asked banks to report deposits in any account aggregating Rs 10 lakh in a year, as well as cash payments of Rs 1 lakh or more on credit card bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks have also been asked to report deposits over Rs 10 lakh a year to the I-T department. In a January 17 notification, the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) had made it mandatory for a banking company or a cooperative bank to report cash deposits aggregating to Rs 10 lakh or more in a financial year, in one or more accounts (other than a current account and time deposit) of a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cash payments of Rs 1 lakh or more will also be reported Payments of an amount aggregating to Rs 1 lakh or more in cash, along with payments of Rs 10 lakh or more made by any mode (including cheque or wire transfer), towards settling credit card dues in a year will also have to reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOREX aggregating to Rs 10 lakh or more will also be reported Purchase of foreign exchange, including travellers cheque and forex card, aggregating to Rs 10 lakh or more will also need to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Property sales for over Rs 30 lakh needs to be reported to taxmen too Moreover, the Property Registrar will have to report sale or purchase by any person of immovable property for an amount of Rs 30 lakh or more to tax authorities, the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Employees Union Threaten Nation-Wide Strike On February 7</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/section-of-bank-employees-threaten-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/section-of-bank-employees-threaten-nation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unions are also demanding publishing names of individuals who have defaulted in paying loans of Rs 1 crore and above so that stringent measures could be taken to recover bad loans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A section of bank trade unions have threatened to go on a day-long nation-wide strike on February 7 to press various demands including complete removal of restrictions imposed during demonetisation period and safeguarding the autonomy of the Reserve Bank of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was expected that the government and the RBI would take necessary steps to mitigate the problems faced by the banks and the public but even now, we find that there is acute shortage of cash supply to the banks with the result that branches are not able to honour even the restricted payment of Rs 24,000/100,000 per week,&amp;rdquo; AIBEA General Secretary C H Vekatachalam said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from All India Bank Employees&amp;rsquo; Association( AIBEA), other unions which will be part of the strike are All India Bank Officers&amp;rsquo; Association (AIBOA) and Bank Employees Federation of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unions are also demanding publishing names of individuals who have defaulted in paying loans of Rs 1 crore and above so that stringent measures could be taken to recover bad loans. Other demands of banks include ensuring autonomy of RBI in cash management, compensation to family of general public, bank customers and bank staff who lost their lives in the demonetisation aftermath and payment of overtime to employees and officers for their additional effort during the 50-day demonetisation period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added that the government is interfering by appointing officials to monitor cash management which is affecting the autonomy of RBI. Cash management falls under the sole jurisdiction of RBI, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Humiliated&amp;rdquo; by the events since demonetisation, even RBI employees had written to Governor Urjit Patel protesting the operational &amp;ldquo;mismanagement&amp;rdquo; of the note ban exercise and the government impinging the apex bank&amp;rsquo;s autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a letter, the employees said that the autonomy and image of RBI has been &amp;ldquo;dented beyond repair&amp;rdquo; due to mismanagement and termed the appointment of a senior Finance Ministry official for currency coordination as a &amp;ldquo;blatant encroachment&amp;rdquo; of the RBI&amp;rsquo;s exclusive turf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customers Can Cancel Rail Tickets Booked Through Point-Of-Sale Machines</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-can-cancel-rail-tickets-booked-through-point-of-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-can-cancel-rail-tickets-booked-through-point-of-sale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Railway Ministry today spelt out the procedure for cancelling tickets booked through Point of Sale (PoS) machines as it prepares to install 10,000 of them across ticket reservation counters in a bid to encourage cashless transactions following demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of tickets booked through SBI PoS machines at a reservation counter, a customer can approach a counter and cancel his ticket. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to swipe his card again for cancellation as the refund will be credited directly to his or her bank account within 7 days, according to a statement issued by the Railway Ministry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where a customer has booked his ticket through a non-SBI PoS the customer needs to swipe his credit or debit card at the PoS machine at the time of cancellation. The refund amount will then be credited to his or her account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at a location where there is no PoS a Ticket Deposit Receipt (TDR) will be issued to affect the refund. In a situation where a customer has booked an e-ticket through a PoS IRCTC customer care will have to coordinate the refund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital payment firms hope for tax benefits in Union Budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payment-firms-hope-tax-benefits-union-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payment-firms-hope-tax-benefits-union-budget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They have also requested for extension of the import duty waiver on PoS terminals for card payments beyond March 31 as it expects the demand for such terminals to go up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If demonetisation got ‘Acche Din’ for digital payment companies, further tax incentives and rewards are things these entities are hoping for in the upcoming Union Budget to ensure customers stick to digital payments instruments and don’t migrate back to cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies in this space are hopeful that the Centre will follow the South Korea model where their government succeeded to switch a major chunk of payments in the country to digital means through tax benefits for both merchants and consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The government of South Korea did the maths around the fact that the number of people coming into the tax nets incrementally because of digital payments and the cost of cash to the GDP reducing would offset the temporary hit that they had in terms of tax payments,” said TR Ramachandran, group country manager, India and South Asia for Visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think this would be not only sustainable but also of great attraction for Indians who are careful about saving taxes under investments, home loans, etc,” he said. The payments industry through multiple meetings with finance minister Arun Jaitley is said to have presented various case studies of different countries to showcase a direct relation between tax benefits and uptick of digital transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tax benefits from both sides — merchants as well as consumers — will get more people to transact digitally. Merchants can get discount on service tax, sales tax, etc. while consumers can get benefits on income tax,” said Paresh Rajde, founder of Mumbai-based domestic remittance and payments company Suvidhaa Infoserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global payments company Mastercard said that the government should focus on small merchants and promote digital payments among them to address issues around credit underwriting and onboarding for this sector. “One of the biggest resistance factors for consumers to adopt electronic payments is their fears around safety and security. It is critical that the government take the safety and security agenda very seriously and invest in technology and fraud protection tools,” said Porush Singh, country corporate officer and division president South Asia for Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bankers said one major reason why merchants and small shopkeepers prefer to transact in cash is because they want to avoid tax net. Hence if they are given tax benefits on accepting payments digitally there would be more number of people taking it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industry has also requested for extension of the import duty waiver on PoS terminals for card payments beyond March 31as it expects the demand for such terminals to go up. While industry executives seek more support from the government to promote digital payments, there is also talk around some mention of cyber security as there are security concerns around digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everything that the government has announced, from UPI payments to Aadhaar authentication, there are huge security concerns around its implementation,” said Bhavin Turakhia, chief executive at payments technology company Zeta. “The government needs to recognise such concerns for both cards as well as UPI,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes Ban: Tax Department Gets Over Rs 300 Crore Declarations Under PMGKY</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/notes-ban-tax-department-gets-over-rs-300-crore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/notes-ban-tax-department-gets-over-rs-300-crore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax department has received confirmations for over Rs 300 crore declarations from across the country till now as part of the ongoing black money window called the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), brought out by the government post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officials said I-T department offices across the country have got a number of small to big declarations in this regard after the taxman launched a large number of search, survey, seizure and electronic database analysis operations to check stash funds hoarded or generated post the November 8, 2016 notes ban.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A top I-T department official confirmed that the declarations have reached &amp;ldquo;well above Rs 300 crore as per latest updated data.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An analysis report prepared in this regard, also accessed by PTI, said the latest declarations worth about Rs 140 crore have come from a clutch of over three dozen jewellers based in 16 cities of Maharashtra after the department carried out searches and surveys against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report added that a prominent jeweller in Hyderabad has also approached the department to declare alleged black funds to the tune of Rs 100 crore after his claim of getting &amp;ldquo;advance money from over 5,200 customers on the night of November 8 last year was found wrong&amp;rdquo; post I-T probe and the local police and the Enforcement Directorate went on to register criminal cases under their respective laws in this instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A doctor in a western state is also understood to have approached the taxman to declare Rs 11.50 crore of stash funds, it said adding in an another case involving the same professional declarations worth Rs 7 crore are being made  after the department nabbed the &amp;lsquo;benami&amp;rsquo; owner of the black money as one taxi driver and later confronted him with the man whose money it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A film producer based in Mumbai, it said, is also understood to have come forward to declare Rs 40 crore unaccounted income under the PMGKY which provides immunity from severe penalties and imprisonment under tax laws. There are few more such cases, the official said, coming across from various parts of the country but collating them ona regular basis is a time taking affair. In a case in the national capital, an operative of hawala business has represented his case before the taxman to declare Rs 80 lakh stash funds under the PMGKY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the PMGKY, undisclosed income deposited in any bank or post office account can be declared by paying 50 per cent of it in taxes and surcharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a quarter of the total sum is to be parked in a non-interest bearing deposit for four years. PMGKY was announced following the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to scrap Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes. Offering tax dodgers confidentially and immunity from prosecution, PMGKY commenced on December 17, 2016 and will remain open up to March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not declaring black money under the scheme now but showing it as income in the tax return form would lead to a total levy of 77.25 per cent in taxes and penalty. In case the disclosure is not made either using the scheme or in return, a further 10 per cent penalty on tax will be levied followed by prosecution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>