<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 19 To Rs 9,999: What Jio Prepaid, Postpaid Users Get</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering free voice calls and roaming on all its post-paid and pre-paid plans. Also there is no charge for data used to make 4G voice calls under all its plans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. Beyond the daily 4G data limits of 1GB and 2GB per day across its prepaid recharges and postpaid plans, wherever specified, subscribers will continue to use unlimited internet at a reduced speed of 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service - prepaid and postpaid alike - include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are various plans offered by Jio, as per its website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREPAID&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for just one day, Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid offerings start from the Rs 19 recharge, which includes 200 MB of 4G data for Prime members and 100 MB for non-Prime members, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 49&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s next recharge is priced at Rs 49. Jio Prime members recharging with the Rs 49 voucher get 600 MB of high speed data over a validity of three days. The 4G data on offer under this pack is limited to 300 MB for non-Prime members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 96&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge comes with 1GB of 4G data per day. That is for Prime members. Non-Prime members get 600MB of 4G data for seven days with a recharge of Rs 96.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 149&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data valid for 28 days for Prime users and 1GB for non-Prime subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime subscribers buying their first recharge of Rs 309 will get 1GB of 4G data per day for 84 days, as per the Jio website. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first recharge of Rs 509 offers 2GB of 4G data daily, for 84 days. This is comparable with half of the daily 4G data on offer in the Rs 309 pack. Data benefits on subsequent recharges of Rs 509 will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Rs 999 recharge comes with a validity of 120 days, in which subscribers get 120 GB of 4G data. Subsequent recharges are limited to 60 GB of 4G data for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A first recharge of Rs 1,999 comes with 185 GB of 4G data and validity of 150 days. The 4G data on offer is 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 4,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those buying their first recharge after subscribing to Prime will get 410 GB of 4G data with a validity of 240 days. Users will get 350 GB of 4G data with a validity of 180 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is priced at Rs. 9,999. Those buying their first recharge of Rs 9,999 are being offered 810 GB of 4G data with a validity of 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;postpaid&#34;&gt;POSTPAID&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First cycle: Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data per day - which sums up to 90GB of 4G data - for a period of three months under this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequent cycle: Customers will get 30GB of 4G data for a period of one month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering 2GB of 4G data per day for a period of three months on the first cycle, and one month on subsequent cycles. Therefore, users get 180GB of 4G data for three months in the first cycle, and 60GB for one month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first cycle, Jio is offering 180 GB of 4G data for three months under the Rs 999 postpaid plan. Users will get 60 GB of 4G data per month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How railway insurance has become a boon for many</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the Railway Ministry introduced an optional Indian railway travel insurance scheme for e-ticketing passengers in September 2016, the move was welcomed. But little did we know how useful the policy would become soon after. Given the recent spate of train accidents that have left many passengers injured and caused several deaths, the insurance scheme has come as a boon for many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy can be bought by passengers when booking tickets online from the IRCTC website or through the mobile app. Earlier, the cost of this policy was 92 paise per passenger for an insurance cover of Rs 10 lakh in cases of demise or permanent disability. However, Dipankar Acharya, Country Head-Affinity and Strategic Relationships, Royal Sundaram General Insurance, points out, “From 10 December 2016 the cost of premium for this policy is subsidised by the railways so passengers don’t have to pay anything. Everyone should opt for this insurance policy while travelling by railways.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy is valid from the time of departure of train to the time of arrival of train at the destination. If an accident occurs during the journey, the injured passenger or the nominee of the deceased passenger will get the claim amount. If an insured passenger is injured, and it causes their demise within 12 months of the accident, their nominee can also claim Rs 10 lakh as per insurance policy. In case of injuries, passenger can claim hospitalisation expenses up to Rs 2 lakh which includes room rent for hospital, medicines, diagnostic test, nursing charges, ICU charges, operation theatre charges, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the exclusions under this policy are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intentional self-injury, suicide or attempted suicide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim in instances wherein ticket was booked by the Insured, but they did not board the train, irrespective of whether the train ticket was cancelled or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim in instances where the ticket was booked but wasn’t confirmed, but the passenger still boarded the train.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any medical treatment which was not medically necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has tied up with three general insurance companies - ICICI Lombard, Royal Sundaram and Shriram General Insurance - for policy issuance. Once you book the tickets, you will receive the policy details on your registered mobile number and mentioned email ID. The next important step is to update the name of your nominee on the insurance company’s website before travelling. “The benefit of appointing a nominee is that it helps to settle the claim quickly in the wake of unfortunate train accidents. If a nominee is not appointed, the process of claim settlement much longer, since legal heir certificate has to be produced,” says Acharya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a claim, the insured or nominee must submit a report of the railway authority confirming the accident of the train, a claim form, medical reports, death or disability certificate, ID proof, and NEFT details and a cancelled cheque to the insurance company. After the submission, the claim is settled within 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Easing the burden&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The insured passenger or nominee can claim the following amounts.&lt;/em&gt;
*On death: Rs 10 lakh
*On permanent total disability: Rs 10 lakh
*On permanent partial disability: Rs 7.5 lakh
*Hospitalisation expenses for injury: Rs 2 lakh
*Transportation of mortal remains: Rs 10,000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also bear logo of 125th anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year &amp;ldquo;1891&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in English shall be written on the upper and lower periphery of the coin respectively. The year &amp;ldquo;1916&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in international numerals shall be written respectively on left and right top of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI said the existing coins in this denomination shall also continue to be legal tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 5 coin, the RBI said the coin&amp;rsquo;s face will bear an image depicting centre facade of Allahabad High Court Building emerging from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 1866-2016 in English numerals shall be written at the bottom of the image, the RBI said in a release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on &lt;em&gt;Rs 3,050&lt;/em&gt; crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.
He did not give further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department, on April 5, wrote to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) asking it to give a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo; on the penalty issue, and also outline the basis and provisions of law under which the said amount had been recommended by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources familiar with the matter said that DoT, in its communication, has also asked the Trai to provide information on the number of subscribers acquired by Reliance Jio during the testing phase (that is prior to its commercial launch). The incumbent operators and the Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio clashed last year over the issue of call connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio cried foul that its customers were suffering from call failures as the incumbent operators were not giving it sufficient interconnect capacity. The operators, in turn, charged the newcomer of unleashing a &amp;ldquo;tsunami&amp;rdquo; of free traffic on their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interconnection enables mobile users to make calls to customers of other telecom networks and is, therefore, crucial for smooth functioning of mobile services. In October last year, Trai recommended to the Telecom Department, the imposition of total penalty of Rs 3,050 crore on the three incumbent operators Bharti Airtel, Vodafone and Idea Cellular for allegedly denying interconnectivity to the
new entrant that led to deterioration in the quality of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Trai&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, the penalty for Airtel and Vodafone worked out to about Rs 1,050 crore each, while in case of Idea Cellular stood at about Rs 950 crore. The regulator, in fact, had stopped short of recommending cancellation of their telecom licences saying it may lead to significant consumer inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the issue was placed before the Telecom Commission earlier this year, the highest policy-making body of the telecom department, it favoured referring the matter back to Trai for a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Commission asked DoT to seek clarification from Trai on nearly a dozen points, including whether the stipulated 90-day period was given to the three telecom operators for providing point of interconnection to the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Offers Education Loan At 8.5% Interest Rate. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI is offering an interest rate of 8.5 per cent on education loans for studying in select business schools. As part of SBI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Scholar Loan&amp;rdquo; scheme, select leading institutions where Indian students can get the concessional rate of interest include Indian Institute of Management (IIM)-Ahmedabad, IIM-Calcutta and Indian School of Business-Hyderabad or ISB-Hyderabad. This was said in a tweet by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI which recently unveiled a new brand identity after merging its operations with six other banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years. Scholar loans offer an interest rate between 8.5 per cent and 10.6 per cent and cover higher education courses in select 120 premier Indian institutions, as per SBI&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-scholar-loan-rates_650x400_81492094420.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education loan at rate of interest of 8.5%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s scholar loans cover a multitude of courses from institutions under four categories: &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;. An effective rate of interest of 8.5 per cent is offered on institutes listed by SBI under the AA category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Institutes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has listed seven &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo; institutions - for which Indian students can apply for up to Rs. 30 lakh of loans - including four IIMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These Indian institutions are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Ahmedabad IIM-Calcutta IIM-Bangalore IIM-Kozhikode Indian School of Business, Hyderabad Indian School of Business, Mohali Campus Xavier Labour Relations Institute, Jamshedpur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is covered?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The loans disbursed under SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme covers college fees (including examination, hostel, library and laboratory fees), purchase of books, equipment and instrument as well as travel expenses and expenses on exchange programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approval time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers quick sanctioning of scholar loans at designated campus branches or more than 5,000 select branches, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Reduces Term Deposit Rates By Up To 0.5%</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI said the rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India has cut its term deposit rates by up to 50 basis points for various maturities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the new structure, for two to less than three years deposits, SBI will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier, the bank said. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For deposits maturing between three years and 10 years, the rates have been lowered by 25 basis points to 6.50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lender will be offering the new rates for fresh deposits and renewals and are applicable from April 29, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short term deposits, that is, for deposits maturing between seven days to less than two years, the rates have been left unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank is offering highest rates of 6.90 per cent for one year to 455 days term deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also not changed its marginal cost of funds based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI में टोकन लेकर नहीं करना पड़ेगा इंतजार, बिना लाइन में लगे ऐसे मिलेगी इंस्‍टैंट सर्विस</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/state-bank-of-india-sbi-customers-and-non-customers-can-save-time-through-no-sbi-queue-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/state-bank-of-india-sbi-customers-and-non-customers-can-save-time-through-no-sbi-queue-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;भारतीय स्टेट बैंक (एसबीआई) ने ‘नो क्यू’ सर्विस शुरू की है। अब लोगों को लंबी लाइन में लगने से निजात मिल सकेगा, एसबीआई ने अपनी ई-टोकन सर्विस (e-token) शुरू की है। कस्टमर यह टोकन इसकी नई ऐप नो क्यू (No Queue) से ले सकते हैं। इस सर्विस का फायदा उठाने के लिए स्मार्टफोन होना जरूरी है। यूजर अपने एंड्रॉयड या आईओएस स्मार्टफोन में एसबीआई का नो क्यू ऐप डाउनलोड कर सकते हैं। इसके लिए एसबीआई का ग्राहक होना जरूरी नहीं है। इस ऐप के जरिए स्टेट बैंक की पांच सेवाओं को चुना जा सकता है। इनमें कैश जमा करना, कैश निकालना, चेक डिपॉजिट, डिमांड ड्राफ्ट, एनईएफटी/आरटीजीएस शामिल हैं। यूजर इस ऐप के जरिए ई-टोकन या यूं कहें कि वर्चुअल टिकट ले सकते हैं। इस सर्विस में अभी भारतीय स्टेट बैंक की सभी शाखाअों को शामिल नहीं किया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गूगल प्ले स्टोर पर इस ऐप को लेकर की गई व्याख्या के मुताबिक, ऐप से आपको ‘लाइन में अपनी मौजूदगी का रियल टाइम स्टेटस’ पता चलता रहेगा। यदि आप घर या ऑफिस या रास्ते में कहीं हैं तब आप इसके जरिए ई-टोकन लेकर अपना अच्छा खासा समय बचा सकते हैं। ऐप से आपको यह पता चलता रहेगा कि कितने लोग लाइन में हैं, कितने लोग आपसे आगे हैं। ऐप डाउनलोड करके उस पर रजिस्टर होने वाले सभी ग्राहकों को ये सुविधाएं मिलेंगी। यह ऐप और इसमें मिलने वाली सुविधाएं फ्री हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आपको बता दें कि देश के सबसे बड़े बैंक भारतीय स्टेट बैंक ने होम लोन की ब्याज दरों में कटौती की है। एसबीआई ने 30 लाख रुपये तक के होम लोन पर ब्याज दर में 0.25 फीसदी की कटौती की है। अब 30 लाख रुपये तक का होम लोन ग्राहकों को 8.35 फीसदी की ब्याज दर पर मिलेगा। इससे पहले इन ग्राहकों को 8.60 फीसदी की दर से ब्याज देना होता था। नई दरें 9 मई से लागू हो जाएंगी। वहीं 30 लाख रुपये से ज्यादा के लोन पर  0.10 फीसदी कम ब्याज देना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एसबीआई के मुताबिक, प्रधानमंत्री आवास योजना के तहत ग्राहक 2.67 लाख रुपये की ब्याज सब्सिडी भी ले सकते हैं। वहीं, एसबीआई ने बताया कि अगर कोई नौकरी करने वाली महिला कस्टमर होम लोन लेती है तो उसे 8.35 फीसदी की ब्याज दर पर लोन मिलेगा। वहीं दूसरे ग्राहकों को होम लोन 8.40 फीसदी की दर पर मिलेगा। यह ऑफर केवल 9 मई से 31 जुलाई तक लिए जाने वाले होम लोन पर ही लागू होगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मशीन सूंघकर बताएगी आप बीमार है या नहीं!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ऐसी मशीन आपके सामने होगी जो सूंघकर बता देगी कि आप बीमार हैं या नहीं। रिसर्चर्स एक ऐसी मशीन पर काम कर रहे हैं जो आपकी सांस, ब्लड और यूरीन से आपका रोग पहचान लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हम सभी की एक यूनीक स्मेल होती है जो हजारों कार्बनिक यौगिक से मिलकर बनती है। इस महक से हमारी उम्र, जेनटिक, लाइफस्टाइल, होमटाउन और यहां तक की हमारे मेटाबॉलिक प्रोसेस के बारे में भी पता चलता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्राचीन यूनानी और चीनी चिकित्सक रोग को पहचानने के लिए मरीज की खुश्बू का इस्तेमाल किया करते थे। मॉर्डन मेडिकल रिचर्स में भी यह बात सामने आई है कि किसी की त्वचा और सांस की गंध बीमारी का सूचक हो सकते हैं। एक्सपर्ट रिपोर्ट्स की मानें तो मधुमेह रोगियों की सांस कभी-कभी सड़े हुए सेब जैसी, वहीं टाइफाइड रोगियों की त्वचा बेकिंग ब्रेड जैसी गंध देती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वैसे तो हर डॉक्टर भी कुछ बीमारियों को किसी हद तक सूंघ सकता है, लेकिन यह इस पर निर्भर करता है कि उसकी नाक कितनी संवेदनशील है और वह सूंघ कर बीमारियां पहचानने का कितना अनुभवी है। इस वजह से रिसर्चर्स कम खर्च में एक ऐसे सेंसर पर काम कर रहे हैं जो रोग को पहचान ले।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह सेंसर एक सिलिकॉन चिप है जिस पर कई मेटल लेयर्स और छोटे गोल्ड इलेक्ट्रॉड्स लगे होंगे। यह मोबाइल फोन के सिम कार्ड जैसा दिखाई देगा और केमिकल फिल्टर जैसे काम करेगा। इस मशीन को इलेक्ट्रॉनिक नाक कहें तो गलत नहीं होगा, जो आदमी की नाक की तुलना में कहीं सटीक और बेहतर ढंग से रोग की पहचान कर लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार को संजीवनी बूटी की तरह पेश कर रही सरकार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-linking-only-curb-pan-card-duplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-linking-only-curb-pan-card-duplication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को इनकम टैक्स के पर्मानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के साथ जोड़ना जरूरी करने के सरकार के कदम का विरोध कर रहे लोगों ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट से कहा कि सरकार आधार को सभी बुराइयों के लिए संजीवनी बूटी के तौर पर पेश कर रही है। आधार को PAN के साथ जोड़ने के लिए इनकम टैक्स एक्ट में संशोधन को चुनौती देने वाली याचिकाओं की सुनवाई कर रही दो जजों की बेंच से सीनियर ऐडवोकेट अरविंद पी दातार ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार उन हर्बल दवाओं में से एक बन गया है, जो सभी का उपचार कर सकती हैं&amp;hellip;आतंकवाद, ब्लैक मनी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस संशोधन के जरिए 1 जुलाई से आधार कार्ड से लिंक्ड न होने वाला PAN अवैध हो जाएगा। सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने गुरुवार को इस पर अपना फैसला सुरक्षित रखा। इससे पहले हुई सुनवाइयों में सरकार ने कानून का पक्ष लेते हुए इस बात को गलत बताया था कि इस कदम से प्रिवेसी को खतरा होगा। दातार ने गुरुवार को सरकार के इस नजरिए पर सवाल उठाया कि आधार और PAN को लिंक करने से ब्लैक मनी पर रोक लगेगी। उनका कहना था, &amp;lsquo;इससे पैन कार्ड के डुप्लिकेशन पर रोक लगेगी, ब्लैक मनी पर नहीं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;सरकार के 2005 के डेटा के अनुसार केवल 0.4 पर्सेंट PAN कार्ड डुप्लिकेटेड हैं और इसे देखते हुए इस तरह का कदम उठाना उचित नहीं है। 0.4 पर्सेंट के लिए 99.6 पर्सेंट को परेशान करने का क्या मतलब है? इस बदलाव की जरूरत दिखाने वाला नया डेटा कहां है?&amp;rsquo; उनकी दलील थी कि नए सिस्टम से वे छोटे कारोबारी बर्बाद हो जाएंगे जिनके पास किसी कारण से आधार या PAN नहीं होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि इन दोनों को लिंक न करने वाले लोग अपना इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न नहीं भर सकेंगे और इस वजह से उन्हें भारी पेनल्टी चुकानी पड़ सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दातार ने कहा कि कानून में इस तरह के महत्वपूर्ण बदलाव को लेकर संसद में कोई बहस नहीं की गई और न ही इसे एक कमेटी के पास भेजा गया है। उन्होंने बताया कि फाइनेंस बिल पर केवल एक सामान्य चर्चा हुई है। उन्होंने सरकार पर आधार को चरणों में नागरिकों पर थोपने का आरोप लगाया। उनका कहना था कि कानून में कोई भी बदलाव आधार ऐक्ट में संशोधन के जरिए किया जाना चाहिए था, इनकम टैक्स ऐक्ट में नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;याचिकाकर्ताओं ने दलील दी थी कि फिंगरप्रिंट और आइरिस स्कैन लेने वाले आधार को PAN के साथ जोड़ने से व्यक्तियों के शरीर को लेकर अधिकार का उल्लंघन हुआ है। हालांकि, इसे लेकर सरकार के वकील ने पिछले सप्ताह कहा था कि व्यक्ति का शरीर को लेकर अधिकार संपूर्ण नहीं है। सीनियर एडवोकेट सलमान खुर्शीद ने सरकार के इस नजरिए के विरोध में कहा कि कुछ मूल मानवाधिकारों को छीना नहीं जा सकता।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>नोटबंदी के बाद सोने और फर्जी कंपनियों में खपाई गई थी ब्लैक मनी: IT सूत्र</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/black-money-converted-into-gold-stored-in-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/black-money-converted-into-gold-stored-in-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी के बाद ब्लैक मनी से बड़े पैमाने पर सोने की खरीदारी की गई थी या फिर इन अज्ञात पैसों को फर्जी कंपनियां बनाकर उसमें खपाया गया था। नोटबंदी के बाद देशभर में पड़े छापों के दौरान यह जानकारी सामने आई थी। आयकर विभाग के सूत्रों ने बताया कि ब्लैक मनी रखने वाले लोगों ने ये पैसे बैंकों में डिपॉजिट नहीं किए क्योंकि वे अपनी पहचान गुप्त रखना चाहते थे। नोटबंदी के दौरान कई जूलर्स ने लोगों की ब्लैक मनी को सोने में बदल दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जांच में शामिल रहे एक अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo; पिछले साल 8 नवंबर को पीएम नरेंद्र मोदी की नोटबंदी की घोषणा के बाद लोगों ने अपनी ब्लैक मनी को सोने और जूलरी खरीदने में लगा दी। जूलर्स ने इसके बाद अलग-अलग बिल देकर लोगों की असली पहचान छिपा ली।&amp;rsquo; बता दें कि 8 नवंबर को ही पीएम मोदी ने 500 और 1000 रुपये के नोट को चलन से बाहर करने की घोषणा की थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सूत्र ने बताया कि नोटबंदी को जूलर्स ने अपनी बिक्री बढ़ाने का जरिया माना और वे ऐसे पैसों को गहनों की बिक्री दिखाकर बच गए। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जूलर्स ने अज्ञात आय को सोने में बदलने का प्लैटफ़ॉर्म उपलब्ध कराया।&amp;rsquo; जो बिल दिए गए वो अलग-अलग थे और दो लाख रुपये से कम के थे। इसके अलावा खरीदारों की सूची भी फर्जी थी। जांच के बाद पता चला कि कई खरीदार तो वित्तीय तौर पर काफी कमजोर थे और वे बिल में दिखाई गई राशि इतना पैसा खर्च करने की स्थिति में ही नहीं थे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने जूलर्स से सवाल पूछा था कि कैसे नोटबंदी के बाद उनके पास इतनी मांग बढ़ी, खासतौर पर त्योहारी सीजन बीत जाने के बाद। आयकर रेडार के निशाने पर आए सेंको गोल्ड लिमिटेड के चेयरमैन शंकर सेन ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;हमने सभी खरीदारों द्वारा दिए गए नाम और कॉन्टैक्टस के आधार पर सारा रेकॉर्ड रखा है। हम इस मामले में विभाग की जांच में मदद कर रहे हैं और उन्हें सभी दस्तावेज मुहैया करा रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जूलर्स के लिए यह जांच पाना काफी मुश्किल है कि खरीदार ने सही जानकारी दी है या नहीं। खासकर तब जब खरीदारी दो लाख रुपये से कम की हो। गौरतलब है कि आयकर विभाग ने 29 नवंबर के बाद ब्लैक मनी वालों के खिलाफ जांच तेज कर दी थी। दरअसल इस समय तक विभाग सीबीडीटी और अन्य एजेंसियों से पैसों के मूवमेंट पर सूचनाएं एकत्र कर रहा था।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पीएम नरेंद्र मोदी ने बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी के खिलाफ ऐक्शन तेज करने का दिया आदेश</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/prime-minister-narendra-modi-orders-speedy-action-against-unaccounted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/prime-minister-narendra-modi-orders-speedy-action-against-unaccounted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;काले धन पर अंकुश के लिए नोटबंदी जैसा कड़ा कदम उठाने के बाद केंद्र की नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार के निशाने पर अब बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी है। प्रधानमंत्री मोदी ने राजस्व अधिकारियों के साथ समीक्षा बैठक में ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के बारे में जानकारी ली। सूत्रों के मुताबिक पीएम मोदी ने बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी पर ऐक्शन का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैठक में पीएम मोदी ने वित्त मंत्रालय के अधिकारियों से बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी रखने वालों के खिलाफ कार्रवाई तेज करने को कहा। सरकारी सूत्रों के मुताबिक पीएम ने कहा कि ई-असेस्मन्ट जल्द से जल्द लागू होना चाहिए ताकि न्यूनतम हस्तक्षेप हो। असेस्मन्ट कम्प्यूटराइज्ड होना चाहिए। पीएम ने यह भी कहा कि टैक्स के दायरे में और लोग आएं ताकि कर का आधार बढ़ाया जा सके।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने सोमवार को वित्त मंत्रालय द्वारा वस्तु और सेवा कर (जीएसटी) को लागू करने को लेकर की गई तैयारियों और नोटबंदी के बाद कालेधन के खिलाफ अभियान की समीक्षा की। सूत्रों ने बताया कि राजस्व विभाग के साथ बैठक में मोदी ने जीएसटी को लेकर तैयारियों का जायजा लिया। सूत्रों ने कहा कि इस समीक्षा बैठक में वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली, राजस्व सचिव हसमुख अधिया और राजस्व विभाग के अन्य वरिष्ठ अधिकारी मौजूद थे।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Mandatory For Filing Tax Returns, PAN Card From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting of Aadhaar has been made mandatory for filing income tax returns with effect from July 1, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, an official statement said on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961 as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017 provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar /Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from July 1,&amp;rdquo; said a Finance Ministry statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or Enrolment ID will apply only to a person who is eligible to obtain Aadhaar number, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act, 2016, only a resident individual is entitled to obtain Aadhaar. Resident as per the said Act means an individual who has resided in India for a period or periods amounting in all to 182 days or more in the 12 months immediately preceding the date of application for enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the requirement to quote Aadhaar as per section 139AA of the Income-tax Act shall not apply to an individual who is not a resident as per the Aadhaar Act, 2016, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar mandatory to avoid fake PAN cards: Government tells Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government today defended in the Supreme Court its decisionto make Aadhaar mandatory for issuing of PAN cards, saying it was done to curb the use of fake PAN cards across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi told a bench comprising Justices A K Sikri and Ashok Bhushan that the programme of PAN had become suspect as it could be faked while Aadhaar is a &amp;ldquo;secure and robust&amp;rdquo; system by which the identity of an individual cannot be faked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AG said that due to Aadhaar, government has saved over Rs 50,000 crore on the schemes to benefit the poor as well as the pension schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that around 10 lakh PAN cards have been cancelled, while out of the 113.7 crore Aadhaar cards issued, no case of duplication has been found by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that Aadhaar was an effective tool to check the menace of terror funding and circulation of black money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The idea behind Aadhaar is to make a secure and robust system by which the identity of a person cannot be faked,&amp;rdquo; the Attorney General told the court, which would continue hearing the arguments tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court is hearing three petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Section 139 AA of the Income Tax Act which was introduced through the latest budget and the Finance Act 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Section 139AA provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns and making an application for allotment of PAN number with effect from July 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior counsel Shyam Divan, representing the petitioners, had earlier argued that section 139AA was unconstitutional and was in &amp;ldquo;direct collision&amp;rdquo; with the Aadhaar Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had also contended that there was no question of forcing a person to give his consent for Aadhaar and this was an issue which &amp;ldquo;alters the relationship of Republic of India with its citizens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The petitioner had also argued that a law-abiding tax payer cannot be forced to give his Aadhaar number while filing income tax returns and this was like an &amp;ldquo;electronic leash&amp;rdquo; as government would be able to keep a tab on its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nowhere in the world there is such a biometric system which can track a person 24X7. They (government) are doing it even before the age of consent,&amp;rdquo; he had said during the arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had earlier put a poser as to why there was no objection from the lawmakers on the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for making PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rohatgi had also clarified that nowhere in section 139AA of IT Act, was it mentioned that it would be effective with retrospective effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had earlier told the apex court that fake PAN cards were being used to &amp;ldquo;divert funds&amp;rdquo; to shell companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>