<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.
A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4GB Data Per Day For Rs 444</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</guid>
      <description>State-run telecom firm BSNL today increased per day data offering to 4GB at 3G speeds under a new prepaid mobile scheme priced at Rs 444 with 90 days validity.
&amp;ldquo;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) has introduced &amp;lsquo;BSNL Chaukka - 444&amp;rsquo;, a new STV, for truly unlimited data for 90 days as special promotional offer under prepaid mobile services,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.
This is the highest per day data limit being offered by any telecom operator in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.
The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get 224 GB For Rs. 509:Jio Releases New Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</guid>
      <description>As Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s promotional offers - Jio Summer Surprise and Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan - will expire for most users this month, the telecom operator has launched a new offer that provides customers up to 224 GB of 4G data along with other freebies. This comes as part of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive push to gain market share from entrenched players like Bharti Airtel and Vodafone. Jio&amp;rsquo;s new offer replaces its recharge packs priced Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM
Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department has launched a massive hunt for black money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</guid>
      <description>The massive hunt for undeclared cash launched across the country post demonetisation has revealed that these was either converted into gold or routed through shell companies to make it legal tender, IT sleuths have told Indo-Asian News Service.
Income Tax officials said black money holders avoided the bank-deposit route because they wanted to conceal their identities and somehow had &amp;ldquo;managed to get many jewellers&amp;rdquo; to convert their unaudited cash into gold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio’s new plans offer 100% cashback on JioFi on exchange of old dongle, datacard, routers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio has launched a 100% cashback offer with JioFi 4G router, as the Mukesh Ambani-owned tries to attract users of dongles, datacard and wifi routers offered by rival telcos.
The company has come up with two plans where as part of the first plan, users will get a 100% exchange offer where they’ll be required to exchange their existing datacard, dongle or hotspot router at any Jio Digital store or Jio Care store and will get 4G data worth Rs 2010 against the device exchanged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation To Launch RuPay Credit Card Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India has forayed in to the credit card business and would make the commercial launch of its RuPay credit card &amp;ldquo;in a month&amp;rsquo;s time,&amp;rdquo; a top official said today.
&amp;ldquo;Maybe in a month&amp;rsquo;s time we will be able to make the commercial launch (of RuPay credit card),&amp;rdquo; NPCI Chairman M Balachandran told reporters here.
NPCI, which currently offers RuPay debit cards, has partnered with 10 banks including public sector and cooperative banks, to make the pilot launch of the &amp;ldquo;RuPay Credit Card&amp;rdquo;, Balachandran said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.
Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Luxurious Maharajas&#39; Express Offers Free Seats On New Routes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</guid>
      <description>Indian Railways and IRCTC have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.
The Indian Railways’ super-luxury trains, which cater to various tourist circuits throughout India have long been in demand with travellers with deep pockets looking to explore the cities, towns, villages and regional areas, while travelling in style along the world’s fourth largest rail network. Expanding the network of its super-luxury trains, the Indian Railways and Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation Ltd (IRCTC) have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is exempt from PAN card Aadhaar card linking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link the existing Aadhaar numbers with the PAN cards of taxpayers with effect from July 1, 2017. In fact, Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar / Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from 1st July, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब महज 6 रुपए में एक घंटे के लिए अनलिमिटेड 4G डेटा दे रहा है</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-supernight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-supernight/</guid>
      <description>वोडाफोन ने अपने प्रीपेड कन्ज्यूमर्स के लिए नया ऑफर का ऐलान किया है। &amp;lsquo;सुपरनाइट 29&amp;rsquo; ऑफर के तहत वोडाफोन अब रात के 5 घंटों तक अनलिमिटेड 3G/4G डेटा देगा। लोग रात 1 बजे से सुबह 6 बजे के बीच इस ऑफर का फायदा उठा सकेंगे। गौरतलब है कि रिलायंस जियो के डेटा पैक के मुताबिक 1GB डेटा 10 रुपये का पड़ता है। ऐसे में अगर वोडाफोन के ग्राहक रात में हर घंटे 1GB डेटा भी यूज करें तो उन्हें जियो के मुकाबले सस्ता डेटा मिलेगा।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मोदी की &#39;कड़वी दवाइयों&#39; के लिए रहें तैयार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/result-get-ready-for-big-economic-reforms-by-modi-governemnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/result-get-ready-for-big-economic-reforms-by-modi-governemnt/</guid>
      <description>यूपी में बीजेपी की प्रचंड जीत से प्रभावित मोदी सरकार सुधारों की दिशा में अपने कदम और तेज कर सकती है। विदेशी निवेश के मामले में सरकार और उदारवादी रुख अपना सकती है वहीं, भारत में उत्पादन बढ़ाना, कर्ज में डूबे बैंकों का उबारना, सोशल सेक्टर में डिलिवरी सिस्टम को मजबूत करना सरकार के सुधारवादी अजेंडा में शामिल रह सकते हैं।
यूपी में बीजेपी अपनी &amp;lsquo;ट्रिपल सेंचुरी&amp;rsquo; को नोटबंदी पर जनता के ग्रीन सिग्नल के रूप में देख रही है। दो सालों से &amp;lsquo;सबसे बड़ा&amp;rsquo; आर्थिक सुधार माने जाने वाले जीएसटी को पास कराने की कोशिशों में लगी बीजेपी अब अन्य सुधारों की ओर तेज कदम बढ़ाएगी जिससे जीएसटी को लागू करने में भी फायदा होगा। वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने विधानसभा चुनावों में बीजेपी के प्रदर्शन पर ट्वीट किया, &amp;lsquo;विधानसभा चुनावों में बीजेपी की बेहतरीन जीत से फिर यह साबित होता है कि जनता पीएम मोदी के विकास के साथ हैं।&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एक रुपए का नया नोट, नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार का फैसला</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-government-will-issue-one-rupees-note-after-two-decades/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-government-will-issue-one-rupees-note-after-two-decades/</guid>
      <description>एक रुपए से आज भले ही हम ज्यादा कुछ न खरीद पाएं, लेकिन फिर भी केंद्र सरकार देश में इसको चलते रहने देना चाहती है।
एक रुपए से आज भले ही हम ज्यादा कुछ न खरीद पाएं, लेकिन फिर भी केंद्र सरकार देश में इसको चलन में रहने देना चाहती है। सरकार ने इसे 20 साल बाद दोबारा छापने का फैसला किया है। हालांकि, पुराने नोट और सिक्के भी चलन में रहेंगे। भारतीय रिर्जव बैंक (आरबीआई) ने इस बात की पुष्टि की है। आरबीआई ने इस बारे में बताया कि वह जल्द ही एक रुपए के नए नोट चलन में लाएगा। भारत सरकार इन्हें छापेगी। ये नोट कॉइनेज एक्ट 2011 के तहत छापे जाएंगे। फिलहाल एक रुपए के सिक्के चलन में हैं, जो टकसाल में तैयार किए जाते हैं।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जियो ने लॉन्च किया 399 रुपये में 84 दिन की वैधता और 84GB डेटा वाला प्लान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-launches-new-rs-399-plan-with-84-days-validity-revises-old-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-launches-new-rs-399-plan-with-84-days-validity-revises-old-plans/</guid>
      <description>रिलायंस जियो के यूजर्स के लिए अच्छी खबर है। जियो ने अपने यूजर्स के लिए नए प्लान लॉन्च कर दिए हैं। जियो का जियो धन धना धन ऑफर खत्म होने के कगार पर है। Reliance Jio ने यह प्लान प्रीपेड और पोस्टपेड दोनों तरह के यजर्स के लिए पेश किए हैं। कंपनी ने नए प्लान को जियो धन धना धन ऑफर के नाम से ही पेश किया है। इस प्लान का सिर्फ नाम पुराना है बाकी सबकुछ इसमें बदल चुका है। रिलायंस जियो के इन प्लान का पूरा फायदा उठाने के लिए आपके पास जियो प्राइम मेंबरशिप होनी जरूरी है। रिलायंस जियो के प्रीपेड प्लान की शुरुआत 19 रुपये से होती है और सबसे महंगा प्लान 9,999 रुपये का है। जियो धन धना धन ऑफर के शुरुआत में जहां कंपनी 309 रुपये के रीचार्ज वाले पैक पर 1 महीने की वैधता की बात कह रही थी। अब इसी प्लान में ग्राहकों को 56 दिन की वैधता मिलेगी और 4जी स्पीड डेटा भी 56 जीबी ही दिया जाएगा। वहीं, एक प्लान 399 रुपये का है जिसकी वैधता 84 दिन की है। इस प्लान में ग्राहकों को 4जी स्पीड का 1 जीबी डेटा रोजाना मिलेगा। वहीं पोस्टपेड प्लान की शुरुआत 309 रुपये से होती है, इसका सबसे महंगा प्लान 999 रुपये का है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भविष्य में सभी कार्डों की जगह ले लेगा आधार कार्ड: अरुण जेटली</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</guid>
      <description>लोकसभा ने बुधवार को वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली की ओर से पेश वित्त विधेयक को चर्चा के बाद पारित कर दिया। चर्चा के दौरान अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि आने वाले दिनों में आधार ही एकमात्र कार्ड होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि भविष्य में यह वोटर आईडी कार्ड और पैन कार्ड जैसे दस्तावेजों की जगह ले लेगा। इन सभी के मुकाबले एक आधार कार्ड ही किसी भी व्यक्ति की पहचान के लिए काफी होगा। लोकसभा में एक सांसद की ओर से पूछा गया था कि आधार कार्ड जारी किए जाने के बाद भी कई कार्डों की व्यवस्था क्यों लागू है। इसके जवाब में जेटली ने यह बात कही। उन्होंने कहा कि आने वाले वक्त में आधार ही व्यक्तिगत पहचान और पते के लिए पुख्ता सबूत होगा।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भारत के हाइटेक टैलंट को नजरअंदाज कर चीन ने की गलती: चीनी मीडिया</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/china-made-mistake-of-ignoring-indias-high-tech-talent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/china-made-mistake-of-ignoring-indias-high-tech-talent/</guid>
      <description>चीन ने भारत के विज्ञान एवं तकनीकी एक्सपर्ट्स को नजरअंदाज कर गलती की है। यह बात किसी भारतीय नेता या कारोबारी ने नहीं कही है, बल्कि खुद चीन मीडिया ने कही है। चीन के सरकारी अखबार ग्लोबल टाइम्स ने लिखा है कि कम्युनिस्ट देश को भारत के हाइटेक टैलंट को अपनी ओर आकर्षित करना चाहिए ताकि वह आविष्कारों के मामले में अपनी क्षमता को बरकरार रख सके। ग्लोबल टाइम्स में लिखे लेख के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;चीन ने भारतीय टैलंट को नजरअंदाज कर गलती की है। इसकी बजाय हम अमेरिका और यूरोप से आने वाले टैलंट पर निर्भर रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>यूपी: 10वीं पास करने वाली लड़कियों को 10,000 रुपए देगी योगी सरकार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/up-govt-announces-rs-10000-each-to-one-lakh-schoolgirls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/up-govt-announces-rs-10000-each-to-one-lakh-schoolgirls/</guid>
      <description>यूपी में 10वीं और 12वीं के नतीजे घोषित होने बाकी है। परिक्षार्थियों में रिजल्ट को लेकर बहुत उत्सुकता है। इस बीच यूपी के योगी सरकार ने हाईस्कूल की लड़कियों को खुशखबरी सुनाई है। एएनआई के मुताबिक राज्य के उप-मुख्यमंत्री दिनेश शर्मा ने 10वीं कक्षा में पास होने वाली एक लाख लड़कियों को 10,000 रुपए देने
का ऐलान किया है। 10वीं की बोर्ड परीक्षा के रिजल्ट को लेकर कयास लगाए जा रहे हैं कि नतीजे 9 जून को आ सकते हैं। इसके साथ ही कहा जा रहा है कि 10वीं से पहले 12वीं के रिजल्ट घोषित हो सकते हैं।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>हर स्कीम के लिए अनिवार्य न हो आधार: SC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-cant-be-mandatory-for-social-welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-cant-be-mandatory-for-social-welfare/</guid>
      <description>सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने सोमवार को कहा कि सरकार की समाज कल्याण योजनाओं का लाभ उठाने के लिए आधार बायोमीट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन को अनिवार्य नहीं बनाया जा सकता। देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत ने कहा कि सरकार चाहे तो दूसरे क्षेत्रों में आधार को अनिवार्य बना सकती है, जो समाज कल्याण के कार्यक्रमों से नहीं जुड़े हैं। बैंक खाता खोलना ऐसा एक काम हो सकता है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट की जिस बेंच ने यह बात कही, उसमें चीफ जस्टिस जे एस खेहर, जस्टिस डी वाई चंद्रचूड़ और जस्टिस संजय किशन कौल शामिल थे। सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने पहले भी आधार को सभी समाज कल्याण योजनाओं के लिए लाभुकों की पहचान के लिए आधार को अकेला मानक बनाने के खिलाफ आदेश दिया था।</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>