<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.
HIGHLIGHTS  Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%  The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18 specified financial transactions in which quoting of PAN is mandatory now</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</guid>
      <description>Although Aadhaar is gradually gaining more importance than PAN – a ten-digit unique alphanumeric number issued by the Income Tax Department – however, PAN is still important, especially for financial transactions. According to experts, PAN is a way for the Income Tax Department to keep tabs on your financial dealings whereas Aadhaar’s main purpose is to create a centralized database of each citizen residing in India. PAN, in fact, is a very useful tool to estimate the total tax revenue being generated in the country and to be used as an identification document is not its primary job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 financial tasks to do when a parent dies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</guid>
      <description>Goodbyes are the hardest when they are final. It’s worse if it involves one of your parents. The heartbreak is probably lesser in intensity only to that of your surviving parent, the spouse who is left grappling with a crippling emotional void at the fag end of life. Yet, it is critical to take a financial reality check and you, as progeny, are the best suited to do it.
Taking stock of the finances is an overwhelming task and it’s easy to be stumped by the maze of formalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM will now allow you to make payments via Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app will now allow users to send and receive money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number.
This comes shortly after the government announced the Aadhaar Pay which would allow any person with their Aadhaar number linked to a bank account, can make and receive payment electronically.
At the time, IT minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said that BHIM would be able to make Aadhar Payments any biometric authentication, as indicated by this Economic Times report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSNL Offers &#39;Unlimited Data Plan&#39; At Rs. 249</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-offers-unlimited-data-plan-at-rs-249/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-offers-unlimited-data-plan-at-rs-249/</guid>
      <description>India’s state-owned telecom operator Bharat Sanchar Nigam Ltd. (BSNL) has announced an entry level ‘Unlimited Broadband at Rs. 249’ plan for its users in India under which they will get up to 300GB data per month. The new plan also offers free calls during night time on certain days. The introductory offer which is only for new customers is valid for one year after which it will be changed to &amp;lsquo;BBG Combo ULD Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.
The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car insurance: How to get extra cover during monsoon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/car-insurance-how-to-get-extra-cover-during-monsoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/car-insurance-how-to-get-extra-cover-during-monsoon/</guid>
      <description>Is there any special monsoon motor insurance cover available in the market? – Anuj Bansal
For new vehicles up to a certain
number of years, add-on covers like Engine Protect and Return To Invoice is advisable to opt for. These add-on covers are annual contracts and not restricted to a particular season. Engine Protect will indemnify the owner for engine related damages caused to the vehicle due to water ingression in the engine while driving the vehicle in accumulated flood waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.
SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Recharge: Now, Get Flat Rs. 75 Cashback. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-recharge-now-get-flat-rs-75-cashback-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-recharge-now-get-flat-rs-75-cashback-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Recharge your Jio number and get Rs. 75 cashback. This is a new limited-period offer from PhonePe, a Flipkart-owned mobile wallet, which is giving a flat Rs. 75 cashback on Jio prepaid recharge. Reliance Jio had a total subscriber base of 12.3 crore after adding over 6 million customers in June, according to latest figures released by telecom regulator. With revised &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, which Jio launched last month, Jio customers can get 1 GB data per day for 84 days at a recharge of Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.
Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI ATM Withdrawal Rules And Charges For Other Services</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-atm-withdrawal-rules-and-charges-for-other-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-atm-withdrawal-rules-and-charges-for-other-services/</guid>
      <description>State Bank of India or SBI has in recent months revised its charges on various services like ATM withdrawal , cash transactions, issuance of cheque books, exchange of soiled notes and online transfer of funds through Immediate Payment Service (IMPS). SBI has clarified that customers of its mobile wallet State Bank Buddy will be charged 3 per cent plus GST of 18 per cent on transfer from Buddy to bank account using IMPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI- Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</guid>
      <description>HomeIndustry Banking financeFee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI
State Bank of India (SBI) on Wednesday waived charges on all money transfers of less than Rs 1,000 made through the Immediate Payment System (IMPS) channel, in a bid “to promote small ticket size transactions”.
By: FE Bureau | Mumbai | Updated: July 13, 2017 5:02 AM imps, sbi, state bank of india, sbi news, sbi latest news, imps transaction fee SBI’s decision to waive charges on some IMPS transactions may have been the result of more than a nudge from the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is exempt from PAN card Aadhaar card linking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link the existing Aadhaar numbers with the PAN cards of taxpayers with effect from July 1, 2017. In fact, Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar / Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from 1st July, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ATMs Are Going Dry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</guid>
      <description>1: The ATM expansion era is over. ATM extensions will no longer be part of future banking growth, and future ATMs may well be of the mobile kind focused only on rural cash deliveries. But even here, the growth will be limited. Standalone ATM companies may have a future, but only because banks may choose to outsource all their existing networks to them so that they can focus on growing the digital business themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</guid>
      <description>Both Apps uses Unified Payments Interface (UPI) technology to transfer money between any two individuals and between an individual and a merchant.
Navneet Dubey Moneycontrol News
Are you considering using one of the mobile payment apps launched by the government recently? If so, you may be confused on whether you should use the Aadhaar Payment App or Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM)?
Well, there are specific features of each of these apps which differentiate them which you should be aware of.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>