<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Data Safe From Cyber Attacks Assures Aadhaar Body Chairman</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allaying concerns about the security of data in Aadhaar servers in the wake of &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo; ransomware attack, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) today said its database was completely secured and immune to attacks from any kind of malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The data in the Aadhaar servers is in the encrypted form. You cannot do anything with that information, which is in an encrypted form. Aadhaar main systems, which are really so very well-designed and robustly designed that there is no concern about security in Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; UIDAI chairman J Satyanarayana said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just 48 hours back we had big scare all over the world about this ransomware. So, in Aadhaar, people were sleeping peacefully (as they are sure of its security features)&amp;hellip; that it is 100 per cent sure that nothing would happen. Such robust systems were put in place in Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; he said in a programme organised by the Institution of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the government has spent Rs. 7,000 crore on establishment of Aadhaar and reaped benefits of over Rs. 50,000 crore in the form of weeding out bogus beneficiaries of government schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are geared up to do 10 crore transactions per day. And we are increasing up to 40 crore transactions per day. Our servers are capable of taking that load,&amp;rdquo; he further said. According to Satyanarayana, the Telangana government has saved Rs. 55.7 crore between January and July 2016 by deleting 38.63 lakh duplicate or ghost ration cards units using Aadhaar authentication while Andhra Pradesh saved 4,03,142 tonnes of rice and 5,000 kilo litres of kerosene by reducing 8.58 lakh cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said Reliance Jio is one of the largest private players which used Aadhaar data for its subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filing Income Tax Returns? Things To Keep In Mind As Deadline Approaches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The income tax filing website typically has lots of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the close of the financial year, most individuals have completed their tax planning and tax deduction exercise for the year. This leaves the final step in completing one&amp;rsquo;s income tax process - filing ITR or income tax return. Often regarded as a painful formality, you must remember that this is one of the most important income document for any individual. While July 31, 2017 is the last day to file I-T returns, remember that the income tax filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - typically has a lot of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Income Tax returns acts as an important income document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From this year on Aadhaar card is necessary to file I-T returns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I-T returns must be filed if your annual income is over Rs. 2.5 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some important things to remember when filing for tax returns according to leading share trading company and financial consultant Motilal Oswal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Anyone with an annual income of over Rs 2.5 lakh needs to file I-T returns whether the income is taxable or not. The Income Tax Department tracks lifestyle expenses, asset purchases, investments and foreign travel through your PAN card and Aadhaar number so try to be as transparent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Remember that all your sources of income must be filed as part of your I-T returns. Even if your dividends are tax-free, it is still essential to disclose all these details in your I-T returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) If you have made losses on shares or equity-oriented mutual funds, you need to show the loss when you file returns. If you do not disclose the loss in your I-T returns, you lose the benefit of setting off the losses against other gains and also lose the benefit of carrying forward these losses for a period of 8 years, says Motilal Oswal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) You are required to file your returns online on the website of the Income Tax Department. However, your job does not end there. The returns need to be e-verified which can be done by linking it to your registered bank account having the same name details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) While refunds below Rs. 50,000 are directly credited to your bank account via RTGS, refunds above Rs. 50,000 are only paid out by cheque. Hence if your refund is above Rs. 50,000 ensure that your address is updated in the I-T records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Remember that effective July 1, 2017, an Aadhaar card is a prerequisite for filing income tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) If you forget to file returns before the due date of July 31 and do not have any tax payable then you can file the returns by March 31 next year. But refund cases will not be entertained if returns are filed after the cut-off date of July 31.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Group Issues New Threat</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-as-cyberattack-eases-hacking-group-issues-new-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-as-cyberattack-eases-hacking-group-issues-new-threat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shadow Brokers, the group that has taken credit for that leak, threatened on Tuesday to release more recent code to enable hackers to break into the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used computers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governments turned their attention to possible new wave of cyber threats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber extortion campaign has infected more than 300,000 computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The attack has caused most damage in Russia, Taiwan and Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments turned their attention to a possible new wave of cyber threats on Tuesday after the group that leaked U.S. hacking tools used to launch the global WannaCry &amp;ldquo;ransomware&amp;rdquo; attack warned it would release more malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fast-spreading cyber extortion campaign, which has infected more than 300,000 computers worldwide since Friday, eased for second day on Tuesday, but the identity and motive of its creators remain unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack includes elements that belong to the U.S. National Security Agency and were leaked online last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shadow Brokers, the group that has taken credit for that leak, threatened on Tuesday to release more recent code to enable hackers to break into the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used computers, software and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog post written by the group promised from June to release tools every month to anyone willing to pay for access to some of the tech world&amp;rsquo;s biggest commercial secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also threatened to dump data from banks using the SWIFT international money transfer network and from Russian, Chinese, Iranian or North Korean nuclear and missile programs. &amp;ldquo;More details in June,&amp;rdquo; it promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spread of the WannaCry attack - which encrypts a user&amp;rsquo;s data and demands a &amp;ldquo;ransom&amp;rdquo; be paid electronically to free it up again - slowed to a trickle on Tuesday, with few, isolated examples being reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Canada, the Universite de Montreal was hit, with 120 of the French-language university&amp;rsquo;s 8,300 computers affected, according to a university spokeswoman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no new, major incidents in the United States. Fewer than 10 U.S. organizations have reported attacks to the Department of Homeland Security since Friday, a U.S. official told reporters on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack has caused most damage in Russia, Taiwan and Ukraine, according to Czech security firm Avast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States likely avoided greater harm as the attack targeted older versions of Microsoft Corp&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, and more U.S. users have licensed, up-to-date, patched versions of the software, compared to other regions of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Homeland Security began an &amp;ldquo;aggressive awareness campaign&amp;rdquo; to alert the tech industry to the importance of installing the patch that Microsoft issued in March that protected users from the vulnerability exploited by the attack, a U.S. official working on the attack told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft said on Tuesday it was aware of Shadow Brokers&amp;rsquo; most recent claim and that its security teams monitor potential threats in order to &amp;ldquo;help us prioritize and take appropriate action.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft President and Chief Legal Officer Brad Smith said earlier this week the WannaCry attack used elements stolen from the NSA. The U.S. government has not commented directly on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;north-korea-link-probed&#34;&gt;North Korea Link Probed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyber security researchers around the world have said they have found evidence that could link North Korea with the WannaCry cyber attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A researcher from South Korea&amp;rsquo;s Hauri Labs said on Tuesday their own findings matched those of Symantec and Kaspersky Lab, who said on Monday that some code in an earlier version of the WannaCry software had also appeared in programs used by the Lazarus Group, identified by some researchers as a North Korea-run hacking operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is similar to North Korea&amp;rsquo;s backdoor malicious codes,&amp;rdquo; said Simon Choi, a senior researcher with Hauri who has done extensive research into North Korea&amp;rsquo;s hacking capabilities and advises South Korean police and National Intelligence Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Symantec and Kaspersky said it was too early to tell whether North Korea was involved in the attacks, based on the evidence that was published on Twitter by Google security researcher Neel Mehta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FireEye Inc, another large cyber security firm, said it was also investigating, but it was cautious about drawing a link to North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The similarities we see between malware linked to that group and WannaCry are not unique enough to be strongly suggestive of a common operator,&amp;rdquo; FireEye researcher John Miller said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. and European security officials told Reuters on condition of anonymity that it was too early to say who might be behind the attacks, but they did not rule out North Korea as a suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lazarus hackers, acting for impoverished North Korea, have been more brazen in their pursuit of financial gain than others, and have been blamed for the theft of $81 million from the Bangladesh central bank, according to some cyber security firms. The United States accused it of being behind a cyber attack on Sony Pictures in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Korea has denied being behind the Sony and banking attacks. North Korean officials were not immediately available for comment and its state media has been quiet about the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-information-to-share&#34;&gt;No Information To Share&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In China, foreign ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said she had no information to share, when asked about the origin of the attack and whether North Korea might be connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several Asian countries have been affected by the malware, although the impact has not been as widespread as some had feared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Malaysia, cyber security firm LE Global Services said it identified 12 cases so far, including a large government-linked corporation, a government-linked investment firm and an insurance company. It did not name any of the entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We may not see the real picture yet, as companies are not mandated to disclose security breaches to authorities in Malaysia,&amp;rdquo; said LE Global CEO Fong Choong Fook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The real situation may be serious. In one of the cases, the attack was traced back to early April.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s state media said on Tuesday more than 200 computers had been affected, but one of the country&amp;rsquo;s leading anti-virus companies, Bkav, later put the figure at 1,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taiwan Power Co. said that nearly 800 of its computers were affected, although these were used for administration, not for systems involved in electricity generation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: Airtel Doubles Data Benefits In Its Broadband Plans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-airtel-doubles-data-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-airtel-doubles-data-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bharti Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 899 plan in Delhi - which offered 30 GB of high speed data earlier - now offers 60 GB data, the company said a press release.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid India&amp;rsquo;s telecom sector abuzz with talk about Jio&amp;rsquo;s broadband services, Bharti Airtel has announced new broadband plans under which it is offering up to 100 per cent additional high speed data benefits within the same monthly rental plan. Bharti Airtel whose broadband internet plans in the national capital start from Rs 899 a month, said its new plans were aimed at driving India&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation. The announcement by India&amp;rsquo;s largest telecom company comes after rollout of its &amp;lsquo;V-Fiber&amp;rsquo; broadband &amp;ldquo;to serve the exploding demand for reliable high speed data solutions in Indian homes&amp;rdquo;, Airtel said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharti Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 899 plan in Delhi, which offered 30 GB of high speed data earlier, now offers 60 GB data. Also, its Rs 1,099 plan will now offer 90 GB of high speed data compared to 50 GB earlier, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, its Rs 1,299 plan now offers 125 GB compared to 75 GB earlier while the Rs 1,499 plan offers 160 GB instead of 100 GB, the statement noted. &amp;ldquo;Similar large increments in data benefits have been effected at every price point in every city with unlimited calling to any network available across all plans,&amp;rdquo; Bharti Airtel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our new plans are aimed at putting India onto the digital superhighway and complement our superfast broadband offerings like &amp;lsquo;V-Fiber&amp;rsquo;. At Airtel, our mission is to enable a superior digital experience and offer great value to our customers&amp;hellip;We believe these new plans will also drive the adoption of high speed broadband in the country,&amp;rdquo; Bharti Airtel (India) CEO-homes Hemanth Kumar Guruswamy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing customers will be upgraded to new benefits automatically within current bill cycle while new customers can choose from a host of plans that offer great value backed by best-in-class high speed broadband experience, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing operators in the country&amp;rsquo;s telecom industry are witnessing heightened competition due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, say some analysts. Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services - called &amp;ldquo;JioFiber&amp;rdquo; - are being launched in some parts of cities like Mumbai, Delhi and Vadodara. Jio is testing a &amp;ldquo;JioFiber Preview Offer&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;select areas of Mumbai, Delhi-NCR, Ahmedabad, Jamnagar, Surat and Vadodara&amp;rdquo;, Jio Care, the official customer support of the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, had said on microblogging site Twitter earlier this month. (Read: &amp;lsquo;Preview offer&amp;rsquo; of Jio broadband (JioFiber) in these cities)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to a query posted by an individual on Twitter, Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care handle also said the company&amp;rsquo;s network was in the process of being rolled out to other cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customers can check their data balance on &amp;lsquo;My Airtel&amp;rsquo; app,&amp;rdquo; Bharti Airtel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;V-Fiber&amp;rsquo; delivers consistently superfast broadband speeds of up to 100 Mbps to homes. &amp;ldquo;The &amp;lsquo;V-Fiber&amp;rsquo; high speed broadband experience is available to customers within the same plan rentals and requires only a quick modem switch,&amp;rdquo; it noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Delhi-headquartered Bharti Airtel has operations in 17 countries across Asia and Africa. It had over 372 million customers across its operations at the end of March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said.
The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report also says that both prepaid and postpaid customers will have to be re-verified by the telecom companies. It can be done by SMSes. Telecom companies will send verification codes to its customers.
Aadhaar may become the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future, he added.
Recently, Supreme Court has also asked the Central government to link all mobile numbers to Aadhaar within a period of one year. The Apex Court urged Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led government to frame policies regarding rules and regulations to ensure the fact that the SIMs (Subscriber
Identification Module) are not misused by anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apex court has said that its mandatory for all mobile subscribers including pre-paid SIM card users to link their SIM cards to Aadhaar cards. The Court asked the Centre to devise a plan for pre-paid SIM card users so that each person will have to fill and deposit a form whenever he or she recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एयरटेल अपने ब्रॉडबैंड यूजर्स को मुफ्त में देगा डबल डेटा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-to-provide-high-speed-data-to-its/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-to-provide-high-speed-data-to-its/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;एयरटेल ने बुधवार को होम ब्रॉडबैंड यूजर्स के लिए नया प्लान पेश किया है। इस प्लान के मुताबिक, उन्हें अपने उसी मासिक किराए में 100 फीसदी ज्यादा हाईस्पीड डेटा मिलेगा। भारती एयरटेल (इंडिया) के हेमंत कुमार गुरुस्वामी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमारे नए प्लान का लक्ष्य भारत को डिजिटल सुपर हाइवे पर ले जाना है और यह हमारे वी-फाइबर सुपरफास्ट ब्रॉडबैंड से जुड़ा है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनी ने बयान में कहा कि देश में हाईस्पीड डेटा का इस्तेमाल तेजी से बढ़ रहा है। इस मांग को पूरा करने तथा मल्टीडिवाइस माहौल में बिना रुकावट हाईस्पीड डेटा देने के लिए करने के लिए एयरटेल ने भविष्य को ध्यान में रखते हुए &amp;lsquo;वी-फाइबर&amp;rsquo; नेटवर्क तैयार किया है। यह नेटवर्क घरों में लगातार 100 एमबीपीएस का स्पीड देता है। एयरटेल के ब्रॉडबैंड प्लान में किया गया बदलाव वी-फाइबर को ध्यान में रखकर किया गया है। दिल्ली में 899 रुपये के प्लान में अब 30 जीबी की बजाए 60 जीबी डेटा मिलेगा। 1,099 रुपये के प्लान में अब 90 जीबी डेटा, 1,299 रुपये के प्लान में 125 जीबी डेटा, 1,499 रुपये के प्लान में 160 जीबी डेटा मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>खातों की कम जानकारी देने वाले करदाता जांच के दायरे में</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने सत्यापन के लिए 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान की है, जिसमें 1.58 लाख करदाता ऐसे शामिल हैं, जिन्होंने पिछले दिनों अपने खातों की आंशिक घोषणा की थी। नोटबंदी के बाद इंकम टैक्स विभाग को बैंकों द्वारा दायर वित्तीय लेनदेन के बयान (एसएफटी) सहित विभिन्न स्रोतों से कई अहम जानकारी मिली। आईटी विभाग ने कहा कि इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने 1.58 लाख करदाताओं से संबंधित 3.71 लाख नए खातों की पहचान की है, जिन्होंने पहले अपने अकाउंट के बारे में जानकारी दी थी। पहले 18 लाख मामलों के अलावा, 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान ई-वेरिफेकेशन से की गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट पहले से उप्लब्ध डेटा की मदद से विश्लेषण कर रहा है। इस डेटा की मदद से ई-वेरिफिकेशन के लिए नए मामलों की पहचान हो चुकी है। 31 जनवरी को आई-टी विभाग द्वारा शुरू किए गए &amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; के तहत 17.92 लाख लोगों को एसएमएस और ई-मेल भेजे गए हैं, जिन्होंने 10 नवंबर से 30 दिसंबर के बीच 5 लाख और उससे ज्यादा पैसे जमा किए हैं। इनमें से 9 .72 लाख लोगों ने नकदी जमा के स्रोतों पर जवाब दिया है। विभाग ने उन मामलों में वेरिफिकेशन बंद करने का निर्णय लिया है, जहां नकदी के स्रोत का पूरा ब्यौरा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;करदाताओं ने करीब 2.8 9 लाख करोड़ रुपये के नकदी जमा से जुड़े 13.33 लाख खातों के लिए जवाब दे दिए हैं। ऑनलाइन प्रतिक्रियाओं का आंकलन कर खातों की सही जानकारी देने वालों के मामलों में आगे कोई कार्रवाई नहीं की जाएगी। विभाग ने दो विशेष डेटा ऐनालिटिकल एजेंसियों और एक व्यावसायिक प्रक्रिया प्रबंधन एजेंसी को बड़ी मात्रा में नकद जमा के डेटा का विश्लेषण करने, करदाताओं की अनुपालन स्थिति और रिपोर्टिंग संस्थाओं का पता लगाने की जिम्मेदारी दी है। नकदी जमा के सोर्स के रूप में नकद बिक्री का दावा करने वाले पेट्रोल पंप व्यापारियों और संपत्ति खरीददारों जैसे व्यापारों की विस्तृत जांच की जाएगी, जिनका कैश सेल उनके नकद जमा की तुलना में ज्यादा पाया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>टेलिकॉम रेग्युलेटरी ने कहा- आधार के बिना नहीं मिलेगा सिम कार्ड</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card-said/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;यदि आपके पास आधार कार्ड नहीं है तो जल्दी से बनवा लें। टेलिकॉम रेग्युलेटरी अथॉरिटी ऑफ इंडिया (TRAI) ने आधार कार्ड के बगैर सिम कार्ड देने पर रोक लगा दी है। ट्राई की तरफ से जारी गाइडलाइन में कहा गया है कि मोबाइल सिम कार्ड, ब्रॉडबैंड और फिक्स लाइन फोन के लिए आधार कार्ड अनिवार्य होगा। बता दें कि फरवरी में केंद्र सरकार ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट को बताया था लगभग एक साल में देश के सभी सिम कार्डों को आधार कार्ड से जोड़ दिया जाएगा। केंद्र सरकार ने कहा था कि ऐसा मैकेनिज्म लाया जा रहा है, जिससे इन मोबाइल सिम को भी आधार से जोड़ा जा सके।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देश में डिजिटल ट्रांजेक्शन को बढ़ावा देने की बात पर चीफ जस्टिस ऑफ इंडिया खेहर ने कहा था कि मोबाइल सिम कार्ड रखने वालों की पहचान बेहद जरूरी है, ऐसा न होने पर यह धोखाधड़ी से रुपये निकालने के काम में इस्तेमाल हो सकता है। सरकार को जल्द ही पहचान करने की प्रक्रिया करनी चाहिए, वहीं केंद्र की ओर से कहा गया था कि इस मामले में उसे हलफनामा दाखिल करने के लिए वक्त चाहिए। इसके बाद सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने दो हफ्ते का वक्त दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ट्राई के नियम के मुताबिक अब हर सिमकार्ड के लिए ई-केवाईसी जरूरी होगा। ट्राई की ओर से प्रस्तावित नियमों के तहत न सिर्फ नई मोबाइल सिम बल्कि मौजूदा सभी मोबाइल सब्सक्राइबर्स का ई-केवाईसी वेरिफिकेशन जरूरी होगा। किसी दूसरे सर्कल में जाकर मोबाइल फोन कनेक्शन को लेकर काफी दिक्कते आती हैं। लोगों को एड्रेस प्रूफ देने में परेशानी होती है, लेकिन ईकेवाईसी के बाद ये समस्या खत्म हो जाएगी। अब ईकेवाई से एक ही अड्रेस पर पूरे देश में सिम हासिल किया जा सकेगा। इतना ही नहीं ईकेवाईसी की मदद से सिम कार्ड में फर्जीवाड़े को भी रोका जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>तो क्‍या 1 जून से हर एटीएम न‍िकासी पर 25 रुपए वसूलेगा एसबीआई? दूर हुई गफलत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-will-not-be-charged-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-will-not-be-charged-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;एटीएम से पैसे निकालने के नियमों में कोई बदलाव नहीं किया गया है, और पुराने नियम ही लागू रहेंगे।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया के ग्राहकों के लिए एक जरूरी खबर है। मीडिया में चल रही खबरों के विपरीत स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया एटीएम से हर बार पैसे निकालने के लिए 25 रुपये चार्ज नहीं करेगी। स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया की बेबसाइट पर एक सर्कुलर डाला गया है, जिसके मुताबिक एक जून 2017 से एटीएम से हर बार पैसे की निकासी पर 25 रुपये चार्ज लिया जाएगा। एसबीआई के अधिकारी ने इस सर्कुलर के बारे में सफाई देते हुए कहा कि बैंक ऐसी कोई भी रकम नहीं लेने वाला है, क्योंकि ये सर्कुलर एसबीआई मोबाइल वैलेट, जिसे बड्डी भी कहा जाता है, से जुड़ा है। अंग्रेजी वेबसाइट बिजनेस टुडे के मुताबिक एसबीआई जल्द ही नया सर्कुलर जारी करने वाला है। इस&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि एटीएम से पैसे निकालने के नियमों में कोई बदलाव नहीं किया गया है, और पुराने नियम ही लागू रहेंगे।
बता दें कि एसबीआई के इसी सर्कुलर में बताया गया है कि एक महीने में चार निकासी जिसमें की एटीएम से निकाले गये पैसे भी शामिल हैं मुफ़्त होंगे। सर्कुलर में आगे लिखा है कि अगर किसी को चार बार से ज्यादा पैसे निकालने हैं तो 50 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स चार्ज करेगा। ये चार्ज बैंक की शाखा से पैसे निकालने के लिए
रखे गये हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अगर कस्टमर ने दूसरे बैंक के एटीएम का इस्तेमाल किया है तो 20 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स चार्ज किया जाएगा, और अगर एसबीआई की एटीएम से पैसे निकाले जाएंगे तो 10 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स लिया जाएगा।
इस आदेश के मुताबिक अब चेकबुक लेने के लिए भी जेब ढीली करनी पड़ेगी। 1 जून से अगर आप 10 चेक वाला चेकबुक लेते हैं तो आपको 30 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स देना पड़ेगा, 25 चेक वाला चेकबुक लेने पर 75 रुपये और चेकबुक देना पड़ेगा, जबकि 50 चेक वाला चेकबुक लेने पर 150 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स भुगतान करना पड़ेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पहली बार एक साथ 10 न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर्स के निर्माण को सरकार ने दी मंजूरी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-expansion-of-nuclear-power-industry-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-expansion-of-nuclear-power-industry-union/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वर्तमान में कुल 22 रिएक्टर चलाए जा रहे हैं। नए रिएक्टर्स पुरानों की तुलना में ज्यादा क्षमता वाले हैं।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देश की न्यूक्लियर पावर इंडस्ट्री में अभी तक का सबसे बड़ा विस्तार करते हुए केन्द्रीय मंत्रिमंडल ने बुधवार को 10 नए न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर के निर्माण को मंजूरी दे दी है। यह पहली बार है जब इतनी संख्या में न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर्स को एक साथ मंजूरी मिली हो। वर्तमान में कुल 22 रिएक्टर चलाए जा रहे हैं। नए&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रिएक्टर्स पुरानों की तुलना में ज्यादा क्षमता वाले हैं। पुराने 20 रिएक्टर्स 220 MWe (मेगा वॉट इलेक्ट्रिक) वाले और 2005 व 2006 में तारापुर में लगाए गए दो रिएक्टर 540 MWe क्षमता वाले हैं। वहीं, नए रिएक्टर्स की क्षमता 700 MWe होगी। यह दस रिएक्टर्स राजस्थान के माही बंसवाड़ा (यूनिट 1, 2, 3, 4), हरियाणा के गोरखपुर (यूनिट 3 और 4), कर्नाटक के कैगा (यूनिट 5 और 6) और मध्य प्रदेश के चुटका (यूनिट 1 और 2) में लगाए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इसके अलावा बिजली घरों को कोयले की पर्याप्त आपूर्ति सुनिश्चित करने के लिये बुधवार को सरकार ने एक नई कोयला आपूर्ति व्यवस्था संबंधी नीति को मंजूरी दे दी। इसके तहत बिजली क्षेत्र को ईंधन की आपूर्ति नीलामी मार्ग या प्रतिस्पर्धी बोली प्रक्रिया पर आधारित बिजली खरीद करार (पीपीए) के तहत होगी। प्रधानमंत्री&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नरेंद्र मोदी की अध्यक्षता में हुई मंत्रिमंडल की आर्थिक मामलों की समिति (सीसीईए) की बैठक में यह फैसला किया गया। इस कदम से बिजली क्षेत्र की परियोजनाओं को कोयले आपूर्ति उपलब्ध न होने की समस्या को दूर किया जा सकेगा।
बिजली घरों के लिये इस नई कोयला आपूर्ति व्यवस्था से उत्पादकों को व्यवस्थित तरीके से ईंधन की आपूर्ति करने में मदद मिलेगी। सूत्रों के अनुसार सरकार के प्रयास और अंतरराष्ट्रीय बाजार की परिस्थितियों से इस शुष्क ईंधन के दाम नीचे लाने में मदद मिली है और घरेलू उत्पादन बढ़ा है। लेकिन बिजली संयंत्रों को प्रतिस्पर्धी दरों पर कोयला संपर्क उपलब्ध कराने के लिये एक प्रणाली की जरूरत है। सूत्रों का कहना है कि नई नीति से यह चिंता दूर होगी और बिजली घरों के लिये उनकी जरूरत के मुताबिक कोयले की आपूर्ति के वास्ते उचित प्रणाली तैयार होगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>