<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory for Joining a Company</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government has made the biometric authentication using Aadhaar mandatory after facing several scenarios of fake identity theft—including becoming a director on a board of the company or for issuing its returns by company secretaries and chartered accountants—for Companies Act-related transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the sources, the Ministry Of Corporate Affairs has encountered several instances where people have established a Director Identification Number or have been chosen as directors on boards of the company without their consent, a necessity for connecting a board, as their signatures were copied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, in the near future, anyone looking for a Director Identification Number will have to authenticate using biometric devices and fill up the online form that can soon be connected to PCs. In the same way, anyone chosen by the banks or government and financial institutions on boards of the company will have to provide biometric authentication. A parallel setup for company secretaries and CAs is also being operated out, confirmed the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A squad from Infosys has been assigned with placing in the new machine that will be introduced in stages, initiating with the allocation of Director Identification Number. Progressively over a period of couple of years, it will be extended to involve all work related to MCA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be exclusions for non-residents and others, who are not qualified to get Aadhaar such as those people whose iris or fingerprints are not able to capture. MCA considers that the projected system does not encounter any issues since the recent order of the Supreme Court on Aadhaar as the system was destined for authentication. According to sources, the Supreme court had itself recommended that mobile connections be confirmed using Aadhaar and tax department as well as the banks have also been permitted to use the distinctive identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2017, the income tax department has also made Aadhaar compulsory for issuing permanent account numbers since it targets individuals using numerous PANs, which is not legal, to avoid from taxes. Though this move was disapproved, the government thinks that employment of UID can aid in enhancing compliance across various sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go for PM’s insurance schemes on June 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY) were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must have heard about the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY), which were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner. While the first is a life insurance scheme, the other is an accidental cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already enrolled yourself under these schemes and want the cover to continue, then the premium will be auto debited from your account on June 1. You might also have received an SMS from your bank in this respect. However, if you have still not done this and want to go for the schemes, then you can enrol for these schemes on June 1 to get their full benefit as the schemes provide coverage for one-year period from June 1 to May 31. You can go for these schemes anytime during the year, but will have to pay the same premium. So, why to delay? Why not to get enrolled from Day 1?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how these schemes work:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana is a one-year life insurance scheme, which is annually renewable. The scheme provides coverage of Rs 2 lakh for death owing to any reason and is offered to all saving bank account holders in the age group of 18 to 50 years at the annual premium of only Rs 330.
The date of commencement of insurance cover under this scheme is the date of debit of premium from the insured member’s account for joining the scheme and the insurance cover is provided up to May 31 of the subsequent year. However, the risk is not covered for new members during the first 45 days from the date of enrollment into the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover is automatically renewed on June 1 of every year by debiting the premium from the member’s bank account. In case anyone wishes to join the scheme thereafter, one can do so by paying the full year’s premium and submitting the requisite documents.
According to the information provided by the government, as on April 12, 2017, Cumulative Gross enrolment reported by banks subject to verification of eligibility, etc. was about 3.1 crore under PMJJBY. A total of 63291 claims were registered under this scheme, of which 59770 have been disbursed.
Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana is a one-year accident insurance, which can be renewed annually. Under this scheme, accidental death and full disability cover of Rs 2 lakh and partial disability cover of Rs 1 lakh is offered on account of an accident to all saving bank account holders in the age group of 18 to 70 years for a premium of Rs 12 per annum. If you subscribe for this scheme, then the premium will directly auto-debited by the bank from your account.
As on April 12, 2017, cumulative gross enrolment reported by banks subject to verification of eligibility, etc. was about 10 crore under PMSBY. A total of 12816 claims were registered under PMSBY, of which 9646 have been disbursed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt makes Aadhaar mandatory for students</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is aimed at checking the drop-out rate and ensuring quality education&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Yogi Adityanath government in Uttar Pradesh has made Aadhaar Card mandatory for students from Class 1 to 8 in government schools. The Basic Education department has been entrusted with this task involving over 1.75 crore students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Basic Education Minister Anupama Jaiswal said that directions have been issued in this regard. “The main aim of the government is to link their Aadhaar Card number with different welfare schemes, including mid-day meal, run by the state for the welfare of primary students,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aadhaar will also help the basic education department to keep a tab on their attendance as well as their performance. “This will certainly help the government to check the drop-out rate and ensure quality education to primary students,” said the minister after holding review meeting of the department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Yogi government has also decided to replace Khakhi dress of primary students with vibrant pink shirt and blue pants for boys, and pink kurti and blue pyjama for girls. The new dress code would be effective this session from July. Orders have already been placed for the distribution of free dress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, it was CM Adityanath who had raised an objection on school dress in the state saying that students look more like policemen. He had ordered for selection of new dress as per choices of students and parents. After taking opinion from them, the basic education department finally selected the new dress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Basic Education department has also decided to form a six-member committee of mothers in over 1.25 lahh primary schools in the state. Known as ‘Maa’, the committee would randomly check the quality of food being served in mid-day meal. Each primary school will have separate committee to ensure quality food to students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also issued directives to bring every child to schools and ensure distribution of free school bags, shoes, and text book by July first week&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-linked payment system will change the game for digital transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Unique Identification Authority of India is working with banks and the Reserve Bank of India to ensure that merchants who use its mobile-based application for digital transactions earn a commission of up to 1% of the transaction value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With UIDAI suggesting it is on path to get this in place in a couple of months, the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System could give debit cards and e-wallets a run for their money. In contrast to what UIDAI is advocating, all other forms of digital payments require merchants to pay a fee or commission for the use of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Aadhaar-based system is being used for PDS [public distribution system] in Andhra Pradesh, Rajasthan and Gujarat. We are also in discussions with Haryana,” said Ajay Bhushan Pandey, chief executive officer, UIDAI. “We are enrolling banks so that they start accepting Aadhaar-based payments. Two banks have already agreed. The process of integrating merchants with banks will be completed in the next few weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Merchants as business correspondents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once implemented, this model envisages doing away with all charges that are associated with a typical point-of-sale machine. Under the system, UIDAI would enlist merchants as business correspondents. These merchants would use their phones linked to biometric devices for the transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These require a customer to key in their Aadhaar number and verify their fingerprint on the biometric reader connected to the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable a wide acceptability, the government has pushed for linking all savings bank accounts to Aadhaar numbers against a stiff deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a customer transacts with a merchant through Aadhaar Enabled Payment System, the merchant would receive the same incentive that business correspondents employed by banks do, UIDAI has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different banks provide different incentives to business correspondents on the basis of their performance. For instance, the Vidharbha Konkan Gramin Bank, a regional rural bank provides Rs 10 for every new account opened by a business correspondent. If someone deposits money through PoS terminals, the correspondent gets 0.5% of the money. For mobilising a term deposit, the correspondent gets 0.25% of the amount. Similarly, various incentives, as a proportion of the transaction amount, are given to correspondents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Merchants will now be doing the job of a business correspondent,” said Pandey. “So what was being paid as incentives to the correspondent would be extended to merchants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, he suggested, this would reduce the need for banking correspondents as more and more merchants use the Aadhaar app on their phones for transactions. The app itself has been tested by a couple of banks and is being finalised, Pandey said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UIDAI business model would mean the banking system taking on the burden of incentivising the spread of Aadhaar-based payments through mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, at the moment, they earn from other digital transactions. But Pandey said UIDAI was convincing banks that the commission must be seen in the light of existing commission structures for correspondents and the cost of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Costs of going cashless&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A look at the fee structure of PoS machines used to carry out card transactions indicates a substantial cost for the merchant. A third-party PoS provider has multiple layers of charges. These machines are not sold but often given on rent by banks and third-party vendors. Some banks charge the merchants a monthly rental of Rs 400 for a portable PoS machine for two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some banks also recover something called a “commitment charge”. These charges can be a burden on smaller merchants with low volumes of sales. Merchants with a lower sale volume have to pay a higher commitment charge. Competition between different vendors and banks has been bringing down these costs, though, over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks such as the State Bank of India and its public-sector peers offer machines on more lenient terms than third-party vendors. SBI, for instance, says that it doesn’t take a one-time installation charge from any merchant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final layer of the cost of using a PoS machine is the merchant discount rate. This is the charge that banks collect from merchants whenever a card is swiped on the machine. Banks usually charge a lower rate if their own debit cards are used on their PoS machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before January 1, the charges were 0.75% for transactions of value up to Rs 2,000. For transactions above Rs 2,000, a rate of 1% of the transaction value was recovered from the merchant. Foreign cards attracted double the rate while credit card transactions were charged at 1.5%. This was either borne by the merchant or passed on to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After demonetisation, RBI introduced an additional layer of merchant discount rate through a notification issued on December 16, 2016. Between January 1 and March 31 this year, the merchant discount rate for transactions up to Rs 1,000 is to be 0.25%. All others would continue to be charged as before. The rate has been capped at 1%. Clearly, the multiple charges add up to a significant amount for a merchant who has little option but to either bear the cost or to pass it on to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game-changer?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RBI data show that PoS transactions through debit cards touched Rs 31,600 crore in November 2016. In November 2015, this figure stood at Rs 14,800 crore. Banks quite clearly stand to make a killing through these multiple layers of charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile wallets, too, are known to charge as high as 4% for certain types of transactions. Mobile wallet transactions were Rs 3,300 crore in November 2016 as compared to Rs 1,900 crore in November 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where the Aadhaar-linked payment system could be a major disruptor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the National Payments Corporation of India charges 1% on every financial transaction through the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System from the bank. The bank passes this on to the merchant. It’s unclear if these charges would be set off too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandey told Business Standard that a favourable decision could come soon. If it does, it would completely turn the digital transactions ecosystem on its head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change of the business model for digital transactions would require many banks to come on board. NPCI data show that of the 46 public-sector banks and private banks in India, 44 are classified as “member banks” of Aadhaar Enabled Payment System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp:10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on &lt;em&gt;Rs 3,050&lt;/em&gt; crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.
He did not give further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department, on April 5, wrote to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) asking it to give a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo; on the penalty issue, and also outline the basis and provisions of law under which the said amount had been recommended by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources familiar with the matter said that DoT, in its communication, has also asked the Trai to provide information on the number of subscribers acquired by Reliance Jio during the testing phase (that is prior to its commercial launch). The incumbent operators and the Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio clashed last year over the issue of call connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio cried foul that its customers were suffering from call failures as the incumbent operators were not giving it sufficient interconnect capacity. The operators, in turn, charged the newcomer of unleashing a &amp;ldquo;tsunami&amp;rdquo; of free traffic on their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interconnection enables mobile users to make calls to customers of other telecom networks and is, therefore, crucial for smooth functioning of mobile services. In October last year, Trai recommended to the Telecom Department, the imposition of total penalty of Rs 3,050 crore on the three incumbent operators Bharti Airtel, Vodafone and Idea Cellular for allegedly denying interconnectivity to the
new entrant that led to deterioration in the quality of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Trai&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, the penalty for Airtel and Vodafone worked out to about Rs 1,050 crore each, while in case of Idea Cellular stood at about Rs 950 crore. The regulator, in fact, had stopped short of recommending cancellation of their telecom licences saying it may lead to significant consumer inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the issue was placed before the Telecom Commission earlier this year, the highest policy-making body of the telecom department, it favoured referring the matter back to Trai for a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Commission asked DoT to seek clarification from Trai on nearly a dozen points, including whether the stipulated 90-day period was given to the three telecom operators for providing point of interconnection to the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI&#39;s New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1. SBI has clarified that the Rs. 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through its mobile wallet app. SBI’s app Bank Buddy is a new facility that enables withdrawal of cash through ATMs using the bank&amp;rsquo;s mobile wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal saving bank accounts in a month will continue to get eight free ATM transactions (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks) in metros and 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks), the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applies to the Basic Savings Banks Deposit Accounts, SBI further said. SBI’s basic savings account is a limited-services bank account aimed at poorer sections of society to encourage them to start saving without any burden of charges or fees. This type of bank account comes with an ATM-cum-debit free of cost and no annual maintenance charges. A basic savings bank deposit account holder is not eligible to open any other savings bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective June 1. Here are some of the other key changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS or Immediate Payment Service will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh; Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh; and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh
.
&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; If a customer wishes to exchange of more than 20 soiled notes or if the total value of soiled notes is above Rs. 5,000, SBI said it will charge Rs. 2 plus service charge for every soiled note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customer with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs. 30 plus service tax for a 10-leaf cheque book, Rs. 75 with service tax for 25-leaf cheque book and Rs. 150 plus service tax for a 50-leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issuance of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only RuPay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs. 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs. 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCO Bank Says RBI Begins Corrective Action Over High Bad Loans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uco-bank-says-rbi-begins-corrective-action-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uco-bank-says-rbi-begins-corrective-action-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under RBI rules, prompt corrective action is triggered if a bank&amp;rsquo;s net NPL ratio crosses 6 percent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has initiated &amp;ldquo;prompt corrective action&amp;rdquo; for state-run UCO Bank over its high bad loans and negative return on assets, UCO said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UCO, in a filing to the stock exchanges, said the action &amp;ldquo;will not have any material impact&amp;rdquo; on its performance, but did not give details of the corrective action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the second state-run lender to come under the curbs of the Reserve Bank of India after the regulator revised the so-called prompt corrective action framework last month, tightening thresholds around bad loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier on Friday, UCO Bank reported a narrowing of its quarterly loss and bad-loan ratio. It had net non-performing loans (NPLs) of 8.94 percent at the end of March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under RBI rules, prompt corrective action is triggered if a bank&amp;rsquo;s net NPL ratio crosses 6 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDBI Bank, another state-run lender, said on Tuesday it was facing corrective action by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysts say more lenders could come under central bank curbs as regulators strive to clean up bad loans of $150 billion in the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमें ने पैन से आधार को लिंक करने के लिए शुरू की SMS सुविधा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms-i-t-dept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms-i-t-dept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने करदाताओं को एसएमएस सुविधा का उपयोग कर आधार संख्या को पैन नंबर से जोड़ने को कहा है। देश के प्रमुख समाचार पत्रों में दिए गए विज्ञापनों में विभाग ने एसएमएस के जरिए आधार और पैन को आपस में लिंक करने की जानकारी दी है। इसके लिए किसी व्यक्ति को अपने फोन से बड़े अक्षरों में यूआईडीपीएएन के बाद खाली जगह छोड़कर अपनी आधार संख्या और फिर उसके बाद अपनी पैन संख्या को लिखकर 567678 या 56161 को एसएमएस भेजना होगा। इसके अलावा विभाग की ई-फाइलिंग वेबसाइट पर जाकर भी इनको आपस में लिंक किया जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विज्ञापन में कहा गया है कि निर्बाध रूप से इनकम टैक्स से जुड़ी सारी सुविधाएं ऑनलाइन पाते रहने के लिए दोनों नंबरों को लिंक करना बहुत जरूरी है। इसमें कहा गया है, &amp;lsquo;अब नया पैन बनाते वक्त ऐप्लिकेशन फॉर्म में ही आधार नंबर का जिक्र कर देने से दोनों लिंक हो जाएंगे। साथ ही, पैन कार्ड की रीप्रिंटिग वाले चेंज रिक्वेस्ट फॉर्म में आधार नंबर देने से भी यह काम हो सकता है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PAN से आधार कार्ड जोड़ने के लिए आयकर विभाग ने शुरू की नई सुविधा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने आधार और पैन लिंक करने के लिए इसी महीने नई ऑनलाइन सुविधा शुरू की थी। अब आधार और पैन की लिंकिंग को इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न भरने के लिए अनिवार्य बना दिया गया है। डिपार्टमेंट की ई-फाइलिंग वेबसाइट ने अपने होमपेज पर एक नया लिंक दिया है जिसके जरिए आधार को पैन से जोड़ा जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एक रुपए का नया नोट, नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार का फैसला</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-government-will-issue-one-rupees-note-after-two-decades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-government-will-issue-one-rupees-note-after-two-decades/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;एक रुपए से आज भले ही हम ज्यादा कुछ न खरीद पाएं, लेकिन फिर भी केंद्र सरकार देश में इसको चलते रहने देना चाहती है।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक रुपए से आज भले ही हम ज्यादा कुछ न खरीद पाएं, लेकिन फिर भी केंद्र सरकार देश में इसको चलन में रहने देना चाहती है। सरकार ने इसे 20 साल बाद दोबारा छापने का फैसला किया है। हालांकि, पुराने नोट और सिक्के भी चलन में रहेंगे। भारतीय रिर्जव बैंक (आरबीआई) ने इस बात की पुष्टि की है। आरबीआई ने इस बारे में बताया कि वह जल्द ही एक रुपए के नए नोट चलन में लाएगा। भारत सरकार इन्हें छापेगी। ये नोट कॉइनेज एक्ट 2011 के तहत छापे जाएंगे। फिलहाल एक रुपए के सिक्के चलन में हैं, जो टकसाल में तैयार किए जाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक रुपए के इस नए नोट के सबसे ऊपर ‘भारत सरकार’ अंग्रेजी और हिंदी में लिखा होगा। इसके पास में ही वित्त मंत्रालय के सचिव के हस्ताक्षर होंगे। जबकि बाकी नोटों पर भारतीय रिर्जव बैंक के गर्वनर के हस्ताक्षर होते हैं। नोट के आगे का हिस्सा हल्का गुलाबी और हरा रंग का नजर आएगा और जहां ‘एक रुपए’ लिखा होगा, उसके पीछे फूल-पत्ती वाली आकृति बनी होगी। वहीं, पीछे के हिस्से में सागर सम्राट की तस्वीर होगी। उसके बगल में 15 भारतीय भाषाओं में नोट की कीमत लिखी होगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारतीय रिर्जव बैंक के अधिकारी ने इससे जुड़ी जानकारी देते हुए कहा कि एक रुपए का नया नोट को ‘द कॉइनेज एक्ट 2011’ के तहत वैध टेंडर दिया गया है। उधर, केंद्र सरकार की इस पहल का चेन्नई में लोगों ने बढ़-चढ़कर स्वागत किया है। यहां एक चाय की दुकान लगाने वाले अरुण कुमार ने बताया कि फुटकर पैसे न होने से ग्राहकों को चॉकलेट या टॉफी देनी पड़ती थी, जिससे वह परेशान होते थे। अगर नया नोट आता है, तो बेशक इससे समस्या हल हो जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;व्यापारियों का कहना है कि भारतीय रिर्जव बैंक की ओर से उन्हें पर्याप्त मात्रा में सिक्के नहीं मिलते हैं। आमतौर पर दो रुपए और पांच रुपए के सिक्कों की कमी रहती है। कोट्टम के वल्लूर में दुकानदार पी.श्रीनाथ ने बताया कि उन्हें हर महीने अपने कारोबार में 15 हजार रुपयों के सिक्कों की जरूर होती है, लेकिन बैंक की ओर से उन्हें सिर्फ तीन हजार रुपए ही हासिल हो पाते हैं। ऐसे में उन्हें एजेंटों पर निर्भर रहना पड़ता है, जो 10 फीसद कमीशन लेकर उन्हें सिक्के मुहैया कराते हैं। ये एजेंट स्टेशन के आसपास भिखारियों से सिक्के खरीदते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जून से SBI इन सेवाओं के लिए वसूलेगा एक्‍स्‍ट्रा चार्ज, ये होंगे बदलाव</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-customers-bank-will-charge-extra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-customers-bank-will-charge-extra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;देश का सबसे बड़ा बैंक एसबीआई 1 जून से अपनी कई सेवाओं के शुल्‍क में बढ़ोतरी करने जा रहा है। पहली जून से अगर आप एसबीआई जाकर कटे-फटे नोट बदलवाते हैं या एक सीमा से अधिक बार पैसे निकालते हैं तो एसबीआई आपसे चार्ज वसूलेगा। बेसिक सेविंग बैंक डिपॉजिट अकाउंट के ग्राहकों को पैसे निकालने, नए कार्ड इश्यू करवाने जैसी सुविधाएं के लिए भी 1 जून से चार्ज देना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कैश विड्रॉल पर लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एसबीआई से कैश विड्रॉल सिर्फ 4 बार तक के लिए ही मुफ्त रहेगी। इसमें एटीएम ट्रांजैक्शंस भी शामिल हैं। 4 बार से ज्यादा एसबीआई की ब्रांच से भी कैश विड्रॉल करेंगे तो हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 50 रुपए का सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लगेगा। एसबीआई के एटीएम से 4 बार से ज्यादा विड्रॉल करेंगे तो हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 10 रुपए सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स देना होगा। दूसरे बैंक के एटीएम से 4 बार से ज्यादा कैश विड्रॉल पर हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 20 रुपए सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लगेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;आरबीआई ने दिए कटे-फटे नोट को लेकर दिए थे ये निर्देश&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30 अप्रैल को ही आरबीआई ने बैंकों को कटे, लिखे, पुराने व फटे नोटों को लेने के लिए कहा था. रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (आरबीआई) ने बैंकों को साफ निर्देश दिया है कि उन्हें गंदे नोट लेने ही होंगे और इसे लेने से वे इनकार नहीं कर सकते। लेकिन अगर आप एसबीआई में कटे-फटे या गले-गीले नोट जमा कराएंगे तो आपके ऊपर अतिरिक्त चार्ज देना होर्गा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;पुराने कटे-फटे नोट बदलने पर भी लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एसबीआई 20 से ज्यादा या 5,000 रुपए से ज्यादा कटे-फटे नोट बदलवाने पर अब 2 से लेकर 5 रुपए तक का चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स वसूलेगा। इसके तहत हर नोट पर 2 रुपये या हरेक 1,000 रुपये पर 5 रुपये चार्ज, जो भी ज्यादा होगा, वह वसूला जाएगा। 5,000 रुपए तक कीमत होने पर हर नोट पर 2 रुपये चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स वसूला जाएगा और 5000 रुपये से ज्यादा कीमत होने पर हर नोट पर 5 रुपये चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लिया जाएगा। कटे-फटे 20 नोट जिनकी कुल कीमत 5,000 रुपये से ज्यादा नहीं होगी तक बदलने पर एसबीआई कोई सर्विस चार्ज नहीं लगेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बेसिक बैंक डिपॉजिट अकाउंट के नए कार्ड पर भी लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 जून से एसबीआई एक्स्ट्रा डेबिट कार्ड इश्यू करने पर भी चार्ज लेने की तैयारी कर रहा है। एक जून से बैंक सिर्फ रुपे डेबिट कार्ड ही मुफ्त में जारी करेगा। बाकी सभी कार्ड जारी करने पर बैंक ने सर्विस चार्ज लेने का ऐलान कर दिया है। 1 जून से बैंक मास्टर और वीजा कार्ड इश्यू करने पर सर्विस चार्ज लेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जून से ही आधार अनिवार्य</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tells-supreme-court-aadhar-deadline-not-to-be-extended/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tells-supreme-court-aadhar-deadline-not-to-be-extended/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट में साफ कर दिया है कि 30 जून से आधार को अनिवार्य कर दिया जाएगा। केंद्र सरकार ने शुक्रवार को कोर्ट को बताया कि अलग-अलग समाज कल्याण योजनाओं का लाभ लेने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने संबंधी 30 जून की समय सीमा आगे नहीं बढ़ाई जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जस्टिस ए एम खानविलकर और जस्टिस नवीन सिन्हा की पीठ के सामने अटॉर्नी जनरल मुकुल रोहतगी ने कहा कि वेलफेयर स्कीम के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने का मकसद यही है कि इसका लाभ उन लोगों तक नहीं पहुंचे जो अस्तित्व में ही नहीं हैं, जैसा कि सार्वजनिक वितरण प्रणाली जैसी योजनाओं के मामले में पाया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने केंद्र सरकार की विभिन्न अधिसूचनाओं को चुनौती देने और अंतरिम राहत का अनुरोध किए जाने पर भी आपत्ति की और कहा कि इस मामले को 5 सदस्यीय संविधान पीठ के सामने सुनवाई के लिए सूचीबद्ध किया जाना चाहिए। रोहतगी ने कहा कि इससे पहले भी इसी तरह की अंतरिम राहत के लिए याचिकाएं दायर की गईं थीं और वे मामले सुप्रीम कोर्ट के पास लंबित हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पीठ ने कहा कि अंतरिम राहत के लिए दायर सभी याचिकाओं पर वह एक साथ सुनवाई करेगी ताकि दोहराव से बचा जा सके। कोर्ट ने इसके साथ ही इस मामले को 27 जून के लिए सूचीबद्ध करने का निर्देश दिया। सुप्रीम कोर्ट जब इस सवाल पर विचार कर रही थी कि क्या इन मामलों को गर्मी की छुट्टियों के दौरान ही सुनवाई के लिए सूचीबद्ध किया जाए, तभी एक याचिकाकर्ता की ओर से वरिष्ठ अधिवक्ता श्याम दीवान ने कहा कि इसमें शीघ्र सुनवाइ की आवश्यकता है। यदि इस पर 30 जून से पहले सुनवाई नहीं होती है तो फिर केंद्र को इसकी समय सीमा आगे बढ़ानी चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस पर रोहतगी ने कहा कि इसका कोई सवाल ही नहीं उठता। कोर्ट ने अंतरिम राहत का अनुरोध करने वाली सभी याचिकाओं को 27 जून को सूचीबद्ध करने का आदेश दिया है। साथ ही सरकार को तीन सप्ताह के अंदर जवाबी हलफनामा दाखिल करने का आदेश दिया है। शुक्रवार को सुनवाई शुरू होते ही अटॉर्नी जनरल ने कहा कि इसी तरह की अंतरिम राहत के अनुरोध के साथ करीब 6 महीने पहले याचिकाएं दायर की थीं। इन याचिकाओं को मुख्य मामले के साथ जोड़ दिया गया था, जिन पर संविधान पीठ सुनवाई करेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>टैरिफ प्लान पर ट्रांसपैरेंसी को लेकर टेलिकॉम ऑपरेटर में भिड़ंत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-operators-clash-in-on-tariff-plans-for-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-operators-clash-in-on-tariff-plans-for-transparency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मोबाइल टैरिफ प्लान में ट्रांसपैरेंसी को लेकर रिलायंस जियो, भारतीय एयरटेल और आइडिया के बीच तकरार कम होने का नाम नहीं ले रही है। एकतरफ भारती एयरटेल और आइडिया कड़ी प्रतिस्पर्धा के इस दौर में कस्टमर्स को साथ बनाए रखने के लिए कुछ खास ऑफर्स का अधिकार चाहती हैं, वहीं रिलायंस जियो को ऐसा नहीं लगता। भारती एयरटेल और आइडिया का मानना है कि मौजूदा यूजर्स को अपने साथ बनाए रखने के लिए कुछ टैरिफ प्लांस को सीक्रेट रखा जाना चहिए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इससे पहले टैरिफ प्लान में ट्रांसपैरेंसी नहीं होने के कारण रिलायंस जियो ने टेलीकॉम रेगुलेटर ट्राई से शिकायत की थी। जियो का कहना था कि इंडस्ट्री में कुछ कंपनियां एक कैटेगरी के लोगों को अलग-अलग टैरिफ प्लान ऑफर कर रही हैं, जो ट्राई के नियमों का उल्लंघन है। इससे लोगों के साथ धोखा भी हो रहा है। कंपनी का कहना था कि कुछ ऑपरेटर कस्टमर्स को ऐसे प्लान ऑफर कर रहे हैं, जो उसी कैटेगरी के बाकी कस्टमर्स के लिए अवेलेबल नहीं हैं। जियो का कहना है कि सभी टेलीकॉम कंपनियों को कॉमन प्लेटफॉर्म के तहत अपने सभी प्लान ऑफर करने चहिए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;टेलीकॉम अथॉरिटी ऑफ इंडिया (ट्राई) ने टैरिफ असेसमेंट को लेकर एक ओपन हाउस डिस्कशन किया था। इसमें भारतीय एयरटेल और आइडिया का कहना था कि नए और मौजूदा यूजर्स के बीच टैरिफ प्लान को अलग-अलग तरह से ऑफर करने का अधिकार कंपनियों को मिलना चहिए। कंपनियों की दलील थी कि रिटेन्शन ऑफर में डिस्काउंट दिया जाता है, जो मनमानी नहीं है। ये डिस्काउंट एवरेज रेवेन्यू प्रति यूजर और कस्टमर लॉयल्टी जैसे कई पैरामीटर को देखने के बाद दिए जाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दरअसल, टेलीकॉम रेगुलेटर टैरिफ, प्रमोशनल ऑफर्स, डिस्काउंट और ड्यूरेशन जैसे कई मसलों पर 30 दिनों के अंदर एक गाइडलाइन पेश करना चाहता है, जिसका सभी टेलीकॉम कंपनियों को पालन करना होगा। इससे पहले रेगुलेटर सभी पक्षों को अपनी बात रखने का मौका दे रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारती एयरटेल के रेगुलेटरी हेड रवि गांधी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जब कोई कस्टमर किसी ऑपरेटर को छोड़कर जाना चाहता है तब भी कस्टमर और ऑपरेटर के बीच एक रिलेशन जारी रहता है। यह ऑपरेटर का अधिकार है कि वह अपने कस्टमर्स को कुछ ऑफर्स के जरिए फिर से अपने साथ बनाए रखे।&amp;rsquo; हालांकि रिलायंस जियो के अंशुमन ठाकुर इस बात से सहमत नहीं हैं। अंशुमन का कहना है कि इंडस्ट्री में ट्रांसपैरेंसी नहीं है। इसलिए वह चाहते हैं कि सभी टेलीकॉम कंपनियों जो टैरिफ प्लान ऑफर कर रही हैं, वह एक कॉमन प्लेटफॉर्म पर लिस्टेड हों। इस प्लेटफॉर्म के बाहर कोई भी कंपनी कस्टमर्स को कोई दूसरा प्लान ऑफर ना करे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अंशुमन का कहना है कि एक बार जब सभी प्लान एक कॉमन प्लेटफॉर्म पर आ जाएंगे तो कस्टमर्स अपने हिसाब से उनमें से किसी प्लान को चुन सकता है। उन्होंने कहा कि इसलिए ट्राई को इस मसले के लिए सभी कंपनियों के लिए एक गाइडलाइन तैयार करनी चहिए, जिससे किसी के साथ भेदभाव नहीं हो।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>