<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>11 दिन में ही 3.20 रुपये सस्ता हो गया पेट्रोल और डीजल की कीमत में आई 2.41 रुपये प्रति लीटर की कमी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/per-litre-and-diesal-price-cut-2-42-rupees-per-liter-in-just-over-10-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/per-litre-and-diesal-price-cut-2-42-rupees-per-liter-in-just-over-10-days/</guid>
      <description>16 जून से पूरे भारत में अंतरराष्ट्रीय मार्केट के मुताबिक डीजल और पेट्रोल की कीमतें तय होने लगी हैं। अभी तेल की कीमतों में रोजाना कुछ पैसे की कमी आ रही है। 3-4 दिन में महसूस होता है कि तेल की कीमतें कम हुई हैं। 16 जून से लेकर 26 जून तक तेल की कीमतों में काफी कमी आई है। पिछले 11 दिन में दिल्ली में पेट्रोल की कीमत में</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 online jobs that you can do from home</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Whether you’re looking for a respite from your 9 to 5, are unable to commute to work, are a stay at-home parent, or have some other constraint that prevents you from finding a full-time job, there’s no need to waste your earning potential.
There are plenty of opportunities available online that let you work from home. Here are a few options you can consider.
 Virtual assistantship  Entrepreneurs, professionals and small teams often need assistance with various administrative tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.
SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Allows Co-Operative Banks To Deposit Old Notes With RBI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</guid>
      <description>The relaxation comes against the backdrop of reports that many district co-operative banks did not have enough cash to disburse to farmers.
The Finance Ministry on Tuesday allowed banks, post offices and district central cooperative banks to deposit the scrapped Rs 500 and 1,000 rupee notes with the Reserve Bank of India within 30 days and exchange the value of notes deposit with the new notes.
In an official notification the Finance Ministry said, &amp;ldquo;Specified bank notes may be deposited by such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, in any office of the Reserve Bank, within a period of 30 days from the commencement of these rules, and get the exchange value thereof by credit to the account of such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, subject to the satisfaction of the Reserve Bank of the conditions specified in the said notification and the reasons for non-deposit of the specified bank notes within the period under that notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GST will change your online shopping experience from July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-change-your-online-shopping-experience-from-july-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-change-your-online-shopping-experience-from-july-1/</guid>
      <description>Tax collected at source Currently, e-commerce websites do not collect tax in any form. Under the GST, they will collect tax at a fixed rate of 1 per cent while paying to the sellers listed on their websites. This is likely to impact prices and make your online shopping more expensive. Though, the move has been deferred, it is likely to come in force at a later date.
Faster delivery Under the GST, your goods will reach you faster as the retailers will not have to file a separate paperwork for each state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GST will impact your household budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</guid>
      <description>Goods and services tax (GST) comes into effect from 1 July. ET Wealth analyses the impact on some basic expenses in the household consumption basket.
AUTOMOBILES The price difference will be bigger for SUVs (55% to 43%) compared to small cars (30% to 29%).
Base price : Rs 4.75 lakh
Total taxes now* : Rs 1.43 lakh
Under GST : Rs 1.38 lakh
DURABLES : Refrigerators and washing machines For most white goods, there won&amp;rsquo;t be much difference in price as new rates will be close to earlier ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Plan Of Affordable Housing For All By 2022</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-real-estate-act-will-boost-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-real-estate-act-will-boost-housing/</guid>
      <description>The government has backed its Housing for All by 2022 promise with a slew of reforms for buyers and developers alike.
The Indian real estate sector has seen a resurgence of interest in 2017 after a slowdown over the past 2-3 years, buoyed by the affordable housing segment, which includes residential units below Rs 50 lakh. Legislations the like Real Estate (Regulation and Development) Act, 2016, (RERA) and Goods and Services Tax (GST) have signalled that the government is ready to walk the talk for its &amp;lsquo;Housing for All&amp;rsquo; by 2022 promise and many developers and institutional players have flocked to the affordable housing market, a report by Colliers International India, the Indian wing of a global commercial real estate company said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.
Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Announces Mega Auction Of Properties</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</guid>
      <description>The bank will auction off 150 properties,including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country.
State Bank of India (SBI) has a nnounced a sale of properties through a mega e-auction on June 23, 2017. This was said by the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank on microblogging site Twitter. The bank will auction off 150 properties, including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country, SBI said on its website. These properties were pledged as collateral for housing and business loans and were taken over by the bank under the Security and Reconstruction of Financial Assets and Enforcement of Security Interest (Sarfaesi) Act due to non-payment of pending dues by the borrowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammers are trying to get your Aadhaar details via calls, emails</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</guid>
      <description>Watch out! The scammers are out with a new set of tricks to swindle the gullible public. Curiously, the Centre’s directive to link the bank accounts with Aadhaar has apparently made these fraudsters more brazen. Their latest modus operandi is to seek details of the Aadhaar card from unsuspecting victims through phone calls and emails.
Posing as bank executives or tele-callers, they call up potential victims saying, “The bank has decided to link your Aadhaar number with debit card for better customer service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten rules you must follow while filing income tax returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ten-rules-you-must-follow-while-filing-income-tax-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ten-rules-you-must-follow-while-filing-income-tax-return/</guid>
      <description>Who needs to file tax returns?
If the gross taxable income after exemptions, but before deductions, exceeds the basic limit, or if a tax refund has to be claimed, you need to file your tax return.
 _I: THOU SHALL FILE RETURNS IF INCOME EXCEEDS BASIC LIMIT _
Do you have to file your tax return? Taxpayers hold many misconceptions about this. Some think if their income is not taxable, they needn’t file their return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win Rupay Select Credit Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>IDBI Bank announced the launch of ‘Winnings’ Rupay Select Credit Card that offers a range of travel, shopping and dining privileges and also enables earning of rewards points on every spend. The credit card has been launched in association with National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI). This product is similar to the international credit cards offered by VISA and MasterCard.
The ‘Winnings’ RuPay Select Credit Card is a premium credit card variant and is at par with the premium Card variants of International Card networks which is Visa Signature and MasterCard World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>petrol price has fallen Rs 3.5 per litre in just 12 days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-diesel-price-today-falls-11-days-daily-fuel-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-diesel-price-today-falls-11-days-daily-fuel-price/</guid>
      <description>Petrol and diesel prices are falling since the daily fuel price revision was implemented. But unlike earlier, when there would be significant noticeable changes every fortnight, this time, the prices have fallen by just a few paise everyday, barely to the notice of many people across the nation. Put together, however, the change is huge over the last 12 days, since July 16, when the daily revision in retail fuel prices began nationwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न्स तो रखें इन 10 बेसिक बातों का ध्यान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/if-you-have-to-file-income-tax-returns-itr-you-must-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/if-you-have-to-file-income-tax-returns-itr-you-must-know/</guid>
      <description>भारत में इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न्स भरना हमेशा से ही टेढी़ खीर माना जाता रहा है लेकिन नोटबंदी और नए आयकर कानूनों के बाद इसे लेकर लोगों में और भी ज्यादा भ्रम है। वित्त मंत्रालय और आयकर विभाग ने करदाताओं की सुविधा के लिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न्स (आईटीआर) फॉर्म को पहले से आसान बना दिया है। सबसे बड़ी दुविधा यही है कि किसी टैक्स रिटर्न भरना चाहिए किसे नहीं। जिन लोगों की सालाना आय इनकम टैक्स छूट की थोड़ी-बहुत अधिक होती है वो इसे लेकर खास गफलत में रहते हैं। कुछ लोगों को लगता है कि चूंकि उनकी आय पर टीडीएस (टैक्स डिडक्टेड एट सोर्स) कट चुका है इसलिए उन्हें आईटीआर भरने की जरूरत नहीं है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>खातों की कम जानकारी देने वाले करदाता जांच के दायरे में</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</guid>
      <description>आयकर विभाग ने सत्यापन के लिए 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान की है, जिसमें 1.58 लाख करदाता ऐसे शामिल हैं, जिन्होंने पिछले दिनों अपने खातों की आंशिक घोषणा की थी। नोटबंदी के बाद इंकम टैक्स विभाग को बैंकों द्वारा दायर वित्तीय लेनदेन के बयान (एसएफटी) सहित विभिन्न स्रोतों से कई अहम जानकारी मिली। आईटी विभाग ने कहा कि इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने 1.58 लाख करदाताओं से संबंधित 3.71 लाख नए खातों की पहचान की है, जिन्होंने पहले अपने अकाउंट के बारे में जानकारी दी थी। पहले 18 लाख मामलों के अलावा, 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सरकारी योजनाओं के लिए अब अक्टूबर से जरूरी होगा आधार कार्ड</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sep-30-deadline-for-availing-benefit-of-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sep-30-deadline-for-availing-benefit-of-social/</guid>
      <description>सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने सामाजिक कल्याण से जुड़ी विभिन्न योजनाओं का लाभ लेने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने वाली सरकारी अधिसूचना पर अंतरिम आदेश पारित करने से इनकार कर दिया। हालांकि, कोर्ट ने कहा कि जिन लोगों के पास अभी आधार कार्ड नहीं है, उन्हें सरकारी योजनाओं से वंचित नहीं किया जा सकता है। कोर्ट ने अपने 9 जून के फैसले का हवाला देते हुए कहा कि इस मामले में इससे अधिक अवलोकन की जरूरत नहीं है। न्यायालय ने मामले की अगली सुनवाई की तारीख 7 जुलाई निर्धारित की है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>स्विच ऑफ रहने पर भी दिमाग भटकाते हैं स्मार्टफोन: रिसर्च</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-when-they-are-switched-off-smartphones-distract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-when-they-are-switched-off-smartphones-distract/</guid>
      <description>एक नई स्टडी में खुलासा हुआ है कि स्मार्टफोन की उपस्थिति ब्रेन की संज्ञान लेने की क्षमता पर प्रतिकूल असर डालती है जिससे ब्रेन की डेटा प्रोसेस करने की शक्ति भी कम हो जाती है। अगर स्मार्टफोन आपके बेहद नजदीक या पहुंच में हैं तो स्विच ऑफ मोड में रहने पर भी यह हमारे दिमाग पर प्रतिकूल असर डालता है। यूएस की यूनिवर्सिटी ऑफ टेक्सस के मेककॉम्ब स्कूल ऑफ बिजनस की रिसर्च में यह खुलासा हुआ है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Data Safe From Cyber Attacks Assures Aadhaar Body Chairman</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</guid>
      <description>UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.
Allaying concerns about the security of data in Aadhaar servers in the wake of &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo; ransomware attack, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) today said its database was completely secured and immune to attacks from any kind of malware.
&amp;ldquo;The data in the Aadhaar servers is in the encrypted form. You cannot do anything with that information, which is in an encrypted form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Not Valid Proof of Citizenship</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-valid-proof-citizenship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-valid-proof-citizenship/</guid>
      <description>##FACTS
The Court was considering a bail plea of a person who was booked under Section 14F of the Indian Foreigners Act. The person claimed that she is an Indian Citizen that the issuance of the Aadhaar card was in view of long residence of the petitioner in the country.
ISSUES BEFORE THE COURT
 new passport rules which were announced by Minister of State for External Affairs VK Singh on December 23 where Aadhaar and E-Aadhaar with Date of Birth will now be considered as a valid identity proof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Not Responsible For Theft From Lockers, Says Reserve Bank</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-have-no-liability-for-loss-of-valuables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-have-no-liability-for-loss-of-valuables/</guid>
      <description>Some banks, in their locker hiring agreements, have made it clear that any item stored in the locker is at the customer&amp;rsquo;s own risk and he or she may, in their own interest, insure the valuables.
Do not expect any compensation for theft or burglary of valuables in safe deposit boxes of public sector banks as the locker hiring agreement absolves them of all liability.
This bitter truth was disclosed in an RTI response by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and 19 PSU banks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>