<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 financial tasks to do when a parent dies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</guid>
      <description>Goodbyes are the hardest when they are final. It’s worse if it involves one of your parents. The heartbreak is probably lesser in intensity only to that of your surviving parent, the spouse who is left grappling with a crippling emotional void at the fag end of life. Yet, it is critical to take a financial reality check and you, as progeny, are the best suited to do it.
Taking stock of the finances is an overwhelming task and it’s easy to be stumped by the maze of formalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9GB Free Data: Vodafone&#39;s Latest Offer In Response To Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</guid>
      <description>Since Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September, incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Vodafone is also currently offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.
Vodafone is giving 9 GB data free to customers in a special scheme, its latest offer to counter Reliance Jio which has come up with aggressive tariff plans. &amp;ldquo;Thank you for making us a 200 million strong family!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST basics: 7 misconceptions cleared</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-myths-busted-a-reality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-myths-busted-a-reality-check/</guid>
      <description>he rumour mills have gone on an overdrive mode since the launch of GST.
Here’s a reality check by ET Wealth for both GST supporters and its detractors.
 Now it’s one nation one tax  Myth : Since GST will replace all other taxes on all goods and services, we are in a single tax regime.
Reality : Though this was the original idea, petroleum products—petrol, diesel—are still outside GST’s ambit and, therefore, their tax rates vary significantly across states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get 224 GB For Rs. 509:Jio Releases New Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</guid>
      <description>As Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s promotional offers - Jio Summer Surprise and Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan - will expire for most users this month, the telecom operator has launched a new offer that provides customers up to 224 GB of 4G data along with other freebies. This comes as part of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive push to gain market share from entrenched players like Bharti Airtel and Vodafone. Jio&amp;rsquo;s new offer replaces its recharge packs priced Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government may hike BHIM referral bonus from Rs 10 to Rs 25</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-may-hike-bhim-referral-bonus-from-rs-10-to-rs-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-may-hike-bhim-referral-bonus-from-rs-10-to-rs-25/</guid>
      <description>Banks and the National Payments Corporation of India have asked the finance ministry to increase the referral bonus on payments app BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) since it has failed to attract consumers. The government is considering the request and may announce revised incentives soon.
Any person who refers BHIM to another gets Rs 10 as an incentive and the person who starts using it gets Rs 25 as an initiating cashback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to file income tax return for tax refunds and what precautions to take</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/claim-income-tax-refund-how-to-file-income-tax-return-for-tax-refunds-and-what-precautions-to-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/claim-income-tax-refund-how-to-file-income-tax-return-for-tax-refunds-and-what-precautions-to-take/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes an individual ends up paying more tax to the government than his/her actual tax liability. In such a scenario the individual becomes eligible for a tax refund. The government allows individuals to claim income tax refund while filing income tax return. An individual should make a point to understand the whole process in order to claim his/her tax refund from the tax authorities.
Having said so, there are several situations where a person becomes eligible for the same:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.
The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said. The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI acts against 50 illegal websites</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</guid>
      <description>It came to the notice of UIDAI that websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services.
Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) has ensured that 12 websites and 12 mobile applications available on the Google Playstore are shut down and has directed to close down 26 more such fraudulent and illegal websites/applications.
It came to the notice of UIDAI that these websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services such as downloading online Aadhaar card, providing status of Aadhaar generation, PVC Aadhaar Card, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.
“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ATMs Are Going Dry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</guid>
      <description>1: The ATM expansion era is over. ATM extensions will no longer be part of future banking growth, and future ATMs may well be of the mobile kind focused only on rural cash deliveries. But even here, the growth will be limited. Standalone ATM companies may have a future, but only because banks may choose to outsource all their existing networks to them so that they can focus on growing the digital business themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why it is necessary to view Form 26AS details before filing income tax return</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-efiling-why-it-is-necessary-to-view-form-26as-details-before-filing-income-tax-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-efiling-why-it-is-necessary-to-view-form-26as-details-before-filing-income-tax-return/</guid>
      <description>With the due date for filing income tax return (ITR) for AY2017-18 approaching on July 31, 2017, there is very little time to file your tax return. However, for an individual tax payer, filing a tax return can be a complicated process with all the detailed reporting requirements. Moreover, before filing your tax return, you also need to check various documents to know the details of your income as well as tax deducted at source (TDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब वॉट्सऐप से भी कर सकेंगे पैसे ट्रांसफर, UPI पेमेंट को मिली हरी झंडी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/whatsapp-gets-nod-for-upi-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/whatsapp-gets-nod-for-upi-payments/</guid>
      <description>पॉप्युलर मेसेजिंग ऐप वॉट्सऐप को नैशनल पेमेंट कॉर्पोरेशन ऑफ इंडिया (NPCI) की ओर से पेमेंट और मनी ट्रांसफर के लिए यूनिफाइड पेमेंट्स इंटरफेस (UPI) के इस्तेमाल की अनुमति मिल गई है। UPI के द्वारा मोबइल ऐप से एक अकाउंट से दूसरे अकाउंट में बिना किसी परेशानी के आसानी से पैसे ट्रांसफर किए जा सकते हैं।
NPCI के मैनेजिंग डायरेक्टर और सीईओ ए पी होता ने वॉट्सऐप को UPI पेमेंट की अनुमति मिलने की पुष्टि की है। पिछले कुछ वक्त से वॉट्सऐप की इस संबंध में ऐक्सिस बैंक,पंजाब नैशनल बैंक समेत कई बैंकों से बात चल रही थी। देश में पहली बार NPCI ने किसी मोबाइल ऐप को पेमेंट के लिए मल्टी बैंक पार्टनरशिप की अनुमति दी है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जियो ने लॉन्च किया 399 रुपये में 84 दिन की वैधता और 84GB डेटा वाला प्लान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-launches-new-rs-399-plan-with-84-days-validity-revises-old-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-launches-new-rs-399-plan-with-84-days-validity-revises-old-plans/</guid>
      <description>रिलायंस जियो के यूजर्स के लिए अच्छी खबर है। जियो ने अपने यूजर्स के लिए नए प्लान लॉन्च कर दिए हैं। जियो का जियो धन धना धन ऑफर खत्म होने के कगार पर है। Reliance Jio ने यह प्लान प्रीपेड और पोस्टपेड दोनों तरह के यजर्स के लिए पेश किए हैं। कंपनी ने नए प्लान को जियो धन धना धन ऑफर के नाम से ही पेश किया है। इस प्लान का सिर्फ नाम पुराना है बाकी सबकुछ इसमें बदल चुका है। रिलायंस जियो के इन प्लान का पूरा फायदा उठाने के लिए आपके पास जियो प्राइम मेंबरशिप होनी जरूरी है। रिलायंस जियो के प्रीपेड प्लान की शुरुआत 19 रुपये से होती है और सबसे महंगा प्लान 9,999 रुपये का है। जियो धन धना धन ऑफर के शुरुआत में जहां कंपनी 309 रुपये के रीचार्ज वाले पैक पर 1 महीने की वैधता की बात कह रही थी। अब इसी प्लान में ग्राहकों को 56 दिन की वैधता मिलेगी और 4जी स्पीड डेटा भी 56 जीबी ही दिया जाएगा। वहीं, एक प्लान 399 रुपये का है जिसकी वैधता 84 दिन की है। इस प्लान में ग्राहकों को 4जी स्पीड का 1 जीबी डेटा रोजाना मिलेगा। वहीं पोस्टपेड प्लान की शुरुआत 309 रुपये से होती है, इसका सबसे महंगा प्लान 999 रुपये का है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सभी बैंकों को आधार एनरॉलमेंट और अपडेट फसिलटी देनी होगी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-banks-to-facilitate-aadhaar-enrolment-update-facility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-banks-to-facilitate-aadhaar-enrolment-update-facility/</guid>
      <description>एचडीएफसी, आईसीआईसीआई, कोटक, ऐक्सिस जैसे प्राइवेट सेक्टर के बैंकों के साथ उन सारे बैंकों को अपने ग्राहकों को आधार एनरॉलमेंट और अपडेट फसिलटी देनी होगी, जिन्हें सरकार ने इस साल 31 दिसंबर तक अपने बैंक अकाउंट्स से आधार को लिंक करने के लिए कहा है। केंद्र ने कहा है कि अगर बैंक खातों को आधार से लिंक नहीं किया जाता तो संचालित नहीं किए जा सकेंगे।
इससे पहले 1 जुलाई के नोटिफिकेशन में सरकार ने वेरिफिकेशन के बाद सभी बैंक खातों को आधार से लिंक करने का आदेश दिया था। इस नोटिफिकेशन के लिए प्रिवेंशन ऑफ मनी लॉन्ड्रिंग (पीएमएलए) में संशोधन भी किया गया था। अधिकतर बैंक आधार और बैंक खाते को लिंक करने की ऑनलाइन फसिलटी दे रहे हैं, लेकिन माना जा रहा है कि कई लोगों के पास अब तक आधार नहीं है या उनका पता या फोटोग्राफ, उनके बैंक रिकॉर्ड के ऐसे डेटा से मेल ना खाते हों। ऐसे में बैंक आधार से उनके खाते को लिंक करने की रिक्वेस्ट ठुकरा सकते हैं। यह गंभीर मसला है क्योंकि जो लोग बैंक खातों को आधार से लिंक नहीं करेंगे, वो 31 दिसंबर के बाद कोई ट्रांजैक्शन नहीं कर पाएंगे।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सावन लगते ही सोना हुआ सस्ता हुआ, चांदी में भी आई 900 रुपए की गिरावट, बाजार में बढ़ी खरीददारी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-price-down-and-silver-drops-to-lowest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-price-down-and-silver-drops-to-lowest/</guid>
      <description>सोने की कीमतों में लगातार दूसरे कारोबारी सत्र में गिरावट आई। विदेशों में कमजोरी के रुख और स्थानीय आभूषण विक्रेताओं की मांग घटने के कारण यहां राष्ट्रीय राजधानी के सर्राफा बाजार में आज सोने की कीमत 120 रुपये की गिरावट के साथ 28,780 रुपये प्रति 10 ग्राम रह गई।
औद्योगिक इकाइयों और सिक्का निर्माताओं के कमजोर उठान के कारण चांदी की कीमत भी 900 रुपये की भारी गिरावट के साथ 37,000 रुपये के स्तर से नीचे 36,500 रुपये प्रति किग्रा पर बंद हुई। बाजार सूत्रों ने कहा कि अमेरिका के अपेक्षाकृत ठोस रोजगार आंकड़े इस वर्ष अधिक अमेरिकी ब्याज दर के बारे में संकेत देते हैं जिससे बहुमूल्य धातुओं की मांग प्रभावित हो सकती है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 reasons to file your tax return early</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-return-7-reasons-to-file-your-tax-return-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-return-7-reasons-to-file-your-tax-return-early/</guid>
      <description>Are you in a never ending battle with your Income Tax Return? Do you for some reason or another get really close to the due date when filing the return? We thought so! To get you out of the practice of filing your return close to the due date, we have compiled a list of the most irresistible benefits to file your Income Tax Returns early:
 Faster refund process: You read it right!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks To Start Charging For Person To Person Payments On UPI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</guid>
      <description>SBI is charging Rs 5 per transaction of up to Rs 1 lakh, Rs 15 for transactions between Rs 1-2 lakh and Rs 25 for those between Rs 2 lakh and Rs 5 lakh, while HDFC Bank is proposing Rs 3 for transactions of up to Rs 25,000 and Rs 5 for those between Rs 25,000 and Rs 1 lakh.
Nearly two years after operationalisation of the Unified Payment Interface (UPI), banks have started moving to charge for peer-to-peer payments on the new platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Mistakes While Filing ITR (Income Tax Return) And How to Avoid Them</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/common-mistakes-while-filing-itr-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/common-mistakes-while-filing-itr-and-how-to-avoid-them/</guid>
      <description>Are you always worried about filing your income tax return (ITR) the wrong way? Here are some of the most common mistakes that people make while filing ITR. By avoiding them, you will be able to file your taxes in a hassle-free manner:
 Filing the wrong ITR form  Using the wrong type of ITR is one of the most common mistakes. If you earn income from salary only, you should file your return in Form ITR 1 (Sahaj).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.
SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonetisation: Opening another window to deposit Rs 500, Rs 1000 notes will be good; here is why</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-opening-another-window-to-deposit-rs-500-rs-1000-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-opening-another-window-to-deposit-rs-500-rs-1000-notes/</guid>
      <description>Seven months after demonetisation, the controversies around it aren’t going away. Apart from the debate over whether it was desirable, the government did all manner of flip-flops—given that this was the first such exercise anywhere in the world, and so there was no playbook to go by, though, that may have been unavoidable. What was not was the time given for people to exchange their old notes, given the rush at banks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>