<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Lucky Grahak, Digi Dhan: Rs 1 Crore Jackpot For Person Making Rs 1,590 Digital Payment</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of the Digi Dhan scheme, three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were declared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Pranab Mukherjee picked six winners from a draw of lots under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes, aimed at promoting digital transactions in the country. &amp;ldquo;In the consumer category, three mega Prizes of Rs 1 crore, Rs 50 lakh and Rs 25 lakh went to the Consumers using Rupay Debit Cards making digital payment of less than Rs.1,000,&amp;rdquo; an official release said. Three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were also declared at the event on the final day of the 100-day scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction of Rs. 1,590 won a Central Bank of India customer a lucky draw of Rs. 1 crore under the consumer category, as part of the government&amp;rsquo;s promotional scheme to popularise digital payments. The President congratulated all the six winners - three consumers and three merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am happy today to be a part of the digital payment movement that India has embarked upon. I congratulate each one of you who has contributed in this mission to make India a less cash society,&amp;rdquo; the President said in his address on the occasion of mega draw of lots for the two schemes held at Rashtrapati Bhawan on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners will be felicitated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on April 14 at Nagpur on the occasion of Ambedkar Jayanti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his address, Mr Mukherjee asked citizens to extend their unstinted support to the mission of a less-cash India. &amp;ldquo;India has a long way to go to become a cash less society. The initiatives of the government are a good beginning and we need to sustain and nurture these with active participation from all segments of the society&amp;hellip;It is necessary to reduce cash in circulation and impart greater urgency to promoting secure digital payment methods to ensure greater transparency,&amp;rdquo; the President said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the consumer section, the second prize of Rs 50 lakh went to a Bank of Baroda customer while the third prize of Rs. 25 lakh was bagged by a customer of Punjab National Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the three customers had made the transactions using their RuPay debit cards. The names of three winners were not yet known as the draw only displayed their transaction numbers. These will be matched with card details to identify the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital transactions have gathered momentum giving a fillip to the less cash economy post demonetisation thanks to the initiatives taken by the government. NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digidhan Vyapar schemes have played a catalytic role in making it a mass movement, the statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressing that India is on the cusp of a digital revolution, Mr Mukherjee noted that more than one billion Indians have a unique identity number with a biometric identifier which is unique in its own way. &amp;ldquo;Even countries which are technologically far more advanced than India with comparatively much smaller size population do not have such a system in place. The Aadhaar card initiative is a watershed event in the development story of India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs. 1,000 notes on November 9 last year, the government took a slew of measures to promote digital payments in the country. It had launched the Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes on December 25 last year for consumers and merchants, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes are being implemented by the National Payment Corporation of India (NPCI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the scheme, daily, weekly and monthly rewards worth Rs. 256 crore have been disbursed to over 16 lakh citizens over the past 100 days for making and accepting small transactions digitally. Over the past 100 days, everyday 15,000 consumers have qualified for total prize money of Rs. 1.5 crore, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The draw has seen a positive impact from various age groups and occupations in adopting digital payments methods. We have seen a steady increase in the number of transactions made using all payment methods,&amp;rdquo; said A P Hota, MD and CEO of National Payment Corporation of India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar card linking has mitigated 65L bogus ration card holders: Harsh Gupta</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-mitigated-65l-bogus-ration-card-holders-harsh-gupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-mitigated-65l-bogus-ration-card-holders-harsh-gupta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The linking of Aadhaar card numbers with the ration cards has helped the Department of Food and Civil Supplies to weed out 65 lakh bogus ration cards across the state, said Secretary to the department, Harsh Gupta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing media persons after chairing a progress review meeting here in the city on Sunday, he said, “Aadhaar linking process has been completed, out of the 4.10 crore ration card holders, 3.40 crore had been linked to Aadhaar numbers. Several measures initiated by the department to check pilferage in the public distribution system have helped in saving 35 metric tonnes of food grains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Though there had been an increase in the number of LPG connections, around 90 lakh families were still getting kerosene under the earlier scheme and many had not disclosed their LPG connections,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the data available with oil marketing companies, 99 % of the households in Mysuru district have LPG connection, while majority of the houses in Bengaluru Urban and Rural have gas connections. In order to prevent pilferage, subsidised kerosene (blue) was not being sold at the shops selling non-subsidised kerosene (white),” Gupta added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, “The department has listed out the names of 210 people who have no gas connection to bring them under the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana (PMUJ), launched with the objective of providing LPG connections to families below the poverty line. While the Centre gives free LPG connection, the state government will provide them gas stove with two burners.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deputy Commissioner D Randeep, Deputy Director for Food and Civil Supplies K Rameshwarappa were present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards to be linked with university degrees, certificates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-to-be-linked-with-university-degrees-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-to-be-linked-with-university-degrees-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The proposal is currently under consideration by the &lt;em&gt;ministry of human resource development (MHRD)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to prevent forgery of university degrees and certificates in future, the University Grants Commission (UGC) is planning to link the Aadhaar card number and print the student’s photograph on the degree/certificate from next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposal is currently under consideration by the ministry of human resource development (MHRD). If the proposal gets approved, the commission would issue directions to the universities and educational institutions for the same by next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After receiving fraud degree-related complaints, the MHRD had sought suggestions from the UGC to tackle this issue. So, in the beginning of this month, the commission suggested a proposal of printing the Aadhaar card number and photograph of the student mandatorily on the degrees,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the proposal, having an Aadhar card number will not only prevent forgery, but will also make it easier to store the degrees in a digital format in the National Academic Depositary (NAD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The students will then just have to mention their Aadhaar card number, after which they will be able to access the degree/certificate from anywhere. If the experiment is successful for the universities, then the same will be implemented for Class 10 and 12,” the source added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar may be made mandatory for all 84 DBT schemes: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-made-mandatory-84-dbt-schemes-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-made-mandatory-84-dbt-schemes-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far, furnishing the Aadhaar card has been made mandatory by the government for nearly 34-35 central schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furnishing the Aadhaar card has now been made mandatory by the government for nearly 34-35 central schemes, whether it is investing in the employee provident fund (EPF) or availing mid-day meals in schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report in the Economic Times today, this could soon extend to all 84 schemes so far under the Direct subsidy Benefit Transfer scheme. The 12 digit unique-identity number issued to Indian residents based on their biometric and demographic data, has helped the exchequer save nearly Rs 49,000 crore over the last couple of years in DBT under various schemes including LPG subsidy and helped more than 4.47 crore people open bank accounts through e-KYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the other schemes that are now covered under the mandatory Aadhaar are Sarv Shiksha Abhiyan meant to make elementary education universal, skill training programmes National Social Assistance Programme and Deendayal Antyodaya Yojana, National Action Plan for skill training of disabled and for disabled persons seeking aids and appliances, Swadhar Greh Scheme for rehabilitation of sexually exploited women, and LPG and foodgrains under the public distribution system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be required of NGOs seeking assistance for working on welfare of SCs, backward castes, alcoholics and old people. Residents who are yet to get their Aadhaar card made can do so until June 30. Enrolment facility will be made available by the department at convenient locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone wanting to avail benefits while Aadhaar is still under process, the enrolment slip can be used along with any one of the nine prescribed identity proof documents. However, according to a source, notifications from the department on the use of Aadhaar clearly states, “no person will be denied any benefit for want of Aadhaar if he needs the benefit in a time-bound manner or as an emergency measure”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not compulsory for obtaining marriage certificate: CIC to Govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Chief Information Commission has asked the government and marriage registration authorities to raise awareness and provide publicity through various media that Aadhaar is not compulsory for the purpose of marriage registration scheme, reports LiveLaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commission ruled that the compulsory registration of marriages helps tackle various issues like child marriage, marriage without consent, bigamous marriages, etc., and as such, the government should make it easier and more convenient to facilitate the registration, by not requiring other documents like Aadhaar and making changes for online application for marriage under the Special Marriage Act etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CIC cited Supreme Court’s order from 2014, which ruled that the government should not restrict social benefits to those who are yet to receive their Aadhaar card. Last year, the SC had also said that the card scheme is purely voluntary and cannot be made mandatory for scholarships. However, contrary to its prior stance, the SC asked the Government to link all mobile numbers with Aadhaar card details within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;centre-s-push-to-increase-aadhaar-saturation&#34;&gt;Centre’s push to increase Aadhaar saturation?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usage of Aadhaar as a verification system has been on the rise where multiple services including the IIT JEE, employee provident funds, PDS food grain purchases, RTE admissions and Jharkhand’s food and public distribution systems also using it. Private companies have also started using Aadhaar for verification purposes, such as iris scans by DCB Bank for eKYC, Microsoft’s Skype Lite which supports Aadhaar based verification, etc. However, use of Aadhaar by making it compulsory to avail some services, has come under heavy criticism for not respecting user privacy or being very secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Notes Ban, 18 Lakh Cases Of Income, Bank Account Mismatches Detected: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government authorities have detected 18 lakh cases after demonetisation where the income profiles of people do not match their account profile, the Lok Sabha was informed today. Preliminary information has been sought from such people and many have responded. Those who have not given details would be issued with notices as per procedure, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said during Question Hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to supplementaries, he said there was an extended footprint of digitisation in the banking sector. With digitisation, the risk of tampering of technology also increases. But banks are also hiring experts to develop firewalls around their system to make it increasingly difficult to breach it, Jaitley said, adding that technology has to keep pace with crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that risk assessment was a continuous process for banks who do it individually and collectively. In his written response, Jaitley said as on March 31, 2016, 29 per cent of the savings accounts of public sector banks and regional rural banks sponsored by them were inoperative or lying dormant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A variety of factors have a bearing on an account being inoperative. These may include factors like opening of a new account with change of residence or office, death of the account holder or the relative convenience of operating different accounts, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM gives E-Wallets a run for money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BHIM — or the Bharat Interface For Money — is quickly becoming the favoured mobile payment solution for crores of Indians. Since its launch on December 31 till the end of February, the app had been downloaded 17 million times. Following its Android launch, BHIM is now also available on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is an extension of the Unified Payment System. It allows users to send and receive money through a mobile app that is linked to their bank savings account. This is an elegant solution compared to e-wallets that need to maintain a cash balance in order to be functional. Naturally, the question then arises: Should users switch to BHIM and simply spend from their banks, and stop using e-wallets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences between BHIM and e-wallets, and we’ll examine them here in order to help you understand the pros and cons of both ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bhim-vs-wallets-where-bhim-wins&#34;&gt;BHIM vs Wallets: Where BHIM Wins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Balance, loading &amp;amp; unloading:&lt;/em&gt; The first major difference between BHIM and UPI apps and e-wallets is how you maintain your spending balance. BHIM and UPI apps allow you to send and receive money with your bank account. You do not have to maintain a balance with the app. The app is your bank account, in a sense. But in e-wallets, you must maintain a balance in order to spend from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just that, returning your wallet balance back to your bank account will come with limitations and charges. But with BHIM and UPI, there is no need to send the money back from the app to the bank, since the money has been sitting in your account all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/em&gt; Another aspect where BHIM and UPI apps trump e-wallets. E-wallets do not have interoperability, meaning that if you are using Wallet X, you can only transfer money to another user on Wallet X, and not to a user operating Wallet Y. This isn’t a problem with BHIM, since you may move money between accounts with any bank on the BHIM platform. For example, you may be using an SBI account but you can send and receive money from users on ICICI or HDFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spending limits:&lt;/em&gt; BHIM and UPI score heavily here as well. E-wallets have a monthly spending limit of Rs 10,000 which can be raised to Rs 100,000 after the KYC process wherein users need to submit proof of ID and address in order to become authenticated. But BHIM allows a limit of Rs 10,000 per transaction and Rs 20,000 as the total worth of transactions in a 24-hour cycle. UPI apps go further, allowing you to spend up to Rs 100,000 per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-bhim-lags&#34;&gt;Where BHIM Lags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly two areas where e-wallets have an edge over UPI and BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marketing gimmicks:&lt;/em&gt; E-wallets have been around for a few years and they have had the time to build relationships with merchants and businesses. As a result, e-wallets are useful not just for money transfers but also for earning cashbacks and discounts. Not just that, some e-wallets also operate as e-commerce platforms allowing users to buy merchandise, electronics, tickets, etc. UPI and BHIM, on the other hand, are recent innovations and have some catching up to do in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit usage:* E-wallets allow you to link and spend from your credit card, allowing you to leverage the power of the credit available to you. BHIM works on simpler principles: you get to spend only if you have a bank balance, and you cannot link BHIM and UPI apps to your credit card account yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-bhim-is-catching-up&#34;&gt;How BHIM Is Catching Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest Union Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced a referral bonus and cashback scheme for BHIM users. “The government will launch two new schemes — a referral bonus for consumers and a cash-back scheme for merchants — to promote the use of BHIM,” Jaitley said during his budget speech. With these inclusions, BHIM will become a little more attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
Both e-wallets and UPI-based apps such as BHIM have a long way to go and a big role to play in India where internet penetration and smartphone usage are increasing by leaps and bounds every year. Both need to evolve in order to accommodate the changing needs of the Indian consumer in an increasingly less cash-dependent economy. However, at this point, you may want to have both BHIM and e-wallets installed on your smartphones. They both have some unique services to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Get Time Till June 30 To Obtain PAN From Account Holders</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department has given banks three more months till June 30 to obtain permanent account number (PAN) or Form-60 from all account holders as it looks to tighten the noose around evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the notification, the Income Tax Department said that in Income-Tax Rules 114B, in the fourth proviso, &amp;ldquo;for the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;28th day of February&amp;rsquo; the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;30th day of June&amp;rsquo; shall be substituted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 114B lists various transactions for which quoting PAN is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had in January asked banks, post offices and cooperative banks to document PAN or declaration of Form 60 received from account holders and maintain all records for transactions under Rule 114B of I-T Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had said that persons who have not quoted PAN, or did not furnish Form 60 at the time of opening account, will have to provide the same by February 28. Form 60 is a declaration form filed by an individual without PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the demonetisation move effective November 9, the tax department had asked banks and post offices to report to it all deposits above Rs 2.5 lakh in savings accounts and more than Rs 12.50 lakh in current accounts made between November 10 and December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cash deposits exceeding Rs 50,000 in a single day had to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an estimated Rs 15 lakh crore in junked currency notes coming back into the banking system post demonetisation, the tax department has started analysing the bank deposit trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much You Pay For Petrol, Diesel Could Change Every Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-you-pay-for-petrol-diesel-could-change-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-you-pay-for-petrol-diesel-could-change-every-day/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;State-run oil marketing companies, which control over 90 per cent of the retail fuel market in the country, are mulling a plan that would allow daily changes in the price of petrol and diesel, Economic Times reported on Friday. State-owned Indian Oil Corporation and its two smaller peers Bharat Petroleum and Hindustan Petroleum are considering ways to roll out the plan to review petrol and diesel prices daily, executives from the firms told the daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Petrol, diesel prices depend on global oil prices and rupee rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently, petrol and diesel prices are revised on a fortnightly basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This could change into daily revision of fuel prices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state-run companies declined to immediately comment. The daily price change - also called dynamic fuel pricing - essentially means the companies will not wait for a fortnight to adjust the price of petrol and diesel in tandem with crude price as they do now. Instead, they will change the price every day based on crude price movements. This will help India move to an international standard of fuel pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This will cushion the companies from any loss they face due to currency and crude movements over a 15-day period and will make their margins more predictable,&amp;rdquo; said Dhaval Joshi, analyst with Emkay Global Financial Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move would free private players - Essar Oil and Reliance Industries - which currently follow the price set by state-owned companies, to also shift to a dynamic model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Gives 10GB Data At Rs 100 Under &#39;Data Jackpot&#39; Plan</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-gives-10gb-data-at-rs-100-under-data-jackpot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-gives-10gb-data-at-rs-100-under-data-jackpot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Idea Cellular is offering a promotional &amp;ldquo;Data Jackpot&amp;rdquo; offer for its postpaid users. Under the new Idea offer, users can get up to 10GB of data per month, for first three months, at a monthly rental of Rs 100. Idea&amp;rsquo;s plan is available via its app (My Idea app) only and customers who opt for the offer will get a minimum of 1GB per month for three months, at Rs 100 per month, up to a maximum of 10GB per month. After the three months, those who have opted for the same will get 1GB extra data per month at Rs 100 as an additional benefit. The data benefits under this limited offer may vary from circle to circle, Idea noted.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/idea-cellular-data-jackpot_650x187_81491661007.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;All the major telecom operators are offering various discounts to counter the new entrant Reliance Jio which has commenced a price war in the sector. Telecom regulator TRAI has recently asked Jio to end its &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise offer&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Vodafone India and Idea agreed to merge their operations to create the country&amp;rsquo;s largest mobile phone operator worth more than $23 billion with a 35 per cent market share. The new combined entity of Vodafone and Idea, which are India&amp;rsquo;s number 2 and 3 mobile players respectively, will overtake Bharti Airtel in a bid to tackle a raging price war in the world&amp;rsquo;s second-largest market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britain&amp;rsquo;s Vodafone Group will own 45.1 per cent of the merged entity while the Aditya Birla group, Idea&amp;rsquo;s parent company, will own 26 per cent after paying Rs 3,874 crore cash for a 4.9 per cent stake. The remaining 28.9 per cent will be held by other shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory For Subsidy: Indian Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to curb corruption in the Public Distribution System (PDS), the Indian government had made the Aadhar Card mandatory for availing foodgrain subsidy at PDS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has already made Aadhar Card mandatory for the cooking gas LPG subsidy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has declared Rs 1.4 lakh crore subsidy under the food security law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A timeline till June 30 is given for the common people who avail subsidy to apply for Aadhar Card, the government categorically stated in the notification in this regard that no subsidised foodgrains with Aadhaar after June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since November 2016, the Government of India, under the National Food Security Law (NFSA), has been providing 5 kg of foodgrains per person per month at Rs 1-3/kg to over 80 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification has been applicable from February 8 in all States and Union Territories (UTs) except Assam, Meghalaya and Jammu and Kashmir. This move indicates Government’s serious intetion of digitisation to curb the corruption in PDS as well as a move towards a simplifies delivery process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Still Get Reliance Jio&#39;s &#39;Summer Surprise Offer&#39;? Here Are The Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-you-still-get-jios-summer-surprise-offer-here-are-the-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-you-still-get-jios-summer-surprise-offer-here-are-the-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although, the offer can still be availed over the &amp;ldquo;next few days&amp;rdquo; and those who &amp;ldquo;subscribe before the discontinuation&amp;rdquo; will remain eligible for the complimentary plan,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s website stated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) asked Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio to withdraw the complimentary &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; plan as it did not fit into the &amp;ldquo;regulatory framework&amp;rdquo;. Reliance Jio has accepted the regulator&amp;rsquo;s decision and is in the process of &amp;ldquo;fully complying&amp;rdquo; with it. Jio &amp;lsquo;complimentary&amp;rsquo; offer included free data usage and calls for three months on a recharge of Rs 303 or higher. Although, the offer can still be availed over the &amp;ldquo;next few days&amp;rdquo; and those who &amp;ldquo;subscribe before the discontinuation&amp;rdquo; will remain eligible for the complimentary plan,&amp;rdquo; the company&amp;rsquo;s website stated.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/reliance-jio_650x400_61491559381.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We examined it and found that it was not in accordance with regulatory framework, so we advised them to stop it,&amp;rdquo; TRAI Chairman RS Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the regulator&amp;rsquo;s decision, Cellular Operators Association of India (COAI) said that the TRAI&amp;rsquo;s move to stop the three-month complimentary offer would reduce the deterioration in industry&amp;rsquo;s revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When the regulator establishes a level-playing-field, the market forces establish the right price points,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said, terming the withdrawal of the offer as a &amp;ldquo;relief&amp;rdquo; for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the data released by TRAI, the revenue of telecom sector from consumer services like mobile telephony and data dipped 10.5 per cent to Rs 37,284 crore in the October-December period over the previous three months. The revenue of the sector from the same set of services stood at Rs 41,681 crore in July-September last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incumbent telecom operators have blamed free services of new entrant Reliance Jio for the decline in their quarterly numbers. While Jio provided free 4G service during the period, other telecom operators struggled to compete with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>