<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar. To further incentivize Indians to make the switch to using the BHIM app for transacting business, PM Modi also launched two schemes - cash back for merchants and referral bonus for individual owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Are Some Of The Key Features Of BHIM:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BHIM, short for Bharat Interface for Money, enables its users to transfer money using their mobile phone. The app created a world record by registering 10 million downloads in just four months since its launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. For every successful referral, users can earn Rs. 10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;PM Modi declared on Friday that incentives totalling Rs. 495 crore will be given to merchants for accepting payments through BHIM and existing users for referring it to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 2 MB in size, the latest version of the app enables payments through a fingerprint scanner by authenticating biometric details of the user against the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is available in 12 languages with three new languages (Marathi, Punjabi and Assamese) added in BHIM 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, now allows users to transfer money to contacts saved on the phone. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a cap of Rs. 10,000 for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present account holders of around 30 banks can transact on BHIM 1.3. The app will add Punjab And Maharashtra Co-Operative Bank Ltd, Punjab &amp;amp; Sind Bank and Jammu and Kashmir Bank soon, according to its Google Play Store page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the United Payments Interface (UPI), BHIM users do not need to download mobile applications of multiple banks to transact with different banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the government&amp;rsquo;s move on November 8 last year to demonetise Rs. 500 and Rs. 1,000 currency notes, the number of digital payment apps have logged a nearly 23-fold increase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed by National Payments Corporation of India, BHIM aims pave the way for making payments using fingerprints or iris scanners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Accounts To Be Blocked If Not Self-Certified By April 30. What To Do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions, without which the accounts would be blocked, the income tax department said. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Account holders are informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till 30.4.2017,A/Cs would be blocked : pic.twitter.com/YICvRHqfPm
— Income Tax India (@IncomeTaxIndia) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Investors are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed, the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014-August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016, extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The financial institutions were advised to continue to work on completing the required due diligence, including obtaining self-certifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them. (With agency inputs)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucky Grahak: Student Wins Rs. 1 Crore For Paying Smartphone EMI Through Rupay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lucky-grahak-student-wins-rs-1-crore-for-paying-smartphone-emi-through-rupay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lucky-grahak-student-wins-rs-1-crore-for-paying-smartphone-emi-through-rupay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s schemes to incentivize digital payments &amp;ndash; Lucky Grahak Yojana and DigiDhan Vyapar Yojana &amp;ndash; has awarded 16 lakh winners till now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An EMI payment of Rs. 1,590 for a newly bought mobile phone has earned a mega lottery of Rs. 1 crore for 20 year-old engineering student Shradha Mohan Mengshette under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak Yojana. Mengshette, a second year student of Electrical Engineering from Latur district in Maharashtra, received the cash prize from Prime Minister Narendra Modi at a function in Nagpur today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She won the mega prize for making a transaction of Rs. 1,590 through her Rupay card online.
The second prize of Rs. 50 lakh under the Lucky Grahak Yojana, an official statement said, was won by Hardik Kumar from Khambhat in Gujarat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 29-year-old is a primary school teacher who used his Rupay card for making a transaction of Rs. 1,100. Under the Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana category for merchants, the first prize of Rs. 50 lakh was won by Anand Ananthapadmanabhan for accepting a payment of Rs. 300 at GRT Jewellers in Tambaram, Tamil Nadu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second prize of Rs. 25 lakh was won by Ragini Rajendra Uttekar, owner of a small beauty parlour in Thane, Maharashtra, the statement said. She accepted a payment of Rs. 510 which won her the amount, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s two schemes to incentivize digital payments &amp;ndash; Lucky Grahak Yojana and DigiDhan Vyapar Yojana &amp;ndash; was launched on December 25 last year. According to the statement, Rs. 258 crore of prize money was won by 16 lakh winners, including customers and merchants belonging to different corners of the country and from varied walks of life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operation Clean Money 60,000 individuals including 1,300 ‘high-risk’ cases </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-phase-ii-60k-individuals-including-1300-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-phase-ii-60k-individuals-including-1300-high/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over 60,000 individuals, including 1,300 high-risk persons, will be under the scanner of the income tax department in the second phase of ‘Operation Clean Money’. The second phase of the black money detection programme, which was first started by the tax department post demonetisation, will investigate into claims of excessive cash sales during the demonetisation that did not match the previous profiles of the tax assessees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“More than 60,000 persons, including 1,300 high-risk persons, have been identified for investigation into claims of excessive cash sales during the demonetisation period. More than 6,000 transactions of high value property purchase and 6,600 cases of outward remittances shall be subjected to detailed investigations. All the cases where no response is received shall also be subjected to detailed enquiries,” the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) said in a statement.
The tax department has identified the high risk persons through detailed investigations using advanced data analytics, including integration of data sources, relationship clustering and fund tracking, CBDT said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The high risk categories identified include businesses claiming cash sales as the source of cash deposits that has been found to be in excess of their past profile or industry norms, large cash deposits made by government or PSU employees, persons who have undertaken high value purchases, persons who have used shell entities for layering of funds and where no responses were received, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CBDT, the policy-making body of the department, said it has detected undisclosed income over Rs 9,334 crore between the period of November 9, 2016 till February 28 this year. On November 8 last year, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had announced the decision to scrap high-denomination currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the first phase of the ‘Operation Clean Money’, launched on January 31 this year, the department had sent communications to around 18 lakh individuals asking them to respond online to specific queries relating to cash deposits made during November 9-December 30, the time period given for deposit of scrapped currency notes in banks. Out of the 17.92 lakh persons to whom the queries were sent by the tax department under the first phase of operation Clean Money, 9.46 lakh persons responded have responded to the department as per pre-defined parameters of sources of the cash deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Online queries were raised in 35000 cases and on-line verification was completed in more than 7800 cases. It has been decided to close the verification in cases where explanation of source of cash was found to be justified. In cases where the cash deposit has been declared under Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), the verifications would also be closed,” the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post-demonetisation period saw a rise in number of searches and surveys conducted by the tax department. More than 2,362 search, seizure and survey actions were conducted by the tax department during November 9 last year to February 28, leading to seizure of valuables worth more than Rs 818 crore, which includes cash of Rs 622 crore and detection of undisclosed income of more than Rs 9,334 crore. Over 400 cases have been referred by the tax department to the Enforcement Directorate and the CBI. Surveys have been conducted in more than 3400 cases by assessment units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had also launched a compliance window for assesees to come clean with their undisclosed cash and deposits made after demonetisation through the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY). The three-month long PMGKY scheme received lukewarm response, with only Rs 2,300 crore flowing into government coffers as taxes and penalty by declarants in the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,334 cr undisclosed income detected&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CBDT said it has detected undisclosed income over Rs 9,334 crore between the period of November 9, 2016 till February 28 this year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High risk categories include businesses claiming cash sales as the source of cash deposits found to be in excess of their past profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Price Wars: Airtel, Vodafone, Idea Offers To Rival Jio&#39;s Dhan Dhana Dhan Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-price-wars-airtel-vodafone-idea-offers-to-rival-jios-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-price-wars-airtel-vodafone-idea-offers-to-rival-jios-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio again disrupted the voice calls and internet data tariffs after it decided to withdraw its &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. The company after withdrawing the &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; plan earlier this week launched  a new scheme called &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo;, offering &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs. 309. In response to the  &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer other telecom players like Bharti Airtel,Idea Cellular and Vodafone have also come out with special recharge plans offering their customers free voice calls and high speed 4G internet. Recent reports also suggest that Airtel and Vodafone have done away with roaming charges to counter  Jio&amp;rsquo;s free domestic roaming policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some recharge plans released in the past few days to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 399 plan:&lt;/em&gt; Under this plan, cutomers will get 1 GB of high speed 4G internet data along with 300 minutes of calling per day for Airtel to Airtel customers (1,200 minutes per week) and 3,000 minutes of local and STD calling for 70 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; In this plan customers will get 2 GB of 4G high speed internet for 28 days along with 300 minutes per day of Airtel to Airtel calling (1,200 minutes per week).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; In this plan, customers will get 1 GB of 4G internet per day along with 300 minutes of Airtel to Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for week for 70 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; Select customers can use 1GB data per day for 56 days along with unlimited and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea Rs. 351 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; Idea is offering unlimited local and STD calls and unlimited 3G/2G data per day for 4G handsets for 28 days and this recharge can be done by visiting Idea store.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh. In the present scenario where bank interest rates are on a falling trend, financial planners say that equity mutual funds are one of the best instruments to accumulate long-term savings through systematic investment plan (SIP). Gains from equity mutual funds after a year are tax-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, fund selection is one of the most difficult things to do for a retail investor as it needs lot of research. Financial planners say diversified equity funds are the best to invest through SIP for long term. Here are some funds which have generates over 20 per cent CAGR return in past 20 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Equity Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on January 1, 1995, it is one of the oldest and best performing funds in India. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.95 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 23.56 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This fund has generated a CAGR return of 23.68 per cent since its inception. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998 would have helped you accumulate a corpus of Rs. 2.12 crore by April 1, 2017 implying 17.66 times return in 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;Franklin India Prima Fund:&lt;/em&gt; It is one of the flagship fund of Franklin Templeton India. Since its inception in December 1993, it has generated a CAGR return of 21.04 per cent till now. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 2.38 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 25.11 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Vision Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on October 8, 1995, it has generated a CAGR return of 19.92 per cent till now. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998, would have become Rs. 1.46 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Top 200 Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This flagship fund of HDFC Mutual Fund has generated a CAGR return of 20.88 per cent since its inception in September 1996. If you would have started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.43 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With falling return on bank fixed deposits, equity mutual funds are witnessing increased investment from retail investors now. Equity and equity-linked schemes have seen inflows of more than Rs. 70,000 crore in last financial year according to Association of Mutual Funds in India data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विज्ञापन में कहा गया है कि आयकर विभाग के पास आपकी जमाओं की जानकारी है। विभाग ने कहा है कि इस योजना के तहत कालेधन की घोषणा करने वालों की गोपनीयता सुनिश्चित की जाएगी। विज्ञापन में स्पष्ट चेतावनी दी गई है कि योजना के तहत काले धन की जानकारी नहीं देने वालों को बेनाम कानून के तहत कठोर कार्रवाई का सामना करना होगा। यहां तक कि उनके नाम ईडी और सीबीआई जैसी केंद्रीय जांच एजेंसियों के साथ साझा कर दिए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा कि जो लोग प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना का लाभ लेते हुए अपनी काली कमाई उजागर नहीं करेंगे, उन्हें जमा राशि पर 137% तक जुर्माना लगाया जा सकता है। उनके मुताबिक, विभाग ऐसे डिफॉल्टरों पर नए बेनामी लेनदेन कानून के तहत कार्रवाई करने से भी नहीं हिचकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत काला धन की जानकारी देने वालों को 49.9 प्रतिशत टैक्स देना होगा, जबकि ऐसा नहीं कर इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न में इस धन का जिक्र करने वालों को टैक्स के साथ-साथ 77.25 प्रतिशत जुर्माना देना होगा। साथ ही, जो लोग योजना के तहत काले धन का खुलासा नहीं करते हैं और जांच आकलन में इसका पता चलता है तो उन्हें 83.25 प्रतिशत की दर से टैक्स वसूला जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो लोग योजना का फायदा लेते हुए काले धन की जानकारी सरकार को नहीं देते हैं और छापेमारी के दौरान छिपा हुआ धन सरेंडर करते हैं तो उन्हें 107.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना होगा। लेकिन, जो लोग छापेमारी में भी काला धन खुद निकाल कर नहीं देते हैं, उन्हें 137.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना पड़ सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बेनामी कानून में दोषियों को 7 साल तक की कैद से दंडित करने का प्रावधान है। इसके अलावा, उस पर आयकर कानून के तहत भी मुकदमा चल सकता है। साथ ही, उस पर बेनामी संपत्ति के उचित बाजार मूल्य का 25 प्रतिशत और दूसरे जुर्माने भी भरने होंगे। गौरतलब है कि सरकार ने नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना की घोषणा की थी। इस योजना के तहत कुल घोषित काले धन का एक चौथाई हिस्सा चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज के सरकार के पास जमा रखने की बाध्यता है। यह योजना पिछले साल 17 दिसंबर को शुरू हुई।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पीएम ने किया नई इनसेंटिव स्कीम का ऐलान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modi-announced-new-incentive-scheme-to-promote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modi-announced-new-incentive-scheme-to-promote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;डिजिधन योजना के 100 दिन पूरे होने पर पीएम मोदी ने कैशलेस स्कीम को बढ़ावा देने के लिए शुक्रवार को नई इनसेंटिव स्कीम का ऐलान किया। नागपुर में एक कार्यक्रम में पीएम ने बताया कि इस प्लान के तहत किसी भी शख्स को भीम ऐप के बारे में सिखाने पर जब वह तीन ट्रांजेक्शन कर लेगा, तो आपके खाते में 10 रुपये आ जाएंगे। इसी तरह यदि कोई व्यापारी अपनी दुकान पर निश्चित संख्या में ग्राहकों से भीम ऐप के जरिए ट्रांजेक्शन कराएगा तो उसके खाते में 25 रुपये आएंगे। पीएम मोदी ने बताया कि यह योजना अक्टूबर तक चलेगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2022 तक सबको घर&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पीएम मोदी ने इस दौरान 2022 तक देश में सभी लोगों को अपना घर देने की बात कही। पीएम ने कहा कि क्या ऐसा संभव नहीं है कि जब देश अपनी आजादी के 75 साल पूरे कर रहा हो तो देश के गरीब से गरीब आदमी के पास अपना घर हो। डॉ. आंबेडकर ने जो सपने देखें हैं, उन्हें पूरा करने का समय आ गया है। बड़ी संख्या में घर बन रहे हैं। गरीब को घर मिलेगा और घर बनाने वालों को रोजगार मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;देश के शहीदों के सपने को साकार करें&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2022 में देश को आजाद हुए 75 साल पूरे हो रहे हैं, आप कल्पना कीजिए की इससे पहले का समय कैसा रहा होगा। उस समय लोग देश के लिए जान की बाजी लगा देते थे और तिरंगा लहराने के लिए फांसी पर चढ़ जाते थे। लेकिन, उन लोगों को आजादी में सांस लेने का मौका नहीं मिला। हमें देश के लिए मरने का सौभाग्य भले ही न मिला हो, लेकिन जीने का मौका मिला है। क्या हम शहीदों के सपने को साकार नहीं कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>होटलों में खाना होगा सस्ता</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modi-government-all-set-to-issue-advisory-against-service-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modi-government-all-set-to-issue-advisory-against-service-charge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;खाद्य एवं उपभोक्ता मामलों के मंत्री राम विलास पासवान ने कहा है कि सरकार राज्यों को एक अडवाइजरी भेजने जा रही है, जिसमें होटलों और रेस्तरां में खाने-पीने पर सर्विस चार्ज वसूली के खिलाफ कार्रवाई को कहा जाएगा। पासवान ने शुक्रवार को मीडियाकर्मियों से कहा, &amp;lsquo;सर्विस चार्ज अवैध है। हमने इसके लिए एक अडवाइजरी बनाई है, जिसे अभी प्रधानमंत्री कार्यालय (पीएमओ) में अप्रूवल के लिए भेजा गया है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने बताया कि पीएमओ से अप्रूव होने के बाद अडवाइजरी सभी राज्यों और केंद्र शासित प्रदेशों को भेजी जाएगी। अडवाइजरी उपभोक्ताओं के अधिकारों के लिए लड़ने वाली वॉलंटरी कंज्यूमर ऑर्गनाइजेशंस (VCOs) के लिए भी उपयोगी होगी। अधिकारी ने अडवाइजरी के बारे में बताते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;किसी भी कस्टमर को सर्विस चार्ज देने के लिए मजबूर नहीं किया जा सकता है। यदि कस्टमर चाहता है तो वह वेटर्स को टिप दे सकता है या फिर बिल में सर्विस चार्ज के लिए सहमित दे सकता है।&amp;rsquo; कस्टमर की अनुमति के बिना सर्विस चार्ज वसूली को कंज्यूमर प्रोटेक्शन ऐक्ट के तहत अवैध माना जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मंत्री ने कहा कि मेन्यू कार्ड के जरिए कस्टमर को सर्विस चार्ज के बारे में जानकारी दी जानी चाहिए। गौरतलब है कि राम विलास पासवान पहले भी होटलों और रेस्तरां में सर्विस चार्ज वसूली को गलत बता चुके हैं। उन्होंने होटलों और रेस्तरां के संचालकों से स्पष्टीकरण मांग चुके हैं। जनवरी में उपभोक्ता मंत्रालय ने कहा था कि सर्विस चार्ज देना अनिवार्य नहीं है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;बहुत से लोग इस बात की शिकायत कर चुके हैं कि होटल्स और रेस्तरां में उनसे 5 से 20 पर्सेंट सर्विस चार्ज लिया जा रहा है। सेवा कैसी भी दें, कंज्यूमर को सर्विस चार्ज देने के लिए मजबूर किया जाता है।&amp;rsquo; मंत्रालय के मुताबिक जबरन सर्विस चार्ज वसूली की शिकायत कंज्यूमर फोरम में की जा सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;पूरे देश में एक एमआरपी पर बोतलबंद पानी&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पासवान ने कहा कि पेप्सी का बोतलबंद पानी ‘एक्वाफिना’ देश भर में एक ही अधिकतम खुदरा बिक्री मूल्य (एमआरपी) पर उपलब्ध होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि क्रिकेट संघ बीसीसीआई इस बात को सुनिश्चित करेगा कि उसके सभी क्रिकेट स्टेडियम में बोतलबंद पानी एक ही एमआरपी पर बेचा जाए। पासवान ने कहा कि किसी भी उत्पाद के दो एमआरपी होने पर कानून के तहत कार्रवाई की जा सकती है और उपभोक्ता अदालतें पहले से इस पर कार्रवाई कर रही हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>₹ 1590 दी थी EMI,1 करोड़ रुपये मिला इनाम</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lucky-grahak-yojana-mega-draw-latur-girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lucky-grahak-yojana-mega-draw-latur-girl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;महाराष्ट्र की 20 साल की एक लड़की को लकी ग्राहक योजना के तहत शुक्रवार को एक करोड़ रुपये का इनाम मिला। नकदरहित लेनदेन को बढ़ावा देने के लिए यह योजना चलाई गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लातूर की इलेक्ट्रिकल इंजिनियरिंग की सेकंड ईयर की स्टूडेंट शारदा मेंगशेट्टे उपभोक्ताओं के लिए करोड़ रुपये के मेगा ड्रॉ की विजेता रही। प्रधानमंत्री मोदी ने यहां उसे सम्मानित किया। अपने नए मोबाइल फोन का ईएमआई भुगतान करने के लिए रुपे कार्ड से 1590 रुपये की लेनदेन के लिए उसे पुरस्कृत किया गया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारत में डिजिटल भुगतान को बढ़ावा देने के लिए नीति आयोग की तरफ से सौ दिनों के लिए लकी ग्राहक योजना और डिजिधन व्यापार योजना चलाई गई थी। योजना के तहत 16 लाख विजेताओं ने 258 करोड़ रुपये का पुरस्कार जीता, जिसमें देश के विभिन्न हिस्से के ग्राहक और व्यापारी शामिल हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches. From the fifth transaction onwards, the customers will have to pay a minimum of Rs 150 per transaction (plus taxes and cess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Earlier, HDFC Bank savings account customers were offered five free transactions and the sixth transaction was charged at Rs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) HDFC Bank after December 30, 2016 reintroduced charges on cash transactions at branches after the deadline to deposit old currency notes ended. The charges were waived off after the government had announced a ban on high value currency notes on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) According to the revised norms which came into effect from March 1, from non-home branch, HDFC Bank customers can deposit/withdraw up to Rs 25,000 per day without any charge but any deposit/withdrawal from non-home branch above Rs 25,000 will attract charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess), whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) At the home branch of HDFC Bank, if the cumulative cash transactions (deposit/withdrawal) exceed Rs 2 lakh, a transaction charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess) whichever is higher will be levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For example, if a customer withdraws Rs 2 lakh from an account in four transactions and goes for another fifth transaction of Rs 50,000 from the home branch, then the customer will have to pay a charge of Rs 250. Thus, the charges apply only on the fifth transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) However, the charges for withdrawing money from automatic teller machines (ATMs) remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For senior citizens and minor accounts, the limit of Rs 25,000 per day will be applicable but the accounts will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) India&amp;rsquo;s biggest private sector bank ICICI Bank had reintroduced the cash transaction charges at bank branches from January 1, 2017. There will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while thereafter Rs 5 per Rs 1,000 would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150. The third party limit is Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Meanwhile, news agency Press Trust of India reported that another private sector lender Axis Bank has also started charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar to be mandatory for driving licence, effective from October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As per an order issued by the central government, Aadhaar card will become mandatory for issuance of fresh driving licences or for renewal of the same. This rule will come into effect starting October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind the move is to eradicate the issuance of multiple driving licences across different states. It will help the government to enforce traffic regulations more effectively as drivers won’t have multiple driving licences to fall back on, which isn’t an uncommon practice in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linking Aadhaar card to the driver’s licence will enable the government to maintain a centralised database (known as Sarathi). Regional Transport Offices (RTO) from all over the country can log on and instantly check whether the applicant of a driver’s licence has another one in any other part of the country. The National Informatics Centre (NIC) has already uploaded almost all the data available in RTOs across the country on to the common database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union Road Transport Ministry is currently briefing the state governments about the changes that will eventually be incorporated in the process of issuing a driver’s licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This briefing also talks about citizens who do not have an Aadhaar card issued to their name. In that case, he/she will have to submit multiple documents, although it is unclear what those additional documents will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State governments across the nation have come up with hefty penalties for breaking traffic laws and regulations. One such penalty in many states is the confiscation of driver’s licence for a few months or indefinitely, depending on the severity of the law broken.  This move will will surely force citizens to take traffic laws a lot more seriously once their licences are linked to Sarathi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>