<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even if you have Aadhaar, linking it to PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-aadhaar-linking-pan-easier-said-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-aadhaar-linking-pan-easier-said-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The income tax department then verifies your name, date of birth, gender as per PAN and Aadhaar number with UIDAI. Only if the data matches, it will be linked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merely having an Aadhaar number issued to you by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) does not mean you will be able to link it to your Permanent Account Number (PAN) during filing of income tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department website gives you the option to link the Aadhaar number to the PAN once you login into your personal profile. You are required to provide the Aadhaar number there. The income tax department then verifies your name, date of birth, gender as per PAN and Aadhaar number with UIDAI. Only if the data matches, it will be linked. Similarly, if there is a name change post marriage on one document and not on others, Aadhaar linking will be disallowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officers at the help line of the income tax department said that one can use other agencies like NSDL to file their returns. However, they remained mum when asked about how to rectify issues related to different names once Aadhaar became mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has recently started accepting initials that can be put on the PAN card. However, you will be required to put your full name while applying for a verification of data. For instance, if your official name is M Ramamurthy where the full name is Madurai Ramamurthy where Ramamurthy is the first name, I-T will allow initials only for the first name. Hence, you can either print your name on the PAN card as either Ramamurthy or R Madurai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you try to link PAN to your Aadhaar card which accepts initials, there is bound to be a name mismatch. This will lead to a rejection of request for linking Aadhaar card. In several parts of the country, especially the south of India, the names of villages are often suffixed or prefixed to the name of an individual. Here, any name except the first name of the person is considered as surname and will have to be mentioned in full on the PAN card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax consultants are of the view that where there are different names on different identity proofs, the government will need to either provide them more time or have a separate mechanism to resolve such discrepancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the tax department has a mechanism to rectify names on the PAN card, considering the number of people who will have different names on different documents, meeting the July 1 deadline will be an arduous task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Finance Bill 2017, which was passed by the Lok Sabha, has proposed that Aadhaar will now be compulsory from July 1 to file one’s income tax returns. For retaining your PAN number, too, you need to link this number to your IT account.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ने पर अवैध हो जाएगा PAN,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) को आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ा तो संभव है कि 31 दिसंबर के बाद यह अवैध हो जाए। दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के सरकार के फैसले के बाद इसे वित्तीय लेनदेन (फाइनैंशल ट्रांजैक्शंज) के लिए जरूरी नंबर बनाने की दिशा में एक और कदम बढ़ा दिया गया है। सरकार पूरे फाइनैंशल सेक्टर में आधार आधारित नो योर कस्टमर (KYC) को इंटीग्रेट करने पर विचार कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इसकी पुष्टि करते हुए कहा कि सरकार रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) सहित सभी रेग्युलेटर्स के साथ विचार-विमर्श कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार KYC एक तुरंत, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक और मजबूत प्रमाण उपलब्ध कराता है, जिससे सेवा उद्योग की प्रक्रिया बेहतर बनाने में मदद मिलेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने फाइनैंस बिल में एक संशोधन के जरिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के लिए आवेदन पर आधार को अनिवार्य बना दिया है। अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन लोगों के पास पहले से आधार मौजूद है, उन्हें किसी भी वित्तीय मध्यस्थ (फाइनैंशल इंटरमीडियरी) को अपने अंगूठे का निशान उपलब्ध कराना होगा। इसे संबंधित सेक्टर की रिपोर्टिंग एंटिटि को दिया जाएगा, जो इसे UIDAI डेटाबेस से वैलिडेट करेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस डेटा के आधार पर सेंट्रल रजिस्ट्री ऑफ सिक्यॉरिटाइजेशन ऐंड ऐसेट रिकंस्ट्रक्शन ऐंड सिक्यॉरिटी इंट्रेस्ट ऑफ इंडिया (CERSAI) की ओर से एक यूनीक C-KYC नंबर जेनरेट किया जाएगा। इस नंबर का इस्तेमाल बैंक अकाउंट, म्यूचुअल फंड इन्वेस्टमेंट, डीमैट अकाउंट और इंश्योरेंस पॉलिसी सहित सभी फाइनैंशल प्रॉडक्ट्स में किया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा था कि देश में 98 प्रतिशत व्यस्कों या 108 करोड़ से अधिक लोगों को आधार नंबर जारी किया जा चुका है और इसी वजह से सरकार इसका इस्तेमाल बढ़ा रही है। उन्होंने इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के प्रस्ताव पर दोबारा विचार करने की संसद की मांग को खारिज कर दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC सुविधा से PAN के आवेदन के लिए जन्मतिथि या पते जैसी जानकारियों की पुष्टि का इंतजार कर रहे व्यक्ति और एंटिटि अंगूठे के निशान से बायोमेट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन कर सकेंगे। CERSAI ने पिछले वर्ष सभी वित्तीय संस्थानों में एक समान KYC प्रोसेस सुनिश्चित करने के लिए e-KYC की कोशिश शुरू की थी। 2016 में मार्केट रेग्युलेटर सेबी ने आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC को स्वेच्छा से अपनाने पर सहमति दी थी। सभी सरकारी बैंकों से भी इस तरह का अपडेटेड डेटा अथॉरिटी को उपलब्ध कराने का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Govt:Over Rs 153cr awarded to 10lk people to promote e-payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;check if you are winner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dev.digidhanlucky&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px;padding:4px&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/logoapp.png&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on start button in Digi Dhan Lucky Yojana App.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on whether you are a Consumer or a Merchant, click on the corresponding button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box that appears next, provide the mobile phone number registered with your UPI/ USSD/ RuPay/ AEPS account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive an OTP, which you must enter in the box that appears in the middle of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Try Your Luck button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next message will show if you have won under the Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi Dhan Vyapar Yojana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been awarded over Rs 153.5 crore in the last 58 days under Niti Aayog’s schemes to promote digital payments, its CEO Amitabh Kant said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It has been 58 days since the launch of Niti Aayog’s two incentive schemes – Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana to promote digital payments and the public response has been quite encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the latest figures released by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), which has been executing the schemes, nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been disbursed over Rs 153.5 crore as reward money till February 20, 2017,” Kant said at a press conference here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s think-tank said in a statement that among the 9.8 lakh winners are more than 9.2 lakh consumers and 56,000 merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners belong to diverse socio-economic backgrounds, including farmers, merchants, small entrepreneurs, professionals, housewives, students and retired persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Uttar Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh and Delhi have emerged as the top five states/Union Territories with maximum number of winners,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While majority of the winners are in the age group of 21 to 30, Niti Aayog pointed out that a significant number are also above 60 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The diversity in age of winners is from 15 to 66 years, challenging the notion that the old find it difficult to embrace technology to adopt digital payments,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government on December 25 had launched two schemes — Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana — to boost digital transactions post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2GB Data Per Day For Rs. 339:BSNL&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnls-latest-offer-to-counter-jio-airtel-2gb-data-per-day-for-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnls-latest-offer-to-counter-jio-airtel-2gb-data-per-day-for-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a month, consumer will get 30 GB data and 25 minutes free call per day under the offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) on Tuesday launched a plan that will provide 2GB data per day for Rs. 339 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To compete with Jio and other private players, we have introduced the cheapest plan with a rental value of Rs. 339 per month. Under this plan, the consumer will get 2GB per day,&amp;rdquo; said Sanjiv Tyagi, General Manager, BSNL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a month, the consumer will get 30 GB data and 25 minutes free call per day. After consumption of 25 minutes a levy of 25 paisa per minute will be imposed,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan will be effective from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not mandatory for train tickets of senior citizens</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets but the Railways have initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens, Lok Sabha was informed today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu made it clear that Aadhaar number has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, however, said the Railway has initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens through pre-verification of senior citizens based on Aadhaar details on voluntary basis with effect from January 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The system is intended to ensure that the senior citizen concession is not misused by unscrupulous elements by giving fictitious names and to use the data for decision making,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prabhu said to promote cashless ticketing system, various initiatives have been taken by the Indian Railways.
“Our ultimate destination is cashless ticket booking. But the immediate priority is less cash transaction,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cash Transaction Limit, Aadhaar: How It Will Impact You</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/latest-updates-on-cash-transaction-limit-aadhaar-how-it-will-impact-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/latest-updates-on-cash-transaction-limit-aadhaar-how-it-will-impact-you/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For any cash transaction exceeding the limit, an amount equal to the transaction will be charged. Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said, &amp;ldquo;In the official amendment to Finance Bill, the government has proposed that limit of 3 lakh for cash transaction, beyond which it is illegal, will be reduced to 2 lakhs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Penalty for violating the limit is a fine equal to the transaction amount&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fine will be payable by person or establishment receiving cash&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has called for reducing the limit to 2 lakh from April 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government on Tuesday moved a proposal to cap the cash transaction limit at Rs 2 lakh instead of Rs 3 lakh, as mentioned earlier by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Union Budget 2017 speech. For any cash transaction exceeding the limit, an amount equal to the transaction will be charged. Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said, &amp;ldquo;In the official amendment to Finance Bill, the government has proposed that limit of 3 lakh for cash transaction, beyond which it is illegal, will be reduced to 2 lakhs.&amp;rdquo; The penalty for violating this is a fine equivalent to the amount of transaction, he added. The fine will be payable by person or establishment receiving cash. The government has called for reducing the limit to 2 lakh from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the cash restrictions will not apply to the government, any banking company, post office savings bank or co-operative bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government also proposed to make Aadhaar card mandatory for filing income tax returns and applying for a Permanent Account Number (PAN). Any application for a PAN, which is a unique ID assigned to each tax payer, a person will also have to mention your Aadhaar or 12-digit unique ID, which is backed by biometrics like finger prints and iris scans stored in a central repository. From July 1 onwards, any PAN card not linked to an Aadhaar identity will be considered invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply for an Aadhaar card now, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a PAN card or want to file tax returns. The government is working on linking all bank accounts to Aadhaar numbers. From April 1 onwards, Aadhaar IDs will be a pre-requisite for opening an Employee Provident Fund (EPF) account that helps you collate a pension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two (cash transaction limit and Aadhaar) are among the 40 amendments proposed by Mr Jaitley in Lok Sabha yesterday. The move is aimed to curb the black money flow and push the country towards digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT को जवाब नहीं देने वालों के खिलाफ कार्रवाई &#39;निश्चित&#39;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-will-take-action-against-9-29-lakh-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-will-take-action-against-9-29-lakh-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार ने कहा है कि नोटबंदी के वक्त ज़्यादा कैश जमा कराने को लेकर आयकर विभाग द्वारा भेजे गए नोटिस का जवाब नहीं देने वाले 9.29 लाख लोगों के खिलाफ &amp;lsquo;निश्चित रूप से&amp;rsquo; कार्रवाई की जाएगी। आयकर विभाग ने इन लोगों को इसलिए नोटिस भेजा था क्योंकि इनके द्वारा जमा की गई रकम इनकी इनकम प्रोफाइल से मेल नहीं खाती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लोकसभा में फाइनैंस बिल पर हो रही चर्चा पर पूछे गए एक सवाल के जवाब में वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि नोटंबदी के 50 दिनों के दौरान 18 लाख लोगों द्वारा जमा किए गए 500 और 1000 रुपये के पुराने नोट उनकी आय के स्रोतों के अनुपात में नहीं थे। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;फिलहाल रीमोनिटाइज़ेशन का प्रोसेस चल रहा है। लेकिन प्राप्त हुए डेटा की शुरुआती जांच में सीबीडीटी (Central Board of Direct Taxes) और टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने पाया है कि 18 लाख लोगों द्वारा जमा किया गया कैश उनके इनकम प्रोफाइल से मेल नहीं खाता। संबंधित विभागों ने मेल और एसएमएस कर इन लोगों से स्पष्टीकरण मांगा था।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;करीब 8.71 लाख लोगों ने स्पष्टीकरण दिया है, और जिन्होंने कोई प्रतिक्रिया नहीं दी है निश्चित रूप से आयकर विभाग उनके खिलाफ आयकर अधिनियम के तहत ऐक्शन लेगा।&amp;rsquo; नोटबंदी के फायदे बताते हुए वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि इससे सरकार के संसाधनों के प्रोत्साहन में मदद मिलेगी। किसानों को मिलनेवाले फंड, रक्षा क्षेत्र और मनरेगा जैसे मुद्दों पर सभी पार्टियों द्वारा चिंता व्यक्त करने पर वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि इनके लिए ज़्यादा खर्च तभी संभव है जब सरकार के पास और संसाधन हों।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी के दौरान जमा हुई रकम की फाइनल टैली को लेकर किए गए सवालों पर जेटली ने कहा कि आरबीआई द्वारा हरेक नोट गिने जाने के बाद इसकी घोषणा की जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp, From April: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भविष्य में सभी कार्डों की जगह ले लेगा आधार कार्ड: अरुण जेटली</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लोकसभा ने बुधवार को वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली की ओर से पेश वित्त विधेयक को चर्चा के बाद पारित कर दिया। चर्चा के दौरान अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि आने वाले दिनों में आधार ही एकमात्र कार्ड होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि भविष्य में यह वोटर आईडी कार्ड और पैन कार्ड जैसे दस्तावेजों की जगह ले लेगा। इन सभी के मुकाबले एक आधार कार्ड ही किसी भी व्यक्ति की पहचान के लिए काफी होगा। लोकसभा में एक सांसद की ओर से पूछा गया था कि आधार कार्ड जारी किए जाने के बाद भी कई कार्डों की व्यवस्था क्यों लागू है। इसके जवाब में जेटली ने यह बात कही। उन्होंने कहा कि आने वाले वक्त में आधार ही व्यक्तिगत पहचान और पते के लिए पुख्ता सबूत होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाए जाने के सवाल पर जेटली ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;तमाम लोगों को कई पैन नंबर इस्तेमाल करते हुए पाया गया है। इसलिए सरकार ने इस व्यवस्था को लागू करने का फैसला लिया है।&amp;rsquo; जेटली ने एक सवाल के जवाब में कहा, &amp;lsquo;आज 98 फीसदी नागरिकों के पास आधार कार्ड है। टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के दौरान व्यक्ति आधार नंबर दे सकता है या यह बता सकता है कि उसने आवेदन कर दिया है, लेकिन टैक्स चोरी की अनुमति नहीं दी जा सकती है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा लोगों को टैक्स की व्यवस्था से जोड़ने की जरूरत है। इसीलिए सरकार ने इस साल टैक्स स्लैब को नीचे लाने का प्रयास किया है। चर्चा के दौरान जेटली ने नोटबंदी को सही फैसला करार देते हुए इकॉनमिस्ट मार्टिन वॉल्फ के एक आर्टिकल का उदाहरण देते हुए कहा कि उन्होंने इसकी सराहना की है। जेटली ने लेख का हवाला देते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;इससे सरकार को ब्लैक मनी पर टैक्स लगाने का मौका मिला है। बड़े पैमाने पर कैश रखने वाले लोगों के लिए रिस्क पैदा हुआ है। इसके अलावा क्रिमिनल्स के पास जमा संपत्ति सरकार के पास आई है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associate Bank Branches To Become SBI Branches From April 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branches of all five associate banks, which are merging with parent State Bank of India, will begin functioning as SBI branches from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customers, including depositors of State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore will be treated as customers of State Bank of India with effect from April 1, 2017,&amp;rdquo; the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) said in a notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officers and employees, with the exception of the board of directors and executive trustees of the associate banks, will become employees of SBI following the merger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI alone has nearly 20,000 branches, including 191 foreign offices spread across 36 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the five subsidiary banks, only SBBJ, SBM and SBT are listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the government on Monday announced that Bharatiya Mahila Bank will also be merged with SBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation Says No Vulnerability In BHIM App</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-says-no-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-says-no-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPCI significant downloads have been witnessed since the BHIM app was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;National Payments Corporation of India&lt;/em&gt; (NPCI) on Monday said there is no vulnerability or loopholes reported in the Bharat Interface for Money or BHIM application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI has done intensive testing, robust design of security controls and continuous monitoring of its Unified Payments Interface (UPI) infrastructure, the corporation said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The environment in which BHIM or UPI is run by NPCI is highly secure and certified with best global practices,&amp;rdquo; it said, adding that the packages have also been audited by reputed IT security firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI has put in place adequate governance mechanism for banks to report any fraud or system issues and its redressal, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, it said that since BHIM was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, significant downloads have been witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Out of the 19.16 million downloads, 5.1 million customers have been able to link their bank accounts. In many cases customers downloaded the application to see that they have not linked their mobile number to the bank account,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks are expected to reach out to all their customers by various means and ensure universal acceptance of mobile banking services at the earliest,&amp;rdquo; NPCI managing director and CEO A P Hota said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI के सहयोगी बैंकों का 1 अप्रैल को विलय होना तय, महिला बैंक भी बनेगा हिस्सा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/branches-of-associate-banks-will-be-work-as-sbi-branches-from-1st-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/branches-of-associate-banks-will-be-work-as-sbi-branches-from-1st-april/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;यदि आपका बैंक खाता स्टेट बैंक ऑफ बीकानेर ऐंड जयपुर, स्टेट बैंक ऑफ हैदराबाद, स्टेट बैंक ऑफ मैसूर, स्टेट बैंक ऑफ त्रावणकोर और स्टेट बैंक ऑफ पटियाला में है तो यह खबर आपके लिए बेहद जरूरी है। इन बैंकों की देश भर में मौजूद सभी शाखाएं 1 अप्रैल से देश के सबसे बड़े सार्वजनिक बैंक एसबीआई की ब्रांच के तौर पर काम कर शुरू कर देंगी। सरकार इससे पहले ही एसबीआई के सभी असोसिएट बैंकों के विलय का ऐलान कर चुकी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यही नहीं केंद्र सरकार ने भारतीय महिला बैंक के भी स्टेट बैंक में ही विलय का ऐलान किया है। सरकार का कहना है कि इससे महिलाओं तक बेहतर बैंकिंग सुविधाओं को पहुंचाने में मदद मिल सकेगी। स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया के असोसिएट बैंकों की ओर से जारी किए जाने वाले डेबिट और क्रेडिट कार्ड पहले से ही एसबीआई के नेटवर्क के तहत ही काम करते थे। माना जा रहा है कि असोसिएट बैंकों के मर्जर से एसबीआई मजबूत होगा और उसकी वित्तीय स्थिति में बड़ा इजाफा होने की उम्मीद है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पिछले ही दिनों स्टेट बैंक की चेयरपर्सन अरुंधति भट्टाचार्य ने कहा था कि मर्जर के साथ पैरेंट बैंक असोसिएट बैंकों और महिला बैंक से 5,000 करोड़ रुपये की फिक्स्ड पूंजी हासिल करेगा। रिपोर्ट्स के मुताबिक, अगर मर्जर योजनाएं पूरी होती हैं तो एसबीआई के पास 21 लाख करोड़ रुपये से ज्यादा के डिपॉजिट्स होंगे और लोन बुक भी 17.5 लाख करोड़ रुपये के करीब पहुंच जाएगी। भट्टाचार्य ने कहा था, &amp;lsquo;इस सबसे ग्लोबल बैंकों में हमारी रैंकिंग भी सुधरेगी। बैलेंस शीट साइज के हिसाब से हमारी रैंकिंग 59 से सुधरकर 55 पर आ जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can now lock your Aadhaar data to keep it safe from hackers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now, you can lock your Aadhaar biometric details to keep it safe and unlock it whenever you want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With digital payments using Aadhaar data on the rise and cases of misuse being reported, officials of the &lt;em&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India&lt;/em&gt; (UIDAI) have come out with the new security feature to lock the biometric details (fingerprint and retinal scan data).The UIDAI introduced the lock and unlock facility following an uproar that Aadhaar deprived people of their right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric data of citizens is being collected on various platforms for government schemes, often without much safeguards. Aadhaar identification has become almost compulsory in some cases. Banks, mobile phone operators and others have access to it. “People can hack into this data and access individuals’ details, including bank accounts,” a UIDAI official warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Each time you shop and pay using your fingerprint, the data processed by POS machines can be hacked. Fingerprint details can be captured as well,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lock and unlock facility is purely voluntary. “If a person wants to lock his data, he or she can do it. No other person can unlock it. One can keep it locked as long as one wishes,” the official said Once the Aadhaar data is locked, even banks cannot access the biometric information stored in the main server.This will lead to failed transactions due to non-verification or non-authentication of the Aadhaar. The UIDAI is also planning to introduce a mobile application to lockunlock biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>