<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>20 हजार किलोमीटर हाइवे जल्द होंगे हाइस्पीड</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-u-turns-no-side-entry-20000-km-of-highways-will-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-u-turns-no-side-entry-20000-km-of-highways-will-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगले 4 से 5 सालों में नैशनल हाइवे के 20 हजार किलोमीटर से ज्यादा का हिस्सा यू-टर्न और कट्स फ्री होगा। इसके साथ ही हाइवे के दोनों ओर बैरिकेडिंग भी होगी जिससे जानवर हाइवे पर नहीं घुस पाएंगे। मुख्य हाइवेज को इस तरह से तैयार किया जाएगा कि भारी वीइकल्स भी रफ्तार के साथ बिना परेशानी मंजिल तक जल्द पहुंच जाएं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार का यह प्रॉजेक्ट &amp;lsquo;भारतमाला&amp;rsquo; स्कीम का हिस्सा है इसके फेज-1 के तहत कुछ मुख्य मार्गों को कम से कम चार लेन का किया जाएगा। इस फेज पर 3.85 लाख करोड़ रुपए खर्च होंगे। अभी हाइवेज पर कई तरह की स्पीड वाली गाड़ियां चलती है जिससे न केवल हाइवे की स्पीड कम होती बल्कि दुर्घटना की संभावनाएं भी बढ़ जाती हैं। हाइवे मिनिस्ट्री द्वारा की गई एक स्टडी के मुताबिक, जापान के फोर-लेन हाइवे पर एक दिन में करीब 40,000 गाड़ियां चल सकती हैं वहीं, भारत में ऐसे ही हाइवे पर 20,000 गाड़ियां ही चल पाती हैं जिस कारण हाइवे की लेन बढ़ानी पड़ती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नए हाइवेज को बनाने की बजाए पुराने हाइवेज में कुछ बदलाव कर उन्हें अपग्रेड करने का प्रपोजल रोड और ट्रांसपोर्ट मिनिस्ट्री ने आगे बढ़ाया है। मिनिस्ट्री 20 हजार किलोमीटर को &amp;lsquo;ऐक्सेस कंट्रोल्ड&amp;rsquo; करेगी। इस तरह का कॉन्सेप्ट विकसित देशों में अपनाया जाता है। ऐक्सेस कंट्रोल्ड हाइवे में घुसने और निकलने के पॉइंट्स कम होते हैं। अभी हाइवे पर हर छोटी-मोटी जगह पर हाइवे में कट और यू-टर्न होते हैं जिससे गाड़ियों की स्पीड प्रभावित होती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;ऐक्सेस कंट्रोल्ड&amp;rsquo; कॉन्सेप्ट के तहत कुछ हाइवेज की पहचान कर ली गई है। इसमें मुंबई-कोलकाता, मैंगलोर-बेंगलुरु, लुधियाना-कांधला और पोरबंदर से सिलचर को शामिल किया गया है। सूत्रों के मुताबिक, पीएम ऑफिस ने नैशनल हाइवे अथॉरिटी ऑफ इंडिया (NHAI) बोर्ड को इस प्रपोजल पर आगे बढ़ने का सिग्नल दे दिया है। इससे पहले इसी मॉडल के तहत बीजेपी शासन में पूर्व प्रधानमंत्री अटल बिहारी वाजपेयी ने स्वर्णिम चतुर्भुज की शुरुआत की थी जिसके तहत देश के चार मेट्रो शहरों को जोड़ा गया था।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs 333: BSNL Takes On Jio With New Prepaid Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnl-takes-on-jio-with-new-prepaid-offers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnl-takes-on-jio-with-new-prepaid-offers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special tariff voucher &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo;, priced at Rs. 349, comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive tariffs, BSNL has launched prepaid plans priced from Rs 333, under which it is offering 3GB of 3G data per day for up to three months. As part of its revised Rs 339 plan, BSNL is also offering 3GB of high speed data per day. &amp;ldquo;#BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new 333 &amp;amp; 339 STV&amp;rsquo;s offer there is nothing better than this!&amp;rdquo; state-run telecom company BSNL said on site Twitter. New entrant Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing has given rise to a highly competitive Indian telecom market, pushing incumbent players to revise their existing offerings to protect market share, some analysts say. &amp;ldquo;The price war in the Rs 1.5-trillion wireless telecom market will continue this fiscal year as well leaving bruised bottom lines,&amp;rdquo; Crisil&amp;rsquo;s said in a note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333 special tariff voucher, called &amp;ldquo;Triple ACE&amp;rdquo;, comes with a validity of three months and offers 3GB of 3G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-of-the-other-offerings-by-bsnl&#34;&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 339&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL users subscribing to the Rs 339 voucher will now get 3 GB of 3G data, which is high-speed data, per day, instead of 2 GB earlier. The Rs 339 plan - which comes with a validity of 28 days - includes unlimited local and STD BSNL-to-BSNL calls and 25 minutes of local and inter-circle calls made to other networks, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special tariff voucher &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo;, priced at Rs. 349, comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs. 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all four plans - &lt;em&gt;Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 395 and Rs 375&lt;/em&gt;, the internet or data speed is reduced to 80 Kbps after a subscriber exhausts the daily 3G limit, BSNL has said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60% People Facing Frequent Call Drops: Telecom Department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/facing-frequent-call-drops-telecom-department-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/facing-frequent-call-drops-telecom-department-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Out of 3.56 lakh subscribers surveyed across telecom service providers, 2.15 lakh (about 60 per cent) complained about frequent call drops.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 60 per cent people are still facing frequent call drops, with most of them experiencing problem indoors, found a survey by the Department of Telecom (DoT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of 3.56 lakh subscribers surveyed across telecom service providers, 2.15 lakh (about 60 per cent) complained about frequent call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DoT, however, made 26.97 lakh calls to subscribers of various telecom operators in the country, out of which only 3.56 lakh subscribers (about 13 per cent) participated in the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department also claimed that overall call drops have come down by 7 per cent in three months between December 2016 to March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Remaining 87 per cent subscribers, who did not participate, were either not willing or did not have problem of frequent call drops&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; the DoT said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the feedback, the DoT observed that the complaint is &amp;ldquo;mostly indoors&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback is shared with the telecom service providers (TSPs) to take corrective action in a time-bound manner and submit the action taken report (ATR) to DoT Task Force every fortnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;TSPs contact each subscriber, who has reported frequent call drops, through telephonic calls and SMS in English and local languages to collect further details required for resolution of the complaint,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On cumulative basis, since launch of Interactive Voice Response System (IVRS), telecom operators have resolved 13,631 cases related to the call drop issue and also resolved another 7,975 which were reported as frequent call drops but were found to be having other issues related to data, roaming, billing, MNP, mobile device etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of these, 1,406 cases were resolved through optimisation, rectifying hardware or power problems, through field visits etc during the fortnight March 15-31, 2017, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The call drops reported by subscribers have dropped from 64 per cent in December 2016 to 57 per cent at the end of March 2017, a drop of nearly 7 per cent in 3 months,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DoT said the government has facilitated telecom operators to identify black spots and plan new sites or infrastructure to improve their services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operators have planned 987 new sites and boosters out of which 109 have been already installed and commissioned, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At 110 Crore GB Data Traffic A Month, Jio&#39;s Offers For Its Prepaid Users</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a number of recharge options to prepaid subscribers under its paid Prime service. Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website. Jio has become the largest network globally with more than 110 crore GB of data traffic per month and 220 crore voice and video minutes a day, Reliance Industries said in a statement while reporting the group&amp;rsquo;s earnings for financial year 2016-17. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mr Ambani said in the statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All recharges under Jio Prime include free voice call and roaming benefits. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at Jio&amp;rsquo;s various data offerings under its latest recharge options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Rs 19 _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 19 recharge comes with a validity of one day and includes 200 MB of 4G, or high speed, data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 49&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits on offer under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 49 pack include 600 MB of high speed data valid for three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 96&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a validity of seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge includes 7GB of 4G data per day. 4G data comes at a daily limit of 1GB under Jio&amp;rsquo;s fair usage policy, beyond which the speed is reduced to 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 149&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 309&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Jio&amp;rsquo;s three-month benefits on first recharge begin. Subscribers making their first recharge of Rs 309 after taking up Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service will get 1GB of 3G data per day for 84 days, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 509&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimed at &amp;ldquo;daily high data users&amp;rdquo;, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 509 recharge extends the daily 4G data limit offered under the Rs 309 plan to 2GB. Data benefits on subsequent recharges will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first Rs 999 recharge, valid for 120 days, Jio users will get 120 GB of 4G data, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will come with 60 GB of high speed data valid for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s next long-term pack comes at Rs 1,999. The first recharge of this kind includes 185 GB of 4G data valid for 150 days. The 4G data on offer is reduced to 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges, Jio said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 4,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those making their first Prime recharge with the Rs 4,999 pack will get 410 GB of 4G data valid for 240 days. Subsequent recharges will offer 350 GB of such data for 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is the Rs 9,999. The first recharge will offer a total of 810 GB of 4G data valid for 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with a reduced 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar. To further incentivize Indians to make the switch to using the BHIM app for transacting business, PM Modi also launched two schemes - cash back for merchants and referral bonus for individual owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Are Some Of The Key Features Of BHIM:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BHIM, short for Bharat Interface for Money, enables its users to transfer money using their mobile phone. The app created a world record by registering 10 million downloads in just four months since its launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. For every successful referral, users can earn Rs. 10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;PM Modi declared on Friday that incentives totalling Rs. 495 crore will be given to merchants for accepting payments through BHIM and existing users for referring it to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 2 MB in size, the latest version of the app enables payments through a fingerprint scanner by authenticating biometric details of the user against the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is available in 12 languages with three new languages (Marathi, Punjabi and Assamese) added in BHIM 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, now allows users to transfer money to contacts saved on the phone. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a cap of Rs. 10,000 for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present account holders of around 30 banks can transact on BHIM 1.3. The app will add Punjab And Maharashtra Co-Operative Bank Ltd, Punjab &amp;amp; Sind Bank and Jammu and Kashmir Bank soon, according to its Google Play Store page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the United Payments Interface (UPI), BHIM users do not need to download mobile applications of multiple banks to transact with different banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the government&amp;rsquo;s move on November 8 last year to demonetise Rs. 500 and Rs. 1,000 currency notes, the number of digital payment apps have logged a nearly 23-fold increase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed by National Payments Corporation of India, BHIM aims pave the way for making payments using fingerprints or iris scanners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biometric attendance made compulsory from May 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-attendance-made-compulsory-may-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-attendance-made-compulsory-may-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporation has procured 93 machines based on ‘Aadhaar Authentication’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an important step towards streamlining the attendance of employees, Tiruchi Corporation has introduced biometric attendance for all of its officers, staff members and sanitary workers. Biometric machines have been installed at 91 offices and field units of the Corporation. Of the total 93 machines, purchased at a cost of ₹9.37 lakh, two have been kept on standby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machines have been installed at all reporting sections of sanitary workers, junior engineer offices, main office, zonal offices, lorry shed, water head works, and at the Ariyamangalam compost yard. Similarly, 11 urban primary health centres and mother and child health care units have also been brought under the new e-roster system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the machines are based on ‘Aadhaar Authentication’ (fingerprint and iris-based validation). Details of all 2,147 officers and employees of the Corporation have been synchronised with the machines along with their Aadhaar number. To enable the implementation of the e-attendance project, all employees of the Corporation were required to obtain Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The system is working well. Officers, clerical staff members and workers report on time to mark attendance. The issue of late coming has been addressed to a great extent,” said Corporation Commissioner N. Ravichandran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was Aadhaar enabled, supervisory officers can get the attendance details of employees easily. A centralised monitoring facility has also been created. Besides, the system has enabled the personnel department to maintain the attendance records of employees in a more efficient and transparent way, he pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biometric machines have been provided with the work schedule of all employees. For instance, the duty hours of employees in the main office is between 9.30 am and 5.30 pm. However, the work schedule of junior engineers, water head employees, sanitary workers varies. An employee can avail an hour’s permission thrice a month. And any late coming by an hour thrice a month, the machine will mark half a day absent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric attendance has been taken as the base for preparing the salary. While a few employees and sanitary workers have complained that machines did not recognise their thumb impression, the problem will be solved in a few days, Mr. Ravichandran said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-attendance system will be made compulsory from May 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar With Your PAN Card Just by Uploading a Scanned Proof</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Individuals struggling to link their Permanent Account Number with Aadhaar because of differently spelt names can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the tax department is planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for a One-Time Password (OTP), provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the linking of PAN with Aadhaar being made mandatory, individuals can log on to e-filing website of the income tax department or NSDL but the seeding cannot happen if the name is differently spelt in the two cards – like use of full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, government has allowed a simple uploading of a scanned copy of PAN on the Aadhaar website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had through amendment to tax proposals in the Finance Bill of the Budget for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-filing portal has already activated a functionality of linking PAN with Aadhaar. Over 1.08 crore assessees have already Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official said that linking of PAN with Aadhaar should not be cumbersome for people whose registered mobile number with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In case the taxpayer is unable to link PAN with Aadhaar because of discrepancy in name, we are advising them to log in to the Aadhaar website, request for a name change and upload a scanned copy of PAN card as supported proof. This is the simplest way to update name in Aadhaar and only the registered mobile number has to be functional,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This option will hold good for people who have given short forms of their name or in some cases there are some spelling errors in the name provided in Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in certain cases, there are people who have got married and changed their surname and updated the same while getting Aadhaar number, but it does not get reflected in PAN documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such and other name change cases, the tax department is planning to give the OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number and the tax department, on its part, would match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are also contemplating that when taxpayers with name discrepancy logs into the e-filing website for linkage, we will send OTP to the Aadhaar registered mobile number. The taxpayer can link PAN using the OTP. While generating the OTP, we will just check if the year of birth of the taxpayer in PAN card matches with the year given in the Aadhaar document,” the official added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link bank accounts to Aadhaar by April 30: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-bank-accounts-aadhaar-april-30-t-department/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-bank-accounts-aadhaar-april-30-t-department/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accounts opened from July 2014 to August, 2015 will have to submit know your customer (KYC) details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tax officials said that the accounts would include banks, insurance, stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account holders will also have to mention their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounts opened from July 2014 to August, 2015 will have to submit know your customer (KYC) details and their Aadhaar number to banks and financial institutions+ by April 30 and self-certify them to comply with FATCA regulations(Foreign Tax Compliance Act), the tax department said on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the account holders are unable to furnish details and provide self-certification by the new deadline, banks and financial institutions have the option ofblocking the accounts+ .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the details are furnished they can operate the accounts. The provision applies to accounts which come under the ambit of FATCA regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks and financial institutions were asked to obtain self-certification and carry out due diligence for all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015 to comply with the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act(FATCA) pact signed by India and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July 2015, India and the US signed a tax information sharing agreement under a new US law, FATCA, aimed at bolstering efforts for automatic exchange of financial information between the two nations about tax evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,” the tax department said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax officials said that the accounts would include banks, insurance, stocks. Account holders will also have to mention their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No card? Aadhaar, fingerprints will do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance minister also sought to turbo-charge the government’s objective of maximising cashless transactions with institutional support that included waiving all duties on point-of-sale (PoS) machines and biometric readers, improving rural digital infrastructure, tax breaks, cash incentives and easier loans based on digital transactions history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring about structural reforms, a Payments Regulatory Board will be created in the Reserve Bank of India. The governor and deputy governor of RBI will be on this Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sops have been lined up too. The government has announced a ‘referral bonus scheme’ for individuals and a cashback scheme for merchants who use the Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the tax front, the Budget encourages small businesses (with turnover up to Rs 2 crore) by reducing presumptive income tax to 6% on non-cash receipts against 8% at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of digital transaction is on rural and semi-urban areas through post offices, fair price shops and banking correspondents. Petrol pumps, fertilizer depots, municipalities, block offices, road transport offices, universities, colleges, hospitals and other institutions will also be encouraged, and possibly rule-bound at some point of time, to have facilities for digital payments. “A proposal to mandate all government receipts through digital means, beyond a prescribed limit, is under consideration,” Jaitley said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small Industries Development Bank of India (SIDBI) will be encouraged to refinance credit institutions that provide unsecured loans, at reasonable interest rates, to borrowers based on their electronic payment transaction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In my opinion, initiatives like cutting excise duty on manufacturing of payment devices and a Payment Regulatory Board will further boost India’s digital economy,” said Sanjay Rishi, regional president, American Express.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Himanshu Pujara, managing director, Euronet Services India said the measures would allow people in rural areas, those “beyond the 15% data-enabled smartphone users and mobile subscribers across the country” to become a part of the digital payments ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also bear logo of 125th anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year &amp;ldquo;1891&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in English shall be written on the upper and lower periphery of the coin respectively. The year &amp;ldquo;1916&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in international numerals shall be written respectively on left and right top of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI said the existing coins in this denomination shall also continue to be legal tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 5 coin, the RBI said the coin&amp;rsquo;s face will bear an image depicting centre facade of Allahabad High Court Building emerging from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 1866-2016 in English numerals shall be written at the bottom of the image, the RBI said in a release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: How Much Fine You Have To Pay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is charging a fine on savings bank account customers not meeting the average monthly balance requirement. The amount of penalty for non-compliance with monthly average balance or MAB requirement is based on customer location - such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on Twitter while specifying various ranges according to which it will levy the charges. Charges levied for not maintaining the minimum balance depend upon how much the average balance in the account is below the agreed minimum, said SBI, which has&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. SBI also unveiled a new identity after merging its operations with six other banks recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is minimum balance requirement?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI savings bank account customers need to maintain a monthly average balance or MAB, which is the average of daily balances in the account during the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When do SBI savings bank account customers pay this charge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing to maintain the monthly balance as specified by the bank will attract a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What to do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A regular review of your account will help you to ensure the average monthly balance is maintained and avoid the minimal charges,&amp;rdquo; State Bank of India (SBI) said in another tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much fine do I need to pay?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking behemoth SBI has divided its customers into four categories: metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For metro customers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the monthly average balance of an SBI savings bank account holder comes out to be between Rs 2,500 and Rs 5,000 - a shortfall of less than 50 per cent, a charge of Rs 50 plus service tax will be levied, SBI said. For those with a shortfall of between 50 and 75 per cent (MAB from Rs 1,250 to Rs 2,500), a fee of Rs 75 plus service tax will be charged, and Rs 100 plus service tax for those keeping an average less than Rs 749 (more than 75 per cent shortfall).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-semi-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For semi-urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-rural-customers&#34;&gt;For rural customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-minimum.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The charges have been permitted by the Reserve Bank of India and are being levied by banks across the industry &amp;ldquo;and help us in providing better services to the customers&amp;rdquo;, SBI added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides savings bank accounts, SBI offers some other accounts wherein customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After its merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your PAN card could become invalid from July 1: Here&#39;s why</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/invalid-pancard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/invalid-pancard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of applications submitted for correction of names in Permanent Account Number (PAN) cards have seen a significant jump in recent weeks. This is because the government has set a deadline of July 1, 2017, to link one&amp;rsquo;s PAN with his/her Aadhaar number. But people who do not have a consistent style of spelling their names are facing problems in linking their PAN cards with Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kamala Radhakrishnan, Vice President (Business Development) at CAMS, empanelled by the National Securities Depository Ltd (NSDL) for PAN applications, says, &amp;ldquo;We understand there is a significant increase in requests for correction of names in PAN cards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way out for such people is to either correct the details in their PAN cards or get the changes done in their Aadhaar cards. You can also apply for it online by uploading the requisite documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amit Maheshwari, Partner at Ashok Maheshwary &amp;amp; Associates LLP, says, &amp;ldquo;If the details in PAN are incorrect, the person is advised to submit a PAN correction form at the designated centres of NSDL with necessary evidences. Similarly, if the details in Aadhaar are to be corrected, the person should visit the designated centres with necessary evidences to get it rectified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-Resident Indians (NRIs), however, are exempted from quoting Aadhaar numbers while filing income-tax returns back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not link your PAN card with the Aadhaar card within the stipulated time, it may lead to invalidation of your PAN card. If that happens, you will not be able to file your return this year as quoting both PAN and Aadhaar numbers has been made mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar is a 12-digit number code, issued by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI). It is used to establish a person&amp;rsquo;s identity on the basis of demographic and biometric information. The Permanent Account Number or PAN is a 10-digit alphanumeric number issued by the Income-Tax Department for tracking your financial transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the latest data available, there are more than 24.37 crore PAN registered in the country while Aadhaar cards have been issued to 113 crore people. However, only 2.87 crore individuals filed income-tax returns in the assessment year 2012-2013, out of which 1.62 crore did not pay any tax, leaving the number of taxpayers at just one per cent of the country&amp;rsquo;s total population. Due to such a low number of tax payers in the country, the government intends to catch tax evaders with the linkage of PAN cards with Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आपके पास हों तो फिलहाल संभालकर रखें बंद हो चुके नोट, जुलाई में सुप्रीम कोर्ट से मिल सकती है राहत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/supreme-court-ruling-on-note-exchange-window-in-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/supreme-court-ruling-on-note-exchange-window-in-july/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपके पास अब भी 1,000 और 500 रुपये के पुराने नोट बचे हैं तो इसे कम-से-कम जुलाई के आखिर तक सुरक्षित रखिए। सुप्रीम कोर्ट जुलाई में यह तय करेगा कि जो लोग उचित कारणों से या 8 नवंबर 2016 को नोटबंदी की घोषणा करते वक्त प्रधानमंत्री के वादे पर ऐतबार कर 30 दिसंबर 2016 तक पुराने नोट बंद नहीं कर सके, क्या उनके लिए सरकार को एक और मौका दिए जाने को कहा जाना चाहिए या नहीं। गौरतलब है कि प्रधानमंत्री ने 8 नवंबर के भाषण में चलन से बाहर किए गए नोट 30 दिसंबर के बाद भी जमा कराने का मौका दिए जाने की बात कही थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मंगलवार को सुप्रीम कोर्ट में संबंधित याचिका पर सुनवाई के दौरान अटॉर्नी जनरल मुकुल रोहतगी ने केंद्र सरकार का पक्ष रखा। उन्होंने कहा कि नोटबंदी पर लाए गए अध्यादेश में मियाद बढ़ाकर नागरिकों को नोट जमा कराने का एक और मौका दिए जाने की कोई बाध्यता नहीं है। अध्यादेश में चलन से बाहर हुए नोटों को रखना अपराध माना गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दर्जनभर से ज्यादा याचिकाकर्ताओं ने 30 दिसंबर से पहले नोट जमा नहीं करा पाने की विभिन्न वजहों का हवाला दिया। उनके वकीलों ने कोर्ट में शिकायत की कि केंद्र सरकार ने इन मामलों के बिल्कुल जुदा कारणों पर प्रतिक्रिया दिए बिना एक सामान्य सा शपथ पत्र दायर कर दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रोहतगी ने कहा कि सरकार की राय में अब बंद हो चुके नोटों को जमा कराने का कोई दूसरा मौका नहीं दिया जाएगा। केंद्र के शपथ पत्र में एक मामले का जिक्र है जिसमें याचिकाकर्ता ने 66.80 लाख रुपये मूल्य के पुराने नोट जमा कराने की मांग की है और कहा कि वह इसलिए नोट जमा नहीं करा सका क्योंकि उसका बैंक अकाउंट केवाइसी से जुड़ा नहीं था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मुख्य न्यायाधीश जे एस खेहर, जस्टिस डी वाई चंद्रचूड़ और जस्टिस संजय किशन कौल ने पुराने नोटों को रद्दी होते देखने की पीड़ा से राहत पाने के व्यक्तिगत प्रयासों में दिलचस्पी लेने से इनकार कर दिया। इन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम यह फैसला करेंगे कि क्या एक और मौका मिलेगा या नहीं। अगर हां, तो सभी को फायदा होगा।&amp;rsquo; रोहतगी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;अगर सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने पुराने नोट बदलवाने का सीमित मौका देने का फैसला करेगा तो भी यह सरकार ही तय करेगी कि 30 दिसंबर तक नोट जमा नहीं करवा पाने का किसका कारण उचित है और किसका अनुचित।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>नक्सलवाद की कमर तोड़ने के लिए मोदी सरकार ने की ये प्लानिंग, पढ़ें पूरा मामला</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-plans-to-get-foliage-penetration-radar-for-naxal-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-plans-to-get-foliage-penetration-radar-for-naxal-areas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;खास बातें&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ये रडार जल्द ही नक्‍सलियों के खिलाफ ऑपरेशंस में इस्तेमाल किए जाएंगे.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;इन रडारों का इस्तेमाल पश्चिमी देशों में और इजरायल में काफी कामयाब रहा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;अजीत डोभाल ने इस बारे में जानकारी गृह मंत्री को भी दी.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार जल्द ही नक्सल ऑपरेशनों के लिए फोलिएज पैनिट्रेटिंग रडार यानि ऐसा रडारयुक्त कैमरा जो घने जंगलों में छिपे हुए नक्सलियों की गतिविधियों के बारे में जानकारी सुरक्षा बलों दे सकेगा, ख़रीदने जा रही है. एनडीटीवी इंडिया को मिली हुई जानकारी के मुताबिक़, ये रडार जल्द ही ऑपरेशंस में इस्तेमाल किए जाएंगे. इनके ज़रिए सुरक्षा बलों को घने जंगलों की तस्वीरें भी साफ़ तरह से दिखेंगी, जिसके चलते उन्हें नक्‍सलियों के खिलाफ ऑपरेशंस में मदद मिलेगी.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक सीनियर अफ़सर ने एनडीटीवी को बताया कि &amp;ldquo;आतंकियों के खिलाफ इस तरह के रडार का इस्तेमाल पश्चिमी देशों में और इजरायल में काफी कामयाब रहा है.&amp;rdquo;  बुधवार को हुई उच्चस्तरीय बैठक में राष्ट्रीय सुरक्षा सलाहकार अजीत डोभाल ने इस बारे में जानकारी गृह मंत्री को भी दी. गुरुवार को सीआरपीएफ़ सुकमा हादसे की रिपोर्ट केंद्रीय गृह मंत्रालय को सौंपने जा रहा है.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कैसे काम करेगा ये रडार&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार को अलग-अलग लोकेशन पर फिट किया जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार को एक सेन्ट्रल मॉनिटरिंग कंट्रोल रूम से जोड़ा जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार किसी भी मूवमेंट को पकड़ने के साथ ही उस जगह की इमेज और वीडियो बनाकर सीधा कंट्रोल रूम तक पहुंचाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;इस तकनीक के सहारे नक्सलियों की लोकेशन और संख्या के साथ-साथ उनके पास मौजूद हथियार और गोला-बारूद की जानकारी भी कंट्रोल रूम को देगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>