<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>मारुति से जुड़ी इन 5 खास बातों से आप शायद ही वाकिफ हों</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/five-facts-will-give-you-a-new-insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/five-facts-will-give-you-a-new-insight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;एक मारुति कार को बनाने में कर्मचारी लगभग 2,545 स्टेप पूरे करते हैं। वहीं प्लांट की पेंट और बेल्डिंग शॉप पूरी तरह से ऑटोमैटिक होती है।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मारुति सुजुकी देशभर में न सिर्फ अपनी सस्ती, लो मेन्टेनेंस और टिकाऊ गाड़यां बनाने के लिए मशहूर है बल्कि कि देश के टॉप कार मैन्युफैक्चरर्स में से एक है। रिपोर्ट्स के मुताबिक देश में लगभग हर दूसरी बिकने वाली कार मारुति की होती है। मगर मारुति से जुड़ी कई ऐसी खास बाते हैं जिनसे आप पहले शायद ही वाकिफ हों। बिजनेस स्टैडर्ड की एक खबर के मुताबिक ये बातें मारुति मैन्युफैक्चरिंग यूनिट् को अपने आप में खास बनाती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;मारुति के कर्मचारी हर एक कार को पूरा करने के लिए 2,545 स्टेप्स फॉलो करते हैं। वहीं तीन साल पहले (2014) यह नंबर 3,077 स्टेप्स का था।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;मारुति के हरियाणा के मानेसर और गुरुग्राम स्थित दोनों मैन्युफैक्चरिंग प्लांटों में रोज 5 हजार गाड़ियां पेंट करने के लिए 70 हजार लीटर तेल की खपत होती है।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;कारें बनाने के लिए मारुति को हर महीने लगभग 20 हजार टन स्टील की जरूरत होती है जो जापान और कोरिया द्वारा इम्पोर्ट किया जाता है।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;दोनों प्लांटों में 2 हजार चार सौ ऑटोमैटिक रोबॉट्स काम करते हैं। प्लांटों की वेल्डिंग और पेंट शॉप लगभग पूरी तरह से इन ऑटोमैटिक रॉबोट्स के जरिए काम करती है।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;दोनों प्लांटों में रोज 4 हजार ट्रक अंदर-बाहर होते हैं। गाड़ियां बनाने के लिए जिन अलग-अलग पुर्जों की जरूरत होती है ये ट्रक उन्ही से भरे होते हैं। खबर के मुताबिक कंपनी ढाई हजार विक्रेताओं से अपना सामान मंगाती है और लगभग 650 ट्रकों में कार लोड होकर प्लांटों से बाहर डीलरों के पास पहुंचने के लिए निकलती हैं।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Call Drop Problem: No More Tricks, Telecom Minister Warns Operators</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refusing to lower his guard on the issue of call drops, Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement, which leaves no room for any manipulation. &amp;ldquo;We are looking at every aspect of call drop. No trick will work in this case,&amp;rdquo; Sinha told Press Trust of India in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent report from the Department of Telecom (DoT) had said call drops had come down by seven per cent in three months between December 2016 to March 2017. The minister was responding to a query on whether the DoT has taken into account the prolonged use of &amp;lsquo;radio link timeout&amp;rsquo;, a technology that prevents disconnection of calls even if there is no or weak signal. Usually, in such cases, the customer ends up disconnecting the call without it showing up as a call drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not only the DoT report, but even Trai releases official report every quarter&amp;hellip; they clearly show that there is a significant reduction in call drop. However, it is a matter of continuous monitoring. Also, the manner in which BTS (Base Transceiver Stations) have been installed in last 8-9 months is a record,&amp;rdquo; Sinha noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom operators had informed the government that they installed more than 1.60 lakh additional BTS or mobile sites across the country between June 15 and December 31, 2016 and another 1.1 lakh additional mobile sites were committed by March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per a report of the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India, all operators have met call drop standard norms in the three months ended June and September. In October-December 2016, Trai found performance of Aircel below par for call drops in most circles. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha said the IVRS is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones. &amp;ldquo;The IVRS system makes an average 2600-2700 calls everyday. It is helping us in identifying those blind spots where there are regular call drops and telecom service providers are informed about it. They (telecom operators) are trying to sort it out,&amp;rdquo; Sinha added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister emphasised that the government is boosting telecom connectivity across the country, including optical fibre rollout in village panchayats, the North-East and even in Left wing extremism-affected areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have been successful in connecting 91,000 panchayats. In coming 15-20 days, we will meet our target of connecting one lakh panchayats. There was problem of equipment. It was an indigenous technology developed by (state-owned company) C-DOT. Vendors were not available. It took a lot of time in testing,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 50 thousand such equipment have been supplied by Tejas Networks, ITI Ltd and L&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I feel that from next week onwards (optical fibre) in as many as 300 villages per day will be lit. Thereafter, the pace will increase to 400 villages per day. Right now, it is around 100 villages,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JioFiber, Reliance Jio Broadband, In These Cities</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/preview-offer-of-jiofiber-reliance-jio-broadband/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/preview-offer-of-jiofiber-reliance-jio-broadband/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid and postpaid offerings have led to further competition in Indian telecom sector since the launch of its paid &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; services.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services being launched in some areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JioFiber Preview Offer being tested in select Mumbai areas, among others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm provides telecom services under brand Jio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid heightened competition in the telecom sector due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, the market is abuzz about Jio&amp;rsquo;s broadband services - JioFiber. Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services - called &amp;ldquo;JioFiber&amp;rdquo; - are being launched in some parts of cities like Mumbai, Delhi and Vadodara. This was said on Twitter by Jio&amp;rsquo;s official customer support- Jio Care. Jio, whose prepaid and postpaid offerings have led to further competition in Indian telecom sector since the launch of its paid &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; services, is testing a &amp;ldquo;JioFiber Preview Offer&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;select areas of Mumbai, Delhi-NCR, Ahmedabad, Jamnagar, Surat and Vadodara&amp;rdquo;, Jio Care said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care also said the company&amp;rsquo;s network is in the process of being rolled out to other cities. Jio Care was responding to a query posted by an individual on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, is a provider of telecom services under brand Jio. &amp;ldquo;The Company continues to make progress on the roll-out of its Fibre to the Home (FTTH) business offering with beta trials initiated in a few locations. It would expand the scope of the beta trials over the next few months,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Industries said recently while announcing earnings for the financial year ended March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, Reliance Jio has not revealed more details about the JioFiber broadband or its fiber-to-the-home (FTTH) service - which was mentioned by Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani while launching Jio operations in September last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While announcing the launch of pan-India digital services with its &amp;ldquo;Welcome Offer&amp;rdquo; in September last year, Jio had said: &amp;ldquo;In addition to fixed and wireless broadband connectivity offering superior voice and data services on an all-IP network, Jio will also offer end-to-end solutions that address the entire value chain across various digital services in key domains such as education, healthcare, security, communication, financial services, government-citizen interfaces and entertainment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care team did not name any other cities where the JioFiber Preview Offer was being tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some analysts say Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing has intensified competition in the Indian telecom sector, forcing existing players to come up with lower tariffs. Reliance Jio is likely to gain market share from existing telecom operators, ratings agency India Ratings and Research said earlier this month, while revising its outlook on India&amp;rsquo;s telecom services sector outlook from &amp;lsquo;stable&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;negative&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service, which came into effect from April 1, include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio has said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches. From the fifth transaction onwards, the customers will have to pay a minimum of Rs 150 per transaction (plus taxes and cess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Earlier, HDFC Bank savings account customers were offered five free transactions and the sixth transaction was charged at Rs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) HDFC Bank after December 30, 2016 reintroduced charges on cash transactions at branches after the deadline to deposit old currency notes ended. The charges were waived off after the government had announced a ban on high value currency notes on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) According to the revised norms which came into effect from March 1, from non-home branch, HDFC Bank customers can deposit/withdraw up to Rs 25,000 per day without any charge but any deposit/withdrawal from non-home branch above Rs 25,000 will attract charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess), whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) At the home branch of HDFC Bank, if the cumulative cash transactions (deposit/withdrawal) exceed Rs 2 lakh, a transaction charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess) whichever is higher will be levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For example, if a customer withdraws Rs 2 lakh from an account in four transactions and goes for another fifth transaction of Rs 50,000 from the home branch, then the customer will have to pay a charge of Rs 250. Thus, the charges apply only on the fifth transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) However, the charges for withdrawing money from automatic teller machines (ATMs) remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For senior citizens and minor accounts, the limit of Rs 25,000 per day will be applicable but the accounts will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) India&amp;rsquo;s biggest private sector bank ICICI Bank had reintroduced the cash transaction charges at bank branches from January 1, 2017. There will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while thereafter Rs 5 per Rs 1,000 would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150. The third party limit is Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Meanwhile, news agency Press Trust of India reported that another private sector lender Axis Bank has also started charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1,000 Each Month For 20 Years Is Now Rs. 26,00,000 In This Fund</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DSP BlackRock Equity Fund recently completed 20 years of its existence. The fund (dividend option) has delivered 20.65 per cent compound annual growth rate since its inception, outperforming the 13 per cent return of Nifty50 index by a huge margin, says its website. The objective of DSP BlackRock Equity Fund is to seek to generate long-term capital appreciation, from a portfolio that is substantially constituted of equity securities and equity related securities of issuers domiciled in India. DSP BlackRock Equity Fund benchmarks itself against NIFTY 500 index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you consider the NIFTY 500, DSP BlackRock Equity Fund has also outperformed this index by a big margin. NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you had invested Rs 1,000 in the fund each month since its inception? Now you would be sitting on a corpus of nearly Rs 26 lakh as compared to your invested amount of Rs 2.41 lakh crore. If you had invested Rs 4,000 each month, it would have been over a crore now. Returns for investments in dividend plans of schemes are calculated after assuming that the net dividend payouts post statutory taxes &amp;amp; levies, are re-invested back in the scheme. As of March 31, 2017, the fund had assets worth Rs 2,310 crore under management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the country&amp;rsquo;s mutual fund industry managed an asset base of over Rs 18 lakh crore. Mutual funds are investment vehicles made up of a pool of funds collected from a large number of investors. The funds are invested in stocks, bonds and money market instruments, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inflows into domestic equity mutual funds have helped Sensex and Nifty rise to record levels. According to estimates domestic investors are pouring in Rs 4,000 crore every month into equity mutual funds through systematic investment route. Systematic Investment Plans or SIPs are fixed amounts invested at regular intervals in a financial instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1. SBI has clarified that the Rs. 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through its mobile wallet app. SBI’s app Bank Buddy is a new facility that enables withdrawal of cash through ATMs using the bank&amp;rsquo;s mobile wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal saving bank accounts in a month will continue to get eight free ATM transactions (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks) in metros and 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks), the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applies to the Basic Savings Banks Deposit Accounts, SBI further said. SBI’s basic savings account is a limited-services bank account aimed at poorer sections of society to encourage them to start saving without any burden of charges or fees. This type of bank account comes with an ATM-cum-debit free of cost and no annual maintenance charges. A basic savings bank deposit account holder is not eligible to open any other savings bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective June 1. Here are some of the other key changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS or Immediate Payment Service will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh; Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh; and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; If a customer wishes to exchange of more than 20 soiled notes or if the total value of soiled notes is above Rs. 5,000, SBI said it will charge Rs. 2 plus service charge for every soiled note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customer with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs. 30 plus service tax for a 10-leaf cheque book, Rs. 75 with service tax for 25-leaf cheque book and Rs. 150 plus service tax for a 50-leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issuance of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only RuPay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs. 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs. 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एयरटेल-1 साल तक मुफ्त देंगे 4जी डेटा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/micromax-tie-up-offers-1-year-free-4g-service-on-canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/micromax-tie-up-offers-1-year-free-4g-service-on-canvas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;एयरटेल ने मोबाइल कंपनी फर्म माइक्रोमैक्स के साथ मिलकर एक साल तक मुफ्त में 4जी सर्विस पेश करने का ऑफर पेश किया है। कंपनी ने गुरुवार को लॉन्च हुए माइक्रोमैक्स के कैनवास 2 स्मार्टफोन पर यह ऑफर लॉन्च किया है। इसके तहत फ्री 4जी डेटा के अलावा अनलिमिटेड कॉलिंग की भी सुविधा होगी। माइक्रोमैक्स के चीफ मार्केटिंग ऑफिसर सुभजीत सेन ने रिपोर्टरों को बताया, &amp;lsquo;माइक्रोमैक्स कैनवास 2 पर एक साल तक एयरटेल टू एयरटेल अनलिमिटेड कॉलिंग और डेटा की सुविधा होगी। यह सुविधा सभी नए और मौजूदा ग्राहकों को दी जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;माइक्रोमैक्स ने गुरुवार को ही 11,999 रुपये की कीमत वाला VoLTE स्मार्टफोन कैनवास 2 लॉन्च किया है। सेन ने कहा कि माइक्रोमैक्स और एयरटेल के बीच हुए पैक्ट के तहत यूजर्स को हर दिन 1 जीबी 4जी डेटा मिलेगा। इस लिमिट के बाद भी डेटा मिलेगा, लेकिन उसकी स्पीड कम हो जाएगी। कैनवास 2 की खरीद पर ग्राहको को हर दिन देश भर में किसी भी नेटवर्क पर 400 मिनट कॉलिंग के लिए मिलेंगे। इस ऑफर के तहत वीकली लिमिट 1500 मिनट्स की होगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;माइक्रोमैक्स के को-फाउंडर राहुल शर्मा ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;रिलायंस जियो ने जब तीन महीने का फ्री ऑफर लॉन्च किया था तो हमने देखा था कि कैसे उनके स्टोर्स के बाहर लंबी लाइनें लगी थीं। हम नहीं जानते एक साल के लिए लोगों का कैसा रेस्पॉन्स होगा।&amp;rsquo; कंपनी ने गुरुवार से ही रिटेल स्टोर्स पर इस डिवाइस की शिपिंग शुरू कर दी है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ट्रक के पुराने टायर से शुरू किया ट्रेंडी जूते बनाने का बिजनस</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/into-trendy-shoes-made-from-truck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/into-trendy-shoes-made-from-truck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;किसी गैराज या ऑटो पार्ट्स की दुकानों पर किसी कोने में पड़े टायरों को देखकर भले ही आपको वे सब सिर्फ &amp;lsquo;कबाड़&amp;rsquo; लगे, लेकिन कोशिश की जाए तो यह आपके लिए फैशन स्टेटमेंट भी साबित हो सकते हैं। कुछ ऐसा ही कारनामा कर दिखाया है मुंबई के एक एमबीए कपल ने। जे रेज और जोत्सना ने पादुक डॉट कॉम के नाम से ऑनलाइन फुटवेअर शोरूम की शुरुआत की, जो खराब हो चुके टायर से जूते बनाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जे रेज एमबीए करने के कुछ साल बाद तक फॉरन एजुकेशन की इच्छा रखने वालों के लिए कंसल्टेंसी चलाते थे। शादी के बाद पत्नी जोत्सना के साथ मुंबई के चेंबुर इलाके से ऑनलाइन फुटवेअर शोरूम की शुरुआत की। इस ऑनलाइन प्लैटफॉर्म का नाम रखा गया पादुक्स (paaduks.com)। कमाल की बात यह है कि इस प्लैटफॉर्म पर सिर्फ बेकार हो चुके टायर से बने फुटवेअर ही मिलते हैं। कई अलग रंग और डिजाइन में बने इन जूते-चप्पलों की काफी डिमांड बढ़ गई है। ऑनलाइन प्लैटफॉर्म के साथ कुछ स्टोर्स पर भी ये फुटवेअर आपको मिल सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जे ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;हमने 2013 में पादुक की शुरुआत की थी। मैं इंटरनेट पर ब्राउज़िंग कर रहा था, तभी मैंने एक शख्स के बारे में पढ़ा जो इंडोनेशिया से बेकार हो चुके टायर इम्पोर्ट करता है। इन टायरों को वह जूतों के सोल बनाने में इस्तेमाल करता था और फिर उन्हें यूएस में बेचता था। हमें आइडिया बेहद पसंद आया और हमने भारत में ऐसा ही कुछ करने का फैसला लिया।&amp;rsquo; जहां जूतों के सोल के लिए टायर कबाड़ी की दुकान से मिल जाते थे, वहीं जूते के अंदर और बाहर के डिजाइन के लिए कपड़ा और दूसरी चीजें हम लोकल मार्केट से खरीद लेते थे। और इन जूतों की कीमत हमने 399 रुपये से 1100 रुपये तक रखी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पादुक्स में डिजाइन हेड कैरल कॉर्नेलियो ने बताया &amp;lsquo;हमारे जूतों के डिजाइन मेल और फीमेल दोनों के लिए हैं। यहां तक कि हमारे जूते भारतीय पारंपरिक वेश के साथ और ज्यादा अच्छे दिखते हैं, उन्हें कैजुअल ड्रेस के साथ भी पहना जा सकता है। हम बेहद जल्द नया प्रॉडक्ट लॉन्च करने वाले हैं जो पूरी तरह ट्यूब और टायरों से बना है। इन सैंडल का बेस टायर से और स्ट्रेप ट्यूब से बनी है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पादुक्स की कोफाउंडर जोत्सना से जब इस स्टार्टअप की फंडिंग के बारे में पूछा गया तो उन्होंने बताया, &amp;lsquo;हमारे फुटवेअर न सिर्फ इको-फ्रेंडली होते हैं बल्कि वेस्ट मैनेजमेंट का भी अच्छा उदारण हैं। इस वेंचर को शुरू करने में हमने पूरी तरह अपना पैसा लगाया है। हमने बहुत सक्रिय तौर पर फंडिंग के लिए किसी से बात नहीं की, हालांकि आइडिया के लेवल पर हमने कई जगह बात की।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जे ने बताया कि उनका उद्देश्य रिटेल स्टोर से ज्यादा ऑनलाइन प्लैटफॉर्म पर था। उन्होंने बताया, &amp;lsquo;हमने अपने प्रॉडक्ट को प्रमोट करने के लिए सोशल मीडिया का सबसे ज्यादा सहारा लिया। यहां तक कि फेसबुक और इंस्टाग्राम पर बहुत एक्टिव कैंपेन चलाया। हालांकि दिल्ली, बेंगलुरु और पुणे में कुछ रिटेल स्टोर्स पर हमारे प्रॉडक्ट मिल जाएंगे। हमारे प्रॉडक्ट बेंगलुरु में काफी फेमस हैं। हमें मिले कुल ऑनलाइन ऑर्डर का 25 प्रतिशत हिस्सा बेंगलुरु से ही मिलता है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>देशों पर साइबर अटैक: चपेट में ये देसी कंपनियां एवं सरकारी संस्थान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;दुनियाभर के 99 देशों पर हुए साइबर अटैक की चपेट में देश की कई कंपनियां भी आ गईं। रैनसमवेअर वानाक्राइ से प्रभावित हुईं कंपनियों में दो दक्षिण भारतीय बैंक, दिल्ली की दो मैन्युफैक्चरिंग कंपनियां, बहुराष्ट्रीय कंपनी (एमएनसी) की एक मैन्युफैक्चरिंग यूनिट, मुंबई की एक दिग्गज कंपनी और एक एफएमसीजी कंपनी के मुख्यालय शामिल हैं। इनके अलावा, आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के 100 से ज्यादा कंप्यूटर भी इस भयावह हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुरक्षा विशेषज्ञों का मानना है कि इस हमले से हुआ नुकसान और ज्यादा हो सकता है और प्रभावित कंपनियों की तादाद बढ़ सकती है। चूंकि यह हमला वीकेंड में (शुक्रवार को) हुआ है, इसलिए नुकसान का सही-सही आकलन सोमवार को ही किया जा सकता है जब सारे पर्सनल कंप्यूटर्स स्टार्ट किए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EY इंडिया में पाटर्नर (फ्रॉड इन्वेस्टिगेशन ऐंड डिस्प्यूट सर्विसेज) मुकुल श्रीवास्तव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;भारतीय कंपनियां हालिया हमले की चपेट में आई हैं। पिछले एक साल में रैनसमवेअर के मामले बहुत बढ़ गए हैं। अब साइबर क्रिमिनल्स बेहद टेक सेवी हो चुके हैं और हरेक रैनसमवेअर की अपनी यूनीक एन्क्रिप्टिंग मशीनें हैं। ये हमले लगातार बाधा पहुंचाने और फिरौती वसूलने के मकसद से हो रहे हैं। इसलिए संगठनों को ऐसे खतरों का सामना करने के लिए गंभीर उपाय करने होंगे। हम साइबरक्राइम और रैनसमवेअर के खिलाफ समाधान प्रक्रिया में कई देसी एवं वैश्विक कंपनियों के साथ काम कर रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जाल में ऐसे फंसाते हैं हैकर्स, रहें सावधान&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;शुक्रवार को मैलवेअर बड़ी तेजी से फैल गया और दुनियाभर की कंपनियों एवं सरकारी संगठनों में कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए। दरअसल, रैनसमवेअर के डाउनलोड होते ही सभी कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए और उनमें पड़े डेटा एन्क्रिप्ट कर लिए गए। हमलावर ने इन डेटा को रीस्टोर करने के लिए फिरौती की मांग की।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनियां ऐसे हमलों से निपटने के लिए देश के जिन साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर कर रही हैं, उनके मुताबिक ऐसे कई मामले सामने आए हैं जब भारतीय कंपनियों ने अपने प्रभावित कंप्यूटरों को दुबारा ऐक्सेस करने के एवज में फिरौती दी। यूके की नैशनल हेल्थ सर्विसेज (एनएसएस) जैसे वैश्विक संस्थान और रेनॉ, फेडेक्स एवं टेलिफोनिका जैसी कंपनियों ने हमले से प्रभावित होने की जानकारी दी, लेकिन देश की एक भी कंपनी ने नहीं बताया कि उनके कंप्यूटर हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के कंप्यूटरों पर साइबर हमले, फिरौती मांग रहे हैकर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक्सपर्ट्स का कहना है कि शुक्रवार को फैलाया गया मैलवेअर अमेरिका की नैशनल सिक्यॉरिटी एजेंसी का वही इटरनलब्लू टूल है जिसे अप्रैल महीने में द शैडो ब्रॉकर्स नाम के हैकर ग्रुप ने चुरा लिया था। दिग्गज साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी कंपनी अवास्ट ने कहा कि उसने रैनसमवेअर और इसके विभिन्न रूपों के 75,000 मामले देखे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी एक्सपर्ट ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इस हमला कुछ अलग है। इससे कोई एक बार इन्फेक्ट हो गया तो हो गया। इसे हटाने के लिए तीन से चार घंटे लगेंगे और पीसी रीबूट करना पड़ेगा। हालांकि, इसमें कोई नुकसान या कोई डेटा खत्म नहीं होता।&amp;rsquo; साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स के मुताबिक, भारतीय कंपनियों पर रैनसमवेअर अटैक्स के मामले में एक सिलिसला सा जुड़ रहा है। पिछले तीन महीनों में 25 से 30 ऐसे मामले सामने आ चुके हैं जब कंपनियां मैलवेअर का शिकार हुई हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बिजली बिल: आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को जरूरी सेवाओं के लिए अनिवार्य किए जाने का मामला अभी सुप्रीम कोर्ट में लंबित है। इस बीच बिजली बिल के भुगतान को भी आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी शुरू कर दी गई है। केंद्र सरकार ने राज्यों से बिजली के बिलों का डिजिटल भुगतान आधार से जुड़े बैंक खातों के माध्यम से सुनिश्चित करने को कहा है। केंद्रीय ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा है कि बिजली बिल को आधार से जोड़ना ग्राहकों के लिए फायदेमंद साबित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;राज्यों और केंद्र शासित प्रदेशों के ऊर्जा और खदान मंत्रियों की कॉन्फ्रेंस में गोयल ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह जरूरी नहीं है, लेकिन सभी के हित में है क्योंकि अगर आप बिल का भुगतान डिजिटल माध्यम से करेंगे तो आपके पास यह ठीक-ठीक सबूत होगा कि आपने बिल का भुगतान किया है। यह पहल जनता को मदद करेगी और इस संबंध में कोशिश की जानी चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि इसका फैसला राज्यों को लेना है कि वे बिजली बिलों के भुगतान की प्रणाली को आधार से जुड़े खातों से जोड़ें या नहीं, लेकिन निश्चित तौर पर यह कहा जा सकता है कि यह ग्राहकों के हित में है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि सरकार ने हाल में आयकर रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को जरूरी कर दिया है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट में भी सरकार ने अपनी तरफ से साफ किया है कि पैन नंबर के जरिए होने वाले फ्रॉड को रोकने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य किया जाना जरूरी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गोयल ने यह भी कहा कि सरकार राज्यों को बिजली आवंटन के मसौदे को फिर तैयार कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम फॉर्म्युले पर काम कर रहे हैं। हम इस बात पर फिर से विचार कर रहे हैं कि हम इसे (पावर आवंटन पॉलिसी) किस तरह मजबूत बना सकते हैं। फिलहाल गाडगिल फॉर्म्युले पर बिजली का बंटवारा होता है। इसके तहत राज्यों के प्लान के लिए केंद्रीय मदद के लिए नियम और शर्तों को तय किया जाता है। उनका यह भी कहना था कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा बिजली उन को दी जाएगी, जो न्यूक्लियर प्लांट्स स्थापित करने को बढ़ावा देंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिजली के कमर्शल नुकसान में गिरावट और कॉस्ट की बेहतर कवरेज से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन कंपनियों में मामूली बेहतरी से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रिब्यूशन कंपनियों के ऑपरेशनल परफॉर्मेंस में सुधार हुआ है। पावर फाइनेंस कॉर्पोरेशन (PFC) की एक रिपोर्ट में यह बात कही गई है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी 2.0&#39; के लिए पोर्टल बना रहा I-T विभाग</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/it-department-building-portal-for-operation-clean-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/it-department-building-portal-for-operation-clean-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ऐसे लोगों की जांच के लिए एक खास पोर्टल बना रहा है, जिन्होंने अपनी घोषित आमदनी से कहीं ज्यादा जमा किए हैं या बड़ी खरीदारियां की हैं। सीबीडीटी यह कदम ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत उठा रहा है। उस अभियान को नोटबंदी के मद्देनजर काले धन पर लगाम कसने के लिए शुरू किया गया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह प्रस्ताव प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी के सामने राजस्व विभाग की हालिया समीक्षा बैठक में रखा गया था। चर्चा की जानकारी रखने वाले एक उच्च अधिकारी ने ईटी को बताया, &amp;lsquo;हम एक पोर्टल पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो खास इसी मकसद के लिए होगा।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह उन लोगों के लिहाज से विकसित किया जाएगा, जिनकी पहचान ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत हुई थी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह पोर्टल ऐसे लोगों और टैक्स अथॉरिटीज के बीच संवाद का जरिया बनेगा। यह संवाद PAN के जरिए होगा। डिपार्टमेंट इस प्रोसेस में मानव हस्तक्षेप की गुंजाइश यथासंभव कम रखना चाहता है और जोर ई-असेसमेंट पर है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी का दूसरा चरण हाई-रिस्क लोगों पर केंद्रित होगा, जिन्होंने ज्यादा वैल्यू वाले ट्रांजैक्शंस किए थे। ऐसे लोगों की विस्तृत जांच की जाएगी। डेटा एनालिटिक्स के जरिए ऐसे 60,000 से ज्यादा लोगों की पहचान डिपार्टमेंट कर चुका है। जिन मामलों में गहराई से पड़ताल की तैयारी है, वे ज्यादा डिपॉजिट्स के अलावा ज्यादा कीमत की खरीद-फरोख्त से जुड़े हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने कहा कि इस डेडिकेटेड पोर्टल से टैक्स अथॉरिटीज और संदेह के घेरे में आए लोगों के बीच बिना जोर-जबरदस्ती के संवाद पर फोकस सुनिश्चित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पीएम को ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के बारे में डिटेल्ड रिप्रेजेंटेशन दिया गया था और यह भी बताया गया था कि सीबीडीटी ने कौन से कदम उठाए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी को नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद शुरू किया गया था। इसका मकसद अघोषित आमदनी रखने वालों को टैक्स के दायरे में लाना था। डिपार्टमेंट ने लगभग 18 लाख लोगों की पहचान की थी, जिनसे एसएमएस और ईमेल से संपर्क किया गया था और उनसे उनके डिपॉजिट्स पर सफाई मांगी गई थी। ऐसे लोगों से कहा गया था कि या तो वे टैक्स चुकाएं या प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के जरिए पहले की अघोषित आमदनी का खुलासा करें।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनमें से लगभग 10 लाख लोग ई-वेरिफिकेशन प्रोसेस में शामिल हुए थे। डिपार्टमेंट वित्त वर्ष 2017 में करीब 95 लाख नए करदाताओं को कर के दायरे में लाने में सफल रहा। पिछले साल 8 नवंबर को नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद पैन के लिए ऐप्लिकेशंस की संख्या भी बढ़ी क्योंकि विभाग ने बैंकों को निर्देश दिया था कि सभी खातों को PAN से जोड़ा जाए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डिपार्टमेंट को PAN के लिए रोज करीब 173000 आवेदन मिले, जबकि नोटबंदी के पहले इनकी औसत संख्या 83000 हआ करती थी। कुछ दिनों में इनकी तादाद 300000 तक चली गई। डिपार्टमेंट ने 8 नवंबर 2016 सके 31 मार्च 2017 के बीच 4.65 करोड़ PAN अलॉट किए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 GB Free Data: Vodafone&#39;s Latest Offer In Response To Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September, incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Vodafone is also currently offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone is giving &lt;em&gt;9 GB data&lt;/em&gt; free to customers in a special scheme, its latest offer to counter Reliance Jio which has come up with aggressive tariff plans. &amp;ldquo;Thank you for making us a 200 million strong family! As a token of appreciation, we are happy to delight you with free data on your Vodafone mobile,&amp;rdquo; Vodafone said. A Vodafone customer care executive said the 9 GB free data offer has been made to select customers. The 9 GB free data will be applicable &lt;em&gt;at 3 GB/month&lt;/em&gt; for three billing cycles. Vodafone said this 9GB offer is in addition to &amp;ldquo;existing data quota on your plan/pack at no extra cost&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September,&lt;/em&gt; incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Currently, Vodafone is also offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New entrant Reliance Jio has kept the pressure on other operators to cut tariffs and make special offers to customers. Jio&amp;rsquo;s current &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans offer &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs. 309.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Vodafone said that it will offer free incoming calls during international roaming on its network in 45 countries at a daily rental of Rs. 500 along with all international and local outgoing calls for Rs. 1 a minute. In the countries where Vodafone operates, the customer will get 1 megabyte of mobile internet for Rs. 1 which implies 1 GB of data will cost them Rs. 1,024. &amp;ldquo;Keeping in mind the requirements of international travelers, Vodafone had recently introduced the i-RoamFREE proposition offering free incoming calls, Re 1 for all international and local outgoing calls and data at Re 1 per MB in over 45 countries on a daily basis,&amp;rdquo; Vodafone said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price war for data subscribers has dented the bottom lines of wireless telecom service providers, yet none of them is likely to pull a punch, Crisil said in a report. If anything, competition will only heat up further given that market leadership is all-crucial to the business, it said. The proposed merger between Idea and Vodafone - which marks the biggest consolidation in the Indian telecom sector - is also part of this quest to strengthen market position, alongside lowering investment needs and costs, Crisil added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been reported that a new ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; is spreading widely, the RBI advisory to the banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wannacry encrypts the files on infected Windows system and spreads by exploiting vulnerabilities, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI also asked all banks to put in place a software update at ATMs to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate malware attack last year, 3.2 lakh debit cards were compromised in the country. Data of the users who transacted from ATM machines of Hitachi were compromised during May, June and July last year. The Hitachi ATMs deployed by many White Label ATM players and Yes Bank were impacted by the malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, ATMs or automated teller machines are highly vulnerable to such malware attacks as they currently run on old version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, making a software security patch update a necessary exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a total of 2.2 lakh ATMs in India, of which many old ones run on Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, the ransomware has hit systems in more than 150 countries, including Russia and the UK, in one of the most widespread cyber attacks in history. It infected computers running on older versions of Microsoft operating systems like XP, locking access to files on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cyber criminals have demanded a fee of about $300 in crypto-currencies like Bitcoin for unlocking the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has introduced a security patch to tackle the situation, and consumers across the globe have been advised to download the solution at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CERT-In on Monday said it has not received any formal report of cyber attack on India&amp;rsquo;s vital networks by the crippling global ransomware, &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) had said on Sunday that a few systems of the Police Department in Andhra Pradesh were impacted and that the state government has been informed to follow the advisory by the CERT-In.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the Maharashtra Police department said it was partially hit by the ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the alert, the Gujarat government began equipping its state computer systems with anti-virus software and upgrading its Microsoft operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the advisory issued by CERT-In, the ransomware infects other computers on the same network and is also spreading through malicious attachments to e-mails. Security firms have suggested that users immediately disconnect the infected device from the local network to contain the spread of infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, major companies including telecommunications firm Telefonica have been infected. The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>