<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things that are banned for you, from opening a bank account to processing of I-T returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</guid>
      <description>If you thought that filing an income tax return or opening a bank account are the only few things which require Aadhaar cards now, then think again. The fact is Aadhaar has now been made mandatory for so many things, including availing the benefits of various social and government schemes. While for some schemes it has already been made compulsory, for some others it will be made mandatory soon.
Here we are taking a look at 10 such things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much To Save A Day To Become A Crorepati. You Will Be Surprised!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-to-save-a-day-to-become-a-crorepati-you-will-be-surprised/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-to-save-a-day-to-become-a-crorepati-you-will-be-surprised/</guid>
      <description>Accumulating a corpus of Rs. 1 crore is a dream for many. But many individuals who are in their early twenties don&amp;rsquo;t follow a systematic investment habit, thinking that they will start when they earn more. But you will be surprised to know that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to save a lot of money every month to accumulate Rs. 1 crore, provided you start early.
   Time 6% 8% 10% 12%     20 Years Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Mobile Number (SIM) With Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-mobile-number-sim-with-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-mobile-number-sim-with-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link your Aadhaar number to your bank account and your PAN card. The 12-digit biometric ID is now not only necessary to avail schemes but also in financial matters like bank accounts and filing taxes. Even mobile phone service users will now have to verify using Aadhaar numbers. According to the news agency Press Trust of India (PTI), the government is moving ahead with linking Aadhaar with mobile SIM cards and all unlinked phones will be deactivated after February 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Celebrates One Year: Five Key Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-celebrates-one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-celebrates-one-year/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is celebrating its first birthday on Tuesday. The Mukesh Ambani-led mobile and internet service provider, which was commercially launched on September 5, 2016, keeps unleashing a plethora of offers, which have changed the landscape of the Indian telecom sector. As Jio sparked off an intense price war among the debt-ridden domestic telecom industry, its attractive offers have made key rivals like Bharti Airtel, Idea Cellular, Vodafone and even Mukesh’s younger brother Anil Ambani owned-Reliance Communications up the ante in terms of data and call offerings to retain customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Numbers Not Linked To Aadhaar To Be Deactivated After February: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sim-cards-not-linked-to-aadhaar-to-be-deactivated-after-february-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sim-cards-not-linked-to-aadhaar-to-be-deactivated-after-february-report/</guid>
      <description>The government is moving ahead with linking Aadhaar with mobile SIM cards and all unlinked phones will be deactivated after February 2018, said informed sources. Sources told news agency IANS that linking of Aadhaar with mobile is being done as per the orders of Supreme Court passed in February this year in Lokniti foundation case and all SIM cards have to be verified with Aadhaar within a year from the date of judgement, with all unlinked phones to be deactivated after February next year, so criminals, fraudsters and terrorists cannot use the issued SIMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only 5 Free ATM Transactions From October, Punjab National Bank Says</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</guid>
      <description>PNB customers will have to shell out money beginning October if they carry out more than five transactions a month from the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs. At present, account holders of the country&amp;rsquo;s second largest public sector bank can make any number of transactions in a month, financial or non-financial, at the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs without attracting any charge.
&amp;ldquo;The number of free transactions and the charges beyond these free transactions for PNB customers on PNB ATMs have been revised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI Says New Rs. 50 Notes Coming Shortly: Five Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-says-new-rs-50-notes-coming-shortly-five-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-says-new-rs-50-notes-coming-shortly-five-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Just a month after the announcement of new Rs. 20 notes in the Mahatma Gandhi Series-2005, Reserve Bank of India (RBI) on Friday said that it will also bring new Rs. 50 banknotes shortly in circulation. The new Rs. 50 notes will be in the Mahatma Gandhi (New) Series, bearing signatures of RBI governor Urjit R Patel, the central bank said in a press release. With &amp;ldquo;Fluorescent Blue&amp;rdquo; as the base colour, the new note &amp;ldquo;has motif of Hampi with Chariot on the reverse,&amp;rdquo; it added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to verify if aadhaar card and pan card is linked</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-verify-if-both-cards-are-linked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-verify-if-both-cards-are-linked/</guid>
      <description>Steps to Check if Aadhar Card and PAN Card are Linked
 Go to the official website of the Income Tax Department. Enter your credentials – user ID, password, date of birth and captcha. Under ‘_Profile Setting_’ select ‘_Link Aadhaar_’. If your Aadhaar is linked with your PAN, then the display on the page will mention the same.  The benefit of linking Aadhaar and PAN in the income tax e-filing portal is to eliminate the necessity of furnishing your Income Tax acknowledgment while filing for returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>link your Aadhaar number with your bank account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-aadhaar-bank-account-linking-last-date-check-it-in-3-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-aadhaar-bank-account-linking-last-date-check-it-in-3-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Have you recently got a message from your bank asking you to link your Aadhaar number with your bank account? This is most likely in cases where someone has still not linked one’s Aadhaar number to one’s bank account or the bank has failed to do so for some reasons.
For instance, the message from a leading bank says, “Dear Customer, as per a Government of India mandate (under Prevention of Money Laundering Rules, 2005), all bank accounts must be linked with Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>link your SBI account to Aadhaar via ATMs and SMS: Here’s how to do it in easy steps</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-link-aadhaar-card-online-via-atm-sms-state-bank-of-india-heres-how-to-do-it-in-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-link-aadhaar-card-online-via-atm-sms-state-bank-of-india-heres-how-to-do-it-in-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Are you a State Bank of India customer and want to link your Aadhaar number to your SBI account? Or have got a message from the bank to do so? Here’s some good news for you. SBI allows its customers to link their bank accounts to their Aadhaar number in various ways, including their ATM channel and through SMS. You can also get it done by visiting any of their branches or through Internet banking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>