<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Govt:Over Rs 153cr awarded to 10lk people to promote e-payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;check if you are winner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dev.digidhanlucky&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px;padding:4px&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/logoapp.png&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on start button in Digi Dhan Lucky Yojana App.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on whether you are a Consumer or a Merchant, click on the corresponding button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box that appears next, provide the mobile phone number registered with your UPI/ USSD/ RuPay/ AEPS account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive an OTP, which you must enter in the box that appears in the middle of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Try Your Luck button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next message will show if you have won under the Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi Dhan Vyapar Yojana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been awarded over Rs 153.5 crore in the last 58 days under Niti Aayog’s schemes to promote digital payments, its CEO Amitabh Kant said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It has been 58 days since the launch of Niti Aayog’s two incentive schemes – Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana to promote digital payments and the public response has been quite encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the latest figures released by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), which has been executing the schemes, nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been disbursed over Rs 153.5 crore as reward money till February 20, 2017,” Kant said at a press conference here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s think-tank said in a statement that among the 9.8 lakh winners are more than 9.2 lakh consumers and 56,000 merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners belong to diverse socio-economic backgrounds, including farmers, merchants, small entrepreneurs, professionals, housewives, students and retired persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Uttar Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh and Delhi have emerged as the top five states/Union Territories with maximum number of winners,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While majority of the winners are in the age group of 21 to 30, Niti Aayog pointed out that a significant number are also above 60 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The diversity in age of winners is from 15 to 66 years, challenging the notion that the old find it difficult to embrace technology to adopt digital payments,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government on December 25 had launched two schemes — Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana — to boost digital transactions post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 अप्रैल से कार, हेल्थ इंश्योरेंस के लिए ज्यादा चुकाने के लिए रहें तैयार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/general-insurance-premium-set-to-go-up-from-april-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/general-insurance-premium-set-to-go-up-from-april-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;भारतीय बीमा नियामक एवं विकास प्राधिकरण (इरडा) ने बीमा कंपनियों को एजेंटों के कमीशन रीवाइज करने की अनुमति दे दी है। इससे 1 अप्रैल से कार, मोटरसाइकल और स्वास्थ्य बीमा के प्रीमियम में बढ़ोत्तरी होने की संभावना है। इसके बाद बीमा के प्रीमियम की मौजूदा दरें पांच प्रतिशत घट-बढ़ सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह वृद्धि 1 अप्रैल से प्रभावी होने वाली थर्ड पार्टी मोटर बीमा की दरों में की गई बढ़ोत्तरी के अलावा होगी। उल्लेखनीय है कि इरडा (बीमा एजेंटों और बीमा मध्यस्थों को कमीशन या पारिश्रमिक या पारितोषिक) नियम-2016 अगले महीने की 1 तारीख से से लागू होंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इरडा ने कहा कि इन नियमों से कमीशन और पारिश्रमिक दरों में कुछ बदलाव आएंगे और साथ रिवॉर्ड सिस्टम भी शुरू किया जाएगा। इस पर आने वाली लागत को पूरा करने के लिए बीमा कंपनियां अपने प्रॉडक्ट्स की कीमतों में परिवर्तन कर सकती हैं। हालांकि नियामक ने प्रीमियम में पांच प्रतिशत कम-ज्यादा की सीमा तय कर दी है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar to made compulsory for getting driver’s licence: report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-made-compulsory-getting-drivers-licence-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-made-compulsory-getting-drivers-licence-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar’s scope is further expanding. The Times of India reports that Aadhaar will now be made mandatory for obtaining a driver’s licence and renewal of existing licences. The publication added that this was being done prevent issuance of multiple licences under one name. It added that multiple licences were being issued to a single person as fake identifications to beat traffic and criminal offences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union transport ministry is looking at a bringing all the regional transport offices (RTOs) under a central database called Sarathi which will prevent people from getting multiple licences from different RTOs.  The rules are expected to kick off from October this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar is being made compulsory for Income Tax returns and it will also be made mandatory to link mobile numbers to Aadhaar. Last week, the Department of Telecom issued a note saying that all telecom operators will have to ensure that their subscribers link mobile numbers within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driver’s licences are also used as proof of address and identity and are used for opening bank accounts and getting mobile phone connections. However, the Aadhaar to be used as both an identity proof as well as an address proof. Banks and telecom companies use biometric eKYC to open accounts and mobile connections. But the reality is that UIDAI does not validate the address of every applicant. Though applicants are asked to provide an address proof for Aadhaar enrolment, it is optional — the enrolment process (and form) is designed to allow anyone to get an identity without any documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that driver’s licence has security features like holograms in an original document. However, as St_Hill noted in a post, that there is no concept of an “original” Aadhaar card. A printout of Aadhaar information is being treated by various entities as a valid document, so it is easy for a fraudster (even an amateur) to print out details card if he knows your basic information, and start submitting in different places where the government asks us to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Rules On Home Loan To Change From Saturday. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-rules-on-home-loan-benefits-to-change-from-april-see-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-rules-on-home-loan-benefits-to-change-from-april-see-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tax experts say that some high net worth individuals, who used to buy properties on loan and were able to set off the full interest liability against the lettable value of property and thus bring down their tax liability substantially, would be particularly hit from this new tax rule.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the anomaly of interest deduction in respect of let-out property vs self-occupied property, the government has changed income tax rules, which will come into effect from next financial year April 1, 2017 (assessment year 2018-19). In this regard, the government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. According to current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get Rs 2 lakh deduction on interest repayment on home loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on rented properties, effective from April 1, interest paid above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, your interest outgo on a second property is Rs. 5 lakh in a particular year. Assume that you are earning a rent of Rs. 1.5 lakh annually from the property. Such buyers, according to the current rule, are allowed to adjust the difference of Rs. 3.5 lakh (Rs. 5 lakh interest minus Rs. 1.5 lakh). But from the next financial year, they will be allowed deduction of just Rs. 2 lakh. The remaining amount of Rs. 1.5 lakh (Rs. 3.5 lakh minus Rs. 2 lakh) can be carried forward up to eight financial years and be adjusted later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax experts say that some high net worth individuals, who used to buy properties on loan and were able to set off the full interest liability against the lettable value of property and thus bring down their tax liability substantially, would be particularly hit from this new tax rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From April another tax rule related to the properties will also change. The new tax rule will help bring down tax liability from property sale. The holding period of a property for qualifying under long-term gains will get reduced to two years, from three years currently. As per current tax norms, if a property is sold within three years of buying, the profit from the transaction is treated as short-term capital gain and is taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her. So reducing this time period to two years will bring down tax liability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, after two years, the transaction will be able to qualify for long-term capital gains, thus lower taxes. Under long-term capital gains on immovable properties, the profit is taxed at 20 per after indexation. Under indexation, inflation during the holding period is taken into account and thus the purchase price is adjusted, reducing the tax burden on the property seller. There are also other benefits for the seller under the long-term capital gains tax. If the gains are invested in some select government investment schemes, the tax liability goes down significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI:No Plans To Introduce New Denomination Notes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-plans-to-introduce-new-denomination-notes-rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-plans-to-introduce-new-denomination-notes-rbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal had told Parliament on Friday that the government is not planning to print Rs 5,000 and Rs 10,000 currency notes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India currently has no plans of introducing new denomination currencies, a senior RBI official said on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Presently RBI has no idea to introduce currencies of new denominations. The central banking institution wants to encourage cashless transactions, which are helpful to the people&amp;rdquo;, RBI Deputy Governor N.S. Vishwanathan said while speaking at a lecture here on &amp;ldquo;Credit culture and the financial system&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this connection, Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal had told Parliament on Friday that the government is not planning to print &lt;em&gt;Rs 5,000 and Rs 10,000&lt;/em&gt; currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referring to banks&amp;rsquo; non-performing assets (NPAs), or bad loans, Vishwanathan said here that these are affecting the income and profit of banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks cannot escape from the responsibility of controlling NPAs in their balance sheets,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks are expected to base their lending decisions on a careful and prudent assessment of the financial position and repaying capacity of the borrower, while credit should be given to only the right people, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magnitude of the problem can be guaged from the NPA figures of state-run banks, which at the end of the current fiscal&amp;rsquo;s second quarter that ended in September, rose to Rs 6.3 lakh crore, as compared to Rs 5.5 lakh crore at the end of the first quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ने पर अवैध हो जाएगा PAN,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) को आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ा तो संभव है कि 31 दिसंबर के बाद यह अवैध हो जाए। दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के सरकार के फैसले के बाद इसे वित्तीय लेनदेन (फाइनैंशल ट्रांजैक्शंज) के लिए जरूरी नंबर बनाने की दिशा में एक और कदम बढ़ा दिया गया है। सरकार पूरे फाइनैंशल सेक्टर में आधार आधारित नो योर कस्टमर (KYC) को इंटीग्रेट करने पर विचार कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इसकी पुष्टि करते हुए कहा कि सरकार रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) सहित सभी रेग्युलेटर्स के साथ विचार-विमर्श कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार KYC एक तुरंत, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक और मजबूत प्रमाण उपलब्ध कराता है, जिससे सेवा उद्योग की प्रक्रिया बेहतर बनाने में मदद मिलेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने फाइनैंस बिल में एक संशोधन के जरिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के लिए आवेदन पर आधार को अनिवार्य बना दिया है। अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन लोगों के पास पहले से आधार मौजूद है, उन्हें किसी भी वित्तीय मध्यस्थ (फाइनैंशल इंटरमीडियरी) को अपने अंगूठे का निशान उपलब्ध कराना होगा। इसे संबंधित सेक्टर की रिपोर्टिंग एंटिटि को दिया जाएगा, जो इसे UIDAI डेटाबेस से वैलिडेट करेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस डेटा के आधार पर सेंट्रल रजिस्ट्री ऑफ सिक्यॉरिटाइजेशन ऐंड ऐसेट रिकंस्ट्रक्शन ऐंड सिक्यॉरिटी इंट्रेस्ट ऑफ इंडिया (CERSAI) की ओर से एक यूनीक C-KYC नंबर जेनरेट किया जाएगा। इस नंबर का इस्तेमाल बैंक अकाउंट, म्यूचुअल फंड इन्वेस्टमेंट, डीमैट अकाउंट और इंश्योरेंस पॉलिसी सहित सभी फाइनैंशल प्रॉडक्ट्स में किया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा था कि देश में 98 प्रतिशत व्यस्कों या 108 करोड़ से अधिक लोगों को आधार नंबर जारी किया जा चुका है और इसी वजह से सरकार इसका इस्तेमाल बढ़ा रही है। उन्होंने इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के प्रस्ताव पर दोबारा विचार करने की संसद की मांग को खारिज कर दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC सुविधा से PAN के आवेदन के लिए जन्मतिथि या पते जैसी जानकारियों की पुष्टि का इंतजार कर रहे व्यक्ति और एंटिटि अंगूठे के निशान से बायोमेट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन कर सकेंगे। CERSAI ने पिछले वर्ष सभी वित्तीय संस्थानों में एक समान KYC प्रोसेस सुनिश्चित करने के लिए e-KYC की कोशिश शुरू की थी। 2016 में मार्केट रेग्युलेटर सेबी ने आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC को स्वेच्छा से अपनाने पर सहमति दी थी। सभी सरकारी बैंकों से भी इस तरह का अपडेटेड डेटा अथॉरिटी को उपलब्ध कराने का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विज्ञापन में कहा गया है कि आयकर विभाग के पास आपकी जमाओं की जानकारी है। विभाग ने कहा है कि इस योजना के तहत कालेधन की घोषणा करने वालों की गोपनीयता सुनिश्चित की जाएगी। विज्ञापन में स्पष्ट चेतावनी दी गई है कि योजना के तहत काले धन की जानकारी नहीं देने वालों को बेनाम कानून के तहत कठोर कार्रवाई का सामना करना होगा। यहां तक कि उनके नाम ईडी और सीबीआई जैसी केंद्रीय जांच एजेंसियों के साथ साझा कर दिए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा कि जो लोग प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना का लाभ लेते हुए अपनी काली कमाई उजागर नहीं करेंगे, उन्हें जमा राशि पर 137% तक जुर्माना लगाया जा सकता है। उनके मुताबिक, विभाग ऐसे डिफॉल्टरों पर नए बेनामी लेनदेन कानून के तहत कार्रवाई करने से भी नहीं हिचकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत काला धन की जानकारी देने वालों को 49.9 प्रतिशत टैक्स देना होगा, जबकि ऐसा नहीं कर इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न में इस धन का जिक्र करने वालों को टैक्स के साथ-साथ 77.25 प्रतिशत जुर्माना देना होगा। साथ ही, जो लोग योजना के तहत काले धन का खुलासा नहीं करते हैं और जांच आकलन में इसका पता चलता है तो उन्हें 83.25 प्रतिशत की दर से टैक्स वसूला जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो लोग योजना का फायदा लेते हुए काले धन की जानकारी सरकार को नहीं देते हैं और छापेमारी के दौरान छिपा हुआ धन सरेंडर करते हैं तो उन्हें 107.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना होगा। लेकिन, जो लोग छापेमारी में भी काला धन खुद निकाल कर नहीं देते हैं, उन्हें 137.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना पड़ सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बेनामी कानून में दोषियों को 7 साल तक की कैद से दंडित करने का प्रावधान है। इसके अलावा, उस पर आयकर कानून के तहत भी मुकदमा चल सकता है। साथ ही, उस पर बेनामी संपत्ति के उचित बाजार मूल्य का 25 प्रतिशत और दूसरे जुर्माने भी भरने होंगे। गौरतलब है कि सरकार ने नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना की घोषणा की थी। इस योजना के तहत कुल घोषित काले धन का एक चौथाई हिस्सा चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज के सरकार के पास जमा रखने की बाध्यता है। यह योजना पिछले साल 17 दिसंबर को शुरू हुई।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>हर स्कीम के लिए अनिवार्य न हो आधार: SC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-cant-be-mandatory-for-social-welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-cant-be-mandatory-for-social-welfare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने सोमवार को कहा कि सरकार की समाज कल्याण योजनाओं का लाभ उठाने के लिए आधार बायोमीट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन को अनिवार्य नहीं बनाया जा सकता। देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत ने कहा कि सरकार चाहे तो दूसरे क्षेत्रों में आधार को अनिवार्य बना सकती है, जो समाज कल्याण के कार्यक्रमों से नहीं जुड़े हैं। बैंक खाता खोलना ऐसा एक काम हो सकता है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट की जिस बेंच ने यह बात कही, उसमें चीफ जस्टिस जे एस खेहर, जस्टिस डी वाई चंद्रचूड़ और जस्टिस संजय किशन कौल शामिल थे। सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने पहले भी आधार को सभी समाज कल्याण योजनाओं के लिए लाभुकों की पहचान के लिए आधार को अकेला मानक बनाने के खिलाफ आदेश दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चीफ जस्टिस ने कहा कि आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने का मामला महत्वपूर्ण है और इसकी सुनवाई सात जजों की संवैधानिक बेंच के सामने होनी चाहिए, लेकिन उन्होंने तुरंत यह बेंच बनाने में असमर्थता जताई। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह बेंच बनाई जाएगी।&amp;rsquo; अभी सात सदस्यों वाली बेंच के लिए जज ढूंढना मुश्किल हो सकता है। इस महीने के अंत तक तीन जजों की नियुक्ति होने की उम्मीद है। चीफ जस्टिस ने उनके जॉइन करने के बाद अहम मामलों पर विचार करने के लिए संवैधानिक बेंच बनाने का वादा किया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुप्रीम कोर्ट के सोमवार के आदेश का मतलब यह है कि सरकार कल्याणकारी योजनाओं के लाभुकों की पहचान के लिए आधार का इस्तेमाल कर सकती है, लेकिन इसके न होने पर वह लाभ देने से इनकार नहीं कर सकती। सार्वजनिक वितरण प्रणाली या एलपीजी सब्सिडी कल्याणकारी योजना के दायरे में आते हैं। मान लीजिए कि किसी शख्स के पास आधार नंबर नहीं है तो वह इन फायदों को हासिल करने के लिए पहचान के दूसरे सबूतों का इस्तेमाल कर सकता है। देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत पहले भी यह बात कह चुकी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वकील श्याम दीवान ने कई पक्षों की तरफ से आधार बेस्ड आइडेंटिफिकेशन को अनिवार्य बनाने का विरोध किया था। उन्होंने कहा था कि इससे किसी शख्स की प्राइवेसी के लिए खतरा पैदा हो सकता है। इसके बाद सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने मामले पर त्वरित सुनवाई का निर्णय लिया। आधार का इस्तेमाल अभी पेंशन स्कीम के लाभुकों की पहचान, प्रविडेंट फंड और प्रधानमंत्री जन धन योजना के लिए किया जा रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 जुलाई से इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए भी इसे अनिवार्य बनाया गया है। आधार को स्कॉलरशिप स्कीम्स और स्कूलों में मिड डे मील स्कीम्स से भी जोड़ा जा रहा है। श्याम दीवान ने यह आरोप भी लगाया था कि केंद्र सरकार आधार के मामले में देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत के कई आदेशों की अवहेलना कर रही है। इस मामले में उन्होंने ड्राइविंग लाइसेंस के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने जैसे मामलों का जिक्र किया। उन्होंने कहा था कि इस तरह से सरकार अदालत की अवमानना कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto, Health Insurance To Cost More As Regulator Okays Raise For Agents</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Car, motorcycle and health insurance will cost more from April 1 with regulator Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority (IRDAI) giving go-ahead to insurers for revision in commission for agents. The change in premium after modification will be limited to around 5 per cent of the existing rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase will be in addition to the enhanced third party motor insurance rates, which too will come into affect from April. The IRDAI (Payment of Commission or Remuneration or Reward to Insurance Agents and Insurance Intermediaries) Regulations, 2016 comes into effect from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulations, the regulator said, bring about certain revisions in commission/ remuneration rates and also introduce the reward system. These may trigger insurers to revisit the pricing of their products in so far as the costing input relating to commission or remuneration is concerned, said IRDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the change in premium due to the new regulations should be &amp;ldquo;limited to +/- 5 per cent of the existing premium rates of products/add-ons&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, insurers will have to give a certificate that there is &amp;ldquo;no detrimental change&amp;rdquo; in premium rates or any other provision of policies already sold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Prepaid Users Can Get Up To 120GB Extra Data. Here Is How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-prepaid-users-can-get-120gb-extra-data-here-is-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-prepaid-users-can-get-120gb-extra-data-here-is-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier this week, a survey conducted by Bank of America Merrill Lynch said that around 84 per cent of the current Jio members are expected to subscribe for the Prime membership.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime offer, which opened for enrolment on March 1, entitles customers to &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; benefits till March 2018. To sweeten the Prime offer, Jio is offering additional benefits for subscribers who recharge their accounts before March 31, 2017. Those who recharge before March 31, will get up to 10 GB of extra data for one recharge cycle (under different prepaid plans). For example, If subscribers opt for the Rs. 149 prepaid plan (validity 28 days) before March 31, then they will get 1 GB of free data in addition to 2 GB of data originally on offer. Similarly under the Rs. 303 plan, Jio offers 5 GB of free data along with 28 GB of data subscribers are originally entitled for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Jio customer care executive confirmed that a Prime member can lock in the above benefits till March 2018. For example, if a Prime customer recharges his account with the Rs. 499 plan 12 times before March 31, 2017, then he would be entitled to get 120GB of extra data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-prime-650_650x400_41490449016.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

Meanwhile, in the Rs. 999, Rs. 1999, Rs. 4,999 and Rs. 9,999 plans Jio is offering 10 GB of extra data per recharge cycle over and above the data originally on offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rs. 149, Rs. 303 and Rs. 499 plans of Reliance Jio have a validity of 28 days while the Rs. 999 plan offers a validity of 60 days. Meanwhile, the Rs. 1,999 and Rs. 4,999 plans have validity of 90 and 180 days respectively. The Rs. 9,999 plan of Jio comes with a validity of 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio, which started its operations in September 2016, has already crossed the 100 million subscribers mark. Earlier this week, a survey conducted by Bank of America Merrill Lynch said that around 84 per cent of the current Jio members are expected to subscribe for the Prime membership.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even if you have Aadhaar, linking it to PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-aadhaar-linking-pan-easier-said-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-aadhaar-linking-pan-easier-said-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The income tax department then verifies your name, date of birth, gender as per PAN and Aadhaar number with UIDAI. Only if the data matches, it will be linked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merely having an Aadhaar number issued to you by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) does not mean you will be able to link it to your Permanent Account Number (PAN) during filing of income tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department website gives you the option to link the Aadhaar number to the PAN once you login into your personal profile. You are required to provide the Aadhaar number there. The income tax department then verifies your name, date of birth, gender as per PAN and Aadhaar number with UIDAI. Only if the data matches, it will be linked. Similarly, if there is a name change post marriage on one document and not on others, Aadhaar linking will be disallowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officers at the help line of the income tax department said that one can use other agencies like NSDL to file their returns. However, they remained mum when asked about how to rectify issues related to different names once Aadhaar became mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has recently started accepting initials that can be put on the PAN card. However, you will be required to put your full name while applying for a verification of data. For instance, if your official name is M Ramamurthy where the full name is Madurai Ramamurthy where Ramamurthy is the first name, I-T will allow initials only for the first name. Hence, you can either print your name on the PAN card as either Ramamurthy or R Madurai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you try to link PAN to your Aadhaar card which accepts initials, there is bound to be a name mismatch. This will lead to a rejection of request for linking Aadhaar card. In several parts of the country, especially the south of India, the names of villages are often suffixed or prefixed to the name of an individual. Here, any name except the first name of the person is considered as surname and will have to be mentioned in full on the PAN card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax consultants are of the view that where there are different names on different identity proofs, the government will need to either provide them more time or have a separate mechanism to resolve such discrepancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the tax department has a mechanism to rectify names on the PAN card, considering the number of people who will have different names on different documents, meeting the July 1 deadline will be an arduous task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Finance Bill 2017, which was passed by the Lok Sabha, has proposed that Aadhaar will now be compulsory from July 1 to file one’s income tax returns. For retaining your PAN number, too, you need to link this number to your IT account.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2GB Data Per Day For Rs. 339:BSNL&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnls-latest-offer-to-counter-jio-airtel-2gb-data-per-day-for-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnls-latest-offer-to-counter-jio-airtel-2gb-data-per-day-for-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a month, consumer will get 30 GB data and 25 minutes free call per day under the offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) on Tuesday launched a plan that will provide 2GB data per day for Rs. 339 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To compete with Jio and other private players, we have introduced the cheapest plan with a rental value of Rs. 339 per month. Under this plan, the consumer will get 2GB per day,&amp;rdquo; said Sanjiv Tyagi, General Manager, BSNL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a month, the consumer will get 30 GB data and 25 minutes free call per day. After consumption of 25 minutes a levy of 25 paisa per minute will be imposed,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan will be effective from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>