<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10% तक बढ़ सकता है ट्रेनों का किराया</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railway-may-hike-10-percent-passenger-fare-suresh-prabhu-will-take-final-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railway-may-hike-10-percent-passenger-fare-suresh-prabhu-will-take-final-call/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आने वाले दिनों में रेल किराया बढ़ सकता है। इस इजाफे के लिए रेलवे के सामने पांच तरह के प्रस्ताव आए हैं। इन प्रस्तावों में हर महीने एक फीसदी किराया बढ़ाने से लेकर एकमुश्त दस फीसदी किराया बढ़ाने की सिफारिश की गई है। हालांकि, किराया किस फॉर्म्युले पर बढ़ाया जाए, इस पर आखिरी फैसला रेलमंत्री सुरेश प्रभु ही लेंगे। प्रस्तावों में राजधानी, शताब्दी और दुरंतो ट्रेनों में फ्लेक्सी फेयर को खत्म करने या घटाने के लिए भी कहा गया है। रेलवे बोर्ड के एक टॉप अफसर ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;बोर्ड के सामने किराया बढ़ाने से संबंधित पांच प्रस्ताव आए हैं। इसका मकसद है कि रेलवे के यात्री किरायों से होने वाली आमदनी में बढ़ोतरी की जाए। हालांकि अभी इस मामले में फैसला नहीं लिया गया है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. हर महीने 1% किराया बढ़े&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रेलवे सूत्रों का कहना है कि इस बात पर विचार किया जा रहा है कि एकमुश्त किराया बढ़ाने के बजाय यह नियम बना दिया जाए कि हर महीने किराये में एक फीसदी बढ़ोतरी होगी। इससे यात्रियों की जेब पर एक ही झटके में बोझ नहीं बढ़ेगा। साथ ही रेलवे की आलोचना भी नहीं होगी। इसका फायदा यह होगा कि साल भर में किराया बढ़ोतरी लगभग 15 फीसदी तक हो जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. फ्लेक्सी फेयर बंद हो&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक प्रस्ताव फ्लेक्सी फेयर हटाने का भी है। हालांकि रेलवे को इससे सालाना लगभग छह सौ करोड़ का फायदा हो रहा है। लेकिन इस वजह से उसे नाराजगी भी झेलनी पड़ रही है। बोर्ड के सूत्रों का कहना है कि फ्लेक्सी फेयर को पूरी तरह से हटाया या फिर उसे कम किया जा सकता है। यानी दस फीसदी सीटों पर दस फीसदी किराया बढ़ाने की जगह पांच फीसदी बढ़ोतरी की जाए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3. एकमुश्त 10% बढ़े&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तीसरा प्रस्ताव है कि अगर फ्लेक्सी फेयर खत्म किया जाता है तो सभी तरह की ट्रेनों की सभी श्रेणियों में दस फीसदी किराया बढ़ा दिया जाए। रेलवे को अभी यात्री किराये से लगभग 45 हजार करोड़ रुपये की आमदनी होती है। अगर दस फीसदी किराया बढ़ता है तो साढ़े चार हजार करोड़ की अतिरिक्त कमाई होगी। एक प्रस्ताव के मुताबिक, किराया पांच फीसदी तक बढ़ाने की भी सिफारिश की गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;4. सेकंड क्लास अलग&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक प्रस्ताव यह भी है कि सेकंड क्लास के यात्रियों पर बोझ न डाला जाए। पीएम नरेंद्र मोदी लगातार गरीब कल्याण की बात कर रहे हैं। ऐसे में रेलवे नहीं चाहता कि ऐसा नजर आए कि वह गरीबों को नजरंदाज कर रहा है। हालांकि रेलवे में एक राय यह भी है कि सेकंड क्लास में भले ही बेहद कम किराया बढ़ाया जाए लेकिन इसमें भी बढ़ोतरी होनी चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;5. थर्ड एसी को बख्शा जाए&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रेलवे के आंकड़ों को देखें तो उसे थर्ड एसी के अलावा हर क्लास में घाटा होता है। मसलन, एसी चेयरकार में उसका हर पैसेंजर पर खर्च एक रुपये 13 पैसे प्रति किमी. आता है। लेकिन आमदनी एक रुपये चार पैसे ही होती है। वहीं थर्ड एसी में यही खर्च 93 पैसे होता है और आमदनी एक रुपये चार पैसे। इसलिए थर्ड एसी छोड़कर बाकी क्लास से कमाई करने का तरीका निकालने की चर्चा है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs. 333: BSNL&#39;s New Plan To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 333, Rs. 339, Rs. 349 and Rs. 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL or Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited has announced three new data plans priced from Rs 333, the latest offering from the telecom operator seen as aimed at Jio&amp;rsquo;s Dhan Dhana Dhan plans. BSNL is offering up to 270 GB of 3G mobile data along with unlimited voice calls for a period of 90 days. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs 333 includes 3 GB per day of unlimited data, beyond which the speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps, the operator said. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing is causing intense competition in Indian telecom industry, forcing incumbent operators to offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attractive mobile data and unlimited voice calls plans, according to analysts. BSNL has also revised its existing Rs 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of data per day, instead of 2 GB earlier, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s revised Rs 339 pack, valid for 28 days, also includes unlimited local and inter-circle BSNL-to-BSNL calls. Calls to other networks are allowed with a limit of 25 minutes per day, beyond which BSNL customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 349 and Rs 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL had earlier launched yearly packs starting from Rs 1,498 and going up to Rs 4,498, which include 18 GB and 80 GB of data for 365 days, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to media, the senior Congress leader said there was a need to upgrade all post offices in the country with latest infrastructure since there was &amp;ldquo;vast availability of post offices&amp;hellip;one can find it in every nook and corner of the country, even in remote villages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said passports could be applied from post offices shortly, adding around 86 post offices have already started work in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation, including eight MPs, paid obeisance at the sanctum sanctorum of the Golden Temple here. They also visited the historic Jallianwala Bagh, where they paid tributes to the martyrs who had sacrificed their lives for the freedom of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation thereafter visited the Integrated Check Post (ICP) Attari/Wagah border where they held a meeting with the Custom and BSF officials in order to have a &amp;ldquo;first hand information with regard to the required infrastructure at ICP, import/export activities with Pakistan and problems faced by the officials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members also witnessed the evening beating retreat ceremony at Wagah border.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department has launched a massive hunt for black money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The massive hunt for undeclared cash launched across the country post demonetisation has revealed that these was either converted into gold or routed through shell companies to make it legal tender, IT sleuths have told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income Tax officials said black money holders avoided the bank-deposit route because they wanted to conceal their identities and somehow had &amp;ldquo;managed to get many jewellers&amp;rdquo; to convert their unaudited cash into gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They bought gold and jewellery from jewellers across the cities on November 8 (the night Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced the demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 currency notes from midnight) and, thereafter. Jewellers camouflaged the identities of the actual buyers and offered split bills,&amp;rdquo; an Income Tax official, who was part of the investigations, told IANS on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to him, jewellers saw in demonetisation an opportunity to ramp up their sales and thought &amp;ldquo;they could get away&amp;rdquo; by showing these amounts as sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jewellers offered a platform to convert unreported cash into gold,&amp;rdquo; the official said, adding that split bills were below the value of Rs 2 lakh, the threshold above which buyers have to provide the permanent account number (PAN) issued by the income tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The buyers&amp;rsquo; lists provided by the jewellers were false. After verification, it emerged that many of the buyers were financially weak and not in a position to spend such huge amounts shown in the invoices,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen tried to find an answer to a common question: How did jewellers meet the huge spurt in demand following the announcement of demonetisation, particularly after the festival season?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We found many of these sales were booked as advance collection for future sales. Due to preceding sales during Dhanteras and Diwali, jewellers had a stock crunch and they delivered gold later,&amp;rdquo; another IT official told IANS, asking not to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen said they have stumbled upon records which suggested many shops &amp;ndash; as many as 90 per cent across cities &amp;ndash; were closed at the time of the demonetisation announcement and sales at the day&amp;rsquo;s closing had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Still, we found sales were registered in the accounting system either on November 8 or a date prior to that after the closing sales were reported. These sales were manipulated,&amp;rdquo; another IT official said, also requesting anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sankar Sen, Chairman and MD, Senco Gold Ltd, which was one of the jewellery houses under the I-T department scanner, told IANS: &amp;ldquo;We keep records of all buyers on the basis of the names and contacts provided by the customers. We cooperated with officials and provided all the documents, including the CCTV footage that we had.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is difficult for jewellers to verify whether the customers have provided a legitimate identity or not, particularly when the sale value is less than Rs 2 lakh,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hunt for black money by the IT officials picked up after November 29 as they waited for some time to collect information from the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) or other agencies about the movement of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked how taxmen identified jewellers, an official told IANS: &amp;ldquo;The first set of information showed that jewellers deposited huge amounts of money into banks. Then, we went after jewellers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IT sleuths were able to identify legitimate transactions, easily. &amp;ldquo;We also had given options to the jewellers to disclose the name of actual buyers or declare that the amount is your money,&amp;rdquo; the official said, pointing out that such moves proved successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many actual buyers and jewellers contributed to the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY), an amnesty scheme to declare unreported wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a robust and quick information-sharing system among state and central agencies been in place, the hunt for black money would have been more effective, the officials lamented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A compilation of unique features found in transactions post-demonetisation across states is expected soon,&amp;rdquo; an IT official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Union Finance Ministry, the CBDT has detected undisclosed income of over Rs 9,334 crore between November 9, 2016, and February 28 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under Operation Clean Money (OCM), more than 60,000 persons, including 1,300 high-risk persons, have been identified for investigation into claims of excessive cash sales after demonetisation was announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to officials, shell companies provided a strong support system for black money after demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials found dummy directors of these companies included a cancer patient who signed documents for a Rs 10,000 monthly fee or charges of Rs 200 for every signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials said reporting of cash seizures was relatively less in Kolkata because of the existence of the shell companies as an established channel to stash ill-gotten money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining how active the channel was, the official said: &amp;ldquo;Many cash handlers with whom we interacted told us that the money does not stay for more than half-an-hour at a particular point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shell companies were also used as instruments to buy bullion. &amp;ldquo;We found invoices for bullion sales were generated against such companies while actual beneficiaries received the bullion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Reliance-Jio-VoLTE-feature-phone.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen. It also has a dedicated button for torchlight. Maker of this feature phone is not known yet. Currently we don’t have any specifications of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to recent reports, Jio will launch these VoLTE-enabled feature phones starting at Rs. 999 that will run on Android operating system. Earlier reports said that capability to make VoLTE calls in these feature phones will be enabled by Spreadtrum chips, and Jio is in talks with Qualcomm and MediaTek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Jio plans start as low as Rs. 149 per month offering unlimited calls, this will be useful for those who make a lot of calls and need a cheap phone with a keypad. We should know more details about more upcoming VoLTE-enabled feature phones from Jio soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Savings Account Minimum Balance Requirement. Read Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. The minimum balance requirement for SBI customers varies depending on geographies such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural. If the minimum balance drops below a particular threshold, SBI will charge a fee from the account holder. SBI says the minimum balance in your savings bank account is the monthly average balance - the average of daily balances in the account during the month. SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holders of SBI&amp;rsquo;s savings bank account in urban areas need to maintain a monthly average balance (MAB) of Rs 3,000, Rs 2,000 in case of those in semi-urban areas and Rs 1,000 in rural areas. This was said on Thursday by SBI - which recently merged its operations with six other banks - on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting 31 crore depositors, SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For metropolitan areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Under 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For rural areas, the penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance ranges from Rs 20 to Rs 50 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI offers other types of accounts where it customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. Small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products offered SBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1. After the merger, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आयकर विभाग करेगा 60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों की जांच</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-operation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; के दूसरे चरण में आयकर विभाग 60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों की जांच करेगा। शुक्रवार को दोबारा लॉन्च हुए इस ऑपरेशन का मकसद नोटबंदी के बाद पैदा हुए ब्लैक मनी का पता लगाना है। विभाग ने इससे पहले ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के पहले चरण में नोटबंदी के दौरान संदिग्ध लेन-देन करने वाले 18 लाख लोगों को नोटिस भेजा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग की नीति निर्माता ईकाइ केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (CBDT) का कहना है कि वह पिछले साल 9 नवंबर से इस साल की 28 फरवरी तक 9,332 करोड़ रुपए की अघोषित आय का पता लगा चुका है। बता दें कि 8 नवंबर को पीएम मोदी ने 500 और 1000 के नोटबंदी की घोषणा की थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों (जिसमें 1300 हाइ रिस्क लोग भी शामिल हैं) की जांच में पहचान हो चुकी है। नोटबंदी के दौरान अधिकतर बड़े लेन-देन कैश में करने वाले लोग नजर में थे। हाइ वैल्यू प्रॉपर्टी खरीद के 6000 मामले और विदेश के शेयर बाजार में पैसा लगाने या विदेश पैसा भेजने के 6,600 मामलों में बारीकी से जांच-पड़ताल होगी। अगर जवाब संतोषजनक नहीं माना गया तो विस्तृत पूछताछ की जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ITR में देनी होगी नोटबंदी के दौरान जमा रकम की जानकारी!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने बताया कि आधुनिक डेटा विश्लेषण का इस्तेमाल करते हुए संदिग्ध कैश डिपॉजिट का पता लगाया है। इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने इस साल 31 जनवरी को &amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; लॉन्च किया गया था। जिसके तहत 17.92 लाख लोगों को ऑनलाइन नोटिस भेजा गया था जिसमें से 9.46 लाख लोगों ने विभाग के प्रश्नों का जवाब दिया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>नोटबंदी के बाद सोने और फर्जी कंपनियों में खपाई गई थी ब्लैक मनी: IT सूत्र</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/black-money-converted-into-gold-stored-in-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/black-money-converted-into-gold-stored-in-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी के बाद ब्लैक मनी से बड़े पैमाने पर सोने की खरीदारी की गई थी या फिर इन अज्ञात पैसों को फर्जी कंपनियां बनाकर उसमें खपाया गया था। नोटबंदी के बाद देशभर में पड़े छापों के दौरान यह जानकारी सामने आई थी। आयकर विभाग के सूत्रों ने बताया कि ब्लैक मनी रखने वाले लोगों ने ये पैसे बैंकों में डिपॉजिट नहीं किए क्योंकि वे अपनी पहचान गुप्त रखना चाहते थे। नोटबंदी के दौरान कई जूलर्स ने लोगों की ब्लैक मनी को सोने में बदल दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जांच में शामिल रहे एक अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo; पिछले साल 8 नवंबर को पीएम नरेंद्र मोदी की नोटबंदी की घोषणा के बाद लोगों ने अपनी ब्लैक मनी को सोने और जूलरी खरीदने में लगा दी। जूलर्स ने इसके बाद अलग-अलग बिल देकर लोगों की असली पहचान छिपा ली।&amp;rsquo; बता दें कि 8 नवंबर को ही पीएम मोदी ने 500 और 1000 रुपये के नोट को चलन से बाहर करने की घोषणा की थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सूत्र ने बताया कि नोटबंदी को जूलर्स ने अपनी बिक्री बढ़ाने का जरिया माना और वे ऐसे पैसों को गहनों की बिक्री दिखाकर बच गए। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जूलर्स ने अज्ञात आय को सोने में बदलने का प्लैटफ़ॉर्म उपलब्ध कराया।&amp;rsquo; जो बिल दिए गए वो अलग-अलग थे और दो लाख रुपये से कम के थे। इसके अलावा खरीदारों की सूची भी फर्जी थी। जांच के बाद पता चला कि कई खरीदार तो वित्तीय तौर पर काफी कमजोर थे और वे बिल में दिखाई गई राशि इतना पैसा खर्च करने की स्थिति में ही नहीं थे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने जूलर्स से सवाल पूछा था कि कैसे नोटबंदी के बाद उनके पास इतनी मांग बढ़ी, खासतौर पर त्योहारी सीजन बीत जाने के बाद। आयकर रेडार के निशाने पर आए सेंको गोल्ड लिमिटेड के चेयरमैन शंकर सेन ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;हमने सभी खरीदारों द्वारा दिए गए नाम और कॉन्टैक्टस के आधार पर सारा रेकॉर्ड रखा है। हम इस मामले में विभाग की जांच में मदद कर रहे हैं और उन्हें सभी दस्तावेज मुहैया करा रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जूलर्स के लिए यह जांच पाना काफी मुश्किल है कि खरीदार ने सही जानकारी दी है या नहीं। खासकर तब जब खरीदारी दो लाख रुपये से कम की हो। गौरतलब है कि आयकर विभाग ने 29 नवंबर के बाद ब्लैक मनी वालों के खिलाफ जांच तेज कर दी थी। दरअसल इस समय तक विभाग सीबीडीटी और अन्य एजेंसियों से पैसों के मूवमेंट पर सूचनाएं एकत्र कर रहा था।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पीएम नरेंद्र मोदी ने बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी के खिलाफ ऐक्शन तेज करने का दिया आदेश</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/prime-minister-narendra-modi-orders-speedy-action-against-unaccounted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/prime-minister-narendra-modi-orders-speedy-action-against-unaccounted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;काले धन पर अंकुश के लिए नोटबंदी जैसा कड़ा कदम उठाने के बाद केंद्र की नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार के निशाने पर अब बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी है। प्रधानमंत्री मोदी ने राजस्व अधिकारियों के साथ समीक्षा बैठक में ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के बारे में जानकारी ली। सूत्रों के मुताबिक पीएम मोदी ने बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी पर ऐक्शन का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैठक में पीएम मोदी ने वित्त मंत्रालय के अधिकारियों से बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी रखने वालों के खिलाफ कार्रवाई तेज करने को कहा। सरकारी सूत्रों के मुताबिक पीएम ने कहा कि ई-असेस्मन्ट जल्द से जल्द लागू होना चाहिए ताकि न्यूनतम हस्तक्षेप हो। असेस्मन्ट कम्प्यूटराइज्ड होना चाहिए। पीएम ने यह भी कहा कि टैक्स के दायरे में और लोग आएं ताकि कर का आधार बढ़ाया जा सके।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने सोमवार को वित्त मंत्रालय द्वारा वस्तु और सेवा कर (जीएसटी) को लागू करने को लेकर की गई तैयारियों और नोटबंदी के बाद कालेधन के खिलाफ अभियान की समीक्षा की। सूत्रों ने बताया कि राजस्व विभाग के साथ बैठक में मोदी ने जीएसटी को लेकर तैयारियों का जायजा लिया। सूत्रों ने कहा कि इस समीक्षा बैठक में वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली, राजस्व सचिव हसमुख अधिया और राजस्व विभाग के अन्य वरिष्ठ अधिकारी मौजूद थे।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1,500 रुपये का 4G फीचर फोन जल्द बन सकता है हकीकत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4G फीचर फोन या बेसिक मोबाइल फोन, जिसकी कीमत 1,500 रुपये हो, जल्द ही हकीकत बन सकता है। चाइनीज मोबाइल चिप मेकर स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस ने कहा है कि वह मौजूदा लेवल्स से शुरुआती कीमत कम से कम आधा करने पर काम कर रही है। एक डिवेलपमेंट एक्सपर्ट ने कहा कि यह कई कन्ज्यूमर को स्मार्टफोन की ओर शिफ्टिंग से रोक सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस के कंट्री हेड नीरज शर्मा ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, ‘हम एक ऐसी टेक्नॉलजी पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो कि 1,500 रुपये के 4G फीचर फोन को व्यावहारिक बनाती है। हमने अपने पार्टनर्स के लिए कॉन्सेप्ट प्रमोशन पहले ही शुरू कर दिया है।’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लावा और माइक्रोमैक्स जैसी घरेलू मोबाइल फोन कंपनियों के 4G फीचर फोन की कीमतें करीब 3,000 रुपये से शुरू होती हैं। कॉर्बन के अलावा, यह दोनों हैंडसेट मेकर कंपनियां आगे ऐसे फोन की कीमतें घटाना चाहती हैं। इस मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले इंडस्ट्री एग्जिक्यूटिव्स के मुताबिक, रिलायंस जियो इंफोकॉम भी अपनी सहयोगी रिटेल फर्म के जरिए किफायती 4G VoLTE फीचर फोन लाने की योजना बना रही है, इस फोन की कीमत 1,500 रुपये से कम हो सकती है। शंघाई बेस्ड स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस बेसबैंड चिप सेगमेंट में सधी ग्रोथ हासिल कर रही है और यह मीडियाटेक, क्वॉलकॉम जैसे मोबाइल चिप मेकर्स के साथ मुकाबला कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चिपसेट, किसी भी मोबाइल हैंडसेट का एक अहम हिस्सा है और डिवाइस की कीमत में इसकी बड़ी हिस्सेदारी होती है। स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस की रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज के साथ दो साल पुरानी पार्टनरशिप है और इसने RIL के अफोर्डेबल LYF फ्लेम 5 स्मार्टफोन को तैयार किया है। कंपनी ने लावा M1 4G फीचर फोन को भी पावर्ड किया है, जिसकी कीमत 3,599 रुपये है। कंपनी का कहना है कि उसे टेक्नॉलजी ईजाद करने और डिवाइसेज को मार्केट तक पहुंचाने में करीब छह महीने लगते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फाइनेंशल सर्विसेज फर्म जेपी मॉर्गन ने अपनी एक हालिया रिपोर्ट में कहा है कि 2017 में 4G कैपेबिलिटी वाले फीचर फोन पॉपुलर होंगे। इन्हें उम्मीद से कहीं ज्यादा तेजी से आने वाले 4G नेटवर्क से मजबूती मिलेगी। शर्मा ने कहा कि यह देखना काफी रोचक होगा कि ऐसे समय में जबकि मार्केट का झुकाव डेटा प्ले की तरफ है और वॉयस सेगमेंट स्थिर हो गया है, तब ऑपरेटर्स अपनी स्ट्रैटिजी को कैसे पुख्ता बनाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, ‘पिछले छह महीने में मार्केट पूरी तरह से 3G से 4G में शिफ्ट हो गया है और दमदार टेक्नॉलजी के बीच वेंडर्स को अपनी मार्केट स्ट्रैटेजी को दुरुस्त करना होगा।’ उन्होंने कहा कि अडिशनल वैल्यू ऑफर करने वाले LTE फीचर फोन को और आकर्षक तरीके में पैक्ड किया जाना चाहिए। साथ ही उन्हें बढ़ते डेटा मार्केट के हिसाब से टियर-III लोकेशंस और रूरल एरिया में बेचा जाना चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper published under Creative Commons is titled ‘Information Security Practices of Aadhaar (or lack thereof): A documentation of public availability of Aadhaar Numbers with sensitive personal financial information’ and was released on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha and Kodali looked at databases on four government portals — National Social Assistance Programme, National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme, Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh and Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We chose major government programmes that use Aadhaar for payments and banking transactions. We found sensitive and personal data and information accessible on these portals,” the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaked through portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Based on the numbers available on the websites, estimated number of Aadhaar numbers leaked through these 4 portals could be around 130-135 million and the number of bank account numbers leaked at around 100 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these numbers are only from two major government programmes of pensions and rural employment schemes, other major schemes, that have also used Aadhaar for DBT, could have leaked PII similarly due to lack of information security practices,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They fear that data of over 23 crore beneficiaries under DBT of LPG subsidies could be leaked also. Identity theft and financial fraud “risks increase multifold in India…,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar payments unsafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case a financial fraud takes place through Aadhaar enabled Payment System (AePS), the consumer may not be able to assert his claims for compensation due to the terms and conditions around liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These terms force the consumer to take liabilities onto oneself than the payment provider….. Regulations and standards around Aadhaar are at a very early and nascent stage causing (an) increase in financial risk for both consumers and banks to venture into AePS,” they added. The authors also pulled up UIDAI for their inability in providing strong legislation against such leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaky govt portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Social Assistance Programme&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII available – Access to Aadhaar no., name, bank account number, account frozen status  94,32,605&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bank accounts linked with Aadhaar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14,98,919  post office accounts linked with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though total Aadhaar number is 1,56,42,083, not all are linked to bank accounts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NREGA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII Details available: Job card no., Aadhaar number, bank/postal account number, no. of days worked, registration no., account frozen status&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;78,74,315  post office accounts of individual workers seeded with Aadhaar numbers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8,24,22,161 bank accounts of individual workers with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10,96,41,502 total number of Aadhaar numbers stored by portal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other websites&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2500 रुपये में हवाई सफर को हरी झंडी, जानें- इसकी 10 बड़ी बातें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने हिमाचल प्रदेश में सस्ती उड़ान की शुरुआत की. शिमला से दिल्ली के बीच की पहली उड़ान फ्लाइट को हरी झंडी दिखाने के अलावा पीएम मोदी ने दो और फ्लाइट्स को हरी झंडी दिखाई. इस अवसर पर मोदी ने कहा कि पहले एयरलाइंस में राजा महाराजा ही सफर करते थे. देश का गरीब हवाई चप्पल पहनता है, मैं चाहता था कि हवाई चप्पल वाला व्यक्ति हवाई जहाज में बैठे. आज वो बात सच हो रही है. मोदी ने कहा कि भारत में हवाई सेवा के विस्तार के लिए काफी अवसर है. उन्होंने कहा कि हवाई सर्कुलर रुट बनेगा तो ही सभी यात्री इसका लाभ उठा सकेंगे.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;उड़ान स्कीम की 10 बड़ी बातें-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत हवाई यात्रा के लिए 500 किलोमीटर या 1 घंटे के सफर की कीमत ज्यादा से ज्यादा 2,500 रुपया रखी गई है. इसी आधार पर अन्य रुटों का भी किराया निर्धारित किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 128 रूट्स और 5 ऑपरेटरों को उड़ान स्कीम में शामिल किया है. एयर इंडिया की क्षेत्रीय इकाई अलायंस एयर के तहत इन फ्लाइट्स को ऑपरेट किया जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 45 ऐसे एयरपोर्ट्स जो सेवा में नहीं हैं, उन्हें एयर नेटवर्क में कनेक्ट किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;छोटे शहर टियर-2 और टियर-3 के 13 एयरपोर्ट्स, जहां ज्यादा फ्लाइट्स नहीं चलती थीं वहां अब अधिक फ्लाइट्स होंगी. इन शहरों के लोगों को उड़ान स्कीम का फायदा मिल सकें.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान के तहत 5 ऑपरेटर्स का चयन हुआ है जो एयर इंडिया की सब्सिडियरी अलाइड सर्विसेज, स्पाइसजेट, एयर डेक्कन, एयर ओडिशा, टर्बो मेघा हैं.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;कानपुर से दिल्ली के लिए स्पाइसेजट की सेवा अगस्त में शुरू होगी, जबकि कानपुर से वाराणसी और दिल्ली के बीच सितम्बर में एयर ओडिशा के विमान उड़ान भरेंगे.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;अलायंस एय़र आगरा से जयपुर की उड़ान जून में शुरू करेगी, जबकि अगस्त में एय़र डेक्कन ने आगरा और दिल्ली के बीच उड़ान सेवा शुरु करने की तैयारी कर रखी है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;दिल्ली से शिमला के बीच अलायंस एय़र और एयर डेक्कन, दोनों ने ही अगले महीने सेवा शुरु करने का लक्ष्य रखा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;मध्य प्रदेश-छत्तीसगढ़ में अंबिकापुर से विलासपुर और बिलासपुर से रायपुर के बीच सितम्बर में एय़र ओडिशा अपनी सेवा शुरू करेगी. सितम्बर में ही जगदलपुर से रायपुर और विशाखापत्तनम के बीच सेवाएं शुरू हो जाएंगी.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 जून 2016 को शुरु हुई नैशनल सिविल एविएशन पॉलिसी का उड़ान अहम हिस्सा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>