<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4GB Data Per Day For Rs 444</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</guid>
      <description>State-run telecom firm BSNL today increased per day data offering to 4GB at 3G speeds under a new prepaid mobile scheme priced at Rs 444 with 90 days validity.
&amp;ldquo;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) has introduced &amp;lsquo;BSNL Chaukka - 444&amp;rsquo;, a new STV, for truly unlimited data for 90 days as special promotional offer under prepaid mobile services,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.
This is the highest per day data limit being offered by any telecom operator in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange old notes for new at a premium</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</guid>
      <description>Scrapped old notes ­ Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 ­ which were to be exchanged latest by December 20, 2016, are still there. They can be exchanged even now, but for a hefty premium.
Non-Resident Indians (NRIs), who were allowed to exchange old notes till June 30 this year, are being offered a handsome commission for exchanging these notes.
&amp;ldquo;The going rate for exchanging old notes is Rs 9 on every Rs 100, so if you want to exchange Rs 1 crore in old notes, then you would get back Rs 9 lakh in new notes,&amp;rdquo; said Pravin (name changed), who is involved in this trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation To Launch RuPay Credit Card Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India has forayed in to the credit card business and would make the commercial launch of its RuPay credit card &amp;ldquo;in a month&amp;rsquo;s time,&amp;rdquo; a top official said today.
&amp;ldquo;Maybe in a month&amp;rsquo;s time we will be able to make the commercial launch (of RuPay credit card),&amp;rdquo; NPCI Chairman M Balachandran told reporters here.
NPCI, which currently offers RuPay debit cards, has partnered with 10 banks including public sector and cooperative banks, to make the pilot launch of the &amp;ldquo;RuPay Credit Card&amp;rdquo;, Balachandran said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PM insurance schemes on June 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</guid>
      <description>Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY) were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner.
You must have heard about the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY), which were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?
SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.
 Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.
HIGHLIGHTS  The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions  India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI Launches Three New Mobile Apps For Voice, Data Quality Tracking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</guid>
      <description>TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring.
Aiming to protect consumer interests, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Monday launched three new mobile applications and a web portal.
TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring. The app will help mobile phone users rate their experience about voice call quality in real time and help TRAI gather customer experience data along with network data, an official TRAI statement said here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.
To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-Aadhaar as ID proof in Railways</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</guid>
      <description>After receiving several requests from passengers, Railway has agreed to accept e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class. Earlier only printed version was considered as a valid ID.
According to railway ministry, the issue regarding acceptance of e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class was being raised at various foras.
Accordingly, the matter was examined in consultation with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</guid>
      <description>Both Apps uses Unified Payments Interface (UPI) technology to transfer money between any two individuals and between an individual and a merchant.
Navneet Dubey Moneycontrol News
Are you considering using one of the mobile payment apps launched by the government recently? If so, you may be confused on whether you should use the Aadhaar Payment App or Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM)?
Well, there are specific features of each of these apps which differentiate them which you should be aware of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जल्द ही रुपे क्रेडिट कार्ड जारी करेगा नैशनल पेमेंट्स कॉर्पोरेशन</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit/</guid>
      <description>नैशनल पेमेंट्स कॉर्पोरेशन ऑफ इंडिया क्रेडिट ने कार्ड बिजनस में भी कदम रख दिया है और &amp;lsquo;एक महीने में&amp;rsquo; अपने रुपे क्रेडिट कार्ड की कमर्शल लॉन्चिंग भी कर देगा। इस बात की जानकारी एक टॉप अधिकारी ने दी। एनपीसीआई के चेयरमेन एम बालचंद्रन ने रिपोर्टरों को बताया, &amp;lsquo;शायद एक महीने में हम (रुपे क्रेडिट कार्ड की) कर्मशल लॉन्चिंग कर दें।&amp;rsquo;
बालचंद्रन ने कहा कि एनपीसीआई अभी रुपे डेबिट कार्ड्स ऑफर कर रहा है और इसने &amp;lsquo;रुपे क्रेडिट कार्ड&amp;rsquo; की पायलट लॉन्चिंग के लिए 10 सरकारी और कोऑपरेटिव बैंकों से हाथ मिलाया है। एनपीसीआई ने अप्रैल 2012 में रुपे डेबिट कार्ड लॉन्च किया था।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जीएसटी से पहले ऑफर्स की बहार, देखें- कैसे-कैसे ऑफर्स दे रहे हैं कौन-कौन से ब्रैंड्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/the-complete-list-of-best-deals-on-offer-right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/the-complete-list-of-best-deals-on-offer-right-now/</guid>
      <description>अगर आप कार, कपड़े या इलेक्ट्रॉनिक सामान खरीदनेवाले हैं तो 1 जुलाई से पहले तक सुनहरा मौका है। खुदरा दुकानदार और डीलर जीएसटी लागू होने से पहले गोदामों में पड़े माल को तेजी से हटाने की जुगत में हैं, इसलिए वो बंपर ऑफर्स दे रहे हैं। टीवी सेट, रेफ्रिजरेटर, एयर कंडीशनर और वॉशिंग मशीनों के दामों में अच्छी-खासी कटौती की गई है। ध्यान रहे कि आम दिनों में इन सामानों की एमआरपी पर 10 से 15 प्रतिशत छूट ही ऑफर की जाती है। सैमसंग, पैनसॉनिक, हिताची और विडियोकॉन, एलजी इंडिया जैसे ब्रैंड्स कुछ-न-कुछ ऑफर जरूर दे रहे हैं।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भारत के हाइटेक टैलंट को नजरअंदाज कर चीन ने की गलती: चीनी मीडिया</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/china-made-mistake-of-ignoring-indias-high-tech-talent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/china-made-mistake-of-ignoring-indias-high-tech-talent/</guid>
      <description>चीन ने भारत के विज्ञान एवं तकनीकी एक्सपर्ट्स को नजरअंदाज कर गलती की है। यह बात किसी भारतीय नेता या कारोबारी ने नहीं कही है, बल्कि खुद चीन मीडिया ने कही है। चीन के सरकारी अखबार ग्लोबल टाइम्स ने लिखा है कि कम्युनिस्ट देश को भारत के हाइटेक टैलंट को अपनी ओर आकर्षित करना चाहिए ताकि वह आविष्कारों के मामले में अपनी क्षमता को बरकरार रख सके। ग्लोबल टाइम्स में लिखे लेख के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;चीन ने भारतीय टैलंट को नजरअंदाज कर गलती की है। इसकी बजाय हम अमेरिका और यूरोप से आने वाले टैलंट पर निर्भर रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>मारुति से जुड़ी इन 5 खास बातों से आप शायद ही वाकिफ हों</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/five-facts-will-give-you-a-new-insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/five-facts-will-give-you-a-new-insight/</guid>
      <description>एक मारुति कार को बनाने में कर्मचारी लगभग 2,545 स्टेप पूरे करते हैं। वहीं प्लांट की पेंट और बेल्डिंग शॉप पूरी तरह से ऑटोमैटिक होती है।
मारुति सुजुकी देशभर में न सिर्फ अपनी सस्ती, लो मेन्टेनेंस और टिकाऊ गाड़यां बनाने के लिए मशहूर है बल्कि कि देश के टॉप कार मैन्युफैक्चरर्स में से एक है। रिपोर्ट्स के मुताबिक देश में लगभग हर दूसरी बिकने वाली कार मारुति की होती है। मगर मारुति से जुड़ी कई ऐसी खास बाते हैं जिनसे आप पहले शायद ही वाकिफ हों। बिजनेस स्टैडर्ड की एक खबर के मुताबिक ये बातें मारुति मैन्युफैक्चरिंग यूनिट् को अपने आप में खास बनाती है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>वोडाफोन लाया पांच रुपए का र‍िचार्ज</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-ramzan-special-pack-at-rs-5-unlimited-data-and-voice-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-ramzan-special-pack-at-rs-5-unlimited-data-and-voice-calling/</guid>
      <description>इस स्कीम को लॉन्च करते हुए पश्चिम उत्तर प्रदेश और उत्तराखंड के कारोबार प्रमुख दिलीप कुमार गंटा ने कहा कि रमजान का महीना हमारे लिए बहुत ही अहम है।
दूरसंचार कंपनी वोडाफोन ने रमजान के मौके पर पश्चिमी उत्तर प्रदेश और उत्तराखंड के उपभोक्ताओं के लिए स्पेशल स्कीम लॉन्च की है। स्कीम के तहत उपभोक्ता अनलिमिटेड लोकल और एसटीडी कॉल के साथ मुफ्त डेटा का भी लाभ उठा पाएंगे। रमजान स्पेशल पैक में 2जी उपभोक्ता पांच रुपये का रिचार्ज कराकर एक घंटे के लिए अनलिमिटेड डेटा का लाभ उठा सकते हैं, जबकि 3जी उपभोक्ता 19 रुपये का रिचार्ज कराकर एक घंटे के लिए अनलिमिटेड डेटा का इस्तेमाल कर सकते हैं।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar based lic policies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-launches-two-aadhaar-based-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-launches-two-aadhaar-based-policies/</guid>
      <description>Life insurance behemoth LIC has introduced two endowment assurance plans for individuals having Aadhaar card.
While the _Aadhaar Shila _is a plan exclusively designed for women, the other scheme Aadhaar Stambh is meant for men. Absolute amount assured on death under Aadhaar Stambh is 100%, whereas for Aadhaar Shila it is 110% of basic sum assured.
These plans offer a combination of protection and savings and provide a lump-sum amount at the time of maturity for the surviving policyholder and financial support for the family in case of death of the policyholder, a Corporation statement said today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.
SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Allows Co-Operative Banks To Deposit Old Notes With RBI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</guid>
      <description>The relaxation comes against the backdrop of reports that many district co-operative banks did not have enough cash to disburse to farmers.
The Finance Ministry on Tuesday allowed banks, post offices and district central cooperative banks to deposit the scrapped Rs 500 and 1,000 rupee notes with the Reserve Bank of India within 30 days and exchange the value of notes deposit with the new notes.
In an official notification the Finance Ministry said, &amp;ldquo;Specified bank notes may be deposited by such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, in any office of the Reserve Bank, within a period of 30 days from the commencement of these rules, and get the exchange value thereof by credit to the account of such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, subject to the satisfaction of the Reserve Bank of the conditions specified in the said notification and the reasons for non-deposit of the specified bank notes within the period under that notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GST will impact your household budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</guid>
      <description>Goods and services tax (GST) comes into effect from 1 July. ET Wealth analyses the impact on some basic expenses in the household consumption basket.
AUTOMOBILES The price difference will be bigger for SUVs (55% to 43%) compared to small cars (30% to 29%).
Base price : Rs 4.75 lakh
Total taxes now* : Rs 1.43 lakh
Under GST : Rs 1.38 lakh
DURABLES : Refrigerators and washing machines For most white goods, there won&amp;rsquo;t be much difference in price as new rates will be close to earlier ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.
The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either 567678 or 56161.
It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Aadhaar With PAN Made Mandatory: How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>As the government insists that one&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar account and Permanent Account Number (PAN) should be linked by July 31 this year to pay income taxes, millions of Indians have faced issues with syncing the two accounts due to small differences in how their names are spelt. This problem can happen even if there are minor differences in how the name is recorded &amp;ndash; like the use of one&amp;rsquo;s full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking your Aadhaar number with your bank account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-number-bank-account-heres-can-online-sms-atm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-number-bank-account-heres-can-online-sms-atm/</guid>
      <description>The government is gradually making Aadhaar card compulsory for financial transactions and several other procedures such as filing income tax returns and availing government schemes and benefits.
The government recently made Aadhaar mandatory for opening bank accounts as well as for any financial transaction of Rs 50,000 and above. It has asked the existing bank account holders to link their Aadhaar number issued by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) by December 31, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine online jobs that you can do from home</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Whether you’re looking for a respite from your 9 to 5, are unable to commute to work, are a stay at-home parent, or have some other constraint that prevents you from finding a full-time job, there’s no need to waste your earning potential.
There are plenty of opportunities available online that let you work from home. Here are a few options you can consider.
 Virtual assistantship  Entrepreneurs, professionals and small teams often need assistance with various administrative tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Announces Mega Auction Of Properties</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</guid>
      <description>The bank will auction off 150 properties,including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country.
State Bank of India (SBI) has a nnounced a sale of properties through a mega e-auction on June 23, 2017. This was said by the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank on microblogging site Twitter. The bank will auction off 150 properties, including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country, SBI said on its website. These properties were pledged as collateral for housing and business loans and were taken over by the bank under the Security and Reconstruction of Financial Assets and Enforcement of Security Interest (Sarfaesi) Act due to non-payment of pending dues by the borrowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammers are trying to get your Aadhaar details via calls, emails</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</guid>
      <description>Watch out! The scammers are out with a new set of tricks to swindle the gullible public. Curiously, the Centre’s directive to link the bank accounts with Aadhaar has apparently made these fraudsters more brazen. Their latest modus operandi is to seek details of the Aadhaar card from unsuspecting victims through phone calls and emails.
Posing as bank executives or tele-callers, they call up potential victims saying, “The bank has decided to link your Aadhaar number with debit card for better customer service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win Rupay Select Credit Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>IDBI Bank announced the launch of ‘Winnings’ Rupay Select Credit Card that offers a range of travel, shopping and dining privileges and also enables earning of rewards points on every spend. The credit card has been launched in association with National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI). This product is similar to the international credit cards offered by VISA and MasterCard.
The ‘Winnings’ RuPay Select Credit Card is a premium credit card variant and is at par with the premium Card variants of International Card networks which is Visa Signature and MasterCard World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब महज 6 रुपए में एक घंटे के लिए अनलिमिटेड 4G डेटा दे रहा है</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-supernight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-supernight/</guid>
      <description>वोडाफोन ने अपने प्रीपेड कन्ज्यूमर्स के लिए नया ऑफर का ऐलान किया है। &amp;lsquo;सुपरनाइट 29&amp;rsquo; ऑफर के तहत वोडाफोन अब रात के 5 घंटों तक अनलिमिटेड 3G/4G डेटा देगा। लोग रात 1 बजे से सुबह 6 बजे के बीच इस ऑफर का फायदा उठा सकेंगे। गौरतलब है कि रिलायंस जियो के डेटा पैक के मुताबिक 1GB डेटा 10 रुपये का पड़ता है। ऐसे में अगर वोडाफोन के ग्राहक रात में हर घंटे 1GB डेटा भी यूज करें तो उन्हें जियो के मुकाबले सस्ता डेटा मिलेगा।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमें ने पैन से आधार को लिंक करने के लिए शुरू की SMS सुविधा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms-i-t-dept/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms-i-t-dept/</guid>
      <description>आयकर विभाग ने करदाताओं को एसएमएस सुविधा का उपयोग कर आधार संख्या को पैन नंबर से जोड़ने को कहा है। देश के प्रमुख समाचार पत्रों में दिए गए विज्ञापनों में विभाग ने एसएमएस के जरिए आधार और पैन को आपस में लिंक करने की जानकारी दी है। इसके लिए किसी व्यक्ति को अपने फोन से बड़े अक्षरों में यूआईडीपीएएन के बाद खाली जगह छोड़कर अपनी आधार संख्या और फिर उसके बाद अपनी पैन संख्या को लिखकर 567678 या 56161 को एसएमएस भेजना होगा। इसके अलावा विभाग की ई-फाइलिंग वेबसाइट पर जाकर भी इनको आपस में लिंक किया जा सकता है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>खातों की कम जानकारी देने वाले करदाता जांच के दायरे में</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/savings-and-investments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/savings-and-investments/</guid>
      <description>अगर आपके कार इंश्योरेंस का प्रीमियम 10000 रुपये है और आपकी बीमा कंपनी कहे कि 10 साल बाद वह पूरा प्रीमियम लौटा देगी तो क्या इस शर्त पर आप 45000 रुपये चुकाने को राजी होंगे? यह बात बेतुकी लग सकती है, लेकिन यही दलील उन टर्म इंश्योरेंस प्लांस को रफ्तार दे रही हैं, जो बायर को प्रीमियम लौटाने का वादा करते हैं। प्रीमियम लौटाने वाले प्लान का प्राइस किसी आम टर्म प्लान के प्राइस के दोगुने से ज्यादा है। कंपनी इसके अंतर को इनवेस्ट करती है और पॉलिसी पूरी होने पर बायर को प्रीमियम लौटा देती है। हालांकि बायर अगर इन दो प्लान के प्रीमियम के अंतर वाली रकम को किसी सेविंग्स बैंक एकाउंट में भी रखे तो उसे फायदा हो सकता है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.
HIGHLIGHTS  Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change
 Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%
  The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.
A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.
The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avoid Queue At SBI Branches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</guid>
      <description>SBI&amp;rsquo;s virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores.
SBI or State Bank of India is offering a virtual queue ticket or &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo; service through its newly-launched app No Queue, which enables customers to avail select banking services at its select branches without having to stand in queues. SBI customers &amp;ldquo;can book a virtual token&amp;hellip;and skip the queue,&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI said on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department has launched a massive hunt for black money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</guid>
      <description>The massive hunt for undeclared cash launched across the country post demonetisation has revealed that these was either converted into gold or routed through shell companies to make it legal tender, IT sleuths have told Indo-Asian News Service.
Income Tax officials said black money holders avoided the bank-deposit route because they wanted to conceal their identities and somehow had &amp;ldquo;managed to get many jewellers&amp;rdquo; to convert their unaudited cash into gold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.
Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.
Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Luxurious Maharajas&#39; Express Offers Free Seats On New Routes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</guid>
      <description>Indian Railways and IRCTC have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.
The Indian Railways’ super-luxury trains, which cater to various tourist circuits throughout India have long been in demand with travellers with deep pockets looking to explore the cities, towns, villages and regional areas, while travelling in style along the world’s fourth largest rail network. Expanding the network of its super-luxury trains, the Indian Railways and Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation Ltd (IRCTC) have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मोदी की &#39;कड़वी दवाइयों&#39; के लिए रहें तैयार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/result-get-ready-for-big-economic-reforms-by-modi-governemnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/result-get-ready-for-big-economic-reforms-by-modi-governemnt/</guid>
      <description>यूपी में बीजेपी की प्रचंड जीत से प्रभावित मोदी सरकार सुधारों की दिशा में अपने कदम और तेज कर सकती है। विदेशी निवेश के मामले में सरकार और उदारवादी रुख अपना सकती है वहीं, भारत में उत्पादन बढ़ाना, कर्ज में डूबे बैंकों का उबारना, सोशल सेक्टर में डिलिवरी सिस्टम को मजबूत करना सरकार के सुधारवादी अजेंडा में शामिल रह सकते हैं।
यूपी में बीजेपी अपनी &amp;lsquo;ट्रिपल सेंचुरी&amp;rsquo; को नोटबंदी पर जनता के ग्रीन सिग्नल के रूप में देख रही है। दो सालों से &amp;lsquo;सबसे बड़ा&amp;rsquo; आर्थिक सुधार माने जाने वाले जीएसटी को पास कराने की कोशिशों में लगी बीजेपी अब अन्य सुधारों की ओर तेज कदम बढ़ाएगी जिससे जीएसटी को लागू करने में भी फायदा होगा। वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने विधानसभा चुनावों में बीजेपी के प्रदर्शन पर ट्वीट किया, &amp;lsquo;विधानसभा चुनावों में बीजेपी की बेहतरीन जीत से फिर यह साबित होता है कि जनता पीएम मोदी के विकास के साथ हैं।&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एक रुपए का नया नोट, नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार का फैसला</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-government-will-issue-one-rupees-note-after-two-decades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-government-will-issue-one-rupees-note-after-two-decades/</guid>
      <description>एक रुपए से आज भले ही हम ज्यादा कुछ न खरीद पाएं, लेकिन फिर भी केंद्र सरकार देश में इसको चलते रहने देना चाहती है।
एक रुपए से आज भले ही हम ज्यादा कुछ न खरीद पाएं, लेकिन फिर भी केंद्र सरकार देश में इसको चलन में रहने देना चाहती है। सरकार ने इसे 20 साल बाद दोबारा छापने का फैसला किया है। हालांकि, पुराने नोट और सिक्के भी चलन में रहेंगे। भारतीय रिर्जव बैंक (आरबीआई) ने इस बात की पुष्टि की है। आरबीआई ने इस बारे में बताया कि वह जल्द ही एक रुपए के नए नोट चलन में लाएगा। भारत सरकार इन्हें छापेगी। ये नोट कॉइनेज एक्ट 2011 के तहत छापे जाएंगे। फिलहाल एक रुपए के सिक्के चलन में हैं, जो टकसाल में तैयार किए जाते हैं।</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>