<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data leak: Now govt agencies will safeguard your personal info</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The linking of Aadhaar — the 12-digit unique identification number for Indian residents is about to become safer as new rules put the onus on government departments and agencies to safeguard personal data or information held by them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Departments handling the data will have to ensure that end-users are made aware of the data usage and collection and their consent is taken either in writing or electronically, according to new guidelines issued by the government for security of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sensitive personal data such as passwords, financial information (bank account, credit card, debit card and other payment instrument details), medical records and history, sexual orientation, physical and mental health, and biometric information cannot be stored by agencies without encryption, say the guidelines issued by the Ministry of electronics and information technology (IT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure, the Information Technology Act 2000 and Aadhaar Act 2016 have laid down most of these rules. The new guidelines seek answers to questions being asked on data protection under the Aadhaar Act, according to Press Trust of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;uidai-warns-government-departments&#34;&gt;UIDAI warns government departments:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publishing identity information, i.e. Aadhaar number along with demographic information is in clear contravention of the provisions of the Aadhaar Act 2016 and constitutes an offence punishable with imprisonment up to 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publishing of financial information including bank details, being sensitive personal data, is also in contravention of provision under IT Act 2000 with violations liable to pay damages by way of compensation to persons affected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move to protect personal data comes after reports that data of 130 million Aadhaar cardholders has been leaked from four government websites. Reports, based on a study conducted by the Centre for Internet and Society (CIS) said Aadhaar numbers and details have been leaked.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM will now allow you to make payments via Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app will now allow users to send and receive money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes shortly after the government announced the Aadhaar Pay which would allow any person with their Aadhaar number linked to a bank account, can make and receive payment electronically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, IT minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said that BHIM would be able to make Aadhar Payments any biometric authentication, as indicated by this Economic Times report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the government has 14 banks onboard to facilitate payments via Aadhaar Pay, with more to join soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The updated BHIM app now has options where it will allow users to pay with Aadhar number in addition to virtual payment addresses (VPA) and bank account and IFSC codes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar. To further incentivize Indians to make the switch to using the BHIM app for transacting business, PM Modi also launched two schemes - cash back for merchants and referral bonus for individual owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Are Some Of The Key Features Of BHIM:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BHIM, short for Bharat Interface for Money, enables its users to transfer money using their mobile phone. The app created a world record by registering 10 million downloads in just four months since its launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. For every successful referral, users can earn Rs. 10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;PM Modi declared on Friday that incentives totalling Rs. 495 crore will be given to merchants for accepting payments through BHIM and existing users for referring it to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 2 MB in size, the latest version of the app enables payments through a fingerprint scanner by authenticating biometric details of the user against the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is available in 12 languages with three new languages (Marathi, Punjabi and Assamese) added in BHIM 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, now allows users to transfer money to contacts saved on the phone. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a cap of Rs. 10,000 for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present account holders of around 30 banks can transact on BHIM 1.3. The app will add Punjab And Maharashtra Co-Operative Bank Ltd, Punjab &amp;amp; Sind Bank and Jammu and Kashmir Bank soon, according to its Google Play Store page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the United Payments Interface (UPI), BHIM users do not need to download mobile applications of multiple banks to transact with different banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the government&amp;rsquo;s move on November 8 last year to demonetise Rs. 500 and Rs. 1,000 currency notes, the number of digital payment apps have logged a nearly 23-fold increase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed by National Payments Corporation of India, BHIM aims pave the way for making payments using fingerprints or iris scanners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Reminds On Cash Transaction Limit. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-reminds-on-cash-transaction-limit-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-reminds-on-cash-transaction-limit-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under Section 269ST of the Income Tax Act, accepting cash of Rs 2 lakh or more by any individual is restricted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an effort to check corruption and a further push towards digital payments, the government has capped the cash transactions at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1, 2017. Under Section 269ST of the Income Tax Act, accepting cash of Rs 2 lakh or more by any individual is restricted. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his budget speech had proposed the idea of putting a restriction on cash transactions. The government is closely monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Act prohibits such cash dealings on a single day, in respect of a single transaction or transactions relating to one event or occasion from an individual. &amp;ldquo;Contravention of Section 269ST would entail levy of 100 per cent penalty on receiver of the amount,&amp;rdquo; the Income Tax department said in a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The restriction is however not applicable to any receipt by government, banking company, post office savings bank or co-operative bank, the tax department added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post notes ban, the government has also come up with a black money declaration scheme or Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY) under which people holding unaccounted cash could come clean by declaring their wealth and pay 50 per cent as tax and penalty. So far, the PMGKY scheme has not got a &amp;ldquo;good response,&amp;rdquo; the government said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The response (to the PMGKY) has not been so good&amp;hellip;about Rs 5,000 crore of income was declared in PMGKY,&amp;rdquo; Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department also advised people to report cash dealings above the permissible limit or any information regarding unaccounted cash by dropping an email to &amp;lsquo;blackmoneyinfo@incometax.gov.in &amp;lsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile number will be deactivated if not linked with Aadhaar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mobile-number-will-deactivated-not-linked-aadhaar-card-heres-can-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mobile-number-will-deactivated-not-linked-aadhaar-card-heres-can-link/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government had in March 2017, had announced that Aadhaar-based e-KYC (know your customer) will be made mandatory for mobile phone connections. The department of telecommunications (DoT) had then ordered all mobile operators to verify the details of the existing customers by using their unique Aadhaar identity number and biometric details by early 2018. Aadhaar-based e-KYC will also be made compulsory for customers who have to get new SIM cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Airtel and Idea have begun the process of completing this verification. The two service providers are sending messages to their customers to initiate the KYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A message in Airtel store reads: “Link your Aadhaar card to your number now to stay active! As per the Government of India, this is mandatory to enjoy continued services”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To save yourself from getting your services discontinued, here is your guide to link your Aadhaar card with your mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to link the phone number to your Aadhaar card?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• As soon as you receive the SMS, go to the nearby store of your operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Take your Aadhaar card along and give the details there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• After this, you will receive a 4 digit verification code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Once the code is confirmed, fingerprint verification will be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Within 24 hours, you will get another message for “Final verify”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Reply to that message with “Y”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• You will get an SMS that your number is linked to the Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;clear-your-doubts-with-these-answers&#34;&gt;Clear your doubts with these answers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do I need to pay any charges?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is free and you need to get it done through an operator’s store only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can I do online registration?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, don’t go behind any online registration sites, as they are fake. The process is manual and as of now, only offline registration facility is available. Telecom operators haven’t started online registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s the last date?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last date is 6th of February 2018. Do it as soon as possible as it is rightly said, “Sooner the better”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can the Aadhaar card be linked to multiple SIM cards?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you can link it. However, a limit has been set for maximum connections. You need to find it out from your operator store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions mentioned above and get your card linked as soon as possible. It is better to be safe than sorry; following the rule at the earliest will not only benefit you, but will also ensure that you don’t face any issues later on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI में है आपका अकाउंट, अब इन खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-are-now-exempt-from-keeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-are-now-exempt-from-keeping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;एसबीआई ने सरकारी नौकरी करने वालों को भी राहत दी है। और ऐसे अकाउंट होल्डर्स को अब न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस नहीं रखना होगा।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देश के सबसे बड़े सरकारी बैंक स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (SBI) ने अपने यहां खाता रखने वाले ग्राहकों को बड़ी राहत दी है। SBI ने कई प्रकार के खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस ना रखने पर वसूलने वाले चार्ज को हटा दिया है। अब ग्राहक इन खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस नहीं भी रखेंगे तो उन्हें किसी भी प्रकार का शुल्क नहीं देना पड़ेगा। एसबीआई ने ट्वीट कर इस फैसले की जानकारी दी है। एसबीआई के ट्वीट के मुताबिक अब छोटी बचत खातों, बेसिक बचत खातों में मंथली एवरेज बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं है। इसके अलावा प्रधानमंत्री जन धन अकाउंट योजना के तहत खोले गये खातों में भी न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं है। एसबीआई ने सरकारी नौकरी करने वालों को भी राहत दी है। और ऐसे अकाउंट होल्डर्स को अब न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस नहीं रखना होगा। एसबीआई ने सभी कॉरपोरेट सैलरी रखने वालों को भी ये सुविधा दी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;मिनिमम बैलेंस की क्या है सीमा&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि SBI ने एक अप्रैल से अपने बैंकिंग नियमों में बदलाव किया है और कई तरह के खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस ना रखने पर चार्ज लगाया है। एसबीआई का नया नियम देश के 6 मेट्रो शहरों में बचत खातों में 5 हजार रुपये रखने अनिवार्य कर दिये हैं, जबकि शहरी क्षेत्र के खाताधारकों को अपने खाते में 3 हजार रुपये रखने जरुरी होंगे, अर्ध शहरी क्षेत्र के अकाउंट होल्डर्स के लिए ये सीमा 2 हज़ार रुपये हैं, हालांकि ग्रामीण खाताधारकों को थोड़ी राहत दी गई है और उनके लिए हज़ार रुपये ही अपने खाते में रखने जरूरी किये गये हैं। एसबीआई के नये नियमों के मुताबिक ऐसा ना करने पर ग्राहक से 20 से 100 रुपये तक का जुर्माना वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कैसे करें अपने खाते की पहचान&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बड़ा सवाल ये है कि आप इस बात की पहचान कैसे करेंगे कि आपका खाता किस कैटेगरी में आता है। एसबीआई ने स्मॉल और बेसिक सेविंग्स अकाउंट का मतलब बताते हुए लिखा है कि छोटी बचत खाते ढील दिये गये केवाईसी नियमों के तहत खोले जा सकते हैं। लेकिन इन खातों में अधिकत्तम बैलेंस और अधिकत्तम लेनदेन की सीमा तय की गई है। बेसिक सेविग्स अकाउंट केवाईसी नियमों के तहत खोला गया खाता है। बेसिक सेविंग्स खाताधारी दूसरा सेविंग अकाउंट नहीं खोल सकता है। जबकि सभी तरह के सरकारी नौकरियों में सैलरी पाने के लिए खोले गये खाते कॉरपोरेट सैलरी पैकेज के तहत आते हैं। जन-धन खातों के पासबुक में ही लिखा होता है कि ये खाते प्रधानमंत्री जन धन योजना के तहत खोले गये हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI&#39;s New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1. SBI has clarified that the Rs. 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through its mobile wallet app. SBI’s app Bank Buddy is a new facility that enables withdrawal of cash through ATMs using the bank&amp;rsquo;s mobile wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal saving bank accounts in a month will continue to get eight free ATM transactions (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks) in metros and 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks), the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applies to the Basic Savings Banks Deposit Accounts, SBI further said. SBI’s basic savings account is a limited-services bank account aimed at poorer sections of society to encourage them to start saving without any burden of charges or fees. This type of bank account comes with an ATM-cum-debit free of cost and no annual maintenance charges. A basic savings bank deposit account holder is not eligible to open any other savings bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective June 1. Here are some of the other key changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS or Immediate Payment Service will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh; Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh; and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; If a customer wishes to exchange of more than 20 soiled notes or if the total value of soiled notes is above Rs. 5,000, SBI said it will charge Rs. 2 plus service charge for every soiled note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customer with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs. 30 plus service tax for a 10-leaf cheque book, Rs. 75 with service tax for 25-leaf cheque book and Rs. 150 plus service tax for a 50-leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issuance of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only RuPay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs. 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs. 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Face Or Fingerprint Could Soon Replace Your Ticket</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-face-or-fingerprint-could-soon-replace-your-plane-ticket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-face-or-fingerprint-could-soon-replace-your-plane-ticket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first phase of Delta&amp;rsquo;s program will allow its elite-tier passengers to use their fingerprints, rather than their boarding passes, to enter member lounges.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may soon be able to ditch your boarding pass in favor of your fingers or face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, Delta announced a new biometric identification pilot program that will eventually let you use your fingerprints instead of a plane ticket. That followed a JetBlue announcement hours earlier that it is testing a program in Boston that will match pictures of customers&amp;rsquo; faces with the passport database maintained by U.S. Custom and Border Protections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta&amp;rsquo;s program, which kicked off at D.C.&amp;rsquo;s Reagan National Airport, is in partnership with Clear, a company that already lets customers skip to the front of security lines without identification. To be eligible for the program, one must be a member of Delta&amp;rsquo;s frequent flyer SkyMiles program and a Clear subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first phase of Delta&amp;rsquo;s program will allow its elite-tier passengers to use their fingerprints, rather than their boarding passes, to enter member lounges. A planned second phase would allow Delta frequent flyers to use their fingerprint in lieu of a boarding pass. Per its privacy policy, which will cover the Delta program, Clear keeps users&amp;rsquo; biometric information for the term of their subscriptions. Users can ask for their information to be removed from the company&amp;rsquo;s servers and close their accounts at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airline has also announced it will use facial recognition technology for bag drops, with a pilot testing program at Minneapolis-St. Paul International Airport in the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JetBlue&amp;rsquo;s program works in concert with two entities: the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and a tech firm called SITA. Flyers at Boston&amp;rsquo;s Logan International Airport and Aruba&amp;rsquo;s Queen Beatrix International Airport will have the option of going into the normal boarding line, or one with a camera that will snap their picture. SITA will send that photo to the CBP, to match it against the agency&amp;rsquo;s database of passport and visa photos. The match process is instant, JetBlue said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither JetBlue nor SITA has access to the photo database, and the airline will not store users&amp;rsquo; biometric information, JetBlue confirmed in an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the facial scan fails to work, passengers will be moved to the traditional line - so don&amp;rsquo;t travel without your ID just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using biometric data for identification may sound convenient, but people should consider some things before signing up, said Jeramie Scott, national security counsel for the Electronic Privacy Information Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither company has released details on how the government may use information on when and where people&amp;rsquo;s faces have been scanned, he said, nor are there laws to prevent the government from using these types of programs as part of larger surveillance plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a technology that can easily be used for mass, indiscriminate surveillance,&amp;rdquo; he said, of facial recognition technology. &amp;ldquo;Any use for facial recognition for something like this - where it&amp;rsquo;s the government or companies running a facial recognition search on people - needs to be scrutinized very closely by the public, because of the serious risk of mission creep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. Customs and Border Protection did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>इस साल 20000 लोगों को नौकरी देंगे: इन्फोसिस</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/only-400-people-asked-to-leave-will-hire-20000-this-year-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/only-400-people-asked-to-leave-will-hire-20000-this-year-says/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;इन्फोसिस के सीओओ यूबी प्रवीण राव ने कहा कि भारी पैमाने पर नौकरियां कम होने की बात अतिश्योक्ति है। उन्होंने कहा कि कंपनी की योजना इस साल 20,000 लोगों को नौकरी देने की है। राव ने कहा कि इन्फोसिस काफी नौकरियां पैदा कर रहा है और टेक्नॉलजी आधारित परिवर्तनों से इन्फोसिस जैसी कंपनियों के लिए नए अवसर पैदा हो रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;छंटनी को लेकर फैली अफवाहों पर अगर बात करें तो यह परफॉर्मेंस आधारित है और हम हर साल ऐसा करते हैं। ऐसे लोगों की संख्या 300-400 होगी जो कि बीते वर्षों की तरह ही है।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने हालांकि इन्फोसिस के सह-संस्थापक एनआर नारायणमूर्ति की उस बात पर प्रतिक्रिया देने से मना कर दिया जिसमें उन्होंने कहा था कि अगर कंपनियों के सीनियर एग्जिक्यूटिव्स अपनी कटी सैलरी लें और ट्रेनिंग एंप्लॉयी में निवेश करें तो नौकरियों को सुरक्षित रखना संभव है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस मामले में विभिन्न एंप्लॉयी यूनियनों ने लेबर कमिशन और राज्यों सरकारों से मामले में हस्तक्षेप करने की गुहार लगाई है। राव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;मुझे लगता है कि छंटनी की खबरें बहुत बढ़ाचढ़ाकर पेश की जा रही हैं। इन्फोसिस ने पिछले साल 20,000 लोगों को नौकरी दी थी और इस साल भी कंपनी इतने ही लोगों को रोजगार देगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जीएसटी: 2,500 जरूरी वस्तुओं के दाम तय करेंगे वित्त मंत्री</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/finance-minister-to-list-possible-prices-of-2500-goods-in-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/finance-minister-to-list-possible-prices-of-2500-goods-in-gst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;गुड्स ऐंड सर्विसेज टैक्स (जीएसटी) लागू होने के बाद वस्तुओं की कीमतें नियंत्रित रखने के लिए वित्त मंत्रालय सामान्य जरूरत के 2,000-2,500 सामानों और सेवाओं की कीमतें तय करने पर काम कर रहा है। सरकार इस बात पर भी गौर कर रही है कि अभी उनकी कीमतें क्या हैं और जीएसटी लागू होने के बाद क्या हो जाएंगी। सूत्रों ने बताया कि यह डेटा इस महीने के आखिर तक रिलीज कर दिया जाएगा और इसमें सभी बड़े शहरों को समाहित किया जाएगा। एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम छोटे शहरों और ग्रामीण इलाकों के स्तर तक कीमतें कम नहीं कर सकते, हालांकि प्राइस चार्ज सांकेतिक होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार यह सुनिश्चित करना चाहती है कि कारोबारी जमात ऊंची लागत का हवाला देकर नई व्यवस्था का लाभ दाम बढ़ाकर न लेने लगें। दरअसल, प्रमुख वस्तुओं की कीमतें बढ़ीं तो सरकार को संभालना मुश्किल हो जाएगा, इसीलिए वह एक विस्तृत अध्ययन करा रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मौजूदा समय में प्रमुख वस्तुओं और सेवाओं की कीमतों में बढ़ोतरी नहीं की जा सकती। इससे खाने के सामान पर कीमतें नियंत्रित रहेंगी और साबुन जैसे अन्य कन्ज्यूमर गुड्स पर कम टैक्स लगेगा। प्रॉडक्ट कैटिगरी में भी कुछ अंतर रखा गया है जिसकी अर्थशास्त्रियों ने निंदा की है। हालांकि, केंद्रीय वित्त मंत्री और राज्यों के वित्त मंत्रियों वाली जीएसटी काउंसिल ने होटल और रेस्तरां पर मल्टीपल स्लैब के तहत टैक्स लगाने का फैसला किया है। इसी तरह काउंसिल की शनिवार को होनेवाली बैठक में महंगे बिस्किट की तुलना में सस्ते बिस्किट पर लगने वाले टैक्स में अंतर हो सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार को मलेशिया में बनी स्थिति के मद्देनजर जीएसटी लागू होने के बाद कुछ चीजों के दाम में इजाफे का डर लग रहा है। इससे बचने के लिए केंद्र ने जीएसटी कानून में मुनाफाखोरी रोकने का प्रावधान तय किया है। सरकार ने उद्यमों को पहले ही चेतावनी दी है कि अगर उन्होंने नई टैक्स व्यवस्था के तहत होनेवाला लाभ ग्राहकों को नहीं दिया गया तो वह इस प्रावधान को लागू कर सकती है। सरकार ने कीमतें तय करने का फैसला ऑस्ट्रेलिया के उदाहरण से लिया है। वहां की सरकार ने 185 सामान्य इस्तेमाल की वस्तुओं की तीन साल के लिए कीमत तय कर दी थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारत में सरकार ने अभी मुनाफाखोरी पर नजर रखनेवाली एजेंसी की नियुक्ति नहीं की है। अभी कुछ नियम भी नहीं बने हैं, लेकिन सरकार को उम्मीद है कि आने वाले चार सप्ताह में यह काम भी निपटा दिया जाएगा। अधिकारियों का भी मानना है कि सरकार सभी चीजों की कीमतों पर नजर नहीं रख पाएगी और आनेवाली शिकायतों पर भी कार्रवाई नहीं कर पाएगी। केंद्र का मानना है कि इस काम में राज्यों को अहम भूमिका निभानी चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जून से SBI इन सेवाओं के लिए वसूलेगा एक्‍स्‍ट्रा चार्ज, ये होंगे बदलाव</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-customers-bank-will-charge-extra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-customers-bank-will-charge-extra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;देश का सबसे बड़ा बैंक एसबीआई 1 जून से अपनी कई सेवाओं के शुल्‍क में बढ़ोतरी करने जा रहा है। पहली जून से अगर आप एसबीआई जाकर कटे-फटे नोट बदलवाते हैं या एक सीमा से अधिक बार पैसे निकालते हैं तो एसबीआई आपसे चार्ज वसूलेगा। बेसिक सेविंग बैंक डिपॉजिट अकाउंट के ग्राहकों को पैसे निकालने, नए कार्ड इश्यू करवाने जैसी सुविधाएं के लिए भी 1 जून से चार्ज देना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कैश विड्रॉल पर लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एसबीआई से कैश विड्रॉल सिर्फ 4 बार तक के लिए ही मुफ्त रहेगी। इसमें एटीएम ट्रांजैक्शंस भी शामिल हैं। 4 बार से ज्यादा एसबीआई की ब्रांच से भी कैश विड्रॉल करेंगे तो हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 50 रुपए का सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लगेगा। एसबीआई के एटीएम से 4 बार से ज्यादा विड्रॉल करेंगे तो हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 10 रुपए सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स देना होगा। दूसरे बैंक के एटीएम से 4 बार से ज्यादा कैश विड्रॉल पर हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 20 रुपए सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लगेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;आरबीआई ने दिए कटे-फटे नोट को लेकर दिए थे ये निर्देश&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30 अप्रैल को ही आरबीआई ने बैंकों को कटे, लिखे, पुराने व फटे नोटों को लेने के लिए कहा था. रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (आरबीआई) ने बैंकों को साफ निर्देश दिया है कि उन्हें गंदे नोट लेने ही होंगे और इसे लेने से वे इनकार नहीं कर सकते। लेकिन अगर आप एसबीआई में कटे-फटे या गले-गीले नोट जमा कराएंगे तो आपके ऊपर अतिरिक्त चार्ज देना होर्गा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;पुराने कटे-फटे नोट बदलने पर भी लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एसबीआई 20 से ज्यादा या 5,000 रुपए से ज्यादा कटे-फटे नोट बदलवाने पर अब 2 से लेकर 5 रुपए तक का चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स वसूलेगा। इसके तहत हर नोट पर 2 रुपये या हरेक 1,000 रुपये पर 5 रुपये चार्ज, जो भी ज्यादा होगा, वह वसूला जाएगा। 5,000 रुपए तक कीमत होने पर हर नोट पर 2 रुपये चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स वसूला जाएगा और 5000 रुपये से ज्यादा कीमत होने पर हर नोट पर 5 रुपये चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लिया जाएगा। कटे-फटे 20 नोट जिनकी कुल कीमत 5,000 रुपये से ज्यादा नहीं होगी तक बदलने पर एसबीआई कोई सर्विस चार्ज नहीं लगेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बेसिक बैंक डिपॉजिट अकाउंट के नए कार्ड पर भी लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 जून से एसबीआई एक्स्ट्रा डेबिट कार्ड इश्यू करने पर भी चार्ज लेने की तैयारी कर रहा है। एक जून से बैंक सिर्फ रुपे डेबिट कार्ड ही मुफ्त में जारी करेगा। बाकी सभी कार्ड जारी करने पर बैंक ने सर्विस चार्ज लेने का ऐलान कर दिया है। 1 जून से बैंक मास्टर और वीजा कार्ड इश्यू करने पर सर्विस चार्ज लेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>दो लाख से ऊपर के नकद लेनदेन पर आयकर विभाग की पैनी नजर,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-eyes-on-cash-transactions-above-two-lakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-eyes-on-cash-transactions-above-two-lakh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने शुक्रवार (2 जून) को लोगों को दो लाख रुपये से अधिक का नकद लेनदेन करने के प्रति आगाह किया। विभाग ने कहा कि इस तरह के लेनदेन में जिस व्यक्ति को नकद राशि प्राप्त होगी, उसे उतना ही जुर्माना देना होगा। इसके अलावा विभाग ने लोगों से कहा है कि उन्हें यदि इस तरह के लेनदेन की जानकारी मिलती है तो वे इसका ब्योरा ‘blackmoneyinfo@incometax.gov.in’ पर भेज सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने वित्त अधिनियम, 2017 के तहत एक अप्रैल, 2017 से दो लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर रोक लगा दी है। आयकर कानून में नई शामिल 269एसटी धारा एक दिन में इतने नकद लेनदेन पर रोक लगाती है। यह किसी एक व्यक्ति द्वारा एक मामले में दो लाख रुपये से अधिक के लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध लगाती है।
कर विभाग ने प्रमुख दैनिक अखबारों में प्रकाशित विज्ञापनों में कहा है कि धारा 269एसटी का उल्लंघन करने पर नकद राशि प्राप्त करने वाले पर इतनी ही राशि के बराबर जुर्माना लगेगा। वित्त वर्ष 2017-18 के बजट में वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने तीन लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर रोक लगाने का प्रस्ताव किया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त विधेयक में संशोधन के तहत इस सीमा को कम कर दो लाख रुपये कर दिया गया। वित्त विधेयक लोकसभा में मार्च में पारित हुआ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कर विभाग ने कहा है कि यह अंकुश सरकार की किसी प्राप्ति, बैंकिंग कंपनी, डाकघर बचत बैंक या सहकारी बैंक पर लागू नहीं होगा। एक निश्चित सीमा से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध का मकसद कालेधन पर अंकुश लगाना है। कर विभाग ने पिछले साल नोटबंदी के बाद दिसंबर में यह ईमेल पता शुरू किया था, जिस पर दो लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन की सूचना दी जा सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Now Pay Later: IRCTC To Offer Train Tickets On Credit</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potential passengers can book a ticket and pay for it online within 14 days, IRCTC said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation or IRCTC has decided to make booking tickets a hassle-free affair by providing a &amp;lsquo;buy tickets now and pay later&amp;rsquo; service for regular travelers. Soon passengers would be able to buy tickets from the IRCTC website and pay later, an IRCTC official told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential passengers can book a ticket five days prior to the journey with a service charge of 3.5 per cent and pay it in the next 14 days, IRCTC spokesperson Sandip Dutta said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has collaborated with a Mumbai-based firm ePayLater for adding the new service option. The ePayLater platform allows persons to log out immediately after booking tickets and make payments later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The railway agency had earlier introduced &amp;lsquo;pay on delivery&amp;rsquo; category for train tickets booked using its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be applicable for new &amp;ldquo;Buy Now Pay Later&amp;rdquo; feature, users will have fill in basic details including Aadhaar and PAN card details after which they will be able to use the feature with a One Time Password (OTP), ePayLater said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your NPS Account With Aadhaar Number</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPS subscribers have the facility to add their Aadhaar numbers online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPS or National Pension Scheme subscribers have been advised to add Aadhaar number to their accounts. Aadhaar is a 12-digit number issued by Unique Identification Authority of India or UIDAI based on the demographic and biometric information of the person. NPS subscribers can add their Aadhaar numbers online. The Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority (PFRDA), the body which manages NPS, been taking a number of measures to simplify the processes. For example, the Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority has done away with the requirement of submission of a physical application form for opening of an NPS account if done through Aadhaar verification and e-signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to add Aadhaar to your NPS account online:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Log-in to your NPS account (www.cra-nsdl.com)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Click on &amp;ldquo;Update Details&amp;rdquo; tab and then select the option &amp;ldquo;Add/Update Aadhaar Number&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Submit your Aadhaar number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Enter the OTP received from UIDAI on your registered mobile number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) After authentication through OTP, Aadhaar will be linked to your PRAN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PRAN or Permanent Retirement Account Number is a unique number allotted to NPS subscribers that remains the same for the rest of subscriber&amp;rsquo;s life)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NPS body has said that a subscriber is required to seed the Aadhaar in his or her PRAN through this process even if Aadhaar was provided earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: PFRDA has said that the name registered against your PRAN should exactly match the name as registered with &amp;ldquo;UIDAI&amp;rdquo; in Aadhaar. If the correction is required on PRAN card, then the NPS subscriber has to submit a self-attested PRAN card copy and a self-attested Aadhaar card copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For government subscribers, the Aadhaar seeding process will be completed once the request initiated by a subscriber is authorised online by his /her respective Nodal Office, PFRDA said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>