<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Rs 50,000 On Your Provident Fund Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-deposits-to-earn-rs-50-000-more-under-new-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-deposits-to-earn-rs-50-000-more-under-new-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund body EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation&amp;rsquo;s (EPFO) apex decision making body, the Central Board of Trustees (CBT), has recommended a minimum sum assured of Rs 2.5 lakh in the event of death of a subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The CBT has recommended amending the Employees&amp;rsquo; Deposit Linked Insurance Scheme (EDLI) to provide for minimum benefit of Rs 2.5 lakh and loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at a meeting held yesterday,&amp;rdquo; a senior official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The suggested benefits will be available to members after government approval. Initially, these will be provided for two years on a pilot basis and will be reviewed thereafter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the proposal, loyalty-cum-life benefit will be provided to all those members on retirement at 58 or 60 years who have contributed to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability. In these cases, the members who have contributed to the EDLI scheme for less than 20 years will be eligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those members whose average basic wages are up to Rs 5,000 will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of Rs 30,000. Similarly, the members with wages of Rs 5,001-10,000 Will be eligible for Rs 40,000 benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those members getting more than Rs 10,000 monthly wage will be eligible for Rs 50,000 loyalty-cum-life benefit under the proposed scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board has recommended such benefits in view of a huge EDLI corpus of Rs 18,119 crore following addition of interest that accrued on investment of this fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, the dependants of the deceased get a sum assured of up to Rs 6 lakh. There is no provision of minimum insurance and any benefit for surviving members or in cases of permanent disability under the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya launched Aadhaar Seeding Application after the meeting. The EPFO has developed this application with support of Common Service Centres (CSCs) and C-DAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CSCs are ICT-enabled front-end service delivery points at the village level for delivery of government and private services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With implementation of the seeding application, a PF member or pensioner can now walk into any of the field offices of EPFO or CSC outlets with UAN and Aadhaar and seed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO enrolled 49,39,929 workers during January-March 2017. It had launched a special enrolment scheme to cover leftout formal sector workers from January 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Developments On Your Provident Fund (PF) Money You Should Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-aadhaar-to-loyalty-scheme-5-developments-from-epfo-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-aadhaar-to-loyalty-scheme-5-developments-from-epfo-this-month/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From interest rate for 2016-17 to Aadhaar to a new loyalty scheme, there has been a lot of news coming from EPFO or Employees Provident Fund Organisation that manages your provident fund money. EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number to April 30, 2017 for its over four crore members. The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier. EPFO has also extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-the-other-developments&#34;&gt;Here are the other developments:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more. The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided. The benefits will be available for EPFO subscribers after approval from the government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;EPFO&amp;rsquo;s apex decision-making body the Central Board of Trustees (CBT) has recommended a minimum sum assured of Rs 2.5 lakh in the event of death of a subscriber. At present, the dependants of the deceased get a sum assured of up to Rs 6 lakh. There is no provision of minimum insurance and any benefit for surviving members or in cases of permanent disability under the scheme. The benefits will be available for EPFO subscribers after approval from the government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 4 crore subscribers of EPFO will get 8.65 per cent interest on provident fund deposits for 2016-17, as decided by the organisation&amp;rsquo;s trustees in December, Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya has said. The comments follow reports suggesting that the Finance Ministry is nudging the Labour Ministry to lower the EPF interest rate by up to 50 basis points. &amp;ldquo;It is not like that. The CBT (EPFO trustees) had decided to give 8.65 per cent. Our ministry keeps on discussing with Finance Ministry. We would have surplus of Rs 158 crore on providing 8.65 per cent,&amp;rdquo; Mr Dattatreya said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The board of retirement fund body EPFO deferred the proposal to raise investment in stock market to 15 per cent of its investible deposits from current 10 per cent. &amp;ldquo;It was proposed to increase investments in the Exchanges Traded Funds to 15 per cent. But trade unions representatives opposed it,&amp;rdquo; an EPFO trustee said after the meeting. The EPFO has invested Rs 18,069 crore in exchange trade funds (ETFs) till February 18, 2017 and yielded a return of 18.13 per cent on these investments. Earlier, Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya had indicated that the EPFO will increase its investment in ETFs in the backdrop of good returns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly four crore members of retirement fund body EPFO will soon be able to settle their claims like EPF withdrawal through mobile application UMANG. &amp;ldquo;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) is developing online claims settlement process by receiving application online,&amp;rdquo; Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya said in a written reply to the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>70 GB 4G Data At Rs 244, Rs 399: Airtel&#39;s New Plans To Counter Jio &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-gb-4g-data-at-rs-244-rs-399-airtels-new-plans-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-gb-4g-data-at-rs-244-rs-399-airtels-new-plans-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After withdrawing the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, Jio has come up with Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plans offering unlimited data, SMS and voice calling for three months.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bharti-airtel-650_650x400_81492158840.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With the tariff war getting brutal in the telecom space, India&amp;rsquo;s biggest operator Airtel has come up with aggressive new prepaid plans to counter Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s latest &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer. Under Rs 244 plan, Airtel is offering unlimited local and STD calls on Airtel network and 1 GB/day for 70 days. Under the Rs 399 plan, Airtel is offering free local and STD calls on any network as well as 1 GB/day data for 70 days. Under the Rs 345 plan, Airtel is offering unlimited call and 2GB data/day for 28 days. A check on Airtel&amp;rsquo;s website showed these new plans are available for subscription on prepaid numbers through online payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After withdrawing the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, Jio has come up with Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plans offering unlimited data, SMS and voice calling for three months. Starting Rs 309, &amp;lsquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plan offers 1 GB data per day for a period of 84 days. Also, with a recharge of Rs 509, users will get 2 GB data per day for 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry into the telecom space has led to a drop in tariffs as the competition gets intense. The revenue of telecom sector from consumer services like mobile telephony and data dipped 10.5 per cent to Rs 37,284 crore in the October-December period over the previous three months, according to regulator Trai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aggressive offerings from telecom operators have led higher data usage. Two out of three consumers in India want to switch to a new phone within the next 12 months, a report by Counterpoint Research said. &amp;ldquo;As per the survey, two in three users plan to upgrade to a new mobile phone in the next 12 months. This is a departure from an average of 24-30 months to under 20 months upgrade cycle,&amp;rdquo; the report said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At SBI, You Don&#39;t Need To Maintain Minimum Balance In These Accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India is offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has said it is exempting its customers holding certain account types from maintenance of average monthly balance. Such accounts include small savings bank accounts, basic savings bank accounts and Jan Dhan accounts, or the accounts opened under the government&amp;rsquo;s financial inclusion scheme Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana or PMJDY. This was said in a tweet by SBI, which recently adopted a new brand identity after merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank. SBI had earlier decided to increase the minimum balance required for maintaining savings accounts from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, State Bank of India is also offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.
Account holders of the following types of accounts are exempt from requiring to maintain an average monthly balance: pic.twitter.com/61U8QNu7xR
— State Bank of India (@TheOfficialSBI) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement was increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros. In case of non-compliance, savings bank account holders will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs. 100 (in metro cities), as per the bank&amp;rsquo;s website. (Read more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other features SBI offers under these accounts, according to its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-savings-bank-account&#34;&gt;Small savings bank account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account has a maximum balance limit of Rs 50,000 and offers a rate of interest applicable to savings bank accounts. Account holders get an ATM-cum-Debit card, issued free of cost and without any annual maintenance charge, as per the SBI website. All credits in a financial year should not aggregate to more than Rs 1 lakh and Rs 10,000 in case of withdrawals and transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-savings-account&#34;&gt;Basic savings account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s basic savings account has no minimum balance or maximum balance limits. Holders of this account type &amp;ldquo;will not be eligible to open any other Savings Bank Account&amp;rdquo; at the bank. Such an account - in case the customer already holds one - will have to be closed within 30 days of opening the basic savings bank deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;corporate-salary-package&#34;&gt;Corporate salary package&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s salary account under corporate salary package offers many benefits to the employer and the employee alike. This account type reduces employer&amp;rsquo;s paperwork and salary administration cost. Employees get free internet banking and mobile banking services, among other features, as per the SBI website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know how Aadhaar Pay works</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/game-changer-digital-push-know-aadhaar-pay-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/game-changer-digital-push-know-aadhaar-pay-works/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi today launched Aadhaar Pay at Nagpur on the birth anniversary of the Father of Indian Constitution Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar. The app is expected to revolutionise digital payments, especially in rural India, as it is extremely easy to use for merchants as well as customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the government’s digital payments campaign, Aadhaar Pay comes after the launch of the BHIM App on December 30. While launching the BHIM app, PM Modi had said more work was being done which would increase the power of BHIM so much that people would be able to withdraw money even with fingerprints&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the government launched BHIM as a payment application for peer-to-peer transactions post demonetisation, Aadhaar Pay is meant for merchants to receive digital payments from customers over the counter through Aadhaar authentication. The government has named the new payments system as BHIM-Aadhaar sewa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay will be supported by 20 banks initially. The government has requested all public sector banks to go live with Aadhaar Pay and the National Payments Corporation of India, the implementing agency for Aadhaar Enabled Payments Systems, has extended help to the banks to ensure smooth onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-game-changer-app&#34;&gt;A game-changer app&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While, so far, digital payments have been dependent on credit/debit cards and mobile phones, Aadhaar Pay won’t require a phone or a card. Even if a user cannot read or write, he would be able to use it. Low mobile-phone penetration and digital literacy are considered big obstacles in the government’s plan to involve the masses in the digital payments system. Aadhaar Pay will face no such obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-aadhaar-pay-works&#34;&gt;How Aadhaar Pay works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is only for merchants. A merchant has to download the app on a smartphone, connect the app to his bank account and link the phone to a biometric scan machine. To make payment, the customer just have to give his fingerprint. The customer must have an Aadhaar-linked bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;free-transactions&#34;&gt;Free transactions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since transaction charges discourage adoption of digital payments, especially in small towns and rural India, the Aadhaar Pay will levy no transaction fee on the merchant or the customer unlike the card-based digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-secure-app&#34;&gt;A secure app&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Niti Aayog, the Aadhaar Pay is a safe app that uses two main platforms—Aadhaar Payment Bridge (APB) and Aadhaar Enabled Payment System (AEPS). APB will act as repository between the banks and the customers to provide a smooth flow of transactions, while AEPS will help in authenticating the online process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-secure-app-1&#34;&gt;A secure app&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Niti Aayog, the Aadhaar Pay is a safe app that uses two main platforms—Aadhaar Payment Bridge (APB) and Aadhaar Enabled Payment System (AEPS). APB will act as repository between the banks and the customers to provide a smooth flow of transactions, while AEPS will help in authenticating the online process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;incentives-scheme&#34;&gt;Incentives scheme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay comes with incentives for merchants and customers-cash back and referral bonus. Under the referral bonus scheme, both the existing user who refers BHIM and the new user who adopts BHIM would get a cash bonus credited directly to their account. Under the cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. The government has an outlay of Rs 495 crore for the scheme which will run till October 14.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ATMs Are Going Dry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1: The ATM expansion era is over. ATM extensions will no longer be part of future banking growth, and future ATMs may well be of the mobile kind focused only on rural cash deliveries. But even here, the growth will be limited. Standalone ATM companies may have a future, but only because banks may choose to outsource all their existing networks to them so that they can focus on growing the digital business themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: The phenomenon of business correspondents will rise in the short run, and then collapse as rural and unbanked sectors accept digital cash as the way to transfer money. The limiting factors are the absence of reliable power supplies in remote areas, and the gap in the spread of mobile phones to the poor. These shortcomings will be addressed over the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3: Once ATMs and cash start falling in terms of importance, the cash logistics business will, perforce, have to shrink. It is already in trouble after a few months of glory during the peak weeks of demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4: Many banking services may be outsourced. As ATMs shrink, branch rationalisation will also be the order of the day. Banks may outsource one-time customer-acquisition operations and use Aadhaar-based-eKYC to grow their customer bases, as Kotak Mahindra Bank’s 811 account is trying to do. E-KYC will soon become the standard way of acquiring new customers, both for regular banks and payment banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5: Cyber security will see a boom. As digital cash becomes the norm, the real growth in financial sector jobs will be in cyber security, since digital currency systems are vulnerable to hacking and fraud. For example, the unified payments interface (UPI) which allows for peer-to-peer payments using mobile phone numbers could be vulnerable to fraudsters who manage to clone your SIM card. In the past, fraudsters have cloned ATM magnetic strips; next they will target SIMs. Since smartphones will essentially become your digital banking interface, technologies to protect you from losses when you misplace or lose your phone will become paramount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6: Credit cards and payments systems will move out of the physical category and turn virtual. In future, credit and debit cards may be embedded in your phone, as the new Samsung Pay product indicates. Samsung Pay uses finger-print authorisation and PIN for payment at merchant nodes without any physical card having to be swiped. Kotak’s 811 app-based bank account offers virtual debit cards and scan-and-pay options. Once the Bharat QR Code becomes widely adopted by merchants, e-wallets too will become interoperable like credit cards issued by various banks are now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7: Phishing and fraud insurance will become big business. Once the smartphone becomes your wallet, you have to buy insurance to cover yourself against the possibility of fraud. Credit card fraud insurance is not big in India, but digital cash fraud may need better insurance than cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8: The biggest business of them all will be data analytics. As bank charges and payment usage fees fall to low levels, both due to regulation and high-volume usage, banks, virtual banks, card companies, and e-wallets will have to make money from the customer data they now own, as Aadhaar man Nandan Nilekani has repeatedly emphasised. This means financial companies must understand customers better from their spending and payments habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9: Bank employment will fall, as banks hollow out in terms of physical infrastructure and some jobs get outsourced. But they will pay top dollar to techies, since banking is being taken over by technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India is on the cusp of a huge shift in its financial sector. The old certainties are gone. The jobs market is shifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reassuring face of Gandhi on the currency note, with all its certainties, will be replaced with the virtual face of Bhimrao Ambedkar, the Modi government’s mascot for digital cash, with all its exciting uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आयकर विभाग करेगा 60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों की जांच</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-operation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; के दूसरे चरण में आयकर विभाग 60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों की जांच करेगा। शुक्रवार को दोबारा लॉन्च हुए इस ऑपरेशन का मकसद नोटबंदी के बाद पैदा हुए ब्लैक मनी का पता लगाना है। विभाग ने इससे पहले ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के पहले चरण में नोटबंदी के दौरान संदिग्ध लेन-देन करने वाले 18 लाख लोगों को नोटिस भेजा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग की नीति निर्माता ईकाइ केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (CBDT) का कहना है कि वह पिछले साल 9 नवंबर से इस साल की 28 फरवरी तक 9,332 करोड़ रुपए की अघोषित आय का पता लगा चुका है। बता दें कि 8 नवंबर को पीएम मोदी ने 500 और 1000 के नोटबंदी की घोषणा की थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों (जिसमें 1300 हाइ रिस्क लोग भी शामिल हैं) की जांच में पहचान हो चुकी है। नोटबंदी के दौरान अधिकतर बड़े लेन-देन कैश में करने वाले लोग नजर में थे। हाइ वैल्यू प्रॉपर्टी खरीद के 6000 मामले और विदेश के शेयर बाजार में पैसा लगाने या विदेश पैसा भेजने के 6,600 मामलों में बारीकी से जांच-पड़ताल होगी। अगर जवाब संतोषजनक नहीं माना गया तो विस्तृत पूछताछ की जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ITR में देनी होगी नोटबंदी के दौरान जमा रकम की जानकारी!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने बताया कि आधुनिक डेटा विश्लेषण का इस्तेमाल करते हुए संदिग्ध कैश डिपॉजिट का पता लगाया है। इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने इस साल 31 जनवरी को &amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; लॉन्च किया गया था। जिसके तहत 17.92 लाख लोगों को ऑनलाइन नोटिस भेजा गया था जिसमें से 9.46 लाख लोगों ने विभाग के प्रश्नों का जवाब दिया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एक करोड़ बैंक खातों का डेटा लीक, 20 पैसे प्रति कस्टमर के हिसाब से बेचा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/20-paise-each-bank-data-of-1-crore-indians-was/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/20-paise-each-bank-data-of-1-crore-indians-was/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;देश के एक करोड़ लोगों के बैंक खातों की जानकारी &amp;lsquo;ऑन सेल&amp;rsquo; है। बैंक अकाउंट्स से जुड़ी सभी जानकारी सेल वाले रेट से भी सस्ते में उपलब्ध है। पुलिस जांच में पता चला है कि 10 या 20 पैसे में आपके बैंक खाते से जुड़ी जानकारियां बेची जा रही हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दिल्ली के ग्रेटर कैलाश में रहने वाली एक 80 साल की महिला के केस की जांच करते हुए पुलिस को यह जानकारी मिली है। महिला के क्रेडिट कार्ड से 1.46 लाख रुपए उड़ा लिए गए थे। इसी केस की जांच करते हुए पुलिस ने बैंक अकाउंट्स की जानकारी बेचने वाले मॉड्यूल का पर्दाफाश किया। पुलिस को पता चला कि इस मॉड्यूल में बैंक में काम करने वालों और कॉल सेंटर्स से जानकारी निकलवाई जाती थी और फिर उसे बेच दिया जाता था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दक्षिण-पूर्वी दिल्ली के डीसीपी ने दावा किया कि मॉड्यूल के मास्टरमाइंड को गिरफ्तार करने के बाद पुलिस ने एक करोड़ लोगों के बैंक अकाउंट्स की जानकारी रिकवर की। सस्ते रेट में बेची जाने वाली जानकारी में आपका कार्ड नंबर, कार्ड होल्डर का नाम, जन्मतिथि और मोबाइल नंबर है। यह सारा डेटा कई कैटिगरीज में बंटा हुआ है, जिसका कुल साइज 20 जीबी से ज्यादा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गिरफ्तार किया गए पूरन गुप्ता ने बताया कि वह डेटा बल्क में बेचता था। 50 हजार लोगों का डेटा बेचने के वह 10 से 20 हजार लेता था। बताया जा रहा है कि आरोपी ने डेटा मुंबई के एक सप्लायर से खरीदा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डेटा खरीदने वाले इसकी मदद से बैंक के कर्मचारी बन लोगों को फोन करते थे और उनको CVV नंबर और OTP शेयर करने को कहते थे। जिसकी मदद से वह बैंक अकाउंट से पैसे निकालने में सफल हो जाते थे। किसी भी बैंक अकाउंट होल्डर की सारी डिटेल्स होने के कारण लोग इस जाल में फंस जाते थे। इसके अलावा वह रिवॉर्ड पॉइंट्स, कार्ड ब्लॉक जैसे बहाने बना कर पासवर्ड निकलवा लेते थे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हमारे सहयोगी अखबार टाइम्स ऑफ इंडिया ने 6 अप्रैल को रिपोर्ट किया था कि एक 80 साल की महिला के साथ ठगी के आरोप में आशीष कुमार को पुलिस ने गिरफ्तार किया है। आशीष इससे पहले बैंक और वित्तीय संस्थानों सेल्स एग्जिक्यूटिव के पद पर काम कर चुका है। उसने 2013 में हेल्थ इंश्योरेंस बेचने के लिए टेलिकॉलिंग का काम शुरू किया था।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Jio&#39;s &#39;Summer Surprise&#39; Comes &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer: Features, Price And More</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-summer-surprise-comes-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer-features-price-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-summer-surprise-comes-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer-features-price-and-more/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio makes India the highest quality, most affordable data market in the world so that every Indian can do Datagiri,&amp;rdquo; Jio said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has announced a new scheme called &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo;, offering &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs 309. &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; from Reliance Jio Infocomm - the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries - comes days after of the new entrant deciding to withdraw its &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. &amp;ldquo;In order to smoothen the migration from free to paid services, Jio has implemented simple, affordable and regulatory compliant plans in customer interest,&amp;rdquo; Jio said in a release on the Dhan Dhana Dhan scheme. Like its earlier &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer, &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; recharges will further boost Jio&amp;rsquo;s already strong customer retention under Prime as well as attract new customers to its fold, say analysts. (Also read: &amp;lsquo;Your first recharge an auspicious moment for Jio&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio in a statement on Tuesday said it has fully withdrawn its Summer Surprise offer &amp;ldquo;following the advice of Telecom Regulatory Authority of India&amp;rdquo;. For members of its Prime services, Jio announced new &amp;ldquo;all unlimited&amp;rdquo; plans &amp;ldquo;aimed at encouraging Jio subscribers to live the Digital Life without restrictions - Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to get &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; benefits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an existing Jio customer but have not bought your first Jio recharge so far, you &amp;ldquo;need to do so by 15 April 2017 to avoid degradation and/or discontinuation of services&amp;rdquo;. Those unable to subscribe to Prime until now can &amp;ldquo;continue to do so by paying Rs. 408 or Rs. 608 (Jio Prime + recharge price) to avail these benefits&amp;rdquo;, according to Jio.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-benefits-650_650x400_51491977379.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;dhan-dhana-dhan-plans&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 309:&lt;/em&gt; Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;all unlimited&amp;rdquo; plan priced at Rs 309 includes 1GB of 4G data, which is high speed internet, per day. Under Dhan Dhana Dhan offer - which is limited to one recharge only - Prime members will get 84 GB for 84 days, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 509:&lt;/em&gt; The Rs 509 plan &amp;ldquo;for daily high data users&amp;rdquo; includes 168 GB of high speed data (2GB per day at 4G speed) for 84 days on the first recharge.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-rs-309-rs-509_650x400_81491977322.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;em&gt;Rs 309 and Rs 509 plans&lt;/em&gt; include unlimited calling and unlimited SMS. Consumers will get 28 GB of 4G data (1GB per day) and 56 GB of data (2GB per day) for 28 days on subsequent recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509, respectively, as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;datagiri&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Datagiri&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio makes India the highest quality, most affordable data market in the world so that every Indian can do Datagiri,&amp;rdquo; the Jio release noted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Oil To Revise Petrol, Diesel Prices Daily In 5 Cities From May 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-cities-first-petrol-diesel-price-will-change-daily-from-next-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-cities-first-petrol-diesel-price-will-change-daily-from-next-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A pilot for daily revision of petrol and diesel price will be first implemented in Puducherry, Vizag in Andhra Pradesh, Udaipur in Rajasthan, Jamshedpur in Jharkhand and Chandigarh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come May 1, petrol and diesel prices will change every day in sync with international rates, much like what happens in most advanced markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-owned fuel retailers Indian Oil Corp (IOC), Bharat Petroleum Corp Ltd (BPCL) and Hindustan Petroleum Corp Ltd (HPCL), which own over 95 per cent of nearly 58,000 petrol pumps in the country, will launch a pilot for daily price revision in five select cities from May 1 and gradually extend it to all over the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ultimately, we will be driving towards market linked rates on a daily basis at all pumps across the country,&amp;rdquo; IOC Chairman B Ashok told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pilot for daily revision of petrol and diesel price will be first implemented in Puducherry, Vizag in Andhra Pradesh, Udaipur in Rajasthan, Jamshedpur in Jharkhand and Chandigarh, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State fuel retailers currently revise rates on 1st and 16th of every month based on average international price of the fuel in the preceding fortnight and currency exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of using fortnightly average, pump rates will reflect daily movement in international oil prices and rupee-US dollar fluctuations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is technically possible to change rates daily but we have to first do a pilot. Once pilot is done and its implications studied, we will extend it to other parts of the country,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ashok said the pilot is to be &amp;ldquo;launched within one month&amp;rdquo; and did not give a specific date, industry sources said the pilot is planned to be launched on May 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily price change will remove the big leaps in rates that need to be effected at the end of the fortnight and consumer will be more aligned to market dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While petrol price was freed from government control in June 2010, diesel rates were deregulated in October 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, oil companies have freedom to revise rates but often they have been guided by political considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rates differ by only a few paise between pumps of the three state fuel retailers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unbranded petrol at IOC pumps in Delhi costs Rs 66.29 per litre, while the same at BPCL pumps in the city is priced at Rs 66.37 a litre. HPCL pumps sell for Rs 66.48 per litre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unbranded diesel at IOC pumps in Delhi costs Rs 55.61, Rs 55.66 at BPCL outlets and Rs 55.69 a litre at HPCL pumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With daily changes, which are unlikely to more than few paise per litre, the political pressures for not revising rates particularly when they are to be hiked will go, sources said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petrol price was last revised downward by Rs 3.77 a litre on April and diesel rates were cut by Rs 2.91. This was the first revision in two-and-half-months as oil firms did not change prices during assembly elections in five states, including Uttar Pradesh and Punjab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ashok said prices of petrol and diesel in a particular market (city or town) will be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By and large, in a particular market it should be same. Though, there might be marginal difference from pump to pump,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Impact: Vodafone Offers Free 4GB Data On SIM Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-vodafone-offers-free-4gb-data-on-sim-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-vodafone-offers-free-4gb-data-on-sim-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Vodafone 4G SIMs are available at all Vodafone Stores, Vodafone Mini Stores or multi brand outlets located across Mumbai,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone is offering 4GB data free on upgradation to Vodafone Supernet 4G. Vodafone users in Mumbai who upgrade to a 4G SIM card (with 4G handsets) can avail the free data. &amp;ldquo;Vodafone 4G SIMs are available at all Vodafone Stores, Vodafone Mini Stores or multi brand outlets located across Mumbai,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement. The new offer comes a day after the new entrant in telecom sector, Reliance Jio, announced its &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer. Jio has started a price war among the operators by offering various discounts, free data and unlimited voice calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the new 4G SIM, Vodafone prepaid users get 4GB data free for a duration of 10 days. While for postpaid customers, the offer can be availed till their next billing date. &amp;ldquo;The free data shall be added to the customer&amp;rsquo;s data balance on upgrading to a 4G SIM,&amp;rdquo; the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the development, Pushpinder Singh Gujral, business head-Mumbai, Vodafone India, said, &amp;ldquo;Vodafone is proud to be the preferred telecom services provider to over 9 million customers in Mumbai. We are offering 4GB data free for our customers to experience the benefits of our Data Strong Network and enjoy unparalleled mobile internet services.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can switch to the new 4G SIM:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walk in to any nearest outlet and get your 4G SIM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To activate the 4G SIM card, use your existing Vodafone number to SMS &amp;lsquo;SIMEX &lt;your 20 digit new 4G SIM card number&gt;&amp;rsquo; to 55199 (this number will be available on the new SIM card/jacket given to you)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will receive a response SMS from 55199 with partial SIM number entered&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Send the last 6 digits of the new SIM number to 55199 within 2 hours of receiving the SMS mentioned in the above step&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you receive a success SMS, your 4G SIM will be activated within 20 minutes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replace your old SIM in the handset with the new 4G SIM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case customers face any issues with the SIM upgrade process, they can call 199 or seek assistance from the staff at any Vodafone retail store, the company&amp;rsquo;s statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio Ahead In Network Coverage But Trails In 4G Speeds: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-ahead-in-network-coverage-but-trails-in-4g-speeds-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-ahead-in-network-coverage-but-trails-in-4g-speeds-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio carries 90 per cent plus of all data traffic in the country currently while its network capacity share is closer to 35 per cent, the report said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio network coverage is significantly ahead of the other operators but the newcomer trails Airtel in 4G speeds given the high load on its network during the free offer period, says a report by Credit Suisse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our conclusion is that Jio&amp;rsquo;s network coverage is significantly ahead of the other operators. Jio has good coverage in 80 per cent plus of cities surveyed, compared to less than 30 per cent for the others. The difference is even more stark when compared only with 4G networks of incumbents (sub-15 per cent of cities),&amp;rdquo; the latest report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the newcomer did not fare as well when it came to speeds - the survey concluded that Airtel offered the best 4G speeds, while Jio was &amp;ldquo;probably bogged down by load&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We also studied the network speed results across all these locations. Airtel 4G offers the best download speeds in general (12Mbps plus). Jio, Vodafone and Idea are close to each other (7-8Mbps). We suspect Jio&amp;rsquo;s speeds are impacted by the high load on the network in the free offer period,&amp;rdquo; Credit Suisse said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio carries 90 per cent plus of all data traffic in the country currently while its network capacity share is closer to 35 per cent, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competitive pressure is expected to sustain, the report said adding that significant pressure on fundamentals will continue in coming quarters from Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already started seeing the impact of Jio on the incumbents&amp;rsquo; numbers (Bharti 3Q). Our study here shows Jio has built a significant lead in terms of network coverage, and the incumbents have a fair amount of catch up to do (especially on 4G). Importantly, going by recently announced enhanced capex plans, the company continues to invest,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study covers over 30 Indian cities that represent a &amp;ldquo;significant chunk of current data demand and revenues&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting Aadhaar To April 30 For EPFO Extends</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-extends-deadline-for-submitting-aadhaar-to-april-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-extends-deadline-for-submitting-aadhaar-to-april-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund body EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number to April 30, 2017 for its over four crore members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO has also extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have extended the deadline for submission of Aadhaar by subscribers to April 30, 2017. Besides, pensioners can also submit their life certificates till April 30,&amp;rdquo; EPFO&amp;rsquo;s Central Provident Fund Commissioner V P Joy told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO had extended the deadline several times in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also done away with the system of accepting life certificate manually through banks. Pensioners are required to provide life certificates digitally either through their mobile phones or at common service centres or bank branches providing such facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest EPFO order provides that if a pensioner is not able to submit the life certificate in digital format, then the same can be submitted in physical form with valid reasons for not submitting it digitally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also says that a pensioner would cease to receive payments from May if life certificate is not submitted by April 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Lucky Grahak, Digi Dhan: Rs 1 Crore Jackpot For Person Making Rs 1,590 Digital Payment</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of the Digi Dhan scheme, three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were declared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Pranab Mukherjee picked six winners from a draw of lots under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes, aimed at promoting digital transactions in the country. &amp;ldquo;In the consumer category, three mega Prizes of Rs 1 crore, Rs 50 lakh and Rs 25 lakh went to the Consumers using Rupay Debit Cards making digital payment of less than Rs.1,000,&amp;rdquo; an official release said. Three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were also declared at the event on the final day of the 100-day scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction of Rs. 1,590 won a Central Bank of India customer a lucky draw of Rs. 1 crore under the consumer category, as part of the government&amp;rsquo;s promotional scheme to popularise digital payments. The President congratulated all the six winners - three consumers and three merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am happy today to be a part of the digital payment movement that India has embarked upon. I congratulate each one of you who has contributed in this mission to make India a less cash society,&amp;rdquo; the President said in his address on the occasion of mega draw of lots for the two schemes held at Rashtrapati Bhawan on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners will be felicitated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on April 14 at Nagpur on the occasion of Ambedkar Jayanti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his address, Mr Mukherjee asked citizens to extend their unstinted support to the mission of a less-cash India. &amp;ldquo;India has a long way to go to become a cash less society. The initiatives of the government are a good beginning and we need to sustain and nurture these with active participation from all segments of the society&amp;hellip;It is necessary to reduce cash in circulation and impart greater urgency to promoting secure digital payment methods to ensure greater transparency,&amp;rdquo; the President said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the consumer section, the second prize of Rs 50 lakh went to a Bank of Baroda customer while the third prize of Rs. 25 lakh was bagged by a customer of Punjab National Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the three customers had made the transactions using their RuPay debit cards. The names of three winners were not yet known as the draw only displayed their transaction numbers. These will be matched with card details to identify the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital transactions have gathered momentum giving a fillip to the less cash economy post demonetisation thanks to the initiatives taken by the government. NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digidhan Vyapar schemes have played a catalytic role in making it a mass movement, the statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressing that India is on the cusp of a digital revolution, Mr Mukherjee noted that more than one billion Indians have a unique identity number with a biometric identifier which is unique in its own way. &amp;ldquo;Even countries which are technologically far more advanced than India with comparatively much smaller size population do not have such a system in place. The Aadhaar card initiative is a watershed event in the development story of India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs. 1,000 notes on November 9 last year, the government took a slew of measures to promote digital payments in the country. It had launched the Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes on December 25 last year for consumers and merchants, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes are being implemented by the National Payment Corporation of India (NPCI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the scheme, daily, weekly and monthly rewards worth Rs. 256 crore have been disbursed to over 16 lakh citizens over the past 100 days for making and accepting small transactions digitally. Over the past 100 days, everyday 15,000 consumers have qualified for total prize money of Rs. 1.5 crore, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The draw has seen a positive impact from various age groups and occupations in adopting digital payments methods. We have seen a steady increase in the number of transactions made using all payment methods,&amp;rdquo; said A P Hota, MD and CEO of National Payment Corporation of India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>