<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things that are banned for you, from opening a bank account to processing of I-T returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</guid>
      <description>If you thought that filing an income tax return or opening a bank account are the only few things which require Aadhaar cards now, then think again. The fact is Aadhaar has now been made mandatory for so many things, including availing the benefits of various social and government schemes. While for some schemes it has already been made compulsory, for some others it will be made mandatory soon.
Here we are taking a look at 10 such things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.
“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.
He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18 specified financial transactions in which quoting of PAN is mandatory now</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</guid>
      <description>Although Aadhaar is gradually gaining more importance than PAN – a ten-digit unique alphanumeric number issued by the Income Tax Department – however, PAN is still important, especially for financial transactions. According to experts, PAN is a way for the Income Tax Department to keep tabs on your financial dealings whereas Aadhaar’s main purpose is to create a centralized database of each citizen residing in India. PAN, in fact, is a very useful tool to estimate the total tax revenue being generated in the country and to be used as an identification document is not its primary job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 financial tasks to do when a parent dies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</guid>
      <description>Goodbyes are the hardest when they are final. It’s worse if it involves one of your parents. The heartbreak is probably lesser in intensity only to that of your surviving parent, the spouse who is left grappling with a crippling emotional void at the fag end of life. Yet, it is critical to take a financial reality check and you, as progeny, are the best suited to do it.
Taking stock of the finances is an overwhelming task and it’s easy to be stumped by the maze of formalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.27 Lakh Assessees Respond To Income Tax Query On Cash Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-27-lakh-assessees-respond-to-income-tax-query-on-cash-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-27-lakh-assessees-respond-to-income-tax-query-on-cash-deposits/</guid>
      <description>Responding to the SMS/email queries under &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo;, the assessees have disclosed additional 25,000 bank accounts in which cash was deposited.
The I-T Department on Monday said 5.27 lakh assessees, out of 18 lakh who were sent SMS/emails for making suspicious deposits post demonetisation, have submitted their response and warned others of &amp;lsquo;enforcement action&amp;rsquo; if they fail to respond by February 15.
It further said that 99.5 per cent of the 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>508 Km In 3 Hours: India&#39;s First Bullet Train Project In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/508-km-in-3-hours-india-s-first-bullet-train-project-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/508-km-in-3-hours-india-s-first-bullet-train-project-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his Japanese counterpart Shinzo Abe laid the foundation stone for India’s first bullet train project in Ahmedabad on Thursday. The bullet train project touted to revolutionize railways technology in the country. The first line which will connect Ahmedabad to Mumbai can cover the 508 km distance in as little as two hours, the government said. The project will be executed as a joint venture between the Indian Railways and Japanese firm Shinkansen Technology at an estimated cost of Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 smart tips which can help you save more &amp; become rich</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t want to become rich? However, getting wealthy isn’t that easy. It begins with determined consciousness to get wealthy. We all know that to become rich you need to spend less than what you earn. That is because the less you spend, the more you will be able to save. You should save and invest what you have into investments (assets) that appreciate over time. Apart from these, here we are taking a look at a few really easy and ‘anyone can do it’ strategies or DIY tips that can make you a crorepati:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.
The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.
Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar authentication a must for engineering scholarships</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>The state higher and technical education department has made authentication of Aadhaar number a must for backward engineering students to avail scholarships. The move comes against the backdrop of large-scale scholarship scam across the state.
Though decision has been welcomed by city engineering colleges, they feel the authentication process will burden them with extra work.
In a gazette notification dated April 13, the department states that every student desirous of availing benefits under the schemes specified in Schedule ‘A’ need to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo authentication process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.
Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data hack: IIT Kharagpur graduate arrested, earns Rs 40 lakh a year at Ola</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</guid>
      <description>An IIT Kharagpur graduate, Abhinav Srivastava, who allegedly hacked Aadhaar data has been arrested by Bengaluru Police. According to investigation, Srivastava had gained access to the repository of the Unique Identification Development Authority of India’s (UIDAI) Aadhaar project through the Digital India e-hospital portal. The 31-year-old hails from Uttar Pradesh and was arrested in connection with a complaint filed by the UIDAI on July 26, according to Indian Express.
Police said the complaint against Srivastava stated that he accessed UIDAI data without authorisation between January 1 and July 26 for an app called ‘eKYC Verification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Less On Petrol, Diesel While Paying Via BHIM, Cards</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-up-to-rs-0-49-litre-less-on-petrol-diesel-while-paying-via-bhim-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-up-to-rs-0-49-litre-less-on-petrol-diesel-while-paying-via-bhim-cards/</guid>
      <description>Fuel prices are sky-rocketing due to changes in global crude prices resulting in consumers to feel the pinch as the value of domestic fuel prices is determined by it. A daily revision in petrol and diesel rates by oil marketing companies has made the consumers feel the heat more. However, if you pay for fuel using the government&amp;rsquo;s BHIM or Bharat Interface for Money app, you can get 49 paise per litre off on petrol and 41 paise per litre discount on diesel, stated a tweet from Digital India&amp;rsquo;s official account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only 5 Free ATM Transactions From October, Punjab National Bank Says</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</guid>
      <description>PNB customers will have to shell out money beginning October if they carry out more than five transactions a month from the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs. At present, account holders of the country&amp;rsquo;s second largest public sector bank can make any number of transactions in a month, financial or non-financial, at the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs without attracting any charge.
&amp;ldquo;The number of free transactions and the charges beyond these free transactions for PNB customers on PNB ATMs have been revised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is exempt from PAN card Aadhaar card linking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link the existing Aadhaar numbers with the PAN cards of taxpayers with effect from July 1, 2017. In fact, Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar / Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from 1st July, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>link your SBI account to Aadhaar via ATMs and SMS: Here’s how to do it in easy steps</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-link-aadhaar-card-online-via-atm-sms-state-bank-of-india-heres-how-to-do-it-in-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-link-aadhaar-card-online-via-atm-sms-state-bank-of-india-heres-how-to-do-it-in-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Are you a State Bank of India customer and want to link your Aadhaar number to your SBI account? Or have got a message from the bank to do so? Here’s some good news for you. SBI allows its customers to link their bank accounts to their Aadhaar number in various ways, including their ATM channel and through SMS. You can also get it done by visiting any of their branches or through Internet banking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>