<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Rs 50,000 On Your Provident Fund Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-deposits-to-earn-rs-50-000-more-under-new-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-deposits-to-earn-rs-50-000-more-under-new-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund body EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation&amp;rsquo;s (EPFO) apex decision making body, the Central Board of Trustees (CBT), has recommended a minimum sum assured of Rs 2.5 lakh in the event of death of a subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The CBT has recommended amending the Employees&amp;rsquo; Deposit Linked Insurance Scheme (EDLI) to provide for minimum benefit of Rs 2.5 lakh and loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at a meeting held yesterday,&amp;rdquo; a senior official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The suggested benefits will be available to members after government approval. Initially, these will be provided for two years on a pilot basis and will be reviewed thereafter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the proposal, loyalty-cum-life benefit will be provided to all those members on retirement at 58 or 60 years who have contributed to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability. In these cases, the members who have contributed to the EDLI scheme for less than 20 years will be eligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those members whose average basic wages are up to Rs 5,000 will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of Rs 30,000. Similarly, the members with wages of Rs 5,001-10,000 Will be eligible for Rs 40,000 benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those members getting more than Rs 10,000 monthly wage will be eligible for Rs 50,000 loyalty-cum-life benefit under the proposed scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board has recommended such benefits in view of a huge EDLI corpus of Rs 18,119 crore following addition of interest that accrued on investment of this fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, the dependants of the deceased get a sum assured of up to Rs 6 lakh. There is no provision of minimum insurance and any benefit for surviving members or in cases of permanent disability under the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya launched Aadhaar Seeding Application after the meeting. The EPFO has developed this application with support of Common Service Centres (CSCs) and C-DAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CSCs are ICT-enabled front-end service delivery points at the village level for delivery of government and private services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With implementation of the seeding application, a PF member or pensioner can now walk into any of the field offices of EPFO or CSC outlets with UAN and Aadhaar and seed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO enrolled 49,39,929 workers during January-March 2017. It had launched a special enrolment scheme to cover leftout formal sector workers from January 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Developments On Your Provident Fund (PF) Money You Should Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-aadhaar-to-loyalty-scheme-5-developments-from-epfo-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-aadhaar-to-loyalty-scheme-5-developments-from-epfo-this-month/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From interest rate for 2016-17 to Aadhaar to a new loyalty scheme, there has been a lot of news coming from EPFO or Employees Provident Fund Organisation that manages your provident fund money. EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number to April 30, 2017 for its over four crore members. The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier. EPFO has also extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-the-other-developments&#34;&gt;Here are the other developments:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more. The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided. The benefits will be available for EPFO subscribers after approval from the government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;EPFO&amp;rsquo;s apex decision-making body the Central Board of Trustees (CBT) has recommended a minimum sum assured of Rs 2.5 lakh in the event of death of a subscriber. At present, the dependants of the deceased get a sum assured of up to Rs 6 lakh. There is no provision of minimum insurance and any benefit for surviving members or in cases of permanent disability under the scheme. The benefits will be available for EPFO subscribers after approval from the government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 4 crore subscribers of EPFO will get 8.65 per cent interest on provident fund deposits for 2016-17, as decided by the organisation&amp;rsquo;s trustees in December, Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya has said. The comments follow reports suggesting that the Finance Ministry is nudging the Labour Ministry to lower the EPF interest rate by up to 50 basis points. &amp;ldquo;It is not like that. The CBT (EPFO trustees) had decided to give 8.65 per cent. Our ministry keeps on discussing with Finance Ministry. We would have surplus of Rs 158 crore on providing 8.65 per cent,&amp;rdquo; Mr Dattatreya said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The board of retirement fund body EPFO deferred the proposal to raise investment in stock market to 15 per cent of its investible deposits from current 10 per cent. &amp;ldquo;It was proposed to increase investments in the Exchanges Traded Funds to 15 per cent. But trade unions representatives opposed it,&amp;rdquo; an EPFO trustee said after the meeting. The EPFO has invested Rs 18,069 crore in exchange trade funds (ETFs) till February 18, 2017 and yielded a return of 18.13 per cent on these investments. Earlier, Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya had indicated that the EPFO will increase its investment in ETFs in the backdrop of good returns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly four crore members of retirement fund body EPFO will soon be able to settle their claims like EPF withdrawal through mobile application UMANG. &amp;ldquo;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) is developing online claims settlement process by receiving application online,&amp;rdquo; Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya said in a written reply to the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Oil To Revise Petrol, Diesel Prices Daily In 5 Cities From May 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-cities-first-petrol-diesel-price-will-change-daily-from-next-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-cities-first-petrol-diesel-price-will-change-daily-from-next-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A pilot for daily revision of petrol and diesel price will be first implemented in Puducherry, Vizag in Andhra Pradesh, Udaipur in Rajasthan, Jamshedpur in Jharkhand and Chandigarh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come May 1, petrol and diesel prices will change every day in sync with international rates, much like what happens in most advanced markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-owned fuel retailers Indian Oil Corp (IOC), Bharat Petroleum Corp Ltd (BPCL) and Hindustan Petroleum Corp Ltd (HPCL), which own over 95 per cent of nearly 58,000 petrol pumps in the country, will launch a pilot for daily price revision in five select cities from May 1 and gradually extend it to all over the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ultimately, we will be driving towards market linked rates on a daily basis at all pumps across the country,&amp;rdquo; IOC Chairman B Ashok told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pilot for daily revision of petrol and diesel price will be first implemented in Puducherry, Vizag in Andhra Pradesh, Udaipur in Rajasthan, Jamshedpur in Jharkhand and Chandigarh, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State fuel retailers currently revise rates on 1st and 16th of every month based on average international price of the fuel in the preceding fortnight and currency exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of using fortnightly average, pump rates will reflect daily movement in international oil prices and rupee-US dollar fluctuations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is technically possible to change rates daily but we have to first do a pilot. Once pilot is done and its implications studied, we will extend it to other parts of the country,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ashok said the pilot is to be &amp;ldquo;launched within one month&amp;rdquo; and did not give a specific date, industry sources said the pilot is planned to be launched on May 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily price change will remove the big leaps in rates that need to be effected at the end of the fortnight and consumer will be more aligned to market dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While petrol price was freed from government control in June 2010, diesel rates were deregulated in October 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, oil companies have freedom to revise rates but often they have been guided by political considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rates differ by only a few paise between pumps of the three state fuel retailers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unbranded petrol at IOC pumps in Delhi costs Rs 66.29 per litre, while the same at BPCL pumps in the city is priced at Rs 66.37 a litre. HPCL pumps sell for Rs 66.48 per litre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unbranded diesel at IOC pumps in Delhi costs Rs 55.61, Rs 55.66 at BPCL outlets and Rs 55.69 a litre at HPCL pumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With daily changes, which are unlikely to more than few paise per litre, the political pressures for not revising rates particularly when they are to be hiked will go, sources said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petrol price was last revised downward by Rs 3.77 a litre on April and diesel rates were cut by Rs 2.91. This was the first revision in two-and-half-months as oil firms did not change prices during assembly elections in five states, including Uttar Pradesh and Punjab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ashok said prices of petrol and diesel in a particular market (city or town) will be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By and large, in a particular market it should be same. Though, there might be marginal difference from pump to pump,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Impact: Vodafone Offers Free 4GB Data On SIM Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-vodafone-offers-free-4gb-data-on-sim-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-vodafone-offers-free-4gb-data-on-sim-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Vodafone 4G SIMs are available at all Vodafone Stores, Vodafone Mini Stores or multi brand outlets located across Mumbai,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone is offering 4GB data free on upgradation to Vodafone Supernet 4G. Vodafone users in Mumbai who upgrade to a 4G SIM card (with 4G handsets) can avail the free data. &amp;ldquo;Vodafone 4G SIMs are available at all Vodafone Stores, Vodafone Mini Stores or multi brand outlets located across Mumbai,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement. The new offer comes a day after the new entrant in telecom sector, Reliance Jio, announced its &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer. Jio has started a price war among the operators by offering various discounts, free data and unlimited voice calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the new 4G SIM, Vodafone prepaid users get 4GB data free for a duration of 10 days. While for postpaid customers, the offer can be availed till their next billing date. &amp;ldquo;The free data shall be added to the customer&amp;rsquo;s data balance on upgrading to a 4G SIM,&amp;rdquo; the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the development, Pushpinder Singh Gujral, business head-Mumbai, Vodafone India, said, &amp;ldquo;Vodafone is proud to be the preferred telecom services provider to over 9 million customers in Mumbai. We are offering 4GB data free for our customers to experience the benefits of our Data Strong Network and enjoy unparalleled mobile internet services.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can switch to the new 4G SIM:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walk in to any nearest outlet and get your 4G SIM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To activate the 4G SIM card, use your existing Vodafone number to SMS &amp;lsquo;SIMEX &lt;your 20 digit new 4G SIM card number&gt;&amp;rsquo; to 55199 (this number will be available on the new SIM card/jacket given to you)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will receive a response SMS from 55199 with partial SIM number entered&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Send the last 6 digits of the new SIM number to 55199 within 2 hours of receiving the SMS mentioned in the above step&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you receive a success SMS, your 4G SIM will be activated within 20 minutes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replace your old SIM in the handset with the new 4G SIM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case customers face any issues with the SIM upgrade process, they can call 199 or seek assistance from the staff at any Vodafone retail store, the company&amp;rsquo;s statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know how Aadhaar Pay works</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/game-changer-digital-push-know-aadhaar-pay-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/game-changer-digital-push-know-aadhaar-pay-works/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi today launched Aadhaar Pay at Nagpur on the birth anniversary of the Father of Indian Constitution Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar. The app is expected to revolutionise digital payments, especially in rural India, as it is extremely easy to use for merchants as well as customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the government’s digital payments campaign, Aadhaar Pay comes after the launch of the BHIM App on December 30. While launching the BHIM app, PM Modi had said more work was being done which would increase the power of BHIM so much that people would be able to withdraw money even with fingerprints&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the government launched BHIM as a payment application for peer-to-peer transactions post demonetisation, Aadhaar Pay is meant for merchants to receive digital payments from customers over the counter through Aadhaar authentication. The government has named the new payments system as BHIM-Aadhaar sewa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay will be supported by 20 banks initially. The government has requested all public sector banks to go live with Aadhaar Pay and the National Payments Corporation of India, the implementing agency for Aadhaar Enabled Payments Systems, has extended help to the banks to ensure smooth onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-game-changer-app&#34;&gt;A game-changer app&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While, so far, digital payments have been dependent on credit/debit cards and mobile phones, Aadhaar Pay won’t require a phone or a card. Even if a user cannot read or write, he would be able to use it. Low mobile-phone penetration and digital literacy are considered big obstacles in the government’s plan to involve the masses in the digital payments system. Aadhaar Pay will face no such obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-aadhaar-pay-works&#34;&gt;How Aadhaar Pay works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is only for merchants. A merchant has to download the app on a smartphone, connect the app to his bank account and link the phone to a biometric scan machine. To make payment, the customer just have to give his fingerprint. The customer must have an Aadhaar-linked bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;free-transactions&#34;&gt;Free transactions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since transaction charges discourage adoption of digital payments, especially in small towns and rural India, the Aadhaar Pay will levy no transaction fee on the merchant or the customer unlike the card-based digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-secure-app&#34;&gt;A secure app&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Niti Aayog, the Aadhaar Pay is a safe app that uses two main platforms—Aadhaar Payment Bridge (APB) and Aadhaar Enabled Payment System (AEPS). APB will act as repository between the banks and the customers to provide a smooth flow of transactions, while AEPS will help in authenticating the online process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-secure-app-1&#34;&gt;A secure app&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Niti Aayog, the Aadhaar Pay is a safe app that uses two main platforms—Aadhaar Payment Bridge (APB) and Aadhaar Enabled Payment System (AEPS). APB will act as repository between the banks and the customers to provide a smooth flow of transactions, while AEPS will help in authenticating the online process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;incentives-scheme&#34;&gt;Incentives scheme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay comes with incentives for merchants and customers-cash back and referral bonus. Under the referral bonus scheme, both the existing user who refers BHIM and the new user who adopts BHIM would get a cash bonus credited directly to their account. Under the cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. The government has an outlay of Rs 495 crore for the scheme which will run till October 14.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar With Your PAN Card Just by Uploading a Scanned Proof</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Individuals struggling to link their Permanent Account Number with Aadhaar because of differently spelt names can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the tax department is planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for a One-Time Password (OTP), provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the linking of PAN with Aadhaar being made mandatory, individuals can log on to e-filing website of the income tax department or NSDL but the seeding cannot happen if the name is differently spelt in the two cards – like use of full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, government has allowed a simple uploading of a scanned copy of PAN on the Aadhaar website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had through amendment to tax proposals in the Finance Bill of the Budget for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-filing portal has already activated a functionality of linking PAN with Aadhaar. Over 1.08 crore assessees have already Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official said that linking of PAN with Aadhaar should not be cumbersome for people whose registered mobile number with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In case the taxpayer is unable to link PAN with Aadhaar because of discrepancy in name, we are advising them to log in to the Aadhaar website, request for a name change and upload a scanned copy of PAN card as supported proof. This is the simplest way to update name in Aadhaar and only the registered mobile number has to be functional,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This option will hold good for people who have given short forms of their name or in some cases there are some spelling errors in the name provided in Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in certain cases, there are people who have got married and changed their surname and updated the same while getting Aadhaar number, but it does not get reflected in PAN documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such and other name change cases, the tax department is planning to give the OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number and the tax department, on its part, would match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are also contemplating that when taxpayers with name discrepancy logs into the e-filing website for linkage, we will send OTP to the Aadhaar registered mobile number. The taxpayer can link PAN using the OTP. While generating the OTP, we will just check if the year of birth of the taxpayer in PAN card matches with the year given in the Aadhaar document,” the official added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting Aadhaar To April 30 For EPFO Extends</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-extends-deadline-for-submitting-aadhaar-to-april-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-extends-deadline-for-submitting-aadhaar-to-april-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund body EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number to April 30, 2017 for its over four crore members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO has also extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have extended the deadline for submission of Aadhaar by subscribers to April 30, 2017. Besides, pensioners can also submit their life certificates till April 30,&amp;rdquo; EPFO&amp;rsquo;s Central Provident Fund Commissioner V P Joy told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO had extended the deadline several times in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also done away with the system of accepting life certificate manually through banks. Pensioners are required to provide life certificates digitally either through their mobile phones or at common service centres or bank branches providing such facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest EPFO order provides that if a pensioner is not able to submit the life certificate in digital format, then the same can be submitted in physical form with valid reasons for not submitting it digitally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also says that a pensioner would cease to receive payments from May if life certificate is not submitted by April 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ATMs Are Going Dry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1: The ATM expansion era is over. ATM extensions will no longer be part of future banking growth, and future ATMs may well be of the mobile kind focused only on rural cash deliveries. But even here, the growth will be limited. Standalone ATM companies may have a future, but only because banks may choose to outsource all their existing networks to them so that they can focus on growing the digital business themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: The phenomenon of business correspondents will rise in the short run, and then collapse as rural and unbanked sectors accept digital cash as the way to transfer money. The limiting factors are the absence of reliable power supplies in remote areas, and the gap in the spread of mobile phones to the poor. These shortcomings will be addressed over the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3: Once ATMs and cash start falling in terms of importance, the cash logistics business will, perforce, have to shrink. It is already in trouble after a few months of glory during the peak weeks of demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4: Many banking services may be outsourced. As ATMs shrink, branch rationalisation will also be the order of the day. Banks may outsource one-time customer-acquisition operations and use Aadhaar-based-eKYC to grow their customer bases, as Kotak Mahindra Bank’s 811 account is trying to do. E-KYC will soon become the standard way of acquiring new customers, both for regular banks and payment banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5: Cyber security will see a boom. As digital cash becomes the norm, the real growth in financial sector jobs will be in cyber security, since digital currency systems are vulnerable to hacking and fraud. For example, the unified payments interface (UPI) which allows for peer-to-peer payments using mobile phone numbers could be vulnerable to fraudsters who manage to clone your SIM card. In the past, fraudsters have cloned ATM magnetic strips; next they will target SIMs. Since smartphones will essentially become your digital banking interface, technologies to protect you from losses when you misplace or lose your phone will become paramount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6: Credit cards and payments systems will move out of the physical category and turn virtual. In future, credit and debit cards may be embedded in your phone, as the new Samsung Pay product indicates. Samsung Pay uses finger-print authorisation and PIN for payment at merchant nodes without any physical card having to be swiped. Kotak’s 811 app-based bank account offers virtual debit cards and scan-and-pay options. Once the Bharat QR Code becomes widely adopted by merchants, e-wallets too will become interoperable like credit cards issued by various banks are now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7: Phishing and fraud insurance will become big business. Once the smartphone becomes your wallet, you have to buy insurance to cover yourself against the possibility of fraud. Credit card fraud insurance is not big in India, but digital cash fraud may need better insurance than cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8: The biggest business of them all will be data analytics. As bank charges and payment usage fees fall to low levels, both due to regulation and high-volume usage, banks, virtual banks, card companies, and e-wallets will have to make money from the customer data they now own, as Aadhaar man Nandan Nilekani has repeatedly emphasised. This means financial companies must understand customers better from their spending and payments habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9: Bank employment will fall, as banks hollow out in terms of physical infrastructure and some jobs get outsourced. But they will pay top dollar to techies, since banking is being taken over by technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India is on the cusp of a huge shift in its financial sector. The old certainties are gone. The jobs market is shifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reassuring face of Gandhi on the currency note, with all its certainties, will be replaced with the virtual face of Bhimrao Ambedkar, the Modi government’s mascot for digital cash, with all its exciting uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आयकर विभाग करेगा 60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों की जांच</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-operation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; के दूसरे चरण में आयकर विभाग 60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों की जांच करेगा। शुक्रवार को दोबारा लॉन्च हुए इस ऑपरेशन का मकसद नोटबंदी के बाद पैदा हुए ब्लैक मनी का पता लगाना है। विभाग ने इससे पहले ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के पहले चरण में नोटबंदी के दौरान संदिग्ध लेन-देन करने वाले 18 लाख लोगों को नोटिस भेजा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग की नीति निर्माता ईकाइ केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (CBDT) का कहना है कि वह पिछले साल 9 नवंबर से इस साल की 28 फरवरी तक 9,332 करोड़ रुपए की अघोषित आय का पता लगा चुका है। बता दें कि 8 नवंबर को पीएम मोदी ने 500 और 1000 के नोटबंदी की घोषणा की थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों (जिसमें 1300 हाइ रिस्क लोग भी शामिल हैं) की जांच में पहचान हो चुकी है। नोटबंदी के दौरान अधिकतर बड़े लेन-देन कैश में करने वाले लोग नजर में थे। हाइ वैल्यू प्रॉपर्टी खरीद के 6000 मामले और विदेश के शेयर बाजार में पैसा लगाने या विदेश पैसा भेजने के 6,600 मामलों में बारीकी से जांच-पड़ताल होगी। अगर जवाब संतोषजनक नहीं माना गया तो विस्तृत पूछताछ की जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ITR में देनी होगी नोटबंदी के दौरान जमा रकम की जानकारी!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने बताया कि आधुनिक डेटा विश्लेषण का इस्तेमाल करते हुए संदिग्ध कैश डिपॉजिट का पता लगाया है। इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने इस साल 31 जनवरी को &amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; लॉन्च किया गया था। जिसके तहत 17.92 लाख लोगों को ऑनलाइन नोटिस भेजा गया था जिसमें से 9.46 लाख लोगों ने विभाग के प्रश्नों का जवाब दिया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जानें, क्रेडिट कार्ड के बेहद &#39;खास&#39; फायदे</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड रखना यानी उधार की जिंदगी जीना, अरे यह हम नहीं कह रहे बल्कि आमतौर पर इस तरह की बातें हमारे आसपास के लोग बोलते दिख जाते हैं। अगर आप भी ऐसा ही सोचते हैं तो अगले कुछ मिनट्स में आपके यह सोच बदलने वाली है। जी हां, आज हम आपको बता रहे हैं क्रेडिट कार्ड रखने के कुछ बेहद खास फायदे&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-ब-क&#34;&gt;कैश बैक&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कई क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां कुछ खास ब्रैंड्स के साथ 10 से 20 प्रतिशत तक का कैश बैक ऑफर देती हैं। यानी कैशलेश पेमेंट भी करिए और बचत भी पाइए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;र-व-र-ड-प-इ-ट&#34;&gt;रिवॉर्ड पॉइंट&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कैैश बैक के अलावा सभी क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां प्रत्येक ट्रांजैक्शन के वेट के अनुसार पॉइंट्स देती हैं। पॉइंट्स आपके खाते में जुड़ते जाते हैं और बाद में आप इन्हें रिडीम कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-र-ड-ट-ह-स-ट-र&#34;&gt;क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड के प्रयोग से आप अपनी क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री अपने साथ रख सकते हैं। यानि आपको पता रहता है कि आपने कब कहां कितना पैसा खर्च किया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-क-झ-झट-नह&#34;&gt;कैश का झंझट नहीं&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड का सबसे बड़ा फायदा यह है कि आपको इस बात की चिंता करने की नहीं जरूरत होती है कि बैंक में बैलेंस है या नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;emi-क-व-कल-प&#34;&gt;EMI का विकल्प&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अगर आपका मन कोई बड़ी चीज खरीदने का है, लेकिन पैसे नहीं, तो क्रेडिट कार्ड से खरीद कर आप उस पैसे को ईएमआई यानि किश्तों में बदल सकते हैं। कई बार क्रेडिट कार्ड जीरो प्रतिशत ब्याज पर ईएमआई देते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भविष्य में सभी कार्डों की जगह ले लेगा आधार कार्ड: अरुण जेटली</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लोकसभा ने बुधवार को वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली की ओर से पेश वित्त विधेयक को चर्चा के बाद पारित कर दिया। चर्चा के दौरान अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि आने वाले दिनों में आधार ही एकमात्र कार्ड होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि भविष्य में यह वोटर आईडी कार्ड और पैन कार्ड जैसे दस्तावेजों की जगह ले लेगा। इन सभी के मुकाबले एक आधार कार्ड ही किसी भी व्यक्ति की पहचान के लिए काफी होगा। लोकसभा में एक सांसद की ओर से पूछा गया था कि आधार कार्ड जारी किए जाने के बाद भी कई कार्डों की व्यवस्था क्यों लागू है। इसके जवाब में जेटली ने यह बात कही। उन्होंने कहा कि आने वाले वक्त में आधार ही व्यक्तिगत पहचान और पते के लिए पुख्ता सबूत होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाए जाने के सवाल पर जेटली ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;तमाम लोगों को कई पैन नंबर इस्तेमाल करते हुए पाया गया है। इसलिए सरकार ने इस व्यवस्था को लागू करने का फैसला लिया है।&amp;rsquo; जेटली ने एक सवाल के जवाब में कहा, &amp;lsquo;आज 98 फीसदी नागरिकों के पास आधार कार्ड है। टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के दौरान व्यक्ति आधार नंबर दे सकता है या यह बता सकता है कि उसने आवेदन कर दिया है, लेकिन टैक्स चोरी की अनुमति नहीं दी जा सकती है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा लोगों को टैक्स की व्यवस्था से जोड़ने की जरूरत है। इसीलिए सरकार ने इस साल टैक्स स्लैब को नीचे लाने का प्रयास किया है। चर्चा के दौरान जेटली ने नोटबंदी को सही फैसला करार देते हुए इकॉनमिस्ट मार्टिन वॉल्फ के एक आर्टिकल का उदाहरण देते हुए कहा कि उन्होंने इसकी सराहना की है। जेटली ने लेख का हवाला देते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;इससे सरकार को ब्लैक मनी पर टैक्स लगाने का मौका मिला है। बड़े पैमाने पर कैश रखने वाले लोगों के लिए रिस्क पैदा हुआ है। इसके अलावा क्रिमिनल्स के पास जमा संपत्ति सरकार के पास आई है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airtel, Vodafone Launch New Plans To Counter Jio. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-vodafone-launch-new-plans-to-counter-jio-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-vodafone-launch-new-plans-to-counter-jio-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As new comer Jio, the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, continues to offer discounted tariffs under its &amp;ldquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer in a bid to attract more customers, top two telecom players - Airtel and Vodafone - have launched data-oriented prepaid plans and offers to restrict their existing customers to switch to Reliance Jio. From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some of the recharge plans offered by Airtel and Vodafone to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 399 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &lt;em&gt;Rs. 399&lt;/em&gt; recharge pack, Airtel is offering 1GB of 4G data per day along with free voice calls to any network for 70 days. However, there are some limitations on voice calls. You can do 300 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to Airtel (1200 minutes in a week) and for other networks, 3,000 minutes of free local and STD calls for 70 days. If you exhaust the free minutes, Rs. 0.10 per minute will be charged.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bharti-airtel_650x400_61492413333.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel is offering 2GB of data per day at 4G speed for 28 days under its new Rs. 345 recharge pack. Also, now there is no restriction with regard to the timing of data consumption. Under the earlier Rs. 345 recharge pack, users were restricted to use only 500 MB of data daily from 6 am till midnight , and the remaining 500 MB between 12 am and 6 am. Along with the above data, users will also get free voice calls to Airtel and other networks as it is in the Rs. 399 pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs. 244 recharge, users will get 1 GB of 4G data per day for 70 days without any restriction on usage timing. But this pack offers free calls on Airtel networks only (300 minutes of daily Airtel-to-Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for a week for 70 days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above three recharge packs of Airtel have become active from April 15, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs. 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week. If you cross the call limit, a fee of 30 paise per minute will be charged for every call. This offer is not available for every Vodafone users. You can check if the offer is available for you by dialing *121# from your Vodafone number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>