<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Now Pay Later: IRCTC To Offer Train Tickets On Credit</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potential passengers can book a ticket and pay for it online within 14 days, IRCTC said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation or IRCTC has decided to make booking tickets a hassle-free affair by providing a &amp;lsquo;buy tickets now and pay later&amp;rsquo; service for regular travelers. Soon passengers would be able to buy tickets from the IRCTC website and pay later, an IRCTC official told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential passengers can book a ticket five days prior to the journey with a service charge of 3.5 per cent and pay it in the next 14 days, IRCTC spokesperson Sandip Dutta said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has collaborated with a Mumbai-based firm ePayLater for adding the new service option. The ePayLater platform allows persons to log out immediately after booking tickets and make payments later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The railway agency had earlier introduced &amp;lsquo;pay on delivery&amp;rsquo; category for train tickets booked using its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be applicable for new &amp;ldquo;Buy Now Pay Later&amp;rdquo; feature, users will have fill in basic details including Aadhaar and PAN card details after which they will be able to use the feature with a One Time Password (OTP), ePayLater said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your NPS Account With Aadhaar Number</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPS subscribers have the facility to add their Aadhaar numbers online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPS or National Pension Scheme subscribers have been advised to add Aadhaar number to their accounts. Aadhaar is a 12-digit number issued by Unique Identification Authority of India or UIDAI based on the demographic and biometric information of the person. NPS subscribers can add their Aadhaar numbers online. The Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority (PFRDA), the body which manages NPS, been taking a number of measures to simplify the processes. For example, the Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority has done away with the requirement of submission of a physical application form for opening of an NPS account if done through Aadhaar verification and e-signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to add Aadhaar to your NPS account online:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Log-in to your NPS account (www.cra-nsdl.com)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Click on &amp;ldquo;Update Details&amp;rdquo; tab and then select the option &amp;ldquo;Add/Update Aadhaar Number&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Submit your Aadhaar number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Enter the OTP received from UIDAI on your registered mobile number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) After authentication through OTP, Aadhaar will be linked to your PRAN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PRAN or Permanent Retirement Account Number is a unique number allotted to NPS subscribers that remains the same for the rest of subscriber&amp;rsquo;s life)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NPS body has said that a subscriber is required to seed the Aadhaar in his or her PRAN through this process even if Aadhaar was provided earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: PFRDA has said that the name registered against your PRAN should exactly match the name as registered with &amp;ldquo;UIDAI&amp;rdquo; in Aadhaar. If the correction is required on PRAN card, then the NPS subscriber has to submit a self-attested PRAN card copy and a self-attested Aadhaar card copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For government subscribers, the Aadhaar seeding process will be completed once the request initiated by a subscriber is authorised online by his /her respective Nodal Office, PFRDA said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How railway insurance has become a boon for many</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the Railway Ministry introduced an optional Indian railway travel insurance scheme for e-ticketing passengers in September 2016, the move was welcomed. But little did we know how useful the policy would become soon after. Given the recent spate of train accidents that have left many passengers injured and caused several deaths, the insurance scheme has come as a boon for many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy can be bought by passengers when booking tickets online from the IRCTC website or through the mobile app. Earlier, the cost of this policy was 92 paise per passenger for an insurance cover of Rs 10 lakh in cases of demise or permanent disability. However, Dipankar Acharya, Country Head-Affinity and Strategic Relationships, Royal Sundaram General Insurance, points out, “From 10 December 2016 the cost of premium for this policy is subsidised by the railways so passengers don’t have to pay anything. Everyone should opt for this insurance policy while travelling by railways.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy is valid from the time of departure of train to the time of arrival of train at the destination. If an accident occurs during the journey, the injured passenger or the nominee of the deceased passenger will get the claim amount. If an insured passenger is injured, and it causes their demise within 12 months of the accident, their nominee can also claim Rs 10 lakh as per insurance policy. In case of injuries, passenger can claim hospitalisation expenses up to Rs 2 lakh which includes room rent for hospital, medicines, diagnostic test, nursing charges, ICU charges, operation theatre charges, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the exclusions under this policy are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intentional self-injury, suicide or attempted suicide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim in instances wherein ticket was booked by the Insured, but they did not board the train, irrespective of whether the train ticket was cancelled or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim in instances where the ticket was booked but wasn’t confirmed, but the passenger still boarded the train.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any medical treatment which was not medically necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has tied up with three general insurance companies - ICICI Lombard, Royal Sundaram and Shriram General Insurance - for policy issuance. Once you book the tickets, you will receive the policy details on your registered mobile number and mentioned email ID. The next important step is to update the name of your nominee on the insurance company’s website before travelling. “The benefit of appointing a nominee is that it helps to settle the claim quickly in the wake of unfortunate train accidents. If a nominee is not appointed, the process of claim settlement much longer, since legal heir certificate has to be produced,” says Acharya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a claim, the insured or nominee must submit a report of the railway authority confirming the accident of the train, a claim form, medical reports, death or disability certificate, ID proof, and NEFT details and a cancelled cheque to the insurance company. After the submission, the claim is settled within 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Easing the burden&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The insured passenger or nominee can claim the following amounts.&lt;/em&gt;
*On death: Rs 10 lakh
*On permanent total disability: Rs 10 lakh
*On permanent partial disability: Rs 7.5 lakh
*Hospitalisation expenses for injury: Rs 2 lakh
*Transportation of mortal remains: Rs 10,000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 19 A Day 4G Data, Unlimited Calls In New Plans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-offers-4g-data-unlimited-calls-in-new-plans-starting-rs-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-offers-4g-data-unlimited-calls-in-new-plans-starting-rs-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone SuperWeek is priced at Rs 49 and will come with a validity of seven days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India on Thursday announced integrated plans offering unlimited voice and bonus data to its prepaid customers starting from Rs 19 per day. Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s two integrated &amp;ldquo;Voice plus Data&amp;rdquo; plans - Vodafone SuperDay and Vodafone SuperWeek - will enable its prepaid customers to enjoy benefits of unlimited local and STD calling with free data up to 250 MB for seven days. Under its Vodafone SuperDay plan, Vodafone is offering unlimited local and STD Vodafone-to-Vodafone calls and 100 MB data on 4G handsets at Rs 19 per day, the company said in a press release. Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s move comes amid heightened competition witnessed by existing operators in India&amp;rsquo;s telecom industry due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, say analysts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priced at Rs 19, Vodafone SuperDay will come with a validity of one day. Vodafone SuperWeek is priced at Rs 49 and will be valid for seven days. Under the Vodafone SuperWeek plan, the prepaid customers of the telecom operator will get 250 MB of data on 4G handsets, besides unlimited local and STD Vodafone-to-Vodafone calls, the company further said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India, a wholly-owned subsidiary of British telecom company Vodafone Group Plc, is also offering 100 minutes of calls to other networks as an additional benefits in a separate Vodafone SuperWeek plan priced at Rs 89. Vodafone prepaid customers recharging with the Rs 89 plan will get free local and STD calls on its own network, 100 minutes of local and STD calls on other networks and 250 MB of data on 4G devices, the press release added.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/vodafone-prepaid-650-400_650x400_51495700068.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At Vodafone, it is our constant endeavour to provide the best network, service experience and value to our customers. We are delighted to launch SuperDay andSuperWeek under our &amp;lsquo;Super&amp;rsquo; umbrella with the key objective of offering pocket friendly and affordable integrated plans that will appeal to the prepaid customers,&amp;rdquo; said Sandeep Kataria, director-commercial at Vodafone India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The SuperDay and SuperWeek packs are available across all retail outlets, website and the MyVodafone app,&amp;rdquo; the Vodafone India statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These plans will further enable our customers to remain confidently connected and enjoy a worry free Vodafone SuperNetTM4G experience on our best network ever. Moreover, these integrated plans come with unrestricted repeat purchase options ensuring more value to the customer,&amp;rdquo; Mr Kataria added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, another telecom operator Bharti Airtel announced new broadband plans, offering up to 100 per cent additional high speed data benefits. Bharti Airtel, whose broadband internet plans in the national capital start from Rs. 899 a month, said its new plans were aimed at driving India&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Jio, the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a variety of recharge options starting from Rs 19 to its prepaid subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s telecom customer base grew by about half a per cent to 119.45 crore in March, data from telecom regulator TRAI (Telecom Regulatory Authority of India) showed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI&#39;s New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1. SBI has clarified that the Rs. 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through its mobile wallet app. SBI’s app Bank Buddy is a new facility that enables withdrawal of cash through ATMs using the bank&amp;rsquo;s mobile wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal saving bank accounts in a month will continue to get eight free ATM transactions (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks) in metros and 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks), the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applies to the Basic Savings Banks Deposit Accounts, SBI further said. SBI’s basic savings account is a limited-services bank account aimed at poorer sections of society to encourage them to start saving without any burden of charges or fees. This type of bank account comes with an ATM-cum-debit free of cost and no annual maintenance charges. A basic savings bank deposit account holder is not eligible to open any other savings bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective June 1. Here are some of the other key changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS or Immediate Payment Service will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh; Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh; and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh
.
&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; If a customer wishes to exchange of more than 20 soiled notes or if the total value of soiled notes is above Rs. 5,000, SBI said it will charge Rs. 2 plus service charge for every soiled note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customer with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs. 30 plus service tax for a 10-leaf cheque book, Rs. 75 with service tax for 25-leaf cheque book and Rs. 150 plus service tax for a 50-leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issuance of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only RuPay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs. 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs. 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp scam alert! how to be safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-be-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-be-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A WhatsApp scam is going viral all around the world where users could be tricked into paying a fake subscription fee. WhatsApp users are being targeted by a fake message which falsely claims their current &amp;lsquo;subscription&amp;rsquo; has expired.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A WhatsApp scam is going viral all around the world where users could be tricked into paying a fake subscription fee. WhatsApp users are being targeted by a fake message which falsely claims their current ‘subscription’ has expired. It encourages the users to tap on a weird link. While WhatsApp is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a hugely popular messaging app with more than a billion global users, it also is a prime target for malware and scammers. The new malicious link has been telling WhatsApp users that their ‘subscription has expired’. This message is being circulated all around WhatsApp. Additionally, the message asks its users for a verification of their accounts. It also asks the users to buy a lifetime subscription for 0.99 British pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that WhatsApp is a free messaging service, and it does not charge its users at all. There was a time, long back, when it used to charge a small annual amount from its users, but now it does not. The link which is going viral is essentially a scam and you should refrain from clicking on it. If you click on the malicious link, it might give access of your personal data including your bank details to hackers. The fake WhatsApp message reads as: “Your subscription has expired. To verify your account and purchase a lifetime subscription for just 0.99 GBP simply tap on this link.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, several users have taken to Twitter where they are warning others about the new scam. You have been advised to delete the message immediately, if you get it, and also block the sender. In order to block a contact which is not saved to your device, open the WhatsApp conversation and click on ‘Block’. Users may also report the user under ‘Spam’ category. In case you received the fake message from one of your contacts, you can block them too, by clicking on the menu button present on the WhatsApp home screen. Just select Settings, Go to Account, Go to Privacy, Select ‘Blocked contacts’. Then add that contact to your Blocked list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users who have already clicked on the link can safeguard themselves by running an antivirus software on their smartphones to make sure they are not infected with malware.
There have been many such instances where hackers have made use of WhatsApp to circulate dangerous links. Earlier, a spam message was circulated on the messaging app, where it invited users to a WhatsApp Gold version, an invite-only club with special features where they could be able to meet movie stars. There have been cases where links were circulated inviting users to download video-calling. These messages also claimed that PM Narendra Modi wanted to give everyone in India, ‘Rs 500 balance’ free for their mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how you can link PAN with Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-you-can-link-pan-with-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-you-can-link-pan-with-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per the recent amendments made in income-tax laws, Aadhaar card and PAN must be linked, failing which PAN shall be cancelled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-order-to-link-pan-and-aadhaar-card-following-steps-are-to-be-followed&#34;&gt;In order to link PAN and Aadhaar card, following steps are to be followed:-&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a) First register on the Income tax e-filing portal (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://incometax&#34;&gt;http://incometax&lt;/a&gt; indiaefiling.gov.in”) if you are not already registered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b) Log-in to the e-filing portal of the income tax department by entering the log-in ID, password and date of birth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c) On logging in to the site, a pop up window will appear, prompting you to link your PAN card with Aadhaar card. If it doesn’t come, then click on “profile settings” and then “Link Aadhaar”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d) Details regarding name, date of birth and gender will already be mentioned as per the details submitted at the time of registration on the e-filing portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e) Verify the details on screen with the ones mentioned on your Aadhaar card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f) If the details match, enter your Aadhaar card number and click on the “Link Aadhaar” button. If the details do not match, it may pose a problem and the person is advised to get the details amended in his Aadhaar or PAN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;g) A pop-up message will display that your Aadhaar card has been successfully linked to your PAN card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ज्यादा EMI तो नहीं भर रहे हैं आप? यूं पता करें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/are-you-paying-more-emi-for-your-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/are-you-paying-more-emi-for-your-housing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;एक भारी-भरकम होम लोन की ईएमआई आपको &amp;lsquo;गरीब&amp;rsquo; बना सकती है। यह ऐसे हालात होते हैं जहां व्यक्ति महंगी अचल संपत्ति का मालिक तो है लेकिन ईएमआई का भुगतान करने के बाद अन्य खर्चों के लिए उसके पास कुछ नहीं बचता। यह जानने के लिए कि आप अपने घर के लिए ज्यादा भुगतान तो नहीं कर रहे, इन सवालों के जवाब देकर देखें कितने अंक मिले हैं आपको&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अपने खर्चे का अनुमान इस आधार पर लगाएं-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A- 1 पॉइंट
B- 2 पॉइंट
C- 3 पॉइंट&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- हाउस लोन चुकाने के लिए कितने साल बचे हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) &amp;gt;10 साल
b) 5-10 साल
c) &amp;lt;5 साल&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- अपनी आय का कितना हिस्सा होम लोन ईएमआई चुकाने में खर्च करते हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) आय का आधे से ज्यादा हिस्सा
b) आय का लगभग आधा हिस्सा
c) आय का आधे से कम हिस्सा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3- पर्सनल और कार लोन मिलाकर आपको कितने लोन चुकाने हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) मुझे दो से ज्यादा लोन चुकाने हैं।
b) मुझे दो लोन चुकाने हैं।
c) मुझे सिर्फ एक लोन चुकाना है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4- जरूरत पड़ने पर आप कितनी जल्दी अपनी संपत्ति को बेच सकते हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) लगभग दो साल
b) 12 से 24 महाने के बीच
c) 12 महीनों में&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5- लोन की ईएमआई और घर खर्च के बाद आय का कितना हिस्सा सेविंग्स के लिए बचता है?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) &lt;10%
b) 10-30%
c) &gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आपका स्कोर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 पॉइंट्स से ज्यादा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप एक बेहतर स्थिति में हैं और बिना किसी परेशानी के अपनी सभी जरूरतों को पूरा कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8-11 पॉइंट्स&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप सभी जरूरतों के लिए योगदान करने में तब तक मुश्किल स्थिति में हैं, जब तक आप अपनी इनकम-प्रोफ़ाइल बढ़ाने या लागत में कटौती करने में सक्षम न हों।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 पॉइंट्स से कम&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप व्यावहारिक रूप से &amp;lsquo;गरीब-घर&amp;rsquo; हालात में रह रहे हैं। जरूरतें मुश्किल से पूरी हो रही हैं, ऐसे में आपको तत्काल विकल्पों का मूल्यांकन करना होगा ताकि अन्य आवश्यकताओं पर समझौता न करना पड़े।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पीएम नरेंद्र मोदी ने बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी के खिलाफ ऐक्शन तेज करने का दिया आदेश</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/prime-minister-narendra-modi-orders-speedy-action-against-unaccounted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/prime-minister-narendra-modi-orders-speedy-action-against-unaccounted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;काले धन पर अंकुश के लिए नोटबंदी जैसा कड़ा कदम उठाने के बाद केंद्र की नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार के निशाने पर अब बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी है। प्रधानमंत्री मोदी ने राजस्व अधिकारियों के साथ समीक्षा बैठक में ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के बारे में जानकारी ली। सूत्रों के मुताबिक पीएम मोदी ने बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी पर ऐक्शन का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैठक में पीएम मोदी ने वित्त मंत्रालय के अधिकारियों से बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी रखने वालों के खिलाफ कार्रवाई तेज करने को कहा। सरकारी सूत्रों के मुताबिक पीएम ने कहा कि ई-असेस्मन्ट जल्द से जल्द लागू होना चाहिए ताकि न्यूनतम हस्तक्षेप हो। असेस्मन्ट कम्प्यूटराइज्ड होना चाहिए। पीएम ने यह भी कहा कि टैक्स के दायरे में और लोग आएं ताकि कर का आधार बढ़ाया जा सके।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने सोमवार को वित्त मंत्रालय द्वारा वस्तु और सेवा कर (जीएसटी) को लागू करने को लेकर की गई तैयारियों और नोटबंदी के बाद कालेधन के खिलाफ अभियान की समीक्षा की। सूत्रों ने बताया कि राजस्व विभाग के साथ बैठक में मोदी ने जीएसटी को लेकर तैयारियों का जायजा लिया। सूत्रों ने कहा कि इस समीक्षा बैठक में वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली, राजस्व सचिव हसमुख अधिया और राजस्व विभाग के अन्य वरिष्ठ अधिकारी मौजूद थे।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सवालों के जवाब न देने वालों के घर कभी भी पहुंच सकते हैं आयकर विभाग के अधिकारी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/expect-a-visit-from-taxman-if-youve-ignored-income-tax-departments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/expect-a-visit-from-taxman-if-youve-ignored-income-tax-departments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;जिन लोगों ने नोटबंदी के दौरान अपने खाते में मोटी रकम की थी और उस नकदी के स्रोत की जानकारी अब तक नहीं दी है, उनके घर इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट के अधिकारी कभी भी पहुंच सकते हैं। टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स से कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमने इस अभियान को ऐसा रखने की कोशिश की है कि यह दखलंदाजी न लगे, लेकिन अगर लोग खुद आगे नहीं आते तो खासतौर पर बड़े डिपॉजिट वाले मामलों में कुछ वेरिफिकेशन की जरूरत होगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत ऐसे 18 लाख लोगों को एसएमएस और ई-मेल भेजे हैं, जिनके बैंक अकाउंट में 50 दिनों के डीमॉनेटाइजेशन विंडो के दौरान 5 लाख रुपये से ज्यादा रकम जमा कराई गई थी और जिनके डिपॉजिट ट्रांजैक्शंस उनकी इनकम के हिसाब से मेल नहीं खाते। फेसलेस एक्सरसाइज के तहत लोगों से डिपार्टमेंट के पोर्टल पर डिपॉजिट के बारे में सफाई देने के लिए कहा गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लगभग 7.3 लाख लोगों ने 15 फरवरी की बढ़ाई गई समय सीमा के दौरान ईमेल का जवाब दिया और जमा पर सफाई दी है। जो सफाई नहीं देंगे, उनके मामले में डिपार्टमेंट वेरिफिकेशन करेगा। उनसे इनकम टैक्स ऑफिस आकर डिपॉजिट के बारे में सफाई देने के लिए कहा जा सकता है। ऑफिस नहीं आने पर टैक्स ऑफिसर उनके घर जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी के दौरान जिन लोगों ने मोटी रकम जमा कराई थी, लेकिन उसके बारे में सफार्इ नहीं दी थी, उनके पास प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (PMGKY) के तहत 50% टैक्स देकर और 25% रकम चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज जमा कराने का मौका होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स अफसर ऐसे कुछ बड़े मामलों में नोटिस भेजने या सर्वे करने के बारे में सोच रहे हैं, जिनमें लोगों ने उस डिपॉजिट के बारे में संतोषजनक जवाब नहीं दिया था, जो उनकी घोषित आय से ज्यादा थी। सूत्र ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन मामलों में जवाब संतोषजनक नहीं हैं, उनमें नोटिस जारी किया जाएगा। कुछ मामलों में जहां बड़ी रकम डिपॉजिट हुई है और जवाब संतोषजनक नहीं हैं, उनमें सर्वे कराए जाएंगे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी पार्ट 2 के तहत जल्द ईमेल और एसएमएस भेजना शुरू करेगा। इसमें पांच लाख रुपये से कम डिपॉजिट के उन मामलों को कवर किया जाएगा जिनकी पहचान बिग डेटा ऐनालिटिक्स से की गई है। विभाग को नोटबंदी के दौरान हुए डिपॉजिट्स पर बैंकों से बहुत से आंकड़े मिले हैं जिनकी जांच की जा रही है। डिपार्टमेंट डिपॉजिट स्प्लिटिंग या डिपार्टमेंट की नजर में आने से बचने के मकसद से किए गए दूसरे उपाय की पहचान करने के लिए बाहरी एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर कर रहा है। पहचाने गए डिपॉजिटर्स से सफाई देने के लिए कहा जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>स्मार्ट सिटीज के शहरी गरीबों के घर का किराया भी चुकाएगी मोदी सरकार!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-may-pay-your-rent-through-vouchers-soon-in-100-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-may-pay-your-rent-through-vouchers-soon-in-100-cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मोदी सरकार अब आपके फ्लैट, कमरे का किराया चुका सकती है। केंद्र सरकार 100 स्मार्ट सिटीज में जल्द ही 2700 करोड़ रुपए की नई कल्याणकारी योजना की शुरुआत करने जा रही है, जिसके तहत शहरी गरीबों को घर का किराया चुकाने के लिए वाउचर्स दिए जाएंगे। सरकार रेंट वाउचर्स के साथ नई रेंटल हाउजिंग पॉलिसी को गरीबी रेखा से नीचे वाले लोगों के लिए पेश कर सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्मार्ट सिटीज में गरीबों का किराया देने वाली पॉलिसी पर वैसे तो तीन साल से काम चल रहा है, लेकिन इसका पहला कंपोनेंट वित्त वर्ष 2017-18 में लागू किया जा सकता है। स्मार्ट सिटीज में स्कीम को शुरू करने पर हर साल 2,713 करोड़ रुपए की लागत आने की उम्मीद है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस स्कीम को अर्बन पूअर यानी शहरों में रहने वाले गरीबों के लिए लिया जा रहा है, जिससे वहां मजदूरी करने के लिए आने वाले लोगों को मदद मिलेगी। रेंट वाउचर्स को शहरी निकायों की मदद से गरीबों में बांटा जाएगा। किरायेदार इन वाउचर्स को मकान मालिक को देगा, जो उसे किसी सिटीजन सर्विस ब्यूरो से अपने अकाउंट में ट्रांसफर करा सकेंगे। अगर रेंट वाउचर की वैल्यू से अधिक होता है तो किरायेदार को उसका भुगतान अपनी जेब से करना होगा। रेंट वाउचर की वैल्यू शहर और कमरे के साइज के हिसाब से निकाय तय करेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार इस वाउचर स्कीम के लिए डायरेक्ट बेनेफिट ट्रांसफर (DBT) की संभावना भी तलाश रही है। 2011 की जनगणना के मुताबिक, शहरों में करीब 27.5 प्रतिशत आबादी किराए के घरों में रहती है। हालांकि, नैशनल सैंपल सर्वे (NSS) के आंकड़ों के मुताबिक 2009 में शहरों में 35 प्रतिशत लोग किराए के घरों में रहते हैं। इसके अलावा, NSS से यह बात भी सामने आई थी कि यह रेशियो 1991 के बाद से इतना ही बना हुआ है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आवास और शहरी गरीबी उन्मूलन मंत्रालय के एक अधिकारी ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, &amp;lsquo;प्रधानमंत्री की हाउजिंग फॉर ऑल स्कीम के पूरक के तौर पर वाउचर स्कीम को देखा जा रहा है।&amp;rsquo; केंद्र जब्त की गई बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी का इस्तेमाल किफायती घर बनाने के लिए करेगी। इससे घरों की कमी दूर करने में मदद मिलेगी। एक अधिकारी ने&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बताया, &amp;lsquo;हाल में बेनामी प्रॉपर्टीज ऐक्ट को लागू किया गया है। इससे रेंटल हाउजिंग के लिए एक और रास्ता खुल गया है। इन रूल्स में एक ऐसी शर्त डाली जा सकती है कि जो घर केंद्र सरकार जब्त करेगी, उन्हें नीलाम नहीं किया जाएगा बल्कि उन्हें राज्य सरकारों के जरिये केंद्र मिडल इनकम ग्रुप (MIG), लो इनकम ग्रुप (LIG) और गरीबों को रेंटल हाउजिंग के लिए दे सकता है।&amp;rsquo; यह फैसला प्रॉपर्टी की लोकेशन और योग्यता के आधार पर लिया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory for Joining a Company</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government has made the biometric authentication using Aadhaar mandatory after facing several scenarios of fake identity theft—including becoming a director on a board of the company or for issuing its returns by company secretaries and chartered accountants—for Companies Act-related transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the sources, the Ministry Of Corporate Affairs has encountered several instances where people have established a Director Identification Number or have been chosen as directors on boards of the company without their consent, a necessity for connecting a board, as their signatures were copied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, in the near future, anyone looking for a Director Identification Number will have to authenticate using biometric devices and fill up the online form that can soon be connected to PCs. In the same way, anyone chosen by the banks or government and financial institutions on boards of the company will have to provide biometric authentication. A parallel setup for company secretaries and CAs is also being operated out, confirmed the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A squad from Infosys has been assigned with placing in the new machine that will be introduced in stages, initiating with the allocation of Director Identification Number. Progressively over a period of couple of years, it will be extended to involve all work related to MCA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be exclusions for non-residents and others, who are not qualified to get Aadhaar such as those people whose iris or fingerprints are not able to capture. MCA considers that the projected system does not encounter any issues since the recent order of the Supreme Court on Aadhaar as the system was destined for authentication. According to sources, the Supreme court had itself recommended that mobile connections be confirmed using Aadhaar and tax department as well as the banks have also been permitted to use the distinctive identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2017, the income tax department has also made Aadhaar compulsory for issuing permanent account numbers since it targets individuals using numerous PANs, which is not legal, to avoid from taxes. Though this move was disapproved, the government thinks that employment of UID can aid in enhancing compliance across various sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>