<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM will now allow you to make payments via Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app will now allow users to send and receive money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number.
This comes shortly after the government announced the Aadhaar Pay which would allow any person with their Aadhaar number linked to a bank account, can make and receive payment electronically.
At the time, IT minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said that BHIM would be able to make Aadhar Payments any biometric authentication, as indicated by this Economic Times report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.
Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSNL To Offer Ultra Fast 1,000 Mbps Broadband Services</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-to-offer-ultra-fast-1-000-mbps-broadband-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-to-offer-ultra-fast-1-000-mbps-broadband-services/</guid>
      <description>Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today launched a next generation optical fibre-based technology on BSNL network that will enable the state-run firm to provide broadband connection with download speed of up to 1,000 mbps.
Bharat Sanchar Nigam Ltd at present offers broadband facility with top download speed of 100 megabit per second on its fibre-to-the-home network.
&amp;ldquo;BSNL has successfully implemented a major project of NG-OTH technology in 44 cities covering state capitals and major cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car insurance: How to get extra cover during monsoon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/car-insurance-how-to-get-extra-cover-during-monsoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/car-insurance-how-to-get-extra-cover-during-monsoon/</guid>
      <description>Is there any special monsoon motor insurance cover available in the market? – Anuj Bansal
For new vehicles up to a certain
number of years, add-on covers like Engine Protect and Return To Invoice is advisable to opt for. These add-on covers are annual contracts and not restricted to a particular season. Engine Protect will indemnify the owner for engine related damages caused to the vehicle due to water ingression in the engine while driving the vehicle in accumulated flood waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government imposes 10% customs duty on chargers and adapters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-imposes-10-customs-duty-on-chargers-and-adapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-imposes-10-customs-duty-on-chargers-and-adapters/</guid>
      <description>NEW DELHI: The government has imposed a 10% basic customs duty (BCD) on imported chargers and adapters, while exempting parts or raw material used for making these products out of the duty ambit. The move reinstates an advantage that local manufactures had before the introduction of GST.
The industry welcomed the move, saying the step would provide stimulus to local manufacturing and take care of a loophole in rules that allowed for the import of chargers or adapters without paying any duty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.
After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How safe is your Aadhaar data and what security measures are taken by UIDAI: Here’s all you need to know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-safe-is-your-aadhaar-data-and-what-security-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-safe-is-your-aadhaar-data-and-what-security-measures/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number is a 12-digit random number issued by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) to the residents of India after satisfying the verification process laid down by it. The Aadhaar number is a proof of identity and does not confer any right of citizenship or domicile. Aadhaar has become very important now keeping in view the fact that the number has been made compulsory by the government for many financial transactions as well as a host of social schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No GST On Second Hand Goods If Sold Cheaper</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-gst-on-second-hand-goods-if-sold-cheaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-gst-on-second-hand-goods-if-sold-cheaper/</guid>
      <description>The buying and selling of second hand goods will not attract Goods and Services Tax (GST) if sold at a price cheaper than the purchase price, the government said on Saturday.
HIGHLIGHTS
 The clarification comes after doubts regarding the Margin Scheme It can be availed by any registered person dealing in second hand goods Dealers of old and used empty bottles are also included  Rule 32(5) of the Central Goods and Services Tax (CGST) Rules, 2017, provides that where a taxable supply is provided by a person dealing in buying and selling of second hand goods or used goods as such or after such minor processing which does not change the nature of the goods and where no input tax credit has been availed on the purchase of such goods, the value of supply shall be the difference between the selling price and the purchase price and where the value of such supply is negative, it shall be ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI Pushes For Currency Security Features To Be Made In India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-pushes-for-currency-security-features-to-be-made-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-pushes-for-currency-security-features-to-be-made-in-india/</guid>
      <description>In a big &amp;lsquo;Make in India&amp;rsquo; push, the Reserve Bank today came out with fresh tender for currency security features, mandating that the supplier set up the manufacturing unit in the country within two years and gradually increase the local content.
RBI cancelled two tenders issued earlier for supply of security features and fibre for currency notes in order to incorporate &amp;lsquo;Make in India&amp;rsquo; as an essential requirement. The bid document is for supply of different types of security threads, colour-shifting ink, foil patch, security fibre, paper based taggant, ink based taggant, advanced watermark and micro perforation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI new Rs 500 currency. Here&#39;s what is different in new notes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</guid>
      <description>The Reserve Banks of India (RBI) today announced introduction of new Rs 500 currency notes.
The new version will have few different aspects. The one noticeable aspect of the new currency notes is the inclusion of an inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;.
Besides, in the new notes the signature of the RBI Governor will be on the reverse side.
  &amp;ldquo;In continuation of issuing of Rs 500 denomination banknotes in Mahatma Gandhi (new) series from time to time which are currently legal tender, a new batch of banknotes with inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; in both the number panels bearing the signature of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Railways Launches Mobile App That Does More Than Just Booking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-launches-mobile-app-that-does-more-than-just-booking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-launches-mobile-app-that-does-more-than-just-booking/</guid>
      <description>The Railways today launched an integrated mobile application to cater to various passenger requirements, including ticket booking, inquiry, on-board cleaning and ordering meal on a single platform.
The app &amp;ndash; Rail SAARTHI &amp;ndash; was launched here by Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu.
Currently there are multiple mobile app by the Railways. To use different services, users need to search and download each application separately.
In order to provide better customer experience, there was a need for an integrated application which could give a single window interface for these services, Prabhu said after launching the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.
HIGHLIGHTS  Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1 The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent  The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New internet, mobile banking Charges</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/neft-charges-rtgs-charges-by-sbi-set-to-be-cut-but-applicable-only-on-internet-mobile-banking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/neft-charges-rtgs-charges-by-sbi-set-to-be-cut-but-applicable-only-on-internet-mobile-banking/</guid>
      <description>A day after it waived charges on Immediate Payment System (IMPS) transactions of up to Rs 1,000, State Bank of India (SBI) on Thursday lowered transaction charges on transfers made through the National Electronic Funds Transfer (NEFT) and Real Time Gross Settlement (RTGS) channels. NEFT transactions of up to Rs 10,000 will now attract a charge of Rs 1, transactions between Rs 1,001 and Rs 1 lakh will be charged at Rs 2, those between Rs 1 lakh and Rs 2 lakh will be charged Rs 3, while transactions involving higher amounts will be charged Rs 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI- Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</guid>
      <description>HomeIndustry Banking financeFee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI
State Bank of India (SBI) on Wednesday waived charges on all money transfers of less than Rs 1,000 made through the Immediate Payment System (IMPS) channel, in a bid “to promote small ticket size transactions”.
By: FE Bureau | Mumbai | Updated: July 13, 2017 5:02 AM imps, sbi, state bank of india, sbi news, sbi latest news, imps transaction fee SBI’s decision to waive charges on some IMPS transactions may have been the result of more than a nudge from the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suresh Prabhu Launches India&#39;s First Solar Powered Train, Says 24 More To Come</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launches-indias-first-solar-powered-train-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launches-indias-first-solar-powered-train-says/</guid>
      <description>Railway Minister Suresh Prabhakar Prabhu on Friday said more solar-powered coaches will be inducted in the railway&amp;rsquo;s fleet.
&amp;ldquo;Indian Railways is committed for environment conservation and use of cleaner fuels,&amp;rdquo; Prabhu said at an event here.
&amp;ldquo;Indian Railways is trying to increase use of non-conventional sources of energy. More solar-powered trains may be inducted in future.&amp;rdquo;
The minister spoke at an event to launch the first 1,600 HP DEMU train with solar-powered coaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI Launches Three New Mobile Apps For Voice, Data Quality Tracking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</guid>
      <description>TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring.
Aiming to protect consumer interests, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Monday launched three new mobile applications and a web portal.
TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring. The app will help mobile phone users rate their experience about voice call quality in real time and help TRAI gather customer experience data along with network data, an official TRAI statement said here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Department Seeks Explanation From Another 5.56 Lakh For Demonetisation Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-another-5-56-lakh-under-operation-clean-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-another-5-56-lakh-under-operation-clean-money/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department has identified another 5.56 lakh individuals whose tax profiles are found inconsistent with the money deposited by them post demonetisation.
In the second phase of &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo; launched in April with an aim to detect black money generation post demonetisation, the I-T department has used information received under the Statement of Financial Transactions (SFT) from banks to identify additional cases.
&amp;ldquo;These are persons whose tax profiles were found to be inconsistent with the cash deposits made by them during the demonetisation period,&amp;rdquo; a finance ministry statement said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-Aadhaar as ID proof in Railways</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</guid>
      <description>After receiving several requests from passengers, Railway has agreed to accept e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class. Earlier only printed version was considered as a valid ID.
According to railway ministry, the issue regarding acceptance of e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class was being raised at various foras.
Accordingly, the matter was examined in consultation with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to verify if aadhaar card and pan card is linked</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-verify-if-both-cards-are-linked/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-verify-if-both-cards-are-linked/</guid>
      <description>Steps to Check if Aadhar Card and PAN Card are Linked
 Go to the official website of the Income Tax Department. Enter your credentials – user ID, password, date of birth and captcha. Under ‘_Profile Setting_’ select ‘_Link Aadhaar_’. If your Aadhaar is linked with your PAN, then the display on the page will mention the same.  The benefit of linking Aadhaar and PAN in the income tax e-filing portal is to eliminate the necessity of furnishing your Income Tax acknowledgment while filing for returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</guid>
      <description>Both Apps uses Unified Payments Interface (UPI) technology to transfer money between any two individuals and between an individual and a merchant.
Navneet Dubey Moneycontrol News
Are you considering using one of the mobile payment apps launched by the government recently? If so, you may be confused on whether you should use the Aadhaar Payment App or Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM)?
Well, there are specific features of each of these apps which differentiate them which you should be aware of.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>