<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How railway insurance has become a boon for many</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-railway-insurance-has-become-a-boon-for-many/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the Railway Ministry introduced an optional Indian railway travel insurance scheme for e-ticketing passengers in September 2016, the move was welcomed. But little did we know how useful the policy would become soon after. Given the recent spate of train accidents that have left many passengers injured and caused several deaths, the insurance scheme has come as a boon for many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy can be bought by passengers when booking tickets online from the IRCTC website or through the mobile app. Earlier, the cost of this policy was 92 paise per passenger for an insurance cover of Rs 10 lakh in cases of demise or permanent disability. However, Dipankar Acharya, Country Head-Affinity and Strategic Relationships, Royal Sundaram General Insurance, points out, “From 10 December 2016 the cost of premium for this policy is subsidised by the railways so passengers don’t have to pay anything. Everyone should opt for this insurance policy while travelling by railways.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy is valid from the time of departure of train to the time of arrival of train at the destination. If an accident occurs during the journey, the injured passenger or the nominee of the deceased passenger will get the claim amount. If an insured passenger is injured, and it causes their demise within 12 months of the accident, their nominee can also claim Rs 10 lakh as per insurance policy. In case of injuries, passenger can claim hospitalisation expenses up to Rs 2 lakh which includes room rent for hospital, medicines, diagnostic test, nursing charges, ICU charges, operation theatre charges, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the exclusions under this policy are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intentional self-injury, suicide or attempted suicide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim in instances wherein ticket was booked by the Insured, but they did not board the train, irrespective of whether the train ticket was cancelled or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim in instances where the ticket was booked but wasn’t confirmed, but the passenger still boarded the train.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any medical treatment which was not medically necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has tied up with three general insurance companies - ICICI Lombard, Royal Sundaram and Shriram General Insurance - for policy issuance. Once you book the tickets, you will receive the policy details on your registered mobile number and mentioned email ID. The next important step is to update the name of your nominee on the insurance company’s website before travelling. “The benefit of appointing a nominee is that it helps to settle the claim quickly in the wake of unfortunate train accidents. If a nominee is not appointed, the process of claim settlement much longer, since legal heir certificate has to be produced,” says Acharya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a claim, the insured or nominee must submit a report of the railway authority confirming the accident of the train, a claim form, medical reports, death or disability certificate, ID proof, and NEFT details and a cancelled cheque to the insurance company. After the submission, the claim is settled within 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Easing the burden&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The insured passenger or nominee can claim the following amounts.&lt;/em&gt;
*On death: Rs 10 lakh
*On permanent total disability: Rs 10 lakh
*On permanent partial disability: Rs 7.5 lakh
*Hospitalisation expenses for injury: Rs 2 lakh
*Transportation of mortal remains: Rs 10,000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-linked payment system will change the game for digital transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Unique Identification Authority of India is working with banks and the Reserve Bank of India to ensure that merchants who use its mobile-based application for digital transactions earn a commission of up to 1% of the transaction value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With UIDAI suggesting it is on path to get this in place in a couple of months, the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System could give debit cards and e-wallets a run for their money. In contrast to what UIDAI is advocating, all other forms of digital payments require merchants to pay a fee or commission for the use of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Aadhaar-based system is being used for PDS [public distribution system] in Andhra Pradesh, Rajasthan and Gujarat. We are also in discussions with Haryana,” said Ajay Bhushan Pandey, chief executive officer, UIDAI. “We are enrolling banks so that they start accepting Aadhaar-based payments. Two banks have already agreed. The process of integrating merchants with banks will be completed in the next few weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Merchants as business correspondents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once implemented, this model envisages doing away with all charges that are associated with a typical point-of-sale machine. Under the system, UIDAI would enlist merchants as business correspondents. These merchants would use their phones linked to biometric devices for the transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These require a customer to key in their Aadhaar number and verify their fingerprint on the biometric reader connected to the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable a wide acceptability, the government has pushed for linking all savings bank accounts to Aadhaar numbers against a stiff deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a customer transacts with a merchant through Aadhaar Enabled Payment System, the merchant would receive the same incentive that business correspondents employed by banks do, UIDAI has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different banks provide different incentives to business correspondents on the basis of their performance. For instance, the Vidharbha Konkan Gramin Bank, a regional rural bank provides Rs 10 for every new account opened by a business correspondent. If someone deposits money through PoS terminals, the correspondent gets 0.5% of the money. For mobilising a term deposit, the correspondent gets 0.25% of the amount. Similarly, various incentives, as a proportion of the transaction amount, are given to correspondents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Merchants will now be doing the job of a business correspondent,” said Pandey. “So what was being paid as incentives to the correspondent would be extended to merchants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, he suggested, this would reduce the need for banking correspondents as more and more merchants use the Aadhaar app on their phones for transactions. The app itself has been tested by a couple of banks and is being finalised, Pandey said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UIDAI business model would mean the banking system taking on the burden of incentivising the spread of Aadhaar-based payments through mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, at the moment, they earn from other digital transactions. But Pandey said UIDAI was convincing banks that the commission must be seen in the light of existing commission structures for correspondents and the cost of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Costs of going cashless&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A look at the fee structure of PoS machines used to carry out card transactions indicates a substantial cost for the merchant. A third-party PoS provider has multiple layers of charges. These machines are not sold but often given on rent by banks and third-party vendors. Some banks charge the merchants a monthly rental of Rs 400 for a portable PoS machine for two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some banks also recover something called a “commitment charge”. These charges can be a burden on smaller merchants with low volumes of sales. Merchants with a lower sale volume have to pay a higher commitment charge. Competition between different vendors and banks has been bringing down these costs, though, over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks such as the State Bank of India and its public-sector peers offer machines on more lenient terms than third-party vendors. SBI, for instance, says that it doesn’t take a one-time installation charge from any merchant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final layer of the cost of using a PoS machine is the merchant discount rate. This is the charge that banks collect from merchants whenever a card is swiped on the machine. Banks usually charge a lower rate if their own debit cards are used on their PoS machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before January 1, the charges were 0.75% for transactions of value up to Rs 2,000. For transactions above Rs 2,000, a rate of 1% of the transaction value was recovered from the merchant. Foreign cards attracted double the rate while credit card transactions were charged at 1.5%. This was either borne by the merchant or passed on to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After demonetisation, RBI introduced an additional layer of merchant discount rate through a notification issued on December 16, 2016. Between January 1 and March 31 this year, the merchant discount rate for transactions up to Rs 1,000 is to be 0.25%. All others would continue to be charged as before. The rate has been capped at 1%. Clearly, the multiple charges add up to a significant amount for a merchant who has little option but to either bear the cost or to pass it on to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game-changer?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RBI data show that PoS transactions through debit cards touched Rs 31,600 crore in November 2016. In November 2015, this figure stood at Rs 14,800 crore. Banks quite clearly stand to make a killing through these multiple layers of charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile wallets, too, are known to charge as high as 4% for certain types of transactions. Mobile wallet transactions were Rs 3,300 crore in November 2016 as compared to Rs 1,900 crore in November 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where the Aadhaar-linked payment system could be a major disruptor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the National Payments Corporation of India charges 1% on every financial transaction through the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System from the bank. The bank passes this on to the merchant. It’s unclear if these charges would be set off too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandey told Business Standard that a favourable decision could come soon. If it does, it would completely turn the digital transactions ecosystem on its head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change of the business model for digital transactions would require many banks to come on board. NPCI data show that of the 46 public-sector banks and private banks in India, 44 are classified as “member banks” of Aadhaar Enabled Payment System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either &lt;em&gt;567678 or 56161.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said linking the two numbers is the key to &amp;ldquo;seamlessly avail online, a world of income tax facilities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar can also be seeded into PAN database by quoting Aadhaar in PAN application form for new PAN allotment or by quoting Aadhaar in change request form used for reprint of PAN card,&amp;rdquo; it said in the advertisement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income-Tax-department had early this month launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing I-T returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has hosted a new link on its homepage to link the two unique identities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires a person to punch in his PAN number, Aadhaar number and the exact name as given in the Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department had said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number in the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of Income-Tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the I-T department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp:10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on &lt;em&gt;Rs 3,050&lt;/em&gt; crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.
He did not give further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department, on April 5, wrote to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) asking it to give a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo; on the penalty issue, and also outline the basis and provisions of law under which the said amount had been recommended by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources familiar with the matter said that DoT, in its communication, has also asked the Trai to provide information on the number of subscribers acquired by Reliance Jio during the testing phase (that is prior to its commercial launch). The incumbent operators and the Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio clashed last year over the issue of call connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio cried foul that its customers were suffering from call failures as the incumbent operators were not giving it sufficient interconnect capacity. The operators, in turn, charged the newcomer of unleashing a &amp;ldquo;tsunami&amp;rdquo; of free traffic on their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interconnection enables mobile users to make calls to customers of other telecom networks and is, therefore, crucial for smooth functioning of mobile services. In October last year, Trai recommended to the Telecom Department, the imposition of total penalty of Rs 3,050 crore on the three incumbent operators Bharti Airtel, Vodafone and Idea Cellular for allegedly denying interconnectivity to the
new entrant that led to deterioration in the quality of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Trai&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, the penalty for Airtel and Vodafone worked out to about Rs 1,050 crore each, while in case of Idea Cellular stood at about Rs 950 crore. The regulator, in fact, had stopped short of recommending cancellation of their telecom licences saying it may lead to significant consumer inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the issue was placed before the Telecom Commission earlier this year, the highest policy-making body of the telecom department, it favoured referring the matter back to Trai for a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Commission asked DoT to seek clarification from Trai on nearly a dozen points, including whether the stipulated 90-day period was given to the three telecom operators for providing point of interconnection to the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon,Bank Account number portability</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-soon-you-may-be-able-to-port-your-bank-account-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-soon-you-may-be-able-to-port-your-bank-account-number/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;From linking Aadhaar numbers to bank accounts to the increase in digital payments, the days are not far when people can port their account numbers too. Reserve Bank of India&amp;rsquo;s (RBI) deputy governor SS Mundra on Tuesday batted for the need of account number portability and said that &amp;ldquo;the prospect of an aggrieved customer moving his/her account to another bank in the near future is very real.&amp;rdquo; He also spoke about the security issues involved in the electronic banking as the use of technology is being increasing over the recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account number portability has come within the realms of possibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SS Mundra first advocated the idea a couple of years ago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He also spoke on the security issues involved in the electronic banking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At an event organised by the Banking Codes and Standards Board of India (BCSBI) in Mumbai, Mr Mundra said, &amp;ldquo;I first advocated the idea of &amp;lsquo;account number portability&amp;rsquo; a couple of years ago. Back then the concept might have appeared somewhat abstract but with technological advancements in the field of payment system such as UPI etc. coupled with massive enrolments under Aadhaar and their linkage to individual bank accounts, it has come within the realms of possibility.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BCSBI is an independent body set up by RBI, Indian Banks Association (IBA) and scheduled commercial banks with the specific objective of ensuring that customers get fair treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the security risks involved in the online banking, he said, &amp;ldquo;There have been several incidents of theft of personal information, fraudulent use of ATMs, net banking frauds, ATM/Debit card incidents or cases of unauthorized access to bank servers. Hence, there is an immediate need for plugging all the gaps and vulnerabilities in tech-enabled service delivery.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While banks have been granted autonomy in fixing minimum average balance or for charging for premium services, it should not be used as an excuse to deny service or to drive away common man,&amp;rdquo; Mr Mundra said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank is also in the process of reiterating its guidelines to the banks for providing essential minimum relevant details in respect of various transactions in the passbook or statement, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trai Releases An App Which Lets You Rate Call Quality</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sector regulator Trai today said it will soon roll-out an app that enables subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call. The &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app would be available by the end of this month, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) chairman RS Sharma said at &amp;lsquo;Digital Broadcasting in India - Way Forward&amp;rsquo;, a seminar to commemorate the completion of 20 years of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We would like the consumers to assess the quality of calls, through &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app, which will be rolled out by this month end,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, once downloaded, the new app would give the subscribers the choice of assessing the quality of all or a portion of calls. When the call is completed, the users will be able to rate it, and the data will thereafter be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The application will pop up a window and enquire about the quality of the call. The subscriber can give it one star to five stars. There will also be assessment parameters like whether the call was indoors or outside or while travelling,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government and the regulator have refused to lower their guard on the issue of call drops, and have kept a close watch on call quality through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.
Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops. The system is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trai through its analytics portal has also rolled out initiatives that measure data speeds and maps call drops in India, which is the world&amp;rsquo;s second largest telecom market with 1.12 billion mobile subscribers.
Sharma today said that Trai also plans to &amp;ldquo;strengthen&amp;rdquo; the &amp;lsquo;Do Not Disturb&amp;rsquo; or DND service aimed at blocking pesky calls by telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already done a lot of work in this,&amp;rdquo; Sharma said, but refused to elaborate on the upcoming plans. At present, there is a framework for DND registry that allows telecom subscribers to block unwanted communication from telemarketers. Reaching out to such subscribers can result in a heavy fine for telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source familiar with the initiative said that the regulator may look at building specific intelligence features into the system such that pesky messages with certain key words could automatically generate a prompt on whether the users wishes to report the message as a spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the occasion, Communications Minister Manoj Sinha said TRAI&amp;rsquo;s regulatory framework has provided a conducive environment for the sector&amp;rsquo;s growth. It has made the sector more competitive and enhanced accessibility of services at affordable tariffs, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awareness of the some of the main challenges faced by the sector and regulatory framework of today - ranging from convergence to the persisting issue of the digital divide - is therefore necessary to be better equipped to handle these challenges in future,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your PAN card could be invalid without Aadhaar by December. Here’s what to do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar-by-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar-by-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Permanent account numbers (PAN) not linked to Aadhaar cards will likely become invalid after December 31, a government source said on Thursday, as the Centre pushes to widen the use of the 12-digit biometric identity project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permanent account numbers (PAN) not linked to Aadhaar cards will likely become invalid after December 31, a government source said on Thursday, as the Centre pushes to widen the use of the 12-digit biometric identity project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, all taxpayers need to have a PAN number to file income tax return but others, such as students outside the tax bracket, also use the card as a proof of identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government says many of these PAN cards are fraudulently obtained, a practice that can be checked by a unique identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official – who refused to be quoted as he isn’t authorised to talk to media – said the government had arrived at the tentative cutoff date of December 31 as it believed the Aadhaar enrollment process will be complete by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Considering that 98% of the adult population is Aadhaar card holders, a time frame till the end of the year is more than adequate for linking PAN with Aadhaar,” said State Bank of India group’s chief economic adviser Soumya Kanti Ghosh.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/pan-aadhaar.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ज्यादा EMI तो नहीं भर रहे हैं आप? यूं पता करें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/are-you-paying-more-emi-for-your-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/are-you-paying-more-emi-for-your-housing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;एक भारी-भरकम होम लोन की ईएमआई आपको &amp;lsquo;गरीब&amp;rsquo; बना सकती है। यह ऐसे हालात होते हैं जहां व्यक्ति महंगी अचल संपत्ति का मालिक तो है लेकिन ईएमआई का भुगतान करने के बाद अन्य खर्चों के लिए उसके पास कुछ नहीं बचता। यह जानने के लिए कि आप अपने घर के लिए ज्यादा भुगतान तो नहीं कर रहे, इन सवालों के जवाब देकर देखें कितने अंक मिले हैं आपको&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अपने खर्चे का अनुमान इस आधार पर लगाएं-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A- 1 पॉइंट
B- 2 पॉइंट
C- 3 पॉइंट&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- हाउस लोन चुकाने के लिए कितने साल बचे हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) &amp;gt;10 साल
b) 5-10 साल
c) &amp;lt;5 साल&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- अपनी आय का कितना हिस्सा होम लोन ईएमआई चुकाने में खर्च करते हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) आय का आधे से ज्यादा हिस्सा
b) आय का लगभग आधा हिस्सा
c) आय का आधे से कम हिस्सा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3- पर्सनल और कार लोन मिलाकर आपको कितने लोन चुकाने हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) मुझे दो से ज्यादा लोन चुकाने हैं।
b) मुझे दो लोन चुकाने हैं।
c) मुझे सिर्फ एक लोन चुकाना है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4- जरूरत पड़ने पर आप कितनी जल्दी अपनी संपत्ति को बेच सकते हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) लगभग दो साल
b) 12 से 24 महाने के बीच
c) 12 महीनों में&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5- लोन की ईएमआई और घर खर्च के बाद आय का कितना हिस्सा सेविंग्स के लिए बचता है?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) &lt;10%
b) 10-30%
c) &gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आपका स्कोर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 पॉइंट्स से ज्यादा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप एक बेहतर स्थिति में हैं और बिना किसी परेशानी के अपनी सभी जरूरतों को पूरा कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8-11 पॉइंट्स&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप सभी जरूरतों के लिए योगदान करने में तब तक मुश्किल स्थिति में हैं, जब तक आप अपनी इनकम-प्रोफ़ाइल बढ़ाने या लागत में कटौती करने में सक्षम न हों।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 पॉइंट्स से कम&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप व्यावहारिक रूप से &amp;lsquo;गरीब-घर&amp;rsquo; हालात में रह रहे हैं। जरूरतें मुश्किल से पूरी हो रही हैं, ऐसे में आपको तत्काल विकल्पों का मूल्यांकन करना होगा ताकि अन्य आवश्यकताओं पर समझौता न करना पड़े।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पहली बार एक साथ 10 न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर्स के निर्माण को सरकार ने दी मंजूरी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-expansion-of-nuclear-power-industry-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-expansion-of-nuclear-power-industry-union/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वर्तमान में कुल 22 रिएक्टर चलाए जा रहे हैं। नए रिएक्टर्स पुरानों की तुलना में ज्यादा क्षमता वाले हैं।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देश की न्यूक्लियर पावर इंडस्ट्री में अभी तक का सबसे बड़ा विस्तार करते हुए केन्द्रीय मंत्रिमंडल ने बुधवार को 10 नए न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर के निर्माण को मंजूरी दे दी है। यह पहली बार है जब इतनी संख्या में न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर्स को एक साथ मंजूरी मिली हो। वर्तमान में कुल 22 रिएक्टर चलाए जा रहे हैं। नए&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रिएक्टर्स पुरानों की तुलना में ज्यादा क्षमता वाले हैं। पुराने 20 रिएक्टर्स 220 MWe (मेगा वॉट इलेक्ट्रिक) वाले और 2005 व 2006 में तारापुर में लगाए गए दो रिएक्टर 540 MWe क्षमता वाले हैं। वहीं, नए रिएक्टर्स की क्षमता 700 MWe होगी। यह दस रिएक्टर्स राजस्थान के माही बंसवाड़ा (यूनिट 1, 2, 3, 4), हरियाणा के गोरखपुर (यूनिट 3 और 4), कर्नाटक के कैगा (यूनिट 5 और 6) और मध्य प्रदेश के चुटका (यूनिट 1 और 2) में लगाए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इसके अलावा बिजली घरों को कोयले की पर्याप्त आपूर्ति सुनिश्चित करने के लिये बुधवार को सरकार ने एक नई कोयला आपूर्ति व्यवस्था संबंधी नीति को मंजूरी दे दी। इसके तहत बिजली क्षेत्र को ईंधन की आपूर्ति नीलामी मार्ग या प्रतिस्पर्धी बोली प्रक्रिया पर आधारित बिजली खरीद करार (पीपीए) के तहत होगी। प्रधानमंत्री&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नरेंद्र मोदी की अध्यक्षता में हुई मंत्रिमंडल की आर्थिक मामलों की समिति (सीसीईए) की बैठक में यह फैसला किया गया। इस कदम से बिजली क्षेत्र की परियोजनाओं को कोयले आपूर्ति उपलब्ध न होने की समस्या को दूर किया जा सकेगा।
बिजली घरों के लिये इस नई कोयला आपूर्ति व्यवस्था से उत्पादकों को व्यवस्थित तरीके से ईंधन की आपूर्ति करने में मदद मिलेगी। सूत्रों के अनुसार सरकार के प्रयास और अंतरराष्ट्रीय बाजार की परिस्थितियों से इस शुष्क ईंधन के दाम नीचे लाने में मदद मिली है और घरेलू उत्पादन बढ़ा है। लेकिन बिजली संयंत्रों को प्रतिस्पर्धी दरों पर कोयला संपर्क उपलब्ध कराने के लिये एक प्रणाली की जरूरत है। सूत्रों का कहना है कि नई नीति से यह चिंता दूर होगी और बिजली घरों के लिये उनकी जरूरत के मुताबिक कोयले की आपूर्ति के वास्ते उचित प्रणाली तैयार होगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पीएम नरेंद्र मोदी ने बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी के खिलाफ ऐक्शन तेज करने का दिया आदेश</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/prime-minister-narendra-modi-orders-speedy-action-against-unaccounted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/prime-minister-narendra-modi-orders-speedy-action-against-unaccounted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;काले धन पर अंकुश के लिए नोटबंदी जैसा कड़ा कदम उठाने के बाद केंद्र की नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार के निशाने पर अब बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी है। प्रधानमंत्री मोदी ने राजस्व अधिकारियों के साथ समीक्षा बैठक में ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के बारे में जानकारी ली। सूत्रों के मुताबिक पीएम मोदी ने बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी पर ऐक्शन का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैठक में पीएम मोदी ने वित्त मंत्रालय के अधिकारियों से बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी रखने वालों के खिलाफ कार्रवाई तेज करने को कहा। सरकारी सूत्रों के मुताबिक पीएम ने कहा कि ई-असेस्मन्ट जल्द से जल्द लागू होना चाहिए ताकि न्यूनतम हस्तक्षेप हो। असेस्मन्ट कम्प्यूटराइज्ड होना चाहिए। पीएम ने यह भी कहा कि टैक्स के दायरे में और लोग आएं ताकि कर का आधार बढ़ाया जा सके।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने सोमवार को वित्त मंत्रालय द्वारा वस्तु और सेवा कर (जीएसटी) को लागू करने को लेकर की गई तैयारियों और नोटबंदी के बाद कालेधन के खिलाफ अभियान की समीक्षा की। सूत्रों ने बताया कि राजस्व विभाग के साथ बैठक में मोदी ने जीएसटी को लेकर तैयारियों का जायजा लिया। सूत्रों ने कहा कि इस समीक्षा बैठक में वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली, राजस्व सचिव हसमुख अधिया और राजस्व विभाग के अन्य वरिष्ठ अधिकारी मौजूद थे।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पेट्रोल-डीजल प्राइस रोज बदलने से किसका लाभ?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/daily-fuel-price-revisions-to-boost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/daily-fuel-price-revisions-to-boost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;पेट्रोल-डीजल के खुदरा मूल्यों का रोजाना संशोधन करने के सरकार के फैसले से तेल कंपनियों के मार्जिन में सुधार आएगा और उन्हें अच्छा मुनाफा होने की संभावना है। इंडिया रेटिंग ने सोमवार को अपनी रिपोर्ट में कहा कि सरकार के इस कदम की सराहना किया। रिपोर्ट में कहा गया है कि 2010 में पेट्रोल के दाम को, 2014 में डीजल के दाम को नियंत्रण मुक्त करने, एलपीजी से संबंधित गिव इट अप योजना, पीडीएस केरोसिन आवंटन घटाने और उसके दामों में क्रमिक वृद्धि के बाद मार्केटिंग सेक्टर में यह एक अन्य सकारात्मक ढांचागत बदलाव है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इन सभी कदमों से ऑइल मार्केटिंग कंपनियों की बाजार उधारी में भी काफी कमी आई। वर्ष 2014 से लेकर 2016 के बीच सार्वजनिक क्षेत्र की तेल विपणन कंपनियों की बाजार उधारी 29 प्रतिशत घट गई। इसके साथ ही उनकी ब्याज अदायगी भी 37 प्रतिशत तक कम हुई है। सरकार ने पेट्रोल, डीजल के दाम रोजाना आधार पर तय करने के लिए देश के पांच नगरों में इसकी परीक्षण के तौर पर शुरुआत की गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पुद्दुचेरी, आंध्र प्रदेश में विजाग, राजस्थान में उदयपुर, झारखंड में जमशेदपुर और चंडीगढ़ में एक मई से दैनिक आधार पर ईंधन के दाम तय किए जाने शुरू कर दिया गया है। इसे धीरे-धीरे देश के अन्य शहरों में भी शुरू किया जाएगा। दरअसल, रोजाना बदलाव होने पर पेट्रोल, डीजल की कीमत में मामूली अंतर पड़ेगा। ऐसे में रेट रिवाइज करने को लेकर राजनीतिक दबाव खत्म हो जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गौरतलब है कि अभी सरकारी ऑयल मार्केटिंग कंपनियां महीने की पहली और 16वीं तारीख को पेट्रोल और डीजल के दाम की समीक्षा करती हैं। पिछले 15 दिनों में इंटरनैशनल प्राइस और करेंसी एक्सचेंज रेट के आधार पर यह बदलाव किया जाता है। पायलट प्रोजेक्ट के लिए इंटरनैशनल मार्केट के डेली प्राइसेज को आधार बनाया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सवालों के जवाब न देने वालों के घर कभी भी पहुंच सकते हैं आयकर विभाग के अधिकारी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/expect-a-visit-from-taxman-if-youve-ignored-income-tax-departments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/expect-a-visit-from-taxman-if-youve-ignored-income-tax-departments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;जिन लोगों ने नोटबंदी के दौरान अपने खाते में मोटी रकम की थी और उस नकदी के स्रोत की जानकारी अब तक नहीं दी है, उनके घर इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट के अधिकारी कभी भी पहुंच सकते हैं। टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स से कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमने इस अभियान को ऐसा रखने की कोशिश की है कि यह दखलंदाजी न लगे, लेकिन अगर लोग खुद आगे नहीं आते तो खासतौर पर बड़े डिपॉजिट वाले मामलों में कुछ वेरिफिकेशन की जरूरत होगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत ऐसे 18 लाख लोगों को एसएमएस और ई-मेल भेजे हैं, जिनके बैंक अकाउंट में 50 दिनों के डीमॉनेटाइजेशन विंडो के दौरान 5 लाख रुपये से ज्यादा रकम जमा कराई गई थी और जिनके डिपॉजिट ट्रांजैक्शंस उनकी इनकम के हिसाब से मेल नहीं खाते। फेसलेस एक्सरसाइज के तहत लोगों से डिपार्टमेंट के पोर्टल पर डिपॉजिट के बारे में सफाई देने के लिए कहा गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लगभग 7.3 लाख लोगों ने 15 फरवरी की बढ़ाई गई समय सीमा के दौरान ईमेल का जवाब दिया और जमा पर सफाई दी है। जो सफाई नहीं देंगे, उनके मामले में डिपार्टमेंट वेरिफिकेशन करेगा। उनसे इनकम टैक्स ऑफिस आकर डिपॉजिट के बारे में सफाई देने के लिए कहा जा सकता है। ऑफिस नहीं आने पर टैक्स ऑफिसर उनके घर जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी के दौरान जिन लोगों ने मोटी रकम जमा कराई थी, लेकिन उसके बारे में सफार्इ नहीं दी थी, उनके पास प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (PMGKY) के तहत 50% टैक्स देकर और 25% रकम चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज जमा कराने का मौका होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स अफसर ऐसे कुछ बड़े मामलों में नोटिस भेजने या सर्वे करने के बारे में सोच रहे हैं, जिनमें लोगों ने उस डिपॉजिट के बारे में संतोषजनक जवाब नहीं दिया था, जो उनकी घोषित आय से ज्यादा थी। सूत्र ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन मामलों में जवाब संतोषजनक नहीं हैं, उनमें नोटिस जारी किया जाएगा। कुछ मामलों में जहां बड़ी रकम डिपॉजिट हुई है और जवाब संतोषजनक नहीं हैं, उनमें सर्वे कराए जाएंगे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी पार्ट 2 के तहत जल्द ईमेल और एसएमएस भेजना शुरू करेगा। इसमें पांच लाख रुपये से कम डिपॉजिट के उन मामलों को कवर किया जाएगा जिनकी पहचान बिग डेटा ऐनालिटिक्स से की गई है। विभाग को नोटबंदी के दौरान हुए डिपॉजिट्स पर बैंकों से बहुत से आंकड़े मिले हैं जिनकी जांच की जा रही है। डिपार्टमेंट डिपॉजिट स्प्लिटिंग या डिपार्टमेंट की नजर में आने से बचने के मकसद से किए गए दूसरे उपाय की पहचान करने के लिए बाहरी एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर कर रहा है। पहचाने गए डिपॉजिटर्स से सफाई देने के लिए कहा जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>