<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prasad also said 4.47 crore bank accounts have been opened with Aadhaar eKYC as compared to only one lakh accounts opened as of May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the government has linked the BHIM app with Aadhaar so that transactions through the app happens in a transparent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>200 Airports To Be Brought Under UDAN Scheme: Jayanta Sinha</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jayanta Sinha said government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central government has embarked upon a plan to bring 200 airports under the regional air connectivity scheme, Union Minister of State for Aviation Jayanta Sinha said here today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Under the UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) regional air connectivity scheme, 33 airports have been already included since its launch last year in addition to 75 taking the total to 108. We intend to take the number to 200,&amp;rdquo; Mr Sinha said at an interaction at Bharat Chamber of Commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this, we will have multiple rounds of bidding, he said, adding the government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Sinha said so far the subsidy burden was only Rs 200 crore and 13 lakh seats have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pointing out that regional air connectivity was both pro-poor and pro-markets, he said that this twin objective had been met by offering seats at Rs 2,500 per seat per hour of flying and reducing the cost of flying by bringing down the costs of ATF and service charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding Bagdogra airport in West Bengal, he said talks were on for getting land with the state government for building a new modern terminal. He said that all greenfield airports would be built through the PPP route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding unruly behaviour while flying it is expected that both passengers and the cabin crew would adhere with the laid-down guidelines, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks vs e-wallets: Who is winning in cashless India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When two of the biggest banks in the country resist wallets from fintech start-ups, you know a few things are simmering. First, SBI disallowed its net banking users to top up third party wallets and next, ICICI blocked transactions on PhonePe, a Flipkart managed wallet that was launched in partnership with YES Bank – PhonePe allows users to link bank accounts to the smartphone through the National Payments Corporation of India’s encrypted software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While SBI cited security concerns, ICICI said PhonePe was “following restrictive practices allowing users to make payments with only its UPI handle which is in contravention to the UPI guidelines of interoperability…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While security concerns could be real, there is more to it than meets the eye. There is an imminent threat from fintech start-ups to the Indian financial services industry as we see growing disintermediation in mobile payments, financial product comparison/aggregation, lending, and remittances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report by consulting firm Zinnov released mid-2016, investments in the fintech sector crossed $1.3 billion.  Mobile wallet start-ups have received the most funding – they have been using this capital to both aggressively market as well as improve the ease of using their technology. Compared to say a Paytm, SBI’s wallet ‘SBI Buddy’ and ICICI’s ‘Pockets’ have much less brand recall. These privately funded start-ups are now threatening the banks from three sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, banks are worried about relationship with their customers being upended. Banks had failed to notice India’s demographic shift; the young did not want complicated KYC norms even for small transactions such as mobile recharges. They love the app economy and the convenience it provides. Wallets stepped in to provide a better payments experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was a slipping market scenario for traditional banks.  The banking industry’s business model majorly centres around retail as well as corporate lending and not small value transactions. However, according to some estimates, the payments market is a mammoth $500 billion opportunity today when domestic and international remittances, government, utility bills as well as merchant payments are included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New payment categories have come into being as well — taxi payments were always in cash a couple of years ago. Today, tech savvy customers are paying their maid or a driver through money transfers. Many more new categories could emerge.  If these start-ups, armed with private equity money, were to garner a major share of this pie, it would be more than an opportunity lost for traditional banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third threat, and a more serious one, is about data. What happens when users start trusting payment companies? The fallout of such a scenario – where both trust and transactions move to wallet companies – would reflect in a bank’s visibility of customer data or their behaviour patterns. That, in turn, would reduce a bank’s ability to cross sell or up sell other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may, in fact, become reliant on wallet companies for such data. Payment companies, for instance, will be in a better position to judge the credit worthiness of many retail customers the banks are after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, the margins of many banks could slip due to competition. As smart phones become more affordable and pervasive, experts see fintech start-ups scale massively. And if traditional banks don’t align their cost structures with current realities — especially the public sector ones — they can find themselves in a quagmire with only “restrictive practices” as aid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp:10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches. From the fifth transaction onwards, the customers will have to pay a minimum of Rs 150 per transaction (plus taxes and cess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Earlier, HDFC Bank savings account customers were offered five free transactions and the sixth transaction was charged at Rs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) HDFC Bank after December 30, 2016 reintroduced charges on cash transactions at branches after the deadline to deposit old currency notes ended. The charges were waived off after the government had announced a ban on high value currency notes on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) According to the revised norms which came into effect from March 1, from non-home branch, HDFC Bank customers can deposit/withdraw up to Rs 25,000 per day without any charge but any deposit/withdrawal from non-home branch above Rs 25,000 will attract charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess), whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) At the home branch of HDFC Bank, if the cumulative cash transactions (deposit/withdrawal) exceed Rs 2 lakh, a transaction charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess) whichever is higher will be levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For example, if a customer withdraws Rs 2 lakh from an account in four transactions and goes for another fifth transaction of Rs 50,000 from the home branch, then the customer will have to pay a charge of Rs 250. Thus, the charges apply only on the fifth transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) However, the charges for withdrawing money from automatic teller machines (ATMs) remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For senior citizens and minor accounts, the limit of Rs 25,000 per day will be applicable but the accounts will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) India&amp;rsquo;s biggest private sector bank ICICI Bank had reintroduced the cash transaction charges at bank branches from January 1, 2017. There will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while thereafter Rs 5 per Rs 1,000 would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150. The third party limit is Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Meanwhile, news agency Press Trust of India reported that another private sector lender Axis Bank has also started charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test To Check Call Drops Likely From This Month: TRAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/test-to-check-call-drops-likely-from-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/test-to-check-call-drops-likely-from-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Independent drive tests are going to begin. Actually, there was some gap (problem) which has been removed&amp;hellip;they should start probably from this month on,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom regulator Trai is likely to resume from this month its independent drive tests to check call drops and service quality of operators, after a gap of more than five months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Independent drive tests are going to begin. Actually, there was some gap (problem) which has been removed&amp;hellip;they should start probably from this month on,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the telecom operators submit performance monitoring reports to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) regularly, the regulator also undertakes audit and assessment of service quality through independent agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agencies conduct sample &amp;lsquo;drive tests&amp;rsquo; across various cities in the country, as part of audit and assessment of the operators&amp;rsquo; performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The independent drive tests are distinct from operator-assisted tests, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were doing drive tests in 11-12 cities, we will be doing it in more cities (this time). This will be different from the operator-assisted tests,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator-assisted drive test captures real-time data to monitor the level of call drops and voice quality, similar to Trai&amp;rsquo;s independent drive tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, unlike independent drive tests that are conducted by the regulator itself, the &amp;lsquo;operator-assisted&amp;rsquo; tests are conducted in co-ordination with telecom service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator-assisted tests, a new concept, involves the telecom firms&amp;rsquo; equipment and costs, with the regulator monitoring and supervising the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, all drive tests &amp;ndash; be it independent or operator-assisted tests &amp;ndash; assess the performance of networks on various quality benchmarks, including call set-up success rate, call drop, blocked calls and Radio Frequency (RF) coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last round of independent drive tests were conducted by Trai in Amritsar, Delhi, Hyderabad, Bhopal, Chandigarh, Mumbai, Lucknow, Kanpur, Ahmedabad, Ranchi, Darjeeling, Sikkim and Trivandrum in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the last few months that Trai did not undertake independent tests, the operator-assisted tests were conducted in cities including Mathura (UP-West circle), Jaisalmer, (Rajasthan), Ujjain (Madhya Pradesh) and Mangalore (Karnataka) and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the regulator and the Department of Telecom (DoT) have been keeping a vigil on service quality issues such as call drops and call failures through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort to tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of efforts to keep the call quality in check, the Trai plans to roll-out, by the month-end, an app that will enable subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call, once the call is complete. The data will, thereafter, be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>मोदी पूरा करेंगे 2014 का वादा? फोकस 1 करोड़ नौकरियाें पर</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-turns-focus-on-job-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-turns-focus-on-job-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार में तीन साल पूरे करने वाले हैं, जिसे देखते हुए अच्छे दिन के अपने वादों को पूरा करने पर उनका जोर है। 2014 में चुनाव प्रचार के दौरान मोदी ने युवाओं को 1 करोड़ रोजगार के अवसर देने का वादा किया था। हालांकि, बीते तीन सालों में जॉब क्रिएशन में मोदी सरकार का प्रदर्शन अच्छा नहीं रहा है। पीएम मोदी ने निर्देश दिया है कि कैबिनेट को भेजे जाने वाले सभी प्रस्तावों में यह जानकारी जरूर दी जाए कि उन प्रस्तावों पर अमल करने से रोजगार के कितने मौके बनेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वाणिज्य मंत्री निर्मला सीतारमण ने ईटी को बताया कि जिस भी प्रस्ताव के साथ कुछ खर्च जुड़ा होगा, उससे देश में जॉब क्रिएशन होना ही चाहिए और ऐसे प्रस्ताव के साथ जॉब्स एस्टिमेट दिया जाना चाहिए। सीतारमण ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;जब भी कोई प्रस्ताव चर्चा के लिए आता है तो प्रधानमंत्री कैबिनेट मीटिंग में पूछते हैं कि रोजगार के कितने मौके बनेंगे?&amp;rsquo; बता दें कि क्रिसिल की एक रिपोर्ट में कहा गया है कि 15 लाख से ज्यादा लोग हर महीने देश के जॉब मार्केट में रोजगार तलाशने आते हैं। वहीं, मानव श्रम पर निर्भरता घटाने वाले ऑटोमेशन की वजह से स्थिति गंभीर होती जा रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_कई मोर्चों पर चल रहा काम _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ज्यादा रोजगार पैदा करना चाहती है ताकि आमदनी बढ़े और लाखों लोग गरीबी के जाल से बाहर निकलें। सरकार अपनी मैन्युफैक्चरिंग पॉलिसी की समीक्षा भी कर रही है ताकि उसे जॉब क्रिएशन के उद्देश्य के मुताबिक बदला जा सके। वहीं, कौशल बढ़ाने के कार्यक्रम को नए सिरे से तैयार किया जा रहा है। इससे यह सुनिश्चित होगा कि नौकरियों की तलाश में निकलने वाले लोग नई जॉब्स के लिए पहले से तैयार होंगे। बता दें कि इकनॉमिक सर्वे 2017 में कहा गया है कि आबादी में युवाओं की अधिक संख्या से ग्रोथ में होने वाली बढ़ोतरी अगले पांच वर्षों में उच्चतम स्तर पर पहुंच जाएगी क्योंकि तब तक कामकाजी उम्र वाले लोगों की संख्या में ठहराव आ चुका होगा। ऐसे में कौशल और उद्यमिता को बढ़ावा देना जरूरी हो गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_नीति आयोग ने बनाया ऐक्शन प्लान _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ग्रोथ के साथ रोजगार के मौके बनने की रफ्तार बढ़ाने के लिए नीति आयोग ने तीन साल का ऐक्शन प्लान पेश किया है, जिसमें विभिन्न सेक्टरों में जॉब क्रिएशन के कदम उठाने की बात की गई है। मोदी ने भी कहा था, &amp;lsquo;हमारा देश युवाओं का है। हमारी आबादी में 65 प्रतिशत हिस्सा 35 साल से कम के लोगों का है। भारत दुनिया में सबसे बड़ा लोकतंत्र है। किसी भी देश के पास रोजगार के मौके पैदा करने का भारत जितना अवसर नहीं है।&amp;rsquo; बता दें कि सीआईआई के अनुसार, फाइनैंशल इयर 2012 से 2016 के बीच भारत में रोजगार के 1.46 करोड़ मौके बने थे। यानी हर साल 36.5 लाख अवसर। कामकाजी उम्र वाले लोगों की संख्या में 8.41 करोड़ का इजाफा हुआ, लेकिन वास्तिक लेबर फोर्स में बढ़ोतरी केवल 2.01 करोड़ रही। कामकाजी उम्र वाली आबादी का 24% हिस्सा लेबर फोर्स में जुड़ा, जबकि 76% हिस्सा इससे बाहर रहा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST To Lower Tax Burden On Medical Devices, Smartphones: Finance Ministry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-lower-tax-burden-on-medical-devices-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-lower-tax-burden-on-medical-devices-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Goods and Services Tax (GST) will lead to lower tax burden in several commodities, including packaged cement, medicaments, smartphones and medical devices, the Finance Ministry said on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Packaged cement attracts central excise duty of 12.5 per cent plus Rs 125 PMT (per metric tonne) and standard VAT (value-added tax) rate of 14.5 per cent. At these rates, the present total tax incidence works out to more than 29 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we include tax incidence on account of central sales tax (CST), octroi, entry tax, etc., the present total tax incidence would work out to more than 31 per cent. As against this, the proposed GST rate for cement is 28 per cent,&amp;rdquo; the ministry said here in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be lesser tax burden in case of medicaments, including Ayurvedic, Unani, Siddha, Homeopathic or Bio-chemic systems also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medicaments, in general, attract six per cent central excise duty and five per cent VAT. Further, CST, octroi, entry tax, etc. are also applicable in general. At these rates, the present total tax incidence works out to more than 13 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As against this, the proposed GST rate on medicines, including ayurvedic medicines, is 12 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smartphone attracts two per cent central excise duty (one per cent excise duty + one per cent NCCD (national contingency and calamity duty). VAT rates vary from state to state from five to 15 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Weighted average VAT rate on smartphones works out to about 12 per cent. Thus, the present total tax incidence on smart phones works out to more than 13.5 per cent. As against this, the proposed GST rate for smartphones is 12 per cent,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, medical devices, including surgical instruments, in general attract six per cent central excise duty and five per cent VAT. Along with CST, octroi, entry tax, etc., the present total tax incidence on them works out to more than 13 per cent. As against this, the proposed rate under GST is 12 per cent, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worship materials including that required for &amp;lsquo;havan&amp;rsquo; will be under the nil category. However, exact formulation for the same is yet to be finalised.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST To Smoothen Taxation, Bring In Transparency: Experts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-smoothen-taxation-bring-in-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-smoothen-taxation-bring-in-transparency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At an interactive awareness programme for start-ups, the experts said the government is expected to resolve the queries of entrepreneurs regarding GST.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GST will not only ease the process of taxation, but bring in transparency, say experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At an interactive awareness programme for start-ups here, the experts said the government is expected to resolve the queries of entrepreneurs regarding GST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;GST will not only ease the process, but also bring transparency as all the invoices needed to be uploaded by sellers are visible to the buyer every month,&amp;rdquo; said Manish Ojha, Development Head of KDK Softwares Pvt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEO Mohit Bhambani said many startups are into e-commerce and their logistic costs go up, with 11 categories of taxes levied on the road transport sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referring to a report of Crisil, Bhambani said GST can reduce logistics cost of companies producing non-bulk goods by as much as 20 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, he said various road permits are required under state CST rules and also declaration forms for availing of lower taxation rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Likewise, many such hassles will be removed for ease of business operations,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several startups attended the session organised by the city based incubation centre Startup Oasis and KDK softwares.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Plan Of Affordable Housing For All By 2022</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-real-estate-act-will-boost-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-real-estate-act-will-boost-housing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The government has backed its Housing for All by 2022 promise with a slew of reforms for buyers and developers alike.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian real estate sector has seen a resurgence of interest in 2017 after a slowdown over the past 2-3 years, buoyed by the affordable housing segment, which includes residential units below Rs 50 lakh. Legislations the like Real Estate (Regulation and Development) Act, 2016, (RERA) and Goods and Services Tax (GST) have signalled that the government is ready to walk the talk for its &amp;lsquo;Housing for All&amp;rsquo; by 2022 promise and many developers and institutional players have flocked to the affordable housing market, a report by Colliers International India, the Indian wing of a global commercial real estate company said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Most institutional players are looking at affordable housing as a &amp;lsquo;mid-margin and quick turnaround&amp;rsquo; product to ensure reasonable returns,&amp;rdquo; Gagan Randev, National Director, Capital Markets and Investment Services, Colliers International India said. This has been made possible with speedy government approvals and incentives to end-users (especially the first-time home buyers living in rented accommodations to motivate them to own their own dream home), he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-of-the-key-highlights-on-india-s-push-for-affordable-housing&#34;&gt;Here are some of the key highlights on India&amp;rsquo;s push for affordable housing:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The long-awaited infrastructure status to the sector under the Finance Bill 2018, is expected to allow builders easy access to capital at economical rates, clearer investment guidelines and greater transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government has tweaked the definition of affordable housing projects to pave the way for 100 per cent tax subsidy on profits of an affordable housing undertaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arms of established players like Shappoorji Pallonji Joyville and Tata Value Homes, etc, which have rebranded themselves to cater to this mass and exciting segment, Colliers said, noting that it has also drawn institutions and funds like HDFC Capital, IFC, Standard Chartered, Kotak Investment Advisors etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government has also addressed common grievances like the uncertainty of approvals taking too long, developers delaying possession with clearer investment guidelines and greater transparency under RERA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new reforms are also attracting new entrants to the market like Tribeca Developers and sovereign funds like ADIA, which have lined up substantial commitments to the real estate segment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apart from sops for the builders, the government has introduced a slew of benefits for home buyers such as allowing interest subsidy of 3-4 per cent for first time home buyers for loans up to Rs 12 lakhs and Rs 9 lakhs respectively under Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana (PMAY).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many states have also introduced policies for affordable housing to buyers such as zero maintenance fees for five years and check on developers to ensure timely project completions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to a recent study by property portal PropTiger, the affordable housing segment continued to have a higher share in total residential sales and contributed over 50 per cent to the total sales in Q3 FY17 across top nine cities of India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modi government is firming up a plan to create India&#39;s own Harvard</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/hrd-ministry-seeks-cabinet-nod-for-20-world-class-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/hrd-ministry-seeks-cabinet-nod-for-20-world-class-institutions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;India has taken a firm step towards building 20 world-class educational institutions, which will be termed Institutions of Eminence, with the human resource development ministry moving the proposal to the Union Cabinet for approval. Firmly bearing the stamp of the Prime Minister’s Office, this is a new framework to catapult Indian institutions to global recognition by freeing the best of them from the University Grants Commission’s restrictive regulatory regime and ushering in an unprecedented level of institutional autonomy. Here are some of the finer details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-will-make-them-eminent&#34;&gt;WHAT WILL MAKE THEM ‘EMINENT’&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UGC (Institutions of Eminence Deemed to be Universities) regulations, 2017 will govern all such institutions that are conferred with this status, ensuring their complete academic, administrative and financial autonomy. These regulations will override all other UGC regulations and free the institutions of UGC’s restrictive inspection regime, the regulatory control over fee and curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/gr.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The institutions will have to achieve a place in the top 500 of any of the global rankings within 10 years of being declared an institution of eminence and eventually reach the top 100 slot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They will have a teacher:student ratio of 1:20 to begin with and 1:10 in five years, with a student enrolment of 15,000 in 15 years. There will be a good mix of Indian and international faculty, and only those who come with a degree from top 500 institutions in global rankings will be considered eligible foreign faculty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The institutions will be free to select students through a merit-based transparent admission process to ensure no meritorious student is turned away for lack of funds. Up to 30% foreign students vis-a-vis the strength of domestic students can be admitted. The institution will be free to decide its fee structure but will have to declare it in a transparent manner. Any reports of capitation fee will be treated as serious violation. An Ombudsman will be set up to cater to student grievances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One paper will have to be published per faculty member per year on average in a reputed peer reviewed international journal, with publications included in SCOPUS, Web Science, etc to be counted as a research publication. A world-class library with subscriptions to reputed journals related to courses offered will have to be maintained along with cutting-edge research in frontier areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along-term lead campus (30 years minimum) with adequate space for expansion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While private institutions will not get any government funding they will be able to access government funds for specific studies and projects they may execute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full freedom to the institution to decide course structure, the credit hours needed for a degree, fixing of curriculum and syllabus and up to 20% online courses as part of its programmes and fully online certificate courses. Full freedom to hire faculty, even industry personnel as faculty and choose any career progression scheme, salary structure for its faculty. None of its academic collaborations will need government approval unless they are with countries on the foreign ministry’s or home ministry’s ‘negative list’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-is-eligible&#34;&gt;WHO IS ELIGIBLE&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ten government run and ten private institutions will be conferred this status, with Rs 10,000 crore funding earmarked for the former.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While a government-owned institution will apply to HRD ministry for the special status, a private deemed to be university or private state university
will have to be backed by a sponsoring organisation with a total net worth of Rs 5,000 crore and credible members, an identified first chancellor and vice chancellor, and a detailed 15-year vision plan besides a five-year rolling implementation plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The governance structure of the institution and its sponsoring organisation will be different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-will-select&#34;&gt;WHO WILL SELECT&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An empowered expert committee with three to five eminent persons appointed for three years with the final approval of the appointments committee of the Cabinet headed by the PM will select the 20 institutes. The EEC will recommend the names to the UGC, which will forward its decision to the HRD ministry that will issue a letter of intent to such institutions and decide on the final conferment of the status after a memorandum of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;EEC will monitor and review the institutions of eminence to ensure quality, decide on appeals, changes in transfer of sponsorship and liquidation of corpus fund if necessitated amongother things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अनार खाने के फायदे</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/health-benefits-pomegranate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/health-benefits-pomegranate/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;अनार शब्द सुनते ही एक कहावत स्मरण हो आता है-‘एक अनार, सौ बीमार।&amp;rsquo; चौंकिए मत, अनार बीमारियों का घर नहीं है, बल्कि यह तो हमारे शरीर के लिए काफी फायदेमंद होता है। इसके साथ सबसे अच्छी बात यह है कि यह पूरे साल उपलब्ध रहता है। हालांकि कई लोग पौष्टिक फल की श्रेणी में इस शानदार फल को कम आंकते हैं। लेकिन आज हम आप को बताते हैं कि अनार किस तरह हमारे शरीर के लिए फायदेमंद है।
अनार के कई बडे़ फायदे हैं, जैसे अगर आपके घर में कोई गर्भवती महिला है तो आप उसे रोज अनार का जूस पिलाएं। इससे उसका बच्चा स्वस्थ पैदा होगा है और उसके बच्चे को कम वजन जैसी बीमारी का सामना नहीं करना पड़ेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ब-ढ-प-आन-स-बच-ए&#34;&gt;बुढापा आने से बचाए&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बहुत कम लोग ही इस तथ्य से परिचित हैं कि अनार एंटीऑक्सीडेंट का बहुत ही अच्छा स्रोत है। इसलिए यह शरीर की कोशिकाओं को फ्री रेडिकल्स से बचाता है, जिससे आप वक्त से पहले बूढ़े नहीं दिखते। फ्री रेडिकल्स का निर्माण सूर्य की रोशनी और वातावरण में मौजूद विषैले तत्व से होता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्राकृतिक ब्लड थीनर
खून दो तरह से जमते हैं। पहला तो कटने या जलने की स्थिति में खून जमता है, जिससे खून का बहाव रुक जाता है। वहीं दूसरे तरह का खून आंतरिक रूप से जमता है, जो बहुत ही खतरनाक होता है। मसलन हृदय या धमनी में खून जम जाने से इसका परिणाम प्राणघातक भी हो सकता है। अनार में मौजूद एंटीऑक्सीडेंट गुण खून के लिए वही काम करता है, जो पेट के लिए थीनर करता है। यह शरीर में खून को जमने या थक्का बनने से रोकता है।
एथेरॉसक्लेरॉसिस से रोकता है
एथेरॉसक्लेरॉसिस से रोकता है
बढ़ती उम्र और गलत खानपान से रक्तवाहिनी की दीवार कोलेस्ट्रोल व अन्य चीजों से कठोर हो जाती है, जिससे रक्त के बहाव में अवरोध पैदा होता है। अनार का एंटीऑक्सीडेंट गुण कम घनत्व वाले लिपोप्रोटीन और कोलेस्ट्रोल को ऑक्सीडाइजिंग से रोकता है। यानी अनार रक्तवाहिनी की दीवार को अतिरिक्त वसा से कठोर होने से बचाता है।
अनार करता है ऑक्सीजन मास्क की तरह काम
अनार करता है ऑक्सीजन मास्क की तरह काम
साधारण शब्दों में कहें तो अनार का जूस खून में ऑक्सीजन के स्तर को बढ़ाता है। इसका एंटीऑक्सीडेंट कोलेस्ट्रोल को कम करता है, फ्री रेडिकल्स से बचाता है और खून का थक्का बनने से रोकता है। यानी अनार शरीर में खून की प्रवाह को बेहतर बनाता है, जिससे खून में ऑक्सीजन का स्तर भी सुधरता है।
गठिया रोग से रोकथाम
गठिया रोग से रोकथाम&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अनार गठिया रोग से पीड़ित व्यक्ति के कार्टिलेग को नुकसान पहुंचने से बचाता है। यह फल कार्टिलेग को नष्ट करने वाले एंजाइम से लड़ता है और जलन और सूजन से भी सुरक्षा प्रदान कराता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;इर-क-ट-इल-ड-सफ-क-शन-स-बच-त-ह&#34;&gt;इरेक्टाइल डिसफंक्शन से बचाता है&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप माने या न माने, अनार लज्जनजक स्थिति निर्मित होने से भी बचाता है। पर ध्यान रहे, यह कोई आश्चर्यजनक दवा नहीं है। अनार इलेक्टाइल डिसफंक्शन को सामान्य रूप से ही सुधारता है। हालांकि इस विषय को लेकर शोध कार्य जारी है, फिर भी इस फायदे के पक्ष में कई लोग हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;प-र-स-ट-र-ट-क-सर-और-द-ल-क-ब-म-र-स-स-रक-ष&#34;&gt;प्रोस्ट्रेट कैंसर और दिल की बीमारी से सुरक्षा&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस विषय को लेकर भी शोध जारी है, लेकिन दो अलग-अलग अध्ययन कहती है कि अनार का जूस प्रोस्ट्रेट कैंसर से लड़ने में मदद करता है। एक प्रयोगशाला परीक्षण में पाया गया कि अनार का जूस कैंसर सेल के विकास को धीमा कर उसे मार देता है। एक अन्य प्रयोग में यह तथ्य सामने आया कि अनार खून की स्थिति को सुधारता है, जिससे हृदय से संबंधित बीमारी से ग्रसित रोगी को स्वास्थ्य लाभ मिलता है।
सावधानी: अनार का जूस दिल के मरीज की दवाई के साथ रिएक्शन कर सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;दस-त-स-र-हत&#34;&gt;दस्त से राहत&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अगर आप दस्त से जूझ रहे हैं तो अनार खाना अच्छा रहता है। इसका जूस मिचली पैदा होने से भी बचाता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;वजन-नह-बढ-त&#34;&gt;वजन नहीं बढाता&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अनार से वजन नहीं बढ़ता है, क्योंकि यह बिना कैलोरी वाला फल है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;हड-ड-बन-मजब-त&#34;&gt;हड्डी बने मजबूत&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कार्टिलेग को विकृत होने से बचाता है- इस फल से हड्डी को मजबूती मिलती है और कार्टिलेग को विकृत होने से बचाता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ब-लड-प-र-शर-क-कम-करत-ह&#34;&gt;ब्लड प्रेशर को कम करता है&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ब्लड प्रेशर कम करने के लिए भी अनार काफी अच्छा माना जाता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;अल-ज-इमर-र-ग-क-घट-त-ह&#34;&gt;अल्जाइमर रोग को घटाता है&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अल्जाइमर रोग जैसी याददाश्त से संबंधित बीमारी से निजात दिलाने में भी अनार काफी उपयोगी होता है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भगौड़े आर्थिक अपराधियों के लिए अब नया कानून लाएगी सरकार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-to-bring-new-law-for-money-laundering-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-to-bring-new-law-for-money-laundering-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने गुरुवार को आर्थिक अपराधों में भगौडे़ लोगों की संपत्ति को जब्त करने के लिए एक कडे़ कानून का प्रस्ताव रखा है। इसके पीछे मकसद विजय माल्या जैसे लोगों से निपटना है जो कानून की पकड़ से बचने के लिए देश छोड़कर चले गए हैं। भगौडे़ आर्थिक अपराधी विधेयक, 2017 के प्रावधान संसद द्वारा पारित होने के बाद यह आर्थिक अपराधों से निपटने के मौजूदा कानून की जगह ले लेंगे। वित्त मंत्रालय ने कहा कि व्यापक रुप से यह माना जा रहा है कि ऊंचे मूल्य के आर्थिक अपराध करने वाले लोग कानूनी प्रक्रिया को धता बताते हैं। ऐसे में यह जरूरी है कि इस तरह की कार्रवाई पर अंकुश के लिए एक प्रभावी, तेज तर्रार और संवैधानिक रूप से मान्य कानून लाया जाए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस कानून के मसौदे के अनुसार &amp;lsquo;भगौड़ा आर्थिक अपराधी&amp;rsquo; से तात्पर्य है कि किसी व्यक्ति के खिलाफ आर्थिक अपराध में गिरफ्तारी वॉरंट जारी किया गया है और वह व्यक्ति देश छोड़कर चला गया है और आगे की कारवाई का सामना करने के लिए भारत आने से इनकार कर रहा है। इसमें आगे प्रस्ताव किया गया है कि कोई व्यक्ति भगौड़ा आर्थिक अपराधी है इसके लिए सबूत पेश करना अधिकारियों की जिम्मेदारी है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सस्ते हो जाएंगे स्मार्टफोन, सीमेंट और मेडिकल डिवाइस:GST से </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-says-gst-to-make-medical-devices-smartphones-cement-cheaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-says-gst-to-make-medical-devices-smartphones-cement-cheaper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आम लोगों तक स्मार्टफोन्स, मेडिकल डिवाइसेज और सीमेंट जैसे उत्पादों में कम जीएसटी रेट्स का फायदा पहुंचाने के मकसद से सरकार ने टैक्स का पूरा गणित समझाया है। केंद्र सरकार ने बताया है कि कैसे नई व्यवस्था के तहत आम लोगों पर अप्रत्यक्ष कर के बोझ में कमी आएगी। सोमवार को वित्त मंत्रालय की ओर से यह पूरा विश्लेषण जीएसटी काउंसिल की ओर से रेट्स फाइनल किए जाने के कुछ दिन बाद आया। इससे पहले सरकार ने कंपनियों और कारोबारियों को चेतावनी देते हुए कहा था कि यदि जुलाई से लागू होने वाली जीएसटी की व्यवस्था के तहत कम दर वाली चीजों पर ग्राहकों तक लाभ नहीं पहुंचा तो दोषियों पर कड़ा ऐक्शन लिया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_फ्लैट्स की कीमतों में आएगी 5 पर्सेंट की गिरावट _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यही नहीं सरकार की ओर से सर्विसेज को लेकर भी आने वाले दिनों में इस तरह का विस्तृत विश्लेषण सामने आ सकता है। इसकी वजह यह है कि टेलिकॉम और इंश्योरेंस सेक्टर की कंपनियों का भी कहना है कि जीएसटी की व्यवस्था लागू होने के बाद सेवाएं महंगी होंगी, जबकि सरकार का कहना है कि इससे कीमतों में कमी आएगी। मोबाइल फोन और वाइट गुड्स के कुछ मैन्युफैक्चरर्स का कहना है कि जीएसटी लागू होने के बाद कीमतों में इजाफा हो सकता है। दूसरी तरफ सरकार का कहना है कि इससे टैक्स का बोझ कम होगा। इसके अलावा इनपुट टैक्स क्रेडिट और टैक्स रिफंड के लाभ के चलते भी कीमतों में कमी आएगी। यही नहीं कई तरह के सेस और सरचार्जेज में कटौती के चलते भी कीमतें कम होंगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बताया, कैसे सस्ते हो जाएंगे स्मार्टफोन्स&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्मार्टफोन्स के मामले में सरकार ने मैन्युफैक्चरर्स के दावे का जवाब देते हुए कहा कि इन पर 2 पर्सेंट सेंट्रल एक्साइज ड्यूटी और राज्यों के अनुसार 5 से 15 पर्सेंट तक का वैट लगता है। सरकार की ओर से आधिकारिक बयान में कहा गया, &amp;lsquo;स्मार्टफोन्स पर औसत वैट रेट 12 पर्सेंट के आसपास है। वहीं, इन पर मौजूदा टैक्स कम से कम 13.5 पर्सेंट है। इसके मुकाबले हमने स्मार्टफोन्स पर 12 फीसदी जीएसटी का प्रस्ताव दिया है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;मेडिकल डिवाइसेज का भी हिसाब बताया&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मेडिकल डिवाइसेज को लेकर सरकार ने बताया कि इन पर अभी सेंट्रल एक्साइज ड्यूटी और वैट समेत कुल 13 पर्सेंट टैक्स लगता है। वहीं, सरकार ने 12 पर्सेंट जीएसटी लगाने का ही प्रस्ताव दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सेल्फी से ड्यूटी का &#39;सबूत&#39; देंगे ट्रैफिक पुलिसकर्मी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dcp-asks-junior-traffic-cops-to-click-selfies-while-on-duty-and-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dcp-asks-junior-traffic-cops-to-click-selfies-while-on-duty-and-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपको चौराहे पर कोई ट्रैफिक पुलिसवाला सेल्फी लेते हुए दिख जाए तो उसे हैरतभरी नजरों से मत देखिएगा क्योंकि वह सिर्फ अपनी ड्यूटी कर रहा होगा। मुबंई ट्रैफिक पुलिस के DCP ने सभी जूनियर ऑफिसर्स को अपनी ड्यूटी वाली जगह पर से सेल्फी लेकर भेजने के निर्देश दिए हैं। उन्हें ये सेल्फी ऑफिशल वॉट्सऐप ग्रुप पर भेजनी हैं। इससे पहले ऑफिसर्स ग्लोबल पोजिशनिंग सिस्टम ( GPS) या वायरलेस डिवाइसेज़ के जरिए सीनियर्स को अपनी लोकेशन भेजा करते थे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पूर्व उपनगरों और मुलुंड, चेंबुर, ट्रॉम्बे, घाटकोपर, साकिनका, विक्रोली, कुर्ला, माटुंगा और बीकेसी जैसे क्षेत्रों के प्रभारी डॉ. सौरभ त्रिपाठी ने इस नए सेल्फी सिस्टम की शुरुआत की है। डॉक्टर त्रिपाठी मानते हैं कि ऑफिसर्स के ड्यूटी पर मौजूद रहने के सबूत के तौर पर सेल्फी सबसे ज्यादा विश्वसनीय है। सूत्रों का कहना है कि डॉक्टर त्रिपाठी जीपीएस या वायरलेस डिवाइसेज से भेजी गई लोकेशन पर भरोसा नहीं करते।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मुंबई ट्रैफिक पुलिस डिपार्टमेंट के एक सीनियर पुलिस इंस्पेक्टर ने कहा कि त्रिपाठी सर ने हमें पूरे दिन में अलग-अलग टाइम पर 5 सेल्फी भेजने को कहा है। हमें सुबह 9 बजे, 11 बजे और दोपहर 1-2 बजे सेल्फी भेजनी है। इसी तरह शाम को 5 से 8 बजे के बीच ऑफिशल वॉट्सऐप ग्रुप पर सेल्फी भेजने को कहा गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;त्रिपाठी ने इस बात को कन्फर्म करते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;हां, मैंने ट्रैफिक ऑफिसर्स से ड्यूटी के दौरान सेल्फी लेकर ऑफिशल वॉट्सऐप ग्रुप पर भेजने को कहा है क्योंकि सेल्फी के बैकग्राउंड से ट्रैफिक की रियल सिचुएशन पता चलती है।&amp;rsquo; एक सीनियर पुलिस इंस्पेक्टर ने नाम न बताने की शर्त पर कहा, &amp;lsquo;मैं 56 साल का हूं और स्मार्टफोन को बड़ी मुश्किल से चला पाता हूं। मैं कभी ढंग से सेल्फी नहीं ले पाता।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कुछ ट्रैफिक पुलिसवालों ने इस बात को माना भी है कि वे कभी-कभी वॉकी-टॉकी डिवाइसेज पर गलत लोकेशन भी बताते हैं। एक ऑफिसर ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;कभी&amp;ndash;कभी हम जब अपनी ड्यूटी पर पहुंचने वाले होते हैं तो फोन पर कहते हैं कि हम ड्यूटी पर पहुंच गए हैं या बस पहुंचने ही वाले हैं लेकिन हम सभी इस बात को जानते हैं कि सुबह के समय में ट्रैफिक प्रॉब्लम सीरियस होती है और हम समय से स्पॉट पर पहुंचने की कोशिश करते हैं। इसका यह मतलब नहीं कि आप हम पर संदेह करेंगे। इस तरह टेक गैजट्स की निगरानी ऑफिसर्स को डिमोटिवेट करती हैं और ऐसा करना फोर्स के मनोबल के के लिए अच्छा नहीं है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>