<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>18 specified financial transactions in which quoting of PAN is mandatory now</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</guid>
      <description>Although Aadhaar is gradually gaining more importance than PAN – a ten-digit unique alphanumeric number issued by the Income Tax Department – however, PAN is still important, especially for financial transactions. According to experts, PAN is a way for the Income Tax Department to keep tabs on your financial dealings whereas Aadhaar’s main purpose is to create a centralized database of each citizen residing in India. PAN, in fact, is a very useful tool to estimate the total tax revenue being generated in the country and to be used as an identification document is not its primary job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 financial tasks to do when a parent dies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</guid>
      <description>Goodbyes are the hardest when they are final. It’s worse if it involves one of your parents. The heartbreak is probably lesser in intensity only to that of your surviving parent, the spouse who is left grappling with a crippling emotional void at the fag end of life. Yet, it is critical to take a financial reality check and you, as progeny, are the best suited to do it.
Taking stock of the finances is an overwhelming task and it’s easy to be stumped by the maze of formalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 smart tips which can help you save more &amp; become rich</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t want to become rich? However, getting wealthy isn’t that easy. It begins with determined consciousness to get wealthy. We all know that to become rich you need to spend less than what you earn. That is because the less you spend, the more you will be able to save. You should save and invest what you have into investments (assets) that appreciate over time. Apart from these, here we are taking a look at a few really easy and ‘anyone can do it’ strategies or DIY tips that can make you a crorepati:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Money fight: Beware! Banks take this big Aadhaar card step under PMLA</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-to-now-match-original-ids-with-photocopies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-to-now-match-original-ids-with-photocopies/</guid>
      <description>The Government has made it mandatory for banks and financial institutions to check the original identification documents of individuals dealing in cash above the prescribed threshold, to weed out the use of forged or fake copies. The Department of Revenue in the Finance Ministry has issued a gazette notification making an amendment to the Prevention of Money-laundering (Maintenance of Records) Rules. The new rule now requires the reporting entity to compare “the copy of officially valid (identification) document so produced by the client with the original and recording the same on the copy”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadline To Link Aadhaar With Government Schemes Extended till March 31</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/deadline-linking-aadhaar-govt-schemes-now-dec-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/deadline-linking-aadhaar-govt-schemes-now-dec-31/</guid>
      <description>The deadline for mandatory linking of Aadhaar to avail benefits of various government schemes would be extended till March 31 next year, the Centre told the Supreme Court Wednesday. It told a bench headed by Chief Justice Dipak Misra that the deadline for Aadhaar linking to avail benefits of the schemes was to end in December and it has now been decided to extend it till March 31, 2018.
&amp;ldquo;We have decided to extend it till March 31, 2018,&amp;rdquo; Attorney General K K Venugopal told the bench, which also comprised Justices A M Khanwilkar and D Y Chandrachud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get 60GB :Vodafone Latest Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-60gb-additional-data-in-rs-399-plan-ahead-of-diwali-to-counter-jio-airtel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-60gb-additional-data-in-rs-399-plan-ahead-of-diwali-to-counter-jio-airtel/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone is offering 90GB data to post-paid users at a monthly rental of Rs. 399. Vodafone has launched this plan for its prepaid users willing to shift to a post-paid plan. The company has been sending promotional messages to customers, informing them about this offer. Diwali is just a few days away and incumbent telecom operators, which are already reeling under the impact of new entrant Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s bumper offers, do not want to miss out on any chance to woo customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.
Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only 5 Free ATM Transactions From October, Punjab National Bank Says</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</guid>
      <description>PNB customers will have to shell out money beginning October if they carry out more than five transactions a month from the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs. At present, account holders of the country&amp;rsquo;s second largest public sector bank can make any number of transactions in a month, financial or non-financial, at the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs without attracting any charge.
&amp;ldquo;The number of free transactions and the charges beyond these free transactions for PNB customers on PNB ATMs have been revised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs Rs. 1,000 Off On :How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.
After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 97 A Month Unlimited Data,Unlimited Calling:BSNL-Micromax Launch JioPhone Rival </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-micromaxs-bharat-phone-offer-get-unlimited-calling-data-for-rs-97-a-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-micromaxs-bharat-phone-offer-get-unlimited-calling-data-for-rs-97-a-month/</guid>
      <description>Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) is now offering unlimited calling and data for Rs. 97 per month for users of Micromax&amp;rsquo;s 4G VoLTE enabled Bharat phone. Priced at Rs. 2,200, the Bharat 1 phone will support 3G connection as well. &amp;ldquo;I am glad that BSNL has come with two new schemes. This will not only increase BSNL subscribers but also strengthen their financial position,&amp;rdquo; Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha said while launching the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three New Modes Are Here For Aadhaar-SIM Linking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-sim-linking-three-new-modes-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-sim-linking-three-new-modes-announced/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to expedite linking of mobile phone numbers with Aadhaar, the government on Wednesday announced three new modes to complete the process from the comfort of home. Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha said mobile numbers can be linked with Aadhaar through OTP (one time password), app or IVRS facility. This has been done to simplify the process and make it convenient for people, the minister said.
While the authentication of mobile phone number with Aadhaar, a process called re-verification, by visiting stores of telecom firms will continue, the government has also ordered the companies to carry out the exercise at the doorsteps of the disabled, chronically ill and senior citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Rs. 1,399 4G Smartphone, Airtel Counters Reliance Jio, Offers:Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-counters-reliance-jio-offers-4g-smartphone-at-rs-1-399-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-counters-reliance-jio-offers-4g-smartphone-at-rs-1-399-details-here/</guid>
      <description>The intense competition in the Indian telecom sector moved a notch higher with Airtel, India&amp;rsquo;s biggest telecom operator launching a 4G smartphone at an effective price of Rs. 1,399 to counter new-comer Reliance Jio, which aims to grab a bigger pie of the 50 crore feature phone users market in India with its low-cost Jio Phone. Airtel has partnered with domestic handset manufacturer Karbonn to offer Karbon A40 4G smartphone at an effective price of Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50GB Data Plan To Counter Jio&#39;s Diwali Offer:Airtel Launches </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-airtel-launches-50gb-data-plan-for-postpaid-users-ahead-of-diwali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-airtel-launches-50gb-data-plan-for-postpaid-users-ahead-of-diwali/</guid>
      <description>The intense competition in the telecom market is getting further heated up, thanks to incumbent operators and new entrant Reliance Jio. Telecom major Bharti Airtel is offering a whopping 50GB data in a special offer for postpaid customers, according to the official website of the company. The plan also offers unlimited local and STD calls, besides free roaming for incoming and outgoing calls. The data being offered is with 3G/4G speed and it can also be rolled over to the next month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data leak: Now govt agencies will safeguard your personal info</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</guid>
      <description>The linking of Aadhaar — the 12-digit unique identification number for Indian residents is about to become safer as new rules put the onus on government departments and agencies to safeguard personal data or information held by them.
Departments handling the data will have to ensure that end-users are made aware of the data usage and collection and their consent is taken either in writing or electronically, according to new guidelines issued by the government for security of personal data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar must to get government co-contribution for availing Atal Pension Yojana</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</guid>
      <description>The finance ministry on Monday said their subscribers of the Atal Pension Yojana (APY) will have to link their Aadhaar to their accounts for availing up to Rs 1,000 government’s co-contribution.
Any individual who is eligible to receive benefits under the APY will have to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo enrolment under Aadhaar authentication, the ministry said in a statement.
Pension regulator PFRDA has identified nearly 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail Airtel&#39;s Special 3GB Per Day Recharge Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avail-airtels-special-3gb-per-day-recharge-offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avail-airtels-special-3gb-per-day-recharge-offer/</guid>
      <description>Bharti Airtel, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest telecom service provider, is now offering 3GBs of 3G/4G data per day for Rs. 799. Besides this, customers will also get unlimited local and STD calls under the Rs. 799 recharge pack. The Rs. 799 plan, which is valid for a period of 28 days, is only for prepaid users, according to the Airtel website - airtel.in. With the arrival of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio, incumbent telecom operators have ramped up offers to attract customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Of Aadhaar Card: 4 Things To Do By December 31, 2017</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-three-aadhaar-linking-deadlines-not-to-miss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-three-aadhaar-linking-deadlines-not-to-miss/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar is now mandatory for carrying out a number of important tasks. These range from investment in the Public Provident Fund (PPF), National Savings Certificate (NSC) and Kisan Vikas Patra (KVP) schemes to opening of a Post Office account. Aadhaar number or Unique Identity Number (UID), the 12-digit identity number issued by the UIDAI or Unique Identification Authority of India, is based on your biometric data - collected through fingerprints and iris scans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI ATM Withdrawal Limit, Charges And Other Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-atm-withdrawal-limit-charges-and-other-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-atm-withdrawal-limit-charges-and-other-details/</guid>
      <description>SBI or State Bank of India provides the widest network of ATMs in the country (more than 43,000 ATMs across India) to customers. SBI account holders can transact free of cost at the ATMs of State Bank group and its wholly-owned subsidiaries like SBI Commercial and International Bank Ltd using their ATM-cum-debit card. Customers are allowed withdrawals of up to Rs. 2 lakh per day (both national and international) and online purchases of up to Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These Steps Will Help You Correct PAN Card Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-pan-card-details-charges-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-pan-card-details-charges-payment/</guid>
      <description>The Permanent Account Number (PAN), which is a unique 10-character alpha-numeric number, is mandatory to be quoted for filing of income tax returns (ITRs). All your financial transactions can only be processed if you have a PAN. All bank accounts and the Aadhaar identity card of an individual must be linked with PAN. PAN helps the tax department keep a tab on all your financial transactions and also helps it nab tax evaders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI Adds New Security Feature To mAadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-adds-new-security-feature-to-maadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-adds-new-security-feature-to-maadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) today said it has added a new security feature of &amp;lsquo;time-based OTP&amp;rsquo; to its mobile app mAadhaar.
The mAadhaar app allows a person to have his Aadhaar on the registered mobile, without the need to carry physical copy of Aadhar card.
The app - in its beta version - displays demographic data that is available on the Aadhaar card including name, date of birth, gender, address and photograph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>long-term benefits of retaining EPFO membership</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/benefits-of-epf-account-you-may-not-be-aware-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/benefits-of-epf-account-you-may-not-be-aware-of/</guid>
      <description>EPFO or Employees Provident Fund Organisation has been coming up with many initiatives for EPF (employee provident fund) subscribers. Recently, the retirement fund body introduced a composite form (Form 11) which will help in the process of automatic transfer of provident fund when changing jobs. Typically, both the employer and employee contribute 12 per cent of basic salary towards EPF. An employee&amp;rsquo;s 12 per cent contribution goes toward EPF kitty, while 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card: Easy way to Verify Your Email, Mobile Number</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-how-to-verify-your-aadhaar-email-aadhaar-mobile-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-how-to-verify-your-aadhaar-email-aadhaar-mobile-number/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar card, which has printed on it the 12-digit Unique Identity Number (UAN) issued by the UIDAI or Unique Identification Authority of India, is now required to be mandatorily linked with PAN (Permanent Account Number) card and bank accounts. With the government mandating quoting of Aadhaar card for many tasks, it is paramount to verify your Aadhaar number or UID (the number given on Aadhaar card). Be it filing your income tax return (ITR) or submitting your application for a PAN card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar To Help Catch Money Launderers, Fake Bank Accounts, Says Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-to-help-catch-money-launderers-fake-bank-accounts-says-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-to-help-catch-money-launderers-fake-bank-accounts-says-government/</guid>
      <description>Linking bank accounts with Aadhaar will help catching money launderers and fake account holders, Law and IT Minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said on Tuesday. &amp;ldquo;Why we are linking bank account to the Aadhaar. If you do money laundering, you can be caught. If you have fake bank accounts, you will be caught,&amp;rdquo; Mr Prasad said at cyber security conference organised by Observer Research Foundation. He said 60 lakh bank accounts have been linked to Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Minimum Balance, SBI Cuts Account Closure Charges. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-closure-charges-here-are-the-changes-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-closure-charges-here-are-the-changes-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>After slashing monthly average balance requirement and charges for its savings bank account holders, SBI has revised the account closure charges. In a Twitter post, SBI said that closure of regular savings account on conversion to basic savings bank account, which earlier used to attract a charge of Rs. 500 plus GST of 18 per cent, will be nil from October 1, 2017. Similarly, savings accounts closed on settlement of deceased depositors, will also be exempt from charges with effect from October 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checklist of documents and accounts to link with Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/checklist-of-documents-and-accounts-to-link-with-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/checklist-of-documents-and-accounts-to-link-with-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>Like it or not, life without Aadhaar is going to be rather difficult from here on. From getting a mobile connection to getting government subsidies and pension, and conducting financial transactions, you just cannot escape Aadhaar. There is a long list of documents and accounts where linking your Aadhaar number has been made mandatory. Then there are those where it is yet to become compulsory but it can help in revalidation of existing documents or establishing one&amp;rsquo;s identity while applying for new documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customers’ consent must for use of Aadhaar-based e-KYC: IRDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-consent-must-use-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-irdai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-consent-must-use-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-irdai/</guid>
      <description>The use of Aadhaar and accessing of personal information of Unique Identity Authority of India (UIDAI) for e-Know Your Customer (e-KYC) purposes can only be done only on the voluntary consent of customer, the insurance regulator has said.
In a clarification on the existing circulars issued on the matter, the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (IRDAI) said that insurers can use the e-authentication facility being provided by UIDAI either through the fingerprint or iris scanning) or through one time password (OTP) received on client’s mobile number or on e-mail address registered with UIDAI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: BSNL Offers Free Calls, 28 GB Data At Rs 249, 90 GB At Rs 429</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-free-on-net-calls-28-gb-data-at-rs-249-90-gb-at-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-free-on-net-calls-28-gb-data-at-rs-249-90-gb-at-rs/</guid>
      <description>Amid intense competition among telecom companies led by Reliance Jio, BSNL (Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited) has announced a promotional special tariff voucher (STV) or recharge coupon at Rs 249 which includes voice and data benefits. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 249 recharge pack comes with a validity of 28 days, according to its website - bsnl.co.in. Under a limited-period scheme, BSNL prepaid customers recharging their mobile connection with the Rs 249 pack will get 10 GB of data per day, among other benefits, according to the BSNL website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio-Apple Offer: What It Holds For You</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-apple-iphone-offer-10-facts-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-apple-iphone-offer-10-facts-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio has teamed up with Cupertino, US-based Apple in order to garner more users for its telecom network. The two companies recently announced their partnership in which Jio offered to buy back the new models of iPhones at an attractive price. If customers who buy Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone 8/ iPhone 8 Plus/ iPhone X models, recharge with Jio for a plan worth Rs. 799 every months, Reliance will buy back the high-end phones after 12 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI ATM Withdrawal Charges, Revised Minimum Balance Rules. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-revised-minimum-balance-rules-atm-withdrawal-charges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-revised-minimum-balance-rules-atm-withdrawal-charges/</guid>
      <description>SBI, the biggest lender in the country, recently reduced the monthly average balance requirement for metro cities and slashed charges for non-maintenance by up to 50 per cent, effective from October 1. For the purpose of monthly average balance, all SBI savings bank accounts are segregated into four categories of branches - metro, urban, semi-urban and rural. Earlier, the monthly average balance required for savings accounts was Rs. 5,000 in metro branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Basic Savings Account: No Minimum Balance Charges And Other Benefits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-basic-savings-account-no-minimum-balance-charges-and-other-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-basic-savings-account-no-minimum-balance-charges-and-other-benefits/</guid>
      <description>Normal savings account holders, who want to avoid paying minimum balance non-maintaining charges, can convert their account to basic savings bank deposit accounts without any fee, SBI said.
India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI has clarified that charges for non-maintenance of monthly average balance does not apply to all its bank accounts. In a Twitter post, SBI said that basic savings bank deposit accounts are exempted from maintaining monthly average balance. Out of the 40 crore savings bank accounts that SBI has, 13 crore accounts fall under exempted category, the state-owned lender said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Festival Loan Offers, Charges And Other Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-festival-loan-offers-charges-and-other-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-festival-loan-offers-charges-and-other-details-here/</guid>
      <description>If you are planning on take a loan to finance some festive season shopping but do not wish to completely exhaust your credit card or take a personal loan, State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender has rolled out its Festival Loans program. The loans can be used meet any kind of festival related expenses, the bank said, adding that these loans will be cleared with minimum documentation and will carry no administration charges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Without Aadhaar Enrolment Centres To Face Fine From October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-without-aadhaar-enrolment-centres-to-face-fine-from-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-without-aadhaar-enrolment-centres-to-face-fine-from-october/</guid>
      <description>The UIDAI has given banks one more month to open Aadhaar enrolment centres in a stipulated 10 per cent of branches and will impose Rs. 20,000 as fine per uncovered branch after September 30, CEO Ajay Bhushan Pandey said today.
The Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), in July, had asked private as well as public banks to open Aadhaar enrolment and updation facility in one out of 10 branches by August-end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines To Link Aadhaar With PAN, Mobile Number, Bank Account: A Checklist</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/four-deadlines-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan-mobile-number-sim-banks-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/four-deadlines-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan-mobile-number-sim-banks-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Quoting of Aadhaar number - the 12-digit number given on the Aadhaar card - has been made mandatory for many essentials. These range from filing of income tax returns (ITR) to applying for a PAN or permanent account number to using a mobile phone connection. The government is moving ahead with linking Aadhaar with mobile SIM cards, according to a report by news agency Indo-Asian News Service (IANS). All mobile phone numbers or SIMs not linked with Aadhaar will be deactivated after February 2018, the agency said citing informed sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government: Digital Transactions In All Co-Operative Banks By 2018</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-transactions-in-all-co-operative-banks-by-2018-says-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-transactions-in-all-co-operative-banks-by-2018-says-government/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) on Monday said all co-operative banks in the country would be part of digital transactions by March 2018.
&amp;ldquo;The Unified Payments Interface (UPI) ecosystem now covers all public sector undertakings and major private banks. We are in the process of extending the service for co-operative bank. All co-operative banks, which computerised their operation, would be part of digital transactions,&amp;rdquo; said NPCI Managing Director and CEO A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio: Not Rs 1500, you will have to spend at least Rs 4500 to get a refund:Jio Phone terms &amp; conditions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-terms-conditions-not-rs-1500-you-will-have-to-spend-at-least-rs-4500-to-get-a-refund/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-terms-conditions-not-rs-1500-you-will-have-to-spend-at-least-rs-4500-to-get-a-refund/</guid>
      <description>Jio Phone costs Rs 1500 which the company said will be refunded after a period of 3 years. Here&amp;rsquo;s why you will have to pay at least Rs 4,500.
Reliance Jio Phone has finally started getting delivered and if you are staying in a rural area chances are you will get it first. The Jio Phone costs Rs 1500 which the company said will be refunded after a period of 3 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.
Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF Money Transfer Becomes Easier. Here Is The New Rule</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-money-transfer-becomes-easier-here-is-the-new-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-money-transfer-becomes-easier-here-is-the-new-rule/</guid>
      <description>Retirement fund body EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers are no longer required to file separate EPF transfer claims using Form-13 after changing jobs as it will now be done automatically.
Now, at the time of joining new employer, the employees&amp;rsquo; can give details of their previous EPF account in new composite F-11 form to give declaration about their details, a senior official said.
Once the old EPF account details are provided in F-11 form, the funds will be automatically transferred by the EPFO to new EPF account, the official added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI&#39;s New Rule On Minimum Account Balance, Charges Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-new-rule-on-minimum-account-balance-charges-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-new-rule-on-minimum-account-balance-charges-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>SBI (State Bank of India), the biggest lender in the country, brings cheers for the 42 crore customers holding savings accounts in the bank by reducing its monthly average balance (MAB) requirements and charges for non-compliance. That means customers not maintaining sufficient balance in SBI savings bank accounts will now pay lower charges. In a press release, SBI said it has reduced the MAB requirement for metro cities and slashed charges for non-maintenance by up to 50 per cent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammers are trying to get your Aadhaar details via calls, emails</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</guid>
      <description>Watch out! The scammers are out with a new set of tricks to swindle the gullible public. Curiously, the Centre’s directive to link the bank accounts with Aadhaar has apparently made these fraudsters more brazen. Their latest modus operandi is to seek details of the Aadhaar card from unsuspecting victims through phone calls and emails.
Posing as bank executives or tele-callers, they call up potential victims saying, “The bank has decided to link your Aadhaar number with debit card for better customer service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.
To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-facility to link Aadhaar with PAN launched</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</guid>
      <description>I-T Department asks people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.
The Income Tax Department has launched an e-facility to link Aadhaar with Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing IT returns now.
The department’s e-filing website https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in has created the link on its homepage.
The link requires the PAN, the Aadhaar number and the “exact name as given in the Aadhaar card”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things that are banned for you, from opening a bank account to processing of I-T returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</guid>
      <description>If you thought that filing an income tax return or opening a bank account are the only few things which require Aadhaar cards now, then think again. The fact is Aadhaar has now been made mandatory for so many things, including availing the benefits of various social and government schemes. While for some schemes it has already been made compulsory, for some others it will be made mandatory soon.
Here we are taking a look at 10 such things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.
“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.
He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.27 Lakh Assessees Respond To Income Tax Query On Cash Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-27-lakh-assessees-respond-to-income-tax-query-on-cash-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-27-lakh-assessees-respond-to-income-tax-query-on-cash-deposits/</guid>
      <description>Responding to the SMS/email queries under &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo;, the assessees have disclosed additional 25,000 bank accounts in which cash was deposited.
The I-T Department on Monday said 5.27 lakh assessees, out of 18 lakh who were sent SMS/emails for making suspicious deposits post demonetisation, have submitted their response and warned others of &amp;lsquo;enforcement action&amp;rsquo; if they fail to respond by February 15.
It further said that 99.5 per cent of the 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>508 Km In 3 Hours: India&#39;s First Bullet Train Project In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/508-km-in-3-hours-india-s-first-bullet-train-project-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/508-km-in-3-hours-india-s-first-bullet-train-project-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his Japanese counterpart Shinzo Abe laid the foundation stone for India’s first bullet train project in Ahmedabad on Thursday. The bullet train project touted to revolutionize railways technology in the country. The first line which will connect Ahmedabad to Mumbai can cover the 508 km distance in as little as two hours, the government said. The project will be executed as a joint venture between the Indian Railways and Japanese firm Shinkansen Technology at an estimated cost of Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.
The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.
Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar authentication a must for engineering scholarships</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>The state higher and technical education department has made authentication of Aadhaar number a must for backward engineering students to avail scholarships. The move comes against the backdrop of large-scale scholarship scam across the state.
Though decision has been welcomed by city engineering colleges, they feel the authentication process will burden them with extra work.
In a gazette notification dated April 13, the department states that every student desirous of availing benefits under the schemes specified in Schedule ‘A’ need to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo authentication process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.
Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data hack: IIT Kharagpur graduate arrested, earns Rs 40 lakh a year at Ola</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</guid>
      <description>An IIT Kharagpur graduate, Abhinav Srivastava, who allegedly hacked Aadhaar data has been arrested by Bengaluru Police. According to investigation, Srivastava had gained access to the repository of the Unique Identification Development Authority of India’s (UIDAI) Aadhaar project through the Digital India e-hospital portal. The 31-year-old hails from Uttar Pradesh and was arrested in connection with a complaint filed by the UIDAI on July 26, according to Indian Express.
Police said the complaint against Srivastava stated that he accessed UIDAI data without authorisation between January 1 and July 26 for an app called ‘eKYC Verification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>