<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar mandatory to avoid fake PAN cards: Government tells Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government today defended in the Supreme Court its decisionto make Aadhaar mandatory for issuing of PAN cards, saying it was done to curb the use of fake PAN cards across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi told a bench comprising Justices A K Sikri and Ashok Bhushan that the programme of PAN had become suspect as it could be faked while Aadhaar is a &amp;ldquo;secure and robust&amp;rdquo; system by which the identity of an individual cannot be faked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AG said that due to Aadhaar, government has saved over Rs 50,000 crore on the schemes to benefit the poor as well as the pension schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that around 10 lakh PAN cards have been cancelled, while out of the 113.7 crore Aadhaar cards issued, no case of duplication has been found by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that Aadhaar was an effective tool to check the menace of terror funding and circulation of black money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The idea behind Aadhaar is to make a secure and robust system by which the identity of a person cannot be faked,&amp;rdquo; the Attorney General told the court, which would continue hearing the arguments tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court is hearing three petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Section 139 AA of the Income Tax Act which was introduced through the latest budget and the Finance Act 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Section 139AA provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns and making an application for allotment of PAN number with effect from July 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior counsel Shyam Divan, representing the petitioners, had earlier argued that section 139AA was unconstitutional and was in &amp;ldquo;direct collision&amp;rdquo; with the Aadhaar Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had also contended that there was no question of forcing a person to give his consent for Aadhaar and this was an issue which &amp;ldquo;alters the relationship of Republic of India with its citizens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The petitioner had also argued that a law-abiding tax payer cannot be forced to give his Aadhaar number while filing income tax returns and this was like an &amp;ldquo;electronic leash&amp;rdquo; as government would be able to keep a tab on its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nowhere in the world there is such a biometric system which can track a person 24X7. They (government) are doing it even before the age of consent,&amp;rdquo; he had said during the arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had earlier put a poser as to why there was no objection from the lawmakers on the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for making PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rohatgi had also clarified that nowhere in section 139AA of IT Act, was it mentioned that it would be effective with retrospective effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had earlier told the apex court that fake PAN cards were being used to &amp;ldquo;divert funds&amp;rdquo; to shell companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks vs e-wallets: Who is winning in cashless India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When two of the biggest banks in the country resist wallets from fintech start-ups, you know a few things are simmering. First, SBI disallowed its net banking users to top up third party wallets and next, ICICI blocked transactions on PhonePe, a Flipkart managed wallet that was launched in partnership with YES Bank – PhonePe allows users to link bank accounts to the smartphone through the National Payments Corporation of India’s encrypted software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While SBI cited security concerns, ICICI said PhonePe was “following restrictive practices allowing users to make payments with only its UPI handle which is in contravention to the UPI guidelines of interoperability…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While security concerns could be real, there is more to it than meets the eye. There is an imminent threat from fintech start-ups to the Indian financial services industry as we see growing disintermediation in mobile payments, financial product comparison/aggregation, lending, and remittances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report by consulting firm Zinnov released mid-2016, investments in the fintech sector crossed $1.3 billion.  Mobile wallet start-ups have received the most funding – they have been using this capital to both aggressively market as well as improve the ease of using their technology. Compared to say a Paytm, SBI’s wallet ‘SBI Buddy’ and ICICI’s ‘Pockets’ have much less brand recall. These privately funded start-ups are now threatening the banks from three sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, banks are worried about relationship with their customers being upended. Banks had failed to notice India’s demographic shift; the young did not want complicated KYC norms even for small transactions such as mobile recharges. They love the app economy and the convenience it provides. Wallets stepped in to provide a better payments experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was a slipping market scenario for traditional banks.  The banking industry’s business model majorly centres around retail as well as corporate lending and not small value transactions. However, according to some estimates, the payments market is a mammoth $500 billion opportunity today when domestic and international remittances, government, utility bills as well as merchant payments are included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New payment categories have come into being as well — taxi payments were always in cash a couple of years ago. Today, tech savvy customers are paying their maid or a driver through money transfers. Many more new categories could emerge.  If these start-ups, armed with private equity money, were to garner a major share of this pie, it would be more than an opportunity lost for traditional banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third threat, and a more serious one, is about data. What happens when users start trusting payment companies? The fallout of such a scenario – where both trust and transactions move to wallet companies – would reflect in a bank’s visibility of customer data or their behaviour patterns. That, in turn, would reduce a bank’s ability to cross sell or up sell other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may, in fact, become reliant on wallet companies for such data. Payment companies, for instance, will be in a better position to judge the credit worthiness of many retail customers the banks are after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, the margins of many banks could slip due to competition. As smart phones become more affordable and pervasive, experts see fintech start-ups scale massively. And if traditional banks don’t align their cost structures with current realities — especially the public sector ones — they can find themselves in a quagmire with only “restrictive practices” as aid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 19 To Rs 9,999: What Jio Prepaid, Postpaid Users Get</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering free voice calls and roaming on all its post-paid and pre-paid plans. Also there is no charge for data used to make 4G voice calls under all its plans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. Beyond the daily 4G data limits of 1GB and 2GB per day across its prepaid recharges and postpaid plans, wherever specified, subscribers will continue to use unlimited internet at a reduced speed of 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service - prepaid and postpaid alike - include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are various plans offered by Jio, as per its website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREPAID&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for just one day, Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid offerings start from the Rs 19 recharge, which includes 200 MB of 4G data for Prime members and 100 MB for non-Prime members, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 49&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s next recharge is priced at Rs 49. Jio Prime members recharging with the Rs 49 voucher get 600 MB of high speed data over a validity of three days. The 4G data on offer under this pack is limited to 300 MB for non-Prime members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 96&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge comes with 1GB of 4G data per day. That is for Prime members. Non-Prime members get 600MB of 4G data for seven days with a recharge of Rs 96.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 149&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data valid for 28 days for Prime users and 1GB for non-Prime subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime subscribers buying their first recharge of Rs 309 will get 1GB of 4G data per day for 84 days, as per the Jio website. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first recharge of Rs 509 offers 2GB of 4G data daily, for 84 days. This is comparable with half of the daily 4G data on offer in the Rs 309 pack. Data benefits on subsequent recharges of Rs 509 will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Rs 999 recharge comes with a validity of 120 days, in which subscribers get 120 GB of 4G data. Subsequent recharges are limited to 60 GB of 4G data for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A first recharge of Rs 1,999 comes with 185 GB of 4G data and validity of 150 days. The 4G data on offer is 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 4,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those buying their first recharge after subscribing to Prime will get 410 GB of 4G data with a validity of 240 days. Users will get 350 GB of 4G data with a validity of 180 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is priced at Rs. 9,999. Those buying their first recharge of Rs 9,999 are being offered 810 GB of 4G data with a validity of 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;postpaid&#34;&gt;POSTPAID&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First cycle: Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data per day - which sums up to 90GB of 4G data - for a period of three months under this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequent cycle: Customers will get 30GB of 4G data for a period of one month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering 2GB of 4G data per day for a period of three months on the first cycle, and one month on subsequent cycles. Therefore, users get 180GB of 4G data for three months in the first cycle, and 60GB for one month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first cycle, Jio is offering 180 GB of 4G data for three months under the Rs 999 postpaid plan. Users will get 60 GB of 4G data per month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to choose the right credit card: 6 power points to note</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-choose-the-right-credit-card-6-power-points-to-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-choose-the-right-credit-card-6-power-points-to-note/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opt for a credit card whose benefits in the form of cashbacks, discounts, reward points and lifestyle programmes outweigh the various mandatory fees associated with it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit cards today have become an integral part of our lives. They save us from the hassles of carrying cash, allow us to optimise our finances better through interest-free periods and EMI options, enable us to maintain a good credit score and avail attractive cashbacks, discounts and reward points offered by banks. However, with several types of credit cards available in the market, choosing the right one can be confusing for a customer. Here are some factors to be considered while selecting a credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spending-habits&#34;&gt;Spending habits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most credit cards aim at specific type of transactions by offering higher reward points and other benefits on those transactions. For example, while some cards offer cashback on fuel transactions or other daily spends, others offer more reward points on air travels, dining and/or hotel stays. Choose a card that will offer you maximum benefits, according to your lifestyle and spending habits. For example, if you travel a lot, take a credit card that offers travel benefits like air miles, lounge access and hotel vouchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fees&#34;&gt;Fees&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit card issuers charge various types of fees for their services, like joining fee, annual fee, rewards redemption fee, late payment fee and cash advance fee. The joining and annual fee usually ranges between Rs 199–5,000 depending on the card category. However, many card issuers do not charge joining fee and/or annual fee. Many cards also waive off their joining fee on applying through online loan aggregators while others reverse their annual and joining fee on spending a threshold amount through their credit cards. Opt for a credit card whose benefits in the form of cashbacks, discounts, reward points and lifestyle programmes outweigh the various mandatory fees associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;also-watch&#34;&gt;Also Watch:&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/FGMeZGdYUXo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;credit-limit&#34;&gt;Credit limit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit limit refers to the maximum amount that you can spend on your card without incurring any penalty. Exceeding this limit results in incurring an over limit fee on the amount exceeded. Thus, opt for a card that offers at least 3–4 times of your tentative monthly credit card spends. Also, remember that having a higher credit limit will come in handy during financial emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;joining-bonuses&#34;&gt;Joining bonuses&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many credit cards, especially in the premium and travel segments, offer attractive joining bonuses or welcome benefits in the form of free vouchers and additional bonus reward points. Many card issuers also offer exclusive joining bonuses on applying through online aggregators. Compare the joining bonuses among similar cards before zeroing on a particular option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;finance-charges&#34;&gt;Finance charges&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card issuers levy finance charges on non-payment or part-payment of outstanding balance by the due date and on cash withdrawals. This charge is levied right from the date of the transaction until the repayment of the entire outstanding. The finance charge can vary from 22–47% per annum depending on your card type. Though not paying your entire credit card bill on time or withdrawing cash using your credit card is never recommended, you should still consider these charges when applying for a credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credit-score&#34;&gt;Credit score&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approval of your credit card application primarily depends on your credit score, monthly income and occupational details. Each bank gives different weightage to these parameters. However, people with credit scores of 750 and above have higher chances of getting their credit card approved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian ISRAELI-ORIGIN GUNS: INDIA WILL SOON START MAKING THESE FIVE DEADLY GUNS</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arming-india-india-will-soon-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arming-india-india-will-soon-start/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;From India&amp;rsquo;s first private small arms manufacturing unit based at Malanpur, M.P., India, and Israel will manufacture lethal Israeli guns for the Indian armed forces and the world. This has been made possible through a joint venture between Indian defence conglomerate, Punj Lloyd, and Israel Weapon Industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As clearly stated by Army Chief General Bipin Rawat there is a need to invest more in the military, in view of emerging security threats. And these are the guns that will add to the capabilities of the armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/FmkUwDRSdI8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;tavor&#34;&gt;Tavor&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Besides the Israel Defence Forces, it is being used across the world, including by the US and the Special Forces of the Indian Army, Navy and IAF. This weapon was also used during the surgical strikes in POK. The Special Frontier Force (SFF), a covert special operations unit, created with the help of the CIA post the 1962 India-China war, is also using them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bullpup-configuration&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Bullpup Configuration&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bullpup configuration&amp;rdquo; makes it compact, perfect for counter-terrorist operations in built up areas such as J&amp;amp;K.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves gun&amp;rsquo;s accuracy and reduces weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable at all firing positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrosion resistant metal parts. Easily maintainable in adverse battle conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses 5.56mm cartridges, as adopted by NATO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The capacity of 30 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Punj Lloyd pitching it as a replacement for INSAS rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;negev-light-machine-gun&#34;&gt;Negev Light Machine Gun&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Negev_NG7_Light_Machine_Gun.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A robust light machine gun with powerful target acquisition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopted by the Israeli Defence Forces in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also has a semi-automatic mode to provide accurate, controlled fire in close quarter battle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic mode for maximum firepower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mountable&#34;&gt;Mountable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negev cartridges are placed in the gun from a belt, which can contain up to 200 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses 5.56 mm and 7.65 mm cartridges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has different variants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Known to be a reliable weapon under extreme conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important feature: Can be mounted on inside helicopters, over vehicles and naval vessels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gun being used by the Indian armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;galil-sniper&#34;&gt;Galil Sniper&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Galil_Sniper_Rifle.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can hit targets up to 1 km away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even at this range will fire accurately at targets, which are small and mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With this weapon, combat units gain efficiency in firing at long range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The semi-automatic feature ensures it is stable while firing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7.65mm calibre and has a capacity of 10 to 25 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foldable bipod makes it suitable for user&amp;rsquo;s needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;raw-s-aim&#34;&gt;RAW&amp;rsquo;s Aim&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galil sniper being used by the covert RAW unit, Special Frontier Force, and Indian Army.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Army has been searching for sniper rifles for infantry units and Special Forces to replace the Russian Dragunov sniper rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Army&amp;rsquo;s aim is to get the new sniper rifle with greater range, accuracy, and firepower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian Navy&amp;rsquo;s MARCOS also using the rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galil is a family of small arms named after its designer, Yisrael Galil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;world-manufacturing-hub&#34;&gt;World Manufacturing Hub&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/IWI_Punj_Lloyd_Small_Arms_Plant.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Picture of the inauguration of the small arms plant at Malanpur by Madhya Pradesh Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mark Shachar, V.P. Business Development, S K Group, explained the plant will be a hub of manufacturing the weapons for the Indian armed forces and will also export them. &amp;ldquo;We will also make the plant a centre of maintenance for these guns for India and abroad,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 30:you could buy a litre of petrol</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/in-5-years-you-could-buy-a-litre-of-petrol-for-rs-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/in-5-years-you-could-buy-a-litre-of-petrol-for-rs-30/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-s-true&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you remember the last time you paid Rs 30 for a litre of petrol? Well, that was 14 years go, July 2003 to be precise. Seems like petrol will go easy on pockets again. In coming five years, you could be paying as less than Rs 30 per litre for the fuel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;future-tech&#34;&gt;Future tech&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A futuristic technology will be decreasing gthe world&amp;rsquo;s dependence on petrol so much that its prices will crash, predicts Tony Seba, an American futurist famous for predicting a boom in solar power when the prices used to be around ten times of what they are today, which came true eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seba, a serial Silicon Valley entrepreneur, is also an instructor in Entrepreneurship, Disruption and Clean Energy at Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Continuing Studies Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;global-oil-demand-to-go-down&#34;&gt;Global oil demand to go down&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding his prediction, Seba says that it is the rise of self-drive cars that would bring down the global demand for oil, reducing the price of oil to $25 a barrel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oil demand will peak 2021-2020 and will go down 100 million barrels, to 70 million barrels within 10 years. And what that means, the new equilibrium price is going to be $25,&amp;rdquo; says Seba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;affordable-electric-cars&#34;&gt;Affordable electric cars&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though people would not stop using fuelled cars, they would start using self-drive electric vehicles more, which would be cheaper to buy as well as run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;india-to-go-all-electric-by-2030&#34;&gt;India to go all-electric by 2030&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Union power minister Piyush Goyal had also said that India was looking to have all-electric car fleet by 2030, meaning that not a single petrol or diesel car would be sold in the country after 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 5 Recharge, Vodafone Offers Unlimited Data.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone said in a press release that the 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid a telecom industry witnessing Jio&amp;rsquo;s highly competitive tariff pricing, Vodafone India on Tuesday announced unlimited data plans with free local and STD calls priced from Rs 5 per day in the UP West telecom circle. Aimed at the Ramzan festival, Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively, according to a press release by the telecom company. Vodafone customers in these areas can subscribe to &amp;ldquo;Ramzan Special Pack&amp;rdquo; by dialing USSD or Unstructured Supplementary Service Data codes - *444*5# in case of 2G customers and *444*19# for 3G, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dilip Kumar Ganta, business head, UP West &amp;amp; Uttarakhand, Vodafone India said: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;With new data and calling packs, we aim to provide a service which can help customers seamlessly connect with their families and friends and enjoy internet at an affordable cost and share their emotional and spiritual experiences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 5 Ramzan Special Pack offers unlimited mobile data in 2G speed for a validity of one hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next Ramzan Special Pack priced at Rs 19 offers the same benefit in 3G speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 17&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom operator is also offering a calls-only pack at Rs 17. This recharge pack offers local and STD calls at the rate of 30 paise per minute over a validity period of 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 253&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 253 pack in the regions comes with a validity of 28 days and offers unlimited calls (local and STD) and unlimited data in 2G speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 345&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also valid for 28 days, Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 recharge pack in these circles comes with a daily data limit of 1GB along with free local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Face Or Fingerprint Could Soon Replace Your Ticket</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-face-or-fingerprint-could-soon-replace-your-plane-ticket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-face-or-fingerprint-could-soon-replace-your-plane-ticket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first phase of Delta&amp;rsquo;s program will allow its elite-tier passengers to use their fingerprints, rather than their boarding passes, to enter member lounges.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may soon be able to ditch your boarding pass in favor of your fingers or face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, Delta announced a new biometric identification pilot program that will eventually let you use your fingerprints instead of a plane ticket. That followed a JetBlue announcement hours earlier that it is testing a program in Boston that will match pictures of customers&amp;rsquo; faces with the passport database maintained by U.S. Custom and Border Protections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta&amp;rsquo;s program, which kicked off at D.C.&amp;rsquo;s Reagan National Airport, is in partnership with Clear, a company that already lets customers skip to the front of security lines without identification. To be eligible for the program, one must be a member of Delta&amp;rsquo;s frequent flyer SkyMiles program and a Clear subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first phase of Delta&amp;rsquo;s program will allow its elite-tier passengers to use their fingerprints, rather than their boarding passes, to enter member lounges. A planned second phase would allow Delta frequent flyers to use their fingerprint in lieu of a boarding pass. Per its privacy policy, which will cover the Delta program, Clear keeps users&amp;rsquo; biometric information for the term of their subscriptions. Users can ask for their information to be removed from the company&amp;rsquo;s servers and close their accounts at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airline has also announced it will use facial recognition technology for bag drops, with a pilot testing program at Minneapolis-St. Paul International Airport in the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JetBlue&amp;rsquo;s program works in concert with two entities: the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and a tech firm called SITA. Flyers at Boston&amp;rsquo;s Logan International Airport and Aruba&amp;rsquo;s Queen Beatrix International Airport will have the option of going into the normal boarding line, or one with a camera that will snap their picture. SITA will send that photo to the CBP, to match it against the agency&amp;rsquo;s database of passport and visa photos. The match process is instant, JetBlue said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither JetBlue nor SITA has access to the photo database, and the airline will not store users&amp;rsquo; biometric information, JetBlue confirmed in an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the facial scan fails to work, passengers will be moved to the traditional line - so don&amp;rsquo;t travel without your ID just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using biometric data for identification may sound convenient, but people should consider some things before signing up, said Jeramie Scott, national security counsel for the Electronic Privacy Information Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither company has released details on how the government may use information on when and where people&amp;rsquo;s faces have been scanned, he said, nor are there laws to prevent the government from using these types of programs as part of larger surveillance plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a technology that can easily be used for mass, indiscriminate surveillance,&amp;rdquo; he said, of facial recognition technology. &amp;ldquo;Any use for facial recognition for something like this - where it&amp;rsquo;s the government or companies running a facial recognition search on people - needs to be scrutinized very closely by the public, because of the serious risk of mission creep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. Customs and Border Protection did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अनाज और दूध पर टैक्स नहीं, एसी-फ्रिज भी होगा सस्ता</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-slabs-finalised-foodgrains-and-milk-exempted-from-levy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-slabs-finalised-foodgrains-and-milk-exempted-from-levy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;गुड्स ऐंड सर्विसेज टैक्स (जीएसटी) के तहत अधिकतर वस्तुओं की टैक्स दरों को लेकर केंद्र और राज्यों के बीच सहमति बन गई है। श्रीनगर में गुरुवार को शुरू हुई दो दिवसीय जीएसटी काउंसिल की बैठक में रोजमर्रा की चीजों पर टैक्स रेट घटाने का फैसला लिया गया। नए टैक्स सिस्टम के तहत कई जरूरी चीजों की कीमतें कम हो सकती हैं। अनाज और दूध को टैक्स मुक्त कर दिया गया है। प्रोसेस्ड फूड भी सस्ते हो जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;काउंसिल ने पहले दिन 6 चीजों को छोड़ अन्य सभी वस्तुओं पर 5, 12, 18 और 28 प्रतिशत की टैक्स दर तय कर दी है। मिठाई, खाद्य तेल, चीनी, चायपत्ती, कॉफी को 5% टैक्स स्लैब में रखा गया है। हेयर ऑइल, टूथपेस्ट और साबुन पर 18 फीसदी टैक्स लगाया जाएगा। अभी इन पर 28 फीसदी टैक्स लगता है। कोयले और मसालों पर भी 5% टैक्स लगेगा। एंटरटेनमेंट पर 18 पर्सेंट टैक्स लगेगा। जीवनरक्षक दवाओं को 5 प्रतिशत के टैक्स स्लैब में रखा गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कोयले पर टैक्स की दर 5 प्रतिशत होगी, जबकि अभी इस पर 11.69 प्रतिशत का कर लगता है। इससे बिजली उत्पादन सस्ता होगा। जेटली ने संवाददाताओं से कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमने (आज की बैठक में) ज्यादातर वस्तुओं के लिए कर दरों और छूट सूची को अंतिम रूप दे दिया है।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि बैठक के पहले दिन 1211 में से छह को छोड़कर बाकी सभी वस्तुओं के लिए जीएसटी दर तय कर ली गई।&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/gst1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;सूत्रों के मुताबिक छोटी कारों पर 28 फीसदी टैक्स के अलावा सेस लगाया जाएगा। लग्जरी कारों पर टैक्स के अलावा 15% सेस जोड़ा जाएगा। एसी और फ्रिज को भी 28 फीसदी टैक्स दायरे में रखा गया है। हालांकि अभी इन पर अभी 30-31 फीसदी टैक्स लगता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने मीडियाकर्मियों से कहा, &amp;lsquo;किसी भी वस्तु पर बढ़ोतरी नहीं की गई है। कई चीजों पर टैक्स की दरें कम हो जाएंगी। विचार यह है कि जीएसटी का असर महंगाई बढ़ाने वाला ना हो।&amp;rsquo; वहीं राजस्व सेक्रटरी हसमुख अधिया ने रिपोटर्स को बताया कि 1211 आइटम्स में से 7% को छूट के दायरे में रखा गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14% वस्तुओं को 5% के दायरे में रखा गया है। 17% पर 12% टैक्स लगेगा। 43% आइटम्स को 18 पर्सेंट टैक्स लिया जाएगा। अन्य 19% वस्तुओं पर 28 फीसदी टैक्स देना होगा। सोने और बीड़ी पर टैक्स स्लैब का फैसला शुक्रवार को होगा। सर्विस टैक्स की दरें भी दूसरे दिन ही तय की जाएंगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>डिजिटल पेमेंट्स को बढ़ावा देने के लिए चार्ज न वसूलें बैंक: NPCI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-may-ask-banks-not-to-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-may-ask-banks-not-to-charge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;देश में डिजिटल पेमेंट्स रेग्युलेट करने वाली संस्था नैशनल पेमेंट्स कॉर्पोरेशन ऑफ इंडिया (एनपीसीआई) ने बैंकों से यूनिफाइड पेमेंट्स इंटरफेस (UPI) बेस्ड ट्रांजैक्शंस के लिए चार्ज नहीं वसूलने का निवेदन किया है। एनपीसीआई के मुताबिक इससे डिजिटल पेमेंट्स को बढ़ावा दिया जा सकेगा और लोग वापस कैश की ओर नहीं लौटेंगे। देश के दूसरे सबसे बड़े प्राइवेट बैंक एचडीएफसी बैंक ने अपने कस्टमर्स को ईमेल के जरिए बताया है कि बैंक के जरिए होने वाली यूपीआई पेमेंट्स के लिए 10 जुलाई से चार्ज लिया जाएगा। इसके बाद ही एनपीसीआई ने बैंकों से चार्ज न लेने का निवेदन किया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एनपीसीआई के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;एनपीसीआई बैंकों से इस स्तर पर यूपीआई ट्रांजैक्शंस के लिए कस्टमर्स से चार्ज नहीं लेने का निवेदन करेगी। हालांकि, रेग्युलेशन के तहत वे चार्ज लेने के लिए स्वतंत्र हैं। हम बैंकों के साथ एक योजना पर भी काम करना चाहते हैं जिससे कम वैल्यू की ट्रांजैक्शंस के लिए चार्ज न वसूला जाए।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एचडीएफसी बैंक ने अपने कस्टमर्स को भेजे गए ईमेल में बताया कि 25,000 रुपये तक की यूपीआई बेस्ड पेमेंट्स के लिए तीन रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स और 25,000 रुपये से एक लाख रुपये तक की पेमेंट्स के लिए 5 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स लिया जाएगा। बैंकर्स ने ईटी को बताया कि यूपीआई के कामकाज का तरीका इमीडियेट पेमेंट सर्विस (आईएमपीएस) के समान होने के कारण बैंक समझौते के तहत चार्ज वसूलने की योजना बना रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक प्राइवेट बैंक के टेक्नॉलजी हेड ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आईएमपीएस ट्रांजैक्शन के लिए आमतौर पर कॉस्ट लगभग दो रुपये होती है, यूपीआई के लिए 50 पैसे अतिरिक्त देना पड़ता है क्योंकि फाइनैंशल टेक्नॉलजी कंपनी के लिए एक चार्ज है।&amp;rsquo; हालांकि, बहुत से बैंकर्स का मानना है कि डिजिटल पेमेंट्स के लिए शुरुआती दौर में चार्ज वसूलने से कस्टमर्स को दोबारा कैश की तरफ लौटने की जरूरत महसूस होगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यस बैंक और आरबीएल जैसे बैंकों का कहना है कि उनकी यूपीआई ट्रांजैक्शंस के लिए चार्ज वसूलने की कोई योजना नहीं है। रेगुलेटरी फ्रेमवर्क के तहत, बैंकों को ऐसी यूपीआई बेस्ड मर्चेंट पेमेंट्स के लिए कस्टमर्स से चार्ज लेने की अनुमति नहीं हैं जिनमें मर्चेंट डिस्काउंट रेट (एमडीआर) लागू होगा, लेकिन पीटूपी पेमेंट्स के लिए ऐसा कोई नियम नहीं है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैंकर्स की दलील है कि कस्टमर्स को बैंकों से मिलने वाली सर्विसेज के लिए भुगतान करना होगा, लेकिन इंडस्ट्री के एक्सपर्ट्स मानते हैं कि इस तरह के चार्ज से डिजिटल पेमेंट्स को बढ़ावा देने की सरकार की कोशिशों को झटका लगेगा। नोटबंदी के बाद से यूपीआई देश में डिजिटल पेमेंट्स के लिए चेहरे के तौर पर उभरा है। यूपीआई बेस्ड ट्रांजैक्शंस में लगातार बढ़ोतरी हो रही है। अप्रैल में यूपीआई से जुड़ी लगभग 2,200 करोड़ रुपये की 69 लाख ट्रांजैक्शंस हुई थीं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>देशभर में 16 जून से हर रोज पेट्रोल की कीमतों में होगा बदलाव!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-price-will-change-everyday-all-over-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-price-will-change-everyday-all-over-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कई सारे विकसित देशों में रोजाना के आधार पर तेल कंपनियां कीमतों की समीक्षा करती हैं, इसे डायनेमिक फ्यूल प्राइसिंग कहा जाता है।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारतीय तेल कंपनिया देशभर में 16 जून से रोजाना के आधार पर पेट्रोल कीमतों की समीक्षा करेंगी। टीवी चैनल ईटी नाऊ ने पेट्रोलियम और प्राकृतिक गैस मंत्रालय के अज्ञात सूत्रों के हवाले से बुधवार को इस बात की जानकारी दी। चैनल के मुताबिक पायलट प्रोजेक्ट के तौर पर 5 शहरों से शुरू की गई है प्रतिदिन समीक्षा को अब पूरे देश भर में लागू करने की योजना है। देश भर में डीजल की कीमतों की समीक्षा प्रतिदिन के आधार पर होने की फिलहाल कोई जानकारी नहीं है। वर्तमान में भारत की तीन तेल कंपनियां इंडियन ऑयल कोरपोरेशन, भारत पेट्रोलियम तथा हिंदुस्तान कोरपोरेशन 15 दिन में तेल कीमतों की समीक्षा करते हैं। इसके आधार पर तेल की कीमतें तय की जाती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मई की शुरुआत में तीनों कंपनियों ने पुडुचेरी, दक्षिण भारत के विज़ाग, पश्चिम भारत में उदयपुर, पूर्वी भारत में जमशेदपुर तथा उत्तरी भारत में चंडीगढ़ में रोजाना के आधार पर तेल कीमतों का निर्धारण करने का पायलट प्रोजेक्ट शुरू किया था। तेल कंपनियों की ओर से यह प्रोजेक्ट पूरे देश में लागू करने से पहले केवल 5 शहरों में इसलिए शुरू की गई थी ताकि वैश्विक कच्चे तेल की कीमतों में उतार-चढ़ाव में खुद को ढाला जा सके। फ्यूल रिटेल मार्केट में इन तीन कंपनियां का कुल मिलाकर 90 प्रतिशत से ज्यादा आउटलेट्स पर कब्जा है। इस लिहाज से यह कंपनियां व्यावहारिक रूप से ईंधन मूल्य निर्धारण में मानदंड स्थापित करती हैं। उम्मीद है कि रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज और एस्सार ऑयल भी इन्हीं का अनुसरण करेंगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कई सारे विकसित देशों में रोजाना के आधार पर तेल कंपनियां कीमतों की समीक्षा करती हैं, इसे डायनेमिक फ्यूल प्राइसिंग कहा जाता है। प्रतिदिन के आधार पर पेट्रोल और डीजल की कीमतों की समीक्षा कच्चे तेल की कीमतों पर निर्भर करती है और इसे लिए कीमतों का समायोजन करने के लिए 14 दिन के सर्किल का इंतजार नहीं करना पड़ता है। इस कदम से तेल कंपनियां रिटेल प्राइस को कच्चे तेल की कीमतों के आसपास रख सकेंगी और अपना नुकसान कम करने में मदद मिलेगी। वर्तमान में खुदरा मूल्य समायोजन के 14 दिन के सर्किल मुद्रा की कीमतों में उतार-चढ़ाव झेलने में कमजोर है। इस कदम से कंपनियों को मार्जिन के बारे में सटीक जानकारी मिलने में भी सहायता मिलेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>नक्सलवाद की कमर तोड़ने के लिए मोदी सरकार ने की ये प्लानिंग, पढ़ें पूरा मामला</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-plans-to-get-foliage-penetration-radar-for-naxal-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-plans-to-get-foliage-penetration-radar-for-naxal-areas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;खास बातें&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ये रडार जल्द ही नक्‍सलियों के खिलाफ ऑपरेशंस में इस्तेमाल किए जाएंगे.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;इन रडारों का इस्तेमाल पश्चिमी देशों में और इजरायल में काफी कामयाब रहा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;अजीत डोभाल ने इस बारे में जानकारी गृह मंत्री को भी दी.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार जल्द ही नक्सल ऑपरेशनों के लिए फोलिएज पैनिट्रेटिंग रडार यानि ऐसा रडारयुक्त कैमरा जो घने जंगलों में छिपे हुए नक्सलियों की गतिविधियों के बारे में जानकारी सुरक्षा बलों दे सकेगा, ख़रीदने जा रही है. एनडीटीवी इंडिया को मिली हुई जानकारी के मुताबिक़, ये रडार जल्द ही ऑपरेशंस में इस्तेमाल किए जाएंगे. इनके ज़रिए सुरक्षा बलों को घने जंगलों की तस्वीरें भी साफ़ तरह से दिखेंगी, जिसके चलते उन्हें नक्‍सलियों के खिलाफ ऑपरेशंस में मदद मिलेगी.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक सीनियर अफ़सर ने एनडीटीवी को बताया कि &amp;ldquo;आतंकियों के खिलाफ इस तरह के रडार का इस्तेमाल पश्चिमी देशों में और इजरायल में काफी कामयाब रहा है.&amp;rdquo;  बुधवार को हुई उच्चस्तरीय बैठक में राष्ट्रीय सुरक्षा सलाहकार अजीत डोभाल ने इस बारे में जानकारी गृह मंत्री को भी दी. गुरुवार को सीआरपीएफ़ सुकमा हादसे की रिपोर्ट केंद्रीय गृह मंत्रालय को सौंपने जा रहा है.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कैसे काम करेगा ये रडार&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार को अलग-अलग लोकेशन पर फिट किया जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार को एक सेन्ट्रल मॉनिटरिंग कंट्रोल रूम से जोड़ा जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार किसी भी मूवमेंट को पकड़ने के साथ ही उस जगह की इमेज और वीडियो बनाकर सीधा कंट्रोल रूम तक पहुंचाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;इस तकनीक के सहारे नक्सलियों की लोकेशन और संख्या के साथ-साथ उनके पास मौजूद हथियार और गोला-बारूद की जानकारी भी कंट्रोल रूम को देगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सरकार का आदेश, अब ऑनलाइन ही जमा करनी होगी यूनिवर्सिटी और कॉलेज की फीस</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-wont-allow-cash-fees-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-wont-allow-cash-fees-pay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार ने देश के सभी विश्वविद्यालयों और उच्च शिक्षण संस्थानों को आदेश दिया है कि नए अकादमिक सत्र से छात्रों से कैश में फीस न लें। मानव संसाधन विकास मंत्रालय ने विश्वविद्यालय अनुदान आयोग (यूजीसी) से कहा कि वह इस बारे में सभी संस्थानों को अडवाइजरी जारी करे। मंत्रालय ने अपने आदेश में यह सुनिश्चित कराने को कहा है कि सभी यूनिवर्सिटीज में पैसों का लेन-देन का डिजिटल मोड में ही किया जाए। यूनिवर्सिटीज के हेड्स को भेजे गए दिशानिर्देश में कहा गया है, &amp;lsquo;संस्थान में छात्रों की फीस, एग्जाम फीस, वेंडर पेमेंट्स और सैलरी आदि का लेन-देन सिर्फ ऑनलाइन ट्रांजैक्शंस के जरिए ही होना चाहिए।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आदेश में कहा गया है, &amp;lsquo;हॉस्टलों में छात्रों के लिए उपलब्ध सभी सेवाओं के लिए डिजिटल पेमेंट का ही इस्तेमाल किया जाना चाहिए। इसके अलावा कैम्पस में मौजूद सभी कैंटीनों और अन्य संस्थानों को भी इसके लिए प्रोत्साहित किया जाना चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; मंत्रालय ने डिजिटल पेमेंट में भी खासतौर पर BHIM ऐप के इस्तेमाल को प्रोत्साहन देने की राय दी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सभी यूनिवर्सिटीज को कहा गया है कि वे उन ट्रांजैक्शंस की सूची तैयार करें, जिन्हें फिलहाल कैश में ही किया जाता है। उसके बाद उन्हें डिजिटल मोड से करने के विकल्पों पर विचार करें। यही नहीं केंद्र सरकार ने विश्वविद्यालयों को इस मकसद के लिए एक नोडल अधिकारी की नियुक्ति करने को भी कहा है। सभी विश्वविद्यालयों को डिजिटल पेमेंट से जुड़ी रिपोर्ट हर महीने यूजीसी को भेजने को कहा गया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Loan Or Credit Card Loan: Which One To Go For?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a phone call and money gets credited to your account within 2-3 days. Yes, it is this simple today to get credit card loans. Though credit card loans are easier to get, they come at a higher cost than personal loans from banks. So you need to know clearly when to take a credit card loan or a personal loan. Even if the credit card company charges you the same rate of interest as that of personal loan, the cost for servicing credit card loan is higher. Along with processing fees and pre-closure charges, credit card companies also charge service tax on the interest you pay on your loan every month, which is 15 per cent currently (service tax@14%+ Swach Bharat Cess@ 0.5%+ Krishi Klyan Cess @ 0 .5%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you take a personal loan of Rs 1 lakh from a bank at 14 per cent interest for 24 months, then your first month instalment will be Rs 4,802, in which interest component will be Rs 1,166.66 and principal repayment will be Rs 3635.33. If you take the same loan on your credit card at the same interest rate, in the first month you have to pay Rs 4,976.99 which is Rs 175 more than what you pay on a bank loan. This is because of the service tax of Rs 175 on interest of Rs 1,166.66. This service tax is also applicable when you convert your purchases on credit card to equated monthly instalment (EMI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are some instances, where credit card loans are preferred over bank personal loans. If the amount you are opting for is less (less than Rs 50,000) and the tenure you want is less than 1 year, then credit card loans become more useful (even with higher cost) because banks generally do not offer personal loans below Rs 50,000 and for less than one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit cards even offer loans even for six months and for small amounts as low as Rs 10,000. If your requirement for funds is for a short term and you think you can repay it faster, then it is worth going for a credit card loan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>