<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Completely Digitise Air Travel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-completely-digitise-air-travel-says-jayant-sinha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-completely-digitise-air-travel-says-jayant-sinha/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government plans to use Aadhaar to ‘completely digitise’ air travel amid a raging debate on privacy concerns regarding the world’s largest biometric ID database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through verification by Aadhaar, travellers will be able to get a digital boarding pass long before their flight, Minister of State for Civil Aviation Jayant Sinha said in an interview with BloombergQuint’s Sanjay Pugalia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reaching the airport, Aadhaar biometrics would allow seamless entry through the security and check-in points, avoiding the need for a hard copy of the boarding pass, Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application programming interface will be similar to India Stack, which is part of the government’s ‘Digital India’ efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan comes as the Supreme Court hears a batch of petitions challenging the government’s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for filing taxes. There are concerns regarding security of data on government websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent report by non-profit research organisation, the Centre For Internet &amp;amp; Society, pointed out that up to 13.5 crore Aadhaar numbers can be easily accessed through government portals and nearly three-fourths of these are linked to bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government also plans to bring in a Unified Security Architecture (USA) with the help of the Central Industrial Security Force (CISF) to standardise security systems throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unified force will secure all airports, including the regional ones, in a way that the Transport Security Administration works for all U.S. airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;regional-connectivity&#34;&gt;Regional Connectivity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha expects to deploy the USA at more than 200 airports through the UDAN (Ude Desh Ke Aam Naagrik) initiative. It has already increased the number of airports from 75 to 108, Sinha added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UDAN scheme aims to boost regional connectivity with flights covering smaller distances through a market-based mechanism. The flying price has been capped at Rs 2,500 per hour to allow more flyers while airlines will get tax concessions to ensure feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo Airlines, owned by InterGlobe Aviation Ltd., has invested Rs 10,000 crore to acquire 50 turbojets for short-distance flights. Sinha said that national airlines such as IndiGo, SpiceJet, and others, are expected to handle regional routes through subsidiaries. He hopes that this will help shape up the regional aviation industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Loan Or Credit Card Loan: Which One To Go For?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a phone call and money gets credited to your account within 2-3 days. Yes, it is this simple today to get credit card loans. Though credit card loans are easier to get, they come at a higher cost than personal loans from banks. So you need to know clearly when to take a credit card loan or a personal loan. Even if the credit card company charges you the same rate of interest as that of personal loan, the cost for servicing credit card loan is higher. Along with processing fees and pre-closure charges, credit card companies also charge service tax on the interest you pay on your loan every month, which is 15 per cent currently (service tax@14%+ Swach Bharat Cess@ 0.5%+ Krishi Klyan Cess @ 0 .5%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you take a personal loan of Rs 1 lakh from a bank at 14 per cent interest for 24 months, then your first month instalment will be Rs 4,802, in which interest component will be Rs 1,166.66 and principal repayment will be Rs 3635.33. If you take the same loan on your credit card at the same interest rate, in the first month you have to pay Rs 4,976.99 which is Rs 175 more than what you pay on a bank loan. This is because of the service tax of Rs 175 on interest of Rs 1,166.66. This service tax is also applicable when you convert your purchases on credit card to equated monthly instalment (EMI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are some instances, where credit card loans are preferred over bank personal loans. If the amount you are opting for is less (less than Rs 50,000) and the tenure you want is less than 1 year, then credit card loans become more useful (even with higher cost) because banks generally do not offer personal loans below Rs 50,000 and for less than one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit cards even offer loans even for six months and for small amounts as low as Rs 10,000. If your requirement for funds is for a short term and you think you can repay it faster, then it is worth going for a credit card loan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banking on Aadhaar without bank accounts via IndiaPost payments bank can be a real game-changer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banking-aadhaar-without-bank-accounts-via-indiapost-payments-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banking-aadhaar-without-bank-accounts-via-indiapost-payments-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar-based transactions by people even without a bank account through the IndiaPost payments bank’s Aadhaar-pay model could be the real game-changer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears extremely attractive in the context of the government’s drive to promote digital transactions in a big way that Aadhaar numbers of the people—the total number has touched 112 crore already—will be good enough to pay or receive money, even without a bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what IndiaPost payments bank is striving to establish as its basic model once it starts operations in the next few months. According to its CEO A P Singh this can change the face of financial transaction in the country, especially in the rural areas where post offices can play a big role in promoting financial inclusion and handling direct benefit transfers (DBT), which is still around Rs 50,000 crore in a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way it will work is, take for example MGNREGA payment to a worker is sent to the nearest post office mentioning his/her Aadhaar number. The worker will go to the post office, complete the Aadhaar authentication process, and just take out that money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be various options with him apart from just taking cash—he/she can open an account with the IndiaPost payments bank immediately as the e-KYC process is complete with Aadhaar authentication, or just take a pre-paid card which can be used in any ATM to withdraw cash or make payments anywhere just as a debit card does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switch to normal transaction between two persons, and the same thing can be replicated through mobile wallets without bringing in any bank account. Going ahead, India Post is planning to equip the postman with biometric authentication and payment machines to remove the hassle of even going to the post offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the extensive reach of India Post throughout the country, something that has been a major bottleneck for the banks in handling transactions in rural areas and also DBT, Aadhaar-post combine can prove to be a big driver here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That India Post is targeting about 650 districts in the country in the initial stages itself with the help of those having feature phones and even those who have not, through its network, indicates that the door-to-door banking model may soon become a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, for this model to succeed, the mobile and broadband connectivity in the rural areas will also have to improve besides Aadhaar seeding, which to a certain extent is happening at a better pace now than what it was in the UPA years, even after the launch of DBT on January 1, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only about 35% people in India are having internet facility, and out of the 65,475 gram panchayats with access to the optic fibre laid under the BharatNet project, according to a report in The Indian express, less than 25% have active internet. So, even though the government, as announced in the Budget, achieves the target of taking broadband connectivity to 1.5 lakh panchayats by the end of 2017-18—it will be of help if there is a working internet available in these panchayats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filing Income Tax Returns? Things To Keep In Mind As Deadline Approaches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The income tax filing website typically has lots of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the close of the financial year, most individuals have completed their tax planning and tax deduction exercise for the year. This leaves the final step in completing one&amp;rsquo;s income tax process - filing ITR or income tax return. Often regarded as a painful formality, you must remember that this is one of the most important income document for any individual. While July 31, 2017 is the last day to file I-T returns, remember that the income tax filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - typically has a lot of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Income Tax returns acts as an important income document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From this year on Aadhaar card is necessary to file I-T returns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I-T returns must be filed if your annual income is over Rs. 2.5 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some important things to remember when filing for tax returns according to leading share trading company and financial consultant Motilal Oswal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Anyone with an annual income of over Rs 2.5 lakh needs to file I-T returns whether the income is taxable or not. The Income Tax Department tracks lifestyle expenses, asset purchases, investments and foreign travel through your PAN card and Aadhaar number so try to be as transparent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Remember that all your sources of income must be filed as part of your I-T returns. Even if your dividends are tax-free, it is still essential to disclose all these details in your I-T returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) If you have made losses on shares or equity-oriented mutual funds, you need to show the loss when you file returns. If you do not disclose the loss in your I-T returns, you lose the benefit of setting off the losses against other gains and also lose the benefit of carrying forward these losses for a period of 8 years, says Motilal Oswal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) You are required to file your returns online on the website of the Income Tax Department. However, your job does not end there. The returns need to be e-verified which can be done by linking it to your registered bank account having the same name details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) While refunds below Rs. 50,000 are directly credited to your bank account via RTGS, refunds above Rs. 50,000 are only paid out by cheque. Hence if your refund is above Rs. 50,000 ensure that your address is updated in the I-T records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Remember that effective July 1, 2017, an Aadhaar card is a prerequisite for filing income tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) If you forget to file returns before the due date of July 31 and do not have any tax payable then you can file the returns by March 31 next year. But refund cases will not be entertained if returns are filed after the cut-off date of July 31.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Price Wars: Airtel, Vodafone, Idea Offers To Rival Jio&#39;s Dhan Dhana Dhan Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-price-wars-airtel-vodafone-idea-offers-to-rival-jios-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-price-wars-airtel-vodafone-idea-offers-to-rival-jios-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio again disrupted the voice calls and internet data tariffs after it decided to withdraw its &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. The company after withdrawing the &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; plan earlier this week launched  a new scheme called &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo;, offering &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs. 309. In response to the  &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer other telecom players like Bharti Airtel,Idea Cellular and Vodafone have also come out with special recharge plans offering their customers free voice calls and high speed 4G internet. Recent reports also suggest that Airtel and Vodafone have done away with roaming charges to counter  Jio&amp;rsquo;s free domestic roaming policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some recharge plans released in the past few days to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 399 plan:&lt;/em&gt; Under this plan, cutomers will get 1 GB of high speed 4G internet data along with 300 minutes of calling per day for Airtel to Airtel customers (1,200 minutes per week) and 3,000 minutes of local and STD calling for 70 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; In this plan customers will get 2 GB of 4G high speed internet for 28 days along with 300 minutes per day of Airtel to Airtel calling (1,200 minutes per week).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; In this plan, customers will get 1 GB of 4G internet per day along with 300 minutes of Airtel to Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for week for 70 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; Select customers can use 1GB data per day for 56 days along with unlimited and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea Rs. 351 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; Idea is offering unlimited local and STD calls and unlimited 3G/2G data per day for 4G handsets for 28 days and this recharge can be done by visiting Idea store.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Bank Account:Here Are More Ways To Transfer Your Money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-transfer-money-using-sbi-mingle-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-transfer-money-using-sbi-mingle-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India had in July 2016 launched the SBI Mingle app, allowing its customers access various banking services via social media sites Facebook and Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is offering a new facility that helps customers transfer money using their accounts on social media sites Facebook and Twitter. Users can &amp;ldquo;conveniently transfer funds&amp;rdquo; by logging on to SBI&amp;rsquo;s app &amp;lsquo;Mingle&amp;rsquo;. This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on microblogging site Twitter. SBI had in July 2016 launched the SBI Mingle app, allowing its customers access various banking services via these social media platforms. The SBI Mingle app is available on Google Play for Android mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about the SBI Mingle app:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is SBI Mingle?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Mingle is a social banking application that enables SBI customers to perform basic banking activities through the bank&amp;rsquo;s official Facebook page, the bank said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-mingle-650-400_650x287_51494382504.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The SBI Mingle app is available on Google Play for Android mobile users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to use Mingle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI customers need to register through a simple one-time process using either their account number or their ATM/Debit Card details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who can use Mingle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using SBI Mingle, SBI customers can do a host of banking services on their preferred social platform (i.e. Facebook and Twitter) at their own convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which all tasks can I perform using SBI&amp;rsquo;s Mingle app?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon completing the registration process, the SBI customers can perform a variety of tasks using the Mingle app. Some of them include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance enquiry of accounts
Obtaining a mini statement
Transfer money - within and outside SBI
Request for cheque book
Blocking of ATM Cards&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-mingle-services_650x400_61494383417.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1. Announced in a circular on the SBI website on Thursday morning, the revisions initially created confusion among customers over news that all cash withdrawals through ATM will now be charged at Rs. 25 per transaction. The bank later clarified that the Rs 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through SBI’s mobile wallet app “State Bank Buddy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an emailed statement to NDTV Profit, an SBI spokesperson clarified that a limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applied to the Basic Savings Banks deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal Saving Bank accounts will continue to get 8 free ATM transactions (5 SBI ATMs + 3 other bank ATMs) in metros &amp;amp; 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 SBI ATM + 5 Other Bank ATMs) free, the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from ATM charges, SBI also  revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers. Here are some of the other key changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh, Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; Going forward SBI said it will charge 2 rupees for every soiled note on exchange of more than 20 notes or if the total value of exchanged notes is above Rs 5,000 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs 30 plus service tax for a 10 leaf cheque book, Rs 75 with service tax for 25 leaf cheque book and Rs 150 plus service tax for a 50 leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issue of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only Rupay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Department Identifies 18 Lakh People With Suspicious Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-18-lakh-people-with-suspicious-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-18-lakh-people-with-suspicious-deposits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These people will have to reply within 10 days to avoid any notice from the tax department or further enforcement action.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax department has identified 18 lakh people who have made &amp;lsquo;suspicious&amp;rsquo; cash deposits post demonetisation, including those having deposited over Rs 5 lakh, and will send emails and SMSes seeking explanation about their source of funds. These people will have to reply within 10 days to avoid any notice from the tax department or further enforcement action. The department on Tuesday launched &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo; project under which CBDT, with data analysis and profiling of assessees, will send e-communications to people whose cash deposits post November 8 note ban do not match their income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Operation Clean Money/Swachh Dhan Abhiyan is a programming software which will be used to get answers on all the deposits made and after preliminary answers from the people. Then only, if need be, we would take legal action against those people,&amp;rdquo; Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) Chairman Sushil Chandra said 10 days&amp;rsquo; time would be given to people to reply to the e-communication and replies can be filed by logging on to the e-filing portal of the Income Tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the initial phase, we are putting data of those persons who have deposited Rs 5 lakh or more and deposits between Rs 3 lakh and Rs 5 lakh of suspicious nature and who have poor tax compliance after November 8,&amp;rdquo; Chandra said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, this will cover 18 lakh tax payers whose data will be uploaded on e-filing portal. These people while filing reply have to explain to tax department the sources of deposit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandra said that tax department has compiled huge data which shows that there are over 1 crore accounts where above Rs 2 lakh money have been deposited and involves unique PAN of 70 lakh persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have compared these vast data with the income profile, turnover and the various other particulars of income available in the income tax data bank. In the first phase where the deposits in account are not matching with our data, we are putting the same on our e-filing portal seeking explanation of source of income,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandra said the intention of the scheme is to avoid any harassment to the tax payer, they need not come to office and online verification would be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Swachh Dhan Abhiyan is a continuous exercise to widen and deepen the tax base. All the accounts in which money has been deposited will be tracked and we have hired the data analytics and we will identify the ultimate beneficiaries even in layered accounts,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>your Aadhaar is safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amidst concerns regarding Aadhaar data leak, a look at how the unique identification system actually adheres to the principles of privacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy and data protection concerns have become serious in a digital world due to ease of search and aggregation, with or without Aadhaar. Type any name in Google and it will throw up thousands of results, giving data/information publicly available. Hence, the responsibility falls on organisations which collect data from individuals to protect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a state government puts bank account details of MNREGA workers or the PAN details on its portal then one doesn’t need an Aadhaar number to find any information – simply the name will do. There may be multiple people with that name. But so what! You can always find the person with their other attributes, if available publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, each data custodian must become conscious of their responsibility to protect their customer’s data. Aadhaar has been designed as a digital identity platform, which is inclusive, unique and authenticable to participate in any digital transaction. This has transformed service delivery in our country, providing huge convenience to citizens and substantial reduction of leakages. Direct benefit transfer, subscription to various services and authentication at the point of service delivery are some benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UID project has been aware of privacy and data protection issues since the very beginning and has taken every step, as per the best practices available in the world, to ensure they are not violated. The general law on privacy is beyond the ambit of the UIDAI. With the Aadhaar Act in place, let us discuss the provisions relating to privacy and data protection in the Act.
UIDAI’s strategy document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many countries, India does not have a law on privacy. The law relating to it has been evolved by the courts through various judicial pronouncements over the years. Interestingly, the former UIDAI chairman, Nandan Nilekani, had written to the PM as early as in May 2010 suggesting a need for the privacy law. The government prepared a draft bill on Right to Privacy but it was not turned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब भी लोन पर दे रहे हैं ज्यादा ब्याज? जानें, कैसे करा सकते हैं कम</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/still-paying-interest-on-home-loan-at-old-rates-cut-emi-by-switching-to-mcls-linked-rate-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/still-paying-interest-on-home-loan-at-old-rates-cut-emi-by-switching-to-mcls-linked-rate-now/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;बैंक में राशि जमा करने वालों के साथ ही कर्जधारकों को भी ब्याज दरों में बदलाव को लेकर सचेत रहना चाहिए। कई बार नियमों की जानकारी न होने के चलते कर्जधारकों को कई बार गैरजरूरी चार्ज चुकाने पड़ते हैं। जानें, आखिर किन वजहों से कस्टमर्स को बैंकों के ओवरचार्ज चुकाने पड़ते हैं। यदि आप अपने बैंक लोन की ब्याज दर का मित्रों, रिश्तेदारों और अन्य लोगों के इंटरेस्ट रेट से तुलना करते हैं तो पता लगता है कि आपको बड़ी राशि बेवजह चुकानी पड़ रही है। अलग-अलग बैंकों की ब्याज दर अलग होती है, लेकिन एक ही बैंक में भी अलग-अलग ग्राहकों के लिए यह अलग होती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इसकी वजह कस्टमर्स का क्रेडिट स्कोर नहीं होता। कुछ बैंक नए ग्राहकों को तो सस्ते दाम पर लोन उपलब्ध करता हैं, जबकि पुराने कस्टमर्स पर अधिक रेट ही चार्ज करते रहते हैं। फिज्डम के को-फाउंजर रामगणेश अय्यर ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;बैंक अब भी लगातार भेदभावपूर्ण नीति अपनाते हुए मौजूदा ग्राहकों और नए कस्टमर्स के लिए अलग-अलग रेट पर लोन मुहैया कराते हैं। इसे रोका जाना चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; बैंकिंग रेग्युलेटर रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया को इस तरह की गलत नीति पर लगाम कसनी चाहिए। आरबीआई ने मार्जिनल कॉस्ट लेंडिंग रेट मेथड को अप्रैल, 2016 से लागू किया था। इसका मकसद यह था कि रेट कट को तेजी से लागू किया जा सके। इससे पहले प्राइम लेंडिंग रेट के आधार पर ही कर्ज की ब्याज दर तय की जाती थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जिन कर्जधारकों ने 4 या 5 साल पहले लोन लिया था और उन्होंने बैंक से नई व्यवस्था के तहत जोड़ने का आग्रह नहीं किया है, उन्हें आज भी प्राइम लेडिंग रेट सिस्टम के तहत बेस रेट पर ही इंटरेस्ट चुकाना पड़ रहा है। ऐसे में अब जबकि बैंक नए कस्टमर्स को एमसीएलआर के तहत लोन मुहैया करा रहे हैं तो पुराने ग्राहकों को अब भी अधिक ब्याज ही चुकाना पड़ रहा है। आईसर्व फाइनैंशल के सीईओ दीपक सामंत ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;बैंक यदि अलग-अलग रेट ऑफर कर रहे हों तो सबसे सही होता है कि ऐग्रिगेटर्स से संपर्क किया जाए। इससे आपको लोन के इंटरेस्ट रेट पर बारगेन करने का मौका मिलेगा।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यदि आप अपने पुराने लोन पर इंटरेस्ट कम कराना चाहते हैं तो इसके लिए आपको इसे बेस रेट से एमसीएलआर पर शिफ्ट कराना होगा। एक्सपर्ट्स के मुताबिक एमसीएलआर में शिफ्ट कराना अच्छा कदम होगा। इन्वेस्टमेंट एक्सपर्ट बलवंत जैन का कहना है, &amp;lsquo;आरबीआई फिलहाल स्थिर नीतियां अपना रहा है। ब्याज दर में मौजूदा रेट्स से अधिक का इजाफा नहीं होगा। इसेक अलावा आने वाले एक साल के बाद इसमें कमी भी हो सकती है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ल-न-र-स-ट-कर-न-क-च-र-ज&#34;&gt;लोन रीसेट कराने के चार्ज&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैंकों की ओर से दो तरह के लोन मुहैया कराए जाते हैं: फ्लोटिंग और फिक्स्ड रेट। फ्लोटिंग रेट लोन में आरबीआई की ओर से ब्याज दरों में कमी और इजाफे के अनुसार बदलाव होता रहता है, जबकि फिक्स्ड रेट लोन की किस्त समान रहती है। हालांकि बैंक ब्याज दर बढ़ाने में तो जल्दी दिखाते हैं, लेकिन कटौती करने में नहीं। यही नहीं पुराने बेंचमार्क से नए बेंचमार्क में लोन ट्रांसफर के लिए भी बैंक चार्ज वसूलते हैं। बैंक यह चार्ज नए अग्रीमेंट्स के रजिस्ट्रेशन और स्टांप ड्यूटी के लिए भी वसूलते हैं, इसके अलावा अन्य खर्च भी इसमें शामिल होते हैं। हालांकि यह चार्ज बकाया राशि के 0.2% से अधिक नहीं होता है। हालांकि कुछ बैंक 0.5 पर्सेंट तक की राशि वसूलते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आपके पास हों तो फिलहाल संभालकर रखें बंद हो चुके नोट, जुलाई में सुप्रीम कोर्ट से मिल सकती है राहत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/supreme-court-ruling-on-note-exchange-window-in-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/supreme-court-ruling-on-note-exchange-window-in-july/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपके पास अब भी 1,000 और 500 रुपये के पुराने नोट बचे हैं तो इसे कम-से-कम जुलाई के आखिर तक सुरक्षित रखिए। सुप्रीम कोर्ट जुलाई में यह तय करेगा कि जो लोग उचित कारणों से या 8 नवंबर 2016 को नोटबंदी की घोषणा करते वक्त प्रधानमंत्री के वादे पर ऐतबार कर 30 दिसंबर 2016 तक पुराने नोट बंद नहीं कर सके, क्या उनके लिए सरकार को एक और मौका दिए जाने को कहा जाना चाहिए या नहीं। गौरतलब है कि प्रधानमंत्री ने 8 नवंबर के भाषण में चलन से बाहर किए गए नोट 30 दिसंबर के बाद भी जमा कराने का मौका दिए जाने की बात कही थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मंगलवार को सुप्रीम कोर्ट में संबंधित याचिका पर सुनवाई के दौरान अटॉर्नी जनरल मुकुल रोहतगी ने केंद्र सरकार का पक्ष रखा। उन्होंने कहा कि नोटबंदी पर लाए गए अध्यादेश में मियाद बढ़ाकर नागरिकों को नोट जमा कराने का एक और मौका दिए जाने की कोई बाध्यता नहीं है। अध्यादेश में चलन से बाहर हुए नोटों को रखना अपराध माना गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दर्जनभर से ज्यादा याचिकाकर्ताओं ने 30 दिसंबर से पहले नोट जमा नहीं करा पाने की विभिन्न वजहों का हवाला दिया। उनके वकीलों ने कोर्ट में शिकायत की कि केंद्र सरकार ने इन मामलों के बिल्कुल जुदा कारणों पर प्रतिक्रिया दिए बिना एक सामान्य सा शपथ पत्र दायर कर दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रोहतगी ने कहा कि सरकार की राय में अब बंद हो चुके नोटों को जमा कराने का कोई दूसरा मौका नहीं दिया जाएगा। केंद्र के शपथ पत्र में एक मामले का जिक्र है जिसमें याचिकाकर्ता ने 66.80 लाख रुपये मूल्य के पुराने नोट जमा कराने की मांग की है और कहा कि वह इसलिए नोट जमा नहीं करा सका क्योंकि उसका बैंक अकाउंट केवाइसी से जुड़ा नहीं था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मुख्य न्यायाधीश जे एस खेहर, जस्टिस डी वाई चंद्रचूड़ और जस्टिस संजय किशन कौल ने पुराने नोटों को रद्दी होते देखने की पीड़ा से राहत पाने के व्यक्तिगत प्रयासों में दिलचस्पी लेने से इनकार कर दिया। इन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम यह फैसला करेंगे कि क्या एक और मौका मिलेगा या नहीं। अगर हां, तो सभी को फायदा होगा।&amp;rsquo; रोहतगी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;अगर सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने पुराने नोट बदलवाने का सीमित मौका देने का फैसला करेगा तो भी यह सरकार ही तय करेगी कि 30 दिसंबर तक नोट जमा नहीं करवा पाने का किसका कारण उचित है और किसका अनुचित।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एयरटेल अपने ब्रॉडबैंड यूजर्स को मुफ्त में देगा डबल डेटा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-to-provide-high-speed-data-to-its/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-to-provide-high-speed-data-to-its/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;एयरटेल ने बुधवार को होम ब्रॉडबैंड यूजर्स के लिए नया प्लान पेश किया है। इस प्लान के मुताबिक, उन्हें अपने उसी मासिक किराए में 100 फीसदी ज्यादा हाईस्पीड डेटा मिलेगा। भारती एयरटेल (इंडिया) के हेमंत कुमार गुरुस्वामी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमारे नए प्लान का लक्ष्य भारत को डिजिटल सुपर हाइवे पर ले जाना है और यह हमारे वी-फाइबर सुपरफास्ट ब्रॉडबैंड से जुड़ा है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनी ने बयान में कहा कि देश में हाईस्पीड डेटा का इस्तेमाल तेजी से बढ़ रहा है। इस मांग को पूरा करने तथा मल्टीडिवाइस माहौल में बिना रुकावट हाईस्पीड डेटा देने के लिए करने के लिए एयरटेल ने भविष्य को ध्यान में रखते हुए &amp;lsquo;वी-फाइबर&amp;rsquo; नेटवर्क तैयार किया है। यह नेटवर्क घरों में लगातार 100 एमबीपीएस का स्पीड देता है। एयरटेल के ब्रॉडबैंड प्लान में किया गया बदलाव वी-फाइबर को ध्यान में रखकर किया गया है। दिल्ली में 899 रुपये के प्लान में अब 30 जीबी की बजाए 60 जीबी डेटा मिलेगा। 1,099 रुपये के प्लान में अब 90 जीबी डेटा, 1,299 रुपये के प्लान में 125 जीबी डेटा, 1,499 रुपये के प्लान में 160 जीबी डेटा मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>टैरिफ प्लान को लेकर जियो और एयरटेल में फिर टकराव</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/between-reliance-jio-and-airtel-offer-tariff-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/between-reliance-jio-and-airtel-offer-tariff-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;पिछले साल देश के टेलीकॉम मार्केट में प्रवेश करने वाली रिलायंस जियो और देश की सबसे बड़ी टेलिकॉम कंपनी भारती एयरटेल टैरिफ प्लान को लेकर फिर आमने-सामने आ गई हैं। जियो ने एयरटेल पर टैरिफ ऑर्डर का उल्लंघन करने और कुछ टैरिफ प्लान की मार्केटिंग भ्रामक तरीके से करने का आरोप लगयाा है और टेलिकॉम रेग्युलेटर से एयरटेल के खिलाफ कड़ी कार्रवाई करने और भारी पेनाल्टी लगाने को कहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हालांकि, एयरटेल ने इन आरोपों से इनकार करते हुए उल्टा जियो पर टेलीकॉम रेग्युलेटरी अथॉरिटी ऑफ इंडिया (TRAI) के निर्देशों का उल्लंघन करने का आरोप लगाया है। एयरटेल का कहना है कि जियो के ये आरोप नेटवर्क में कमियों सहित उसकी अपनी समस्याओं के लिए दूसरों पर दोष लगाने की पुरानी चाल का हिस्सा हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मुकेश अंबानी के मालिकाना हक वाली जियो ने TRAI को भारती एयरटेल के 293 और 449 रुपये के टैरिफ ऑफर्स के बारे में लेटर लिखकर शिकायत की है कि एयरटेल 4G हैंडसेट रखने वाले नए सब्सक्राइबर्स को ही अधिक बेनेफिट दे रही है और अन्यों को डेटा और वॉयस पर कम बेनेफिट दिए जा रहे हैं। जियो का कहना है कि यह 4G और अन्य सब्सक्राइबर्स के बीच भेदभाव है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जियो के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;इन प्रीपेड फर्स्ट रिचार्ज वाउचर्स के लिए एयरटेल की ओर से दिए गए विज्ञापनों में फ्री डेटा और वॉयस कॉल्स की भ्रामक तरीके से मार्केटिंग की जा रही है जो टेलीकम्युनिकेशन कानूनों का बड़ा उल्लंघन है।&amp;rsquo; जियो ने TRAI से एयरटेल के खिलाफ कड़ी कार्रवाई करने और पेनाल्टी लगाने की मांग की है। जियो ने TRAI से एयरटेल को तुरंत टैरिफ ऑर्डर और प्रमोशनल पैक को वापस लेने का निर्देश देने को कहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एयरटेल के प्रवक्ता ने इन आरोपों से इनकार करते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;टेलीकॉम, ई-कॉमर्स, इंश्योरेंस जैसे किसी भी बिजनेस में डिस्काउंट देना आम बात है और कंपनियां समय-समय पर इन्हें देती रहती हैं।&amp;rsquo; एयरटेल का कहना है कि जियो कई महीनों से फ्री सर्विसेज ऑफर कर रही है और अब यह ऐसे अन्य टेलfकॉम ऑपरेटर्स के खिलाफ उंगली उठा रही है जो अपने यूजर्स को बरकरार रखने के लिए डिस्काउंट की पेशकश कर रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंंपनी के प्रवक्ता ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;वास्तव में जियो TRAI के सभी दिशानिर्देशों का उल्लंघन कर रही है।&amp;rsquo; जियो की दलील है कि एयरटेल भेदभाव करने वाली तरीके से टैरिफ ऑफर कर रही है और उसने टैरिफ से जुड़े दो निर्देशों का उल्लंघन किया है। इनमें से एक ऑर्डर 16 सितंबर 2005 का है, जिसमें कहा गया है कि कस्टमर्स को भ्रमित करने वाले किसी भी टैरिफ प्लान की पेशकश, मार्केटिंग या विज्ञापन नहीं दिया जा सकता। दूसरा टैरिफ ऑर्डर 1999 का है, जिसके तहत एक टेलीकॉम कंपनी मनमाने तरीके से एक क्लास और क्लासिफिकेशन के सब्सक्राइबर्स के बीच भेदभाव नहीं कर सकती।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>प्रधानमंत्री आवास योजना: 31 दिसंबर के बाद पास होम लोन के ब्याज पर सब्सिडी शुरू</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/subsidy-on-housing-loans-applicable-from-january-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/subsidy-on-housing-loans-applicable-from-january-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;18 लाख रुपये से कम सालाना आय वाले जिस किसी व्यक्ति का भी होम लोन ऐप्लिकेशन 1 जनवरी से पास हो रहा है, वह ब्याज पर 3 से 4% तक की सब्सिडी पाने का हकदार हो जाएगा। प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने 31 दिसंबर, 2016 को आवास ऋण के ब्याज पर छूट की घोषणा की थी, लेकिन तब सालाना आय के पैमाने को लेकर स्पष्ट जानकारी नहीं दी गयी थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जरूरी जानकारी: 20 साल के लोन पर पहला घर ले रहे हैं तो 2.4 लाख रुपये का फायदा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नया घर बनाने या खरीदने वाले अविवाहित और कमाऊ युवा भी ब्याज पर छूट का लाभ उठा सकते हैं। हालांकि, खास आय वर्ग के लोग अगर 960 स्क्वॉयर फीट का फ्लैट खरीद रहे हैं तो उन्हें होम लोन के ब्याज पर 3% जबकि 1,184 स्क्वॉयर फीट वाले फ्लैट की खरीद पर ब्याज में 4% की छूट मिलेगी। हाउजिंग फाइनैंस सेक्टर के सूत्रों ने बताया कि हालांकि सरकार ने नीति तैयार कर दी है, लेकिन चुनाव आचार संहिता की वजह से इसकी घोषणा नहीं हुई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दरअसल, वित्त मंत्रालय ने बैंकों और हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कंपनियों के साथ मीटिंग की, जिसमें मध्य आय वर्ग के लिए क्रेडिट लिंक्ड सब्सिडी स्कीम पर चर्चा हुई। आवास ऋण के ब्याज पर छूट मिलने से शहरी इलाकों में घरों की मांग बढ़ने की उम्मीद है जिससे रियल एस्टेट सेक्टर को कारोबार बढ़ाने में मदद मिलेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>