<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Data Safe From Cyber Attacks Assures Aadhaar Body Chairman</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allaying concerns about the security of data in Aadhaar servers in the wake of &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo; ransomware attack, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) today said its database was completely secured and immune to attacks from any kind of malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The data in the Aadhaar servers is in the encrypted form. You cannot do anything with that information, which is in an encrypted form. Aadhaar main systems, which are really so very well-designed and robustly designed that there is no concern about security in Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; UIDAI chairman J Satyanarayana said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just 48 hours back we had big scare all over the world about this ransomware. So, in Aadhaar, people were sleeping peacefully (as they are sure of its security features)&amp;hellip; that it is 100 per cent sure that nothing would happen. Such robust systems were put in place in Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; he said in a programme organised by the Institution of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the government has spent Rs. 7,000 crore on establishment of Aadhaar and reaped benefits of over Rs. 50,000 crore in the form of weeding out bogus beneficiaries of government schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are geared up to do 10 crore transactions per day. And we are increasing up to 40 crore transactions per day. Our servers are capable of taking that load,&amp;rdquo; he further said. According to Satyanarayana, the Telangana government has saved Rs. 55.7 crore between January and July 2016 by deleting 38.63 lakh duplicate or ghost ration cards units using Aadhaar authentication while Andhra Pradesh saved 4,03,142 tonnes of rice and 5,000 kilo litres of kerosene by reducing 8.58 lakh cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said Reliance Jio is one of the largest private players which used Aadhaar data for its subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Not Valid Proof of Citizenship</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-valid-proof-citizenship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-valid-proof-citizenship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;##FACTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Court was considering a bail plea of a person who was booked under Section 14F of the Indian Foreigners Act. The person claimed that she is an Indian Citizen that the issuance of the Aadhaar card was in view of long residence of the petitioner in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ISSUES BEFORE THE COURT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;new passport rules which were announced by Minister of State for External Affairs VK Singh on December 23 where Aadhaar and E-Aadhaar with Date of Birth will now be considered as a valid identity proof.( Aadhaar not valid proof of citizenship or domicile; News 18/ December 26 2016)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether a mere holding of an Aadhaar card grants citizenship to any person&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HELD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court contended Section 9 of the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and other subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act 2016, state that- “9. The Aadhaar number or the authentication thereof shall not, by itself, confer any right of, or be proof of, citizenship or domicile in respect of an Aadhaar number holder.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from this the petitioner also placed reliance of his claim of his citizenship on the residence certificate issued by a representative of a local body. The Court also did away with this claim by holding the letter issued by the representative of the local body as to the residence of the petitioner also does not, ipso facto, confer citizenship on the petitioner.( High Court denies Aadhaar as proof of citizenship/ Blog.scconline/Dec 28, 2016)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;LEARNING OUTCOME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New passport rules have been announced by the Minster of State for External Affairs, where Aadhaar and E-Aadhaar with date of birth is to be considered as a valid identity proof.Aadhaar has been made compulsory for various transaction post demonetization. Aadhaar has been made compulsory for Tirupati devotees who go to Tirumala hills on foot. Aadhaar is now also mandatory for patients at the Outpatient Department (OPD) at Civil hospital in Gurugram. (Aadhaar Card not valid proof of citizenship, rules Calcutta High Court; India.com/ Dec26, 2016) At the same time it has been made clear by the High Court of Calcutta that Aadhaar card shall not confer any right of or be proof of citizenship or domicile thereto while rejecting the claim of an accused who claimed to be an Indian citizen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank. Some banks like SBI also allow customers to link their Aadhaar number to their bank account at an ATM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are different easy ways through which you can update your aadhaar number in your bank account without having to visit your bank branch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To link your Aadhaar to your bank account online:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to the internet banking service of your bank.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the &amp;ldquo;Update Aadhar Card Details&amp;rdquo; option or &amp;ldquo;Aadhaar Card Seeding&amp;rdquo; option and click on it. On clicking, you will be directed to another page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your Aadhaar card number and click on Submit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The last 2 digits of registered mobile number (non-editable) will be displayed to the customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank will communicate the status of the linking to Customer&amp;rsquo;s registered mobile number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To link your Aadhaar card to your bank account though SMS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your mobile number is registered with the Bank, then you can link your Aadhaar number to your bank account through SMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you are an SBI customer send SMS to 567676 in the following format: UID(space)Aadhaar number(space)Account number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the mobile number is not registered or in case the Aadhaar is already linked to Account, an SMS reply will be sent to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your mobile number is registered with the Bank, you will receive an SMS confirmation of the seeding request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many banks are yet to offer the option of linking Aadhaar to bank account through SMS,  so do check through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;your bank’s customer helpline if this option is available.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To link your Aadhaar card to your bank account from an ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some banks like SBI offer an option for seeding Aadhaar from an ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After swiping the ATM card and entering your PIN, Select the menu &amp;ldquo;Service – Registrations&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this menu, select Aadhaar Registration (or Inquiry as per your need)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select the Account type (Savings/Checking) after which you will be asked to enter your Aadhaar number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 30 Aadhaar Deadline Not To Be Extended, Government Tells Top Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of the Unique Identity programme Aadhaar are pending in the Supreme Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is &amp;ldquo;no question&amp;rdquo; of extending the June 30 deadline for making Aadhaar mandatory for availing benefits of various social welfare schemes, the centre today told the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General Mukul Rohatgi told the top court that the idea behind making Aadhaar mandatory for welfare schemes was that the benefit should not go to &amp;ldquo;ghosts&amp;rdquo; as was noticed in schemes like the public distribution system (PDS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also raised preliminary objection to the plea seeking interim relief and challenging various notifications issued by the centre and told a bench, comprising Justices A M Khanwilkar and Navin Sinha, that this matter should be listed for hearing before a five-judge constitution bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Rohatgi said that earlier, some pleas seeking identical interim reliefs were also filed and those matters were pending before the top court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bench said it would be appropriate to hear all these pleas seeking interim relief together to &amp;ldquo;avoid multiplicity&amp;rdquo; and fixed the matter for hearing on June 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the bench was considering whether to list the matter for hearing during the summer vacation, senior advocate Shyam Divan, appearing for the petitioner, said there was urgency involved in it and if the matter was not heard before June 30, &amp;ldquo;the other way was if they (centre) extend the deadline&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;There is no question of that,&amp;rdquo; Mr Rohatgi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Aadhaar are pending in the top court and would be heard by a five-judge constitution bench, which is yet to be set up by the Chief Justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Supreme Court had passed a slew of orders asking the government and its agencies not to make Aadhaar mandatory for extending benefits of their welfare schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top court, however, had allowed the Centre to seek Aadhaar card voluntarily from citizens for extending benefits of schemes like LPG subsidy, Jan Dhan scheme and Public Distribution System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Facility Launched To Link Aadhaar With PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax Department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing income tax returns (ITRs) now. The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals. The link requires a person to punch in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact name as given in the Aadhaar
card&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number and email of the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It urged them to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linking without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no need to login or be registered on e-filing website (of the I-T department). This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for a permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 crore Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Notes Ban, 91 Lakh More Came Under Tax Net, Says Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/post-notes-ban-91-lakh-more-came-under-tax-net-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/post-notes-ban-91-lakh-more-came-under-tax-net-says/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post notes ban, there has been a hike in collection of personal income tax, the finance minister said, adding that the new portal will help honest tax payer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finance Minister says number of assessees has gone up post notes ban&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal income tax collection has gone up post notes ban, he adds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr Jaitley expects further increase in tax returns going ahead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of persons under the tax net has increased by 91 lakh as unaccounted cash lost anonymity post note ban, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launching a new website on &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo;, a programme to bring illegal wealth on books, he said the fallout of the November 8 decision to demonetise higher denomination currency has increased movement towards digitisation, number of assessees going up and tax revenue jumping as also fear of dealing in cash being instilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stating that as many as 91 lakh persons have come under the tax net, Jaitley said he expects further increase in tax returns going ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post demonetisation, there has been a hike in collection of personal income tax, the finance minister said, adding that the new portal will help honest tax payer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT Chairman Sushil Chandra said there was 22 per cent growth in e-filed returns post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many as 17.92 lakh people were identified for unexplained deposits post demonetisation, he said, adding the tax department has identified one lakh suspected tax avoidance cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that an undisclosed income of Rs 16,398 crore was identified post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We identified around 17.92 lakh persons in whose case the cash transactions did not appear in line with the taxpayers&amp;rsquo; profiles. And online verifications of these transactions are underway,&amp;rdquo; Chandra said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 17.92 lakh, so far 9.72 lakh individuals responded to SMSes and e-mails sent by the income tax department.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can now lock your Aadhaar data to keep it safe from hackers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now, you can lock your Aadhaar biometric details to keep it safe and unlock it whenever you want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With digital payments using Aadhaar data on the rise and cases of misuse being reported, officials of the &lt;em&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India&lt;/em&gt; (UIDAI) have come out with the new security feature to lock the biometric details (fingerprint and retinal scan data).The UIDAI introduced the lock and unlock facility following an uproar that Aadhaar deprived people of their right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric data of citizens is being collected on various platforms for government schemes, often without much safeguards. Aadhaar identification has become almost compulsory in some cases. Banks, mobile phone operators and others have access to it. “People can hack into this data and access individuals’ details, including bank accounts,” a UIDAI official warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Each time you shop and pay using your fingerprint, the data processed by POS machines can be hacked. Fingerprint details can be captured as well,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lock and unlock facility is purely voluntary. “If a person wants to lock his data, he or she can do it. No other person can unlock it. One can keep it locked as long as one wishes,” the official said Once the Aadhaar data is locked, even banks cannot access the biometric information stored in the main server.This will lead to failed transactions due to non-verification or non-authentication of the Aadhaar. The UIDAI is also planning to introduce a mobile application to lockunlock biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ने पर अवैध हो जाएगा PAN,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) को आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ा तो संभव है कि 31 दिसंबर के बाद यह अवैध हो जाए। दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के सरकार के फैसले के बाद इसे वित्तीय लेनदेन (फाइनैंशल ट्रांजैक्शंज) के लिए जरूरी नंबर बनाने की दिशा में एक और कदम बढ़ा दिया गया है। सरकार पूरे फाइनैंशल सेक्टर में आधार आधारित नो योर कस्टमर (KYC) को इंटीग्रेट करने पर विचार कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इसकी पुष्टि करते हुए कहा कि सरकार रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) सहित सभी रेग्युलेटर्स के साथ विचार-विमर्श कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार KYC एक तुरंत, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक और मजबूत प्रमाण उपलब्ध कराता है, जिससे सेवा उद्योग की प्रक्रिया बेहतर बनाने में मदद मिलेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने फाइनैंस बिल में एक संशोधन के जरिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के लिए आवेदन पर आधार को अनिवार्य बना दिया है। अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन लोगों के पास पहले से आधार मौजूद है, उन्हें किसी भी वित्तीय मध्यस्थ (फाइनैंशल इंटरमीडियरी) को अपने अंगूठे का निशान उपलब्ध कराना होगा। इसे संबंधित सेक्टर की रिपोर्टिंग एंटिटि को दिया जाएगा, जो इसे UIDAI डेटाबेस से वैलिडेट करेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस डेटा के आधार पर सेंट्रल रजिस्ट्री ऑफ सिक्यॉरिटाइजेशन ऐंड ऐसेट रिकंस्ट्रक्शन ऐंड सिक्यॉरिटी इंट्रेस्ट ऑफ इंडिया (CERSAI) की ओर से एक यूनीक C-KYC नंबर जेनरेट किया जाएगा। इस नंबर का इस्तेमाल बैंक अकाउंट, म्यूचुअल फंड इन्वेस्टमेंट, डीमैट अकाउंट और इंश्योरेंस पॉलिसी सहित सभी फाइनैंशल प्रॉडक्ट्स में किया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा था कि देश में 98 प्रतिशत व्यस्कों या 108 करोड़ से अधिक लोगों को आधार नंबर जारी किया जा चुका है और इसी वजह से सरकार इसका इस्तेमाल बढ़ा रही है। उन्होंने इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के प्रस्ताव पर दोबारा विचार करने की संसद की मांग को खारिज कर दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC सुविधा से PAN के आवेदन के लिए जन्मतिथि या पते जैसी जानकारियों की पुष्टि का इंतजार कर रहे व्यक्ति और एंटिटि अंगूठे के निशान से बायोमेट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन कर सकेंगे। CERSAI ने पिछले वर्ष सभी वित्तीय संस्थानों में एक समान KYC प्रोसेस सुनिश्चित करने के लिए e-KYC की कोशिश शुरू की थी। 2016 में मार्केट रेग्युलेटर सेबी ने आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC को स्वेच्छा से अपनाने पर सहमति दी थी। सभी सरकारी बैंकों से भी इस तरह का अपडेटेड डेटा अथॉरिटी को उपलब्ध कराने का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जवाब नहीं देने वालों के खिलाफ कार्रवाई &#39;निश्चित&#39;:IT</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-will-take-action-against-9-29-lakh-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-will-take-action-against-9-29-lakh-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार ने कहा है कि नोटबंदी के वक्त ज़्यादा कैश जमा कराने को लेकर आयकर विभाग द्वारा भेजे गए नोटिस का जवाब नहीं देने वाले 9.29 लाख लोगों के खिलाफ &amp;lsquo;निश्चित रूप से&amp;rsquo; कार्रवाई की जाएगी। आयकर विभाग ने इन लोगों को इसलिए नोटिस भेजा था क्योंकि इनके द्वारा जमा की गई रकम इनकी इनकम प्रोफाइल से मेल नहीं खाती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लोकसभा में फाइनैंस बिल पर हो रही चर्चा पर पूछे गए एक सवाल के जवाब में वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि नोटंबदी के 50 दिनों के दौरान 18 लाख लोगों द्वारा जमा किए गए 500 और 1000 रुपये के पुराने नोट उनकी आय के स्रोतों के अनुपात में नहीं थे। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;फिलहाल रीमोनिटाइज़ेशन का प्रोसेस चल रहा है। लेकिन प्राप्त हुए डेटा की शुरुआती जांच में सीबीडीटी (Central Board of Direct Taxes) और टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने पाया है कि 18 लाख लोगों द्वारा जमा किया गया कैश उनके इनकम प्रोफाइल से मेल नहीं खाता। संबंधित विभागों ने मेल और एसएमएस कर इन लोगों से स्पष्टीकरण मांगा था।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;करीब 8.71 लाख लोगों ने स्पष्टीकरण दिया है, और जिन्होंने कोई प्रतिक्रिया नहीं दी है निश्चित रूप से आयकर विभाग उनके खिलाफ आयकर अधिनियम के तहत ऐक्शन लेगा।&amp;rsquo; नोटबंदी के फायदे बताते हुए वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि इससे सरकार के संसाधनों के प्रोत्साहन में मदद मिलेगी। किसानों को मिलनेवाले फंड, रक्षा क्षेत्र और मनरेगा जैसे मुद्दों पर सभी पार्टियों द्वारा चिंता व्यक्त करने पर वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि इनके लिए ज़्यादा खर्च तभी संभव है जब सरकार के पास और संसाधन हों।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी के दौरान जमा हुई रकम की फाइनल टैली को लेकर किए गए सवालों पर जेटली ने कहा कि आरबीआई द्वारा हरेक नोट गिने जाने के बाद इसकी घोषणा की जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>प्रतिदिन 4GB-3Gडेटा 444 रुपये में 90 दिन तक </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-new-chukaa-offer-4gb-mobile-broadband-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-new-chukaa-offer-4gb-mobile-broadband-per-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सार्वजनिक क्षेत्र की दूरसंचार सेवा प्रदाता कंपनी बीएसएनएल ने प्रीपेड मोबाइल ग्राहकों के लिए 444 रुपये में प्रतिदिन 4GB मोबाइल डाटा की पेशकश की है। यह पेशकश 3G ग्राहकों के लिए की गई है, जिसकी वैधता 90 दिन है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनी ने एक बयान में कहा कि उसने बीएसएनएल चौका ऑफर की पेशकश की है, जो वास्तव में 90 दिन तक असीमित डाटा इस्तेमाल की सुविधा देगा। कंपनी का दावा है कि यह देशभर में किसी कंपनी द्वारा प्रतिदिन डाटा सीमा की सबसे बड़ी पेशकश है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस योजना के तहत 1 GB 3G मोबाइल डेटा की कीमत 1 रुपये से भी कम होगी, जोकि टेलिकॉम सेक्टर में सबसे कम है। बीएसएनएल के कंज्यूमर मोबिलिटी डायरेक्टर ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम सभी मोबाइल कस्टमर्स को सस्ती और अच्छी सेवा देने को प्रतिबद्ध हैं। टेलिकॉम सेक्टर में मौजूदा ट्रेंड को देखते हुए हम अपने ग्राहकों को बेस्ट प्राइज ऑफर दे रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बैंक खाते के लिए आधार जरूरी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-makes-aadhaar-mandatory-for-opening-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-makes-aadhaar-mandatory-for-opening-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार ने नया बैंक अकाउंट खोलने और पुराने बैंक खाताधारकों के लिए आधार से जुड़ी जानकारी 31 दिसंबर 2017 तक देना ज़रूरी कर दिया है.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;50,000 रुपए से ज्यादा के फाइनेंशियल ट्रांजैक्शंस के लिए भी आधार देना ज़रूरी किया गया है, लेकिन ये कब से अनिवार्य होगा ये अभी स्पष्ट नहीं है.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हम आपको बता रहे हैं कि सरकार की इस कवायद का क्या मकसद है और ग्रहकों के लिए इसमें क्या-क्या बदलाव किए गए हैं.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-आधार नंबर को बैंक अकाउंट से लिंक करने के बाद सरकार के लिए आपके फाइनेंशियल ट्रांजैक्शंस पर नज़र रखना आसान हो जाएगा.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 जून के बाद अगर किसी व्यक्ति के पास बैंक अकाउंट खोलते समय आधार नंबर नहीं है तो उसे आधार के लिए इनरॉलमेंट की एप्लीकेशन का प्रमाण देना होगा और खाता खुलने के छह महीने के भीतर आधार नंबर बैंक को देना होगा.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;अलग-अलग पैन कार्ड का इस्तेमाल करके टैक्स चोरी करने वालों पर लगाम कसने के लिए सरकार ने 2017 के बजट में पैन और आधार को लिंक करने का प्रावधान किया था.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;अगर 31 दिसंबर 2017 तक अपना आधार नंबर बैंक को नहीं देते हैं तो आप आगे बैंकिंग सर्विसेज का लाभ नहीं उठा पाएंगे.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;रेवेन्यू डिपार्टमेंट ने प्रिवेंशन आफ मनी लॉन्ड्रिंग (मेंटीनेंस आफ रिकॉर्ड्स) रूल्स 2005 में संशोधन करके 50,000 या इससे ऊपर के फाइनेंशियल ट्रांजैक्शंस के लिए पैन या फॉर्म 60 के साथ आधार को ज़रूरी किया है.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;अधिकारिक रूप से वैध केवाईसी डॉक्यूमेंट्स के बिना खोले जा सकने वाले स्मॉल अकाउंट्स के लिए नियम सख्त कर दिए गए हैं. ऐसे खाते अब केवल उन बैंक ब्रांचों में खोले जा सकेंगे, जहां कोर बैंकिंग सॉल्यूशन होगा.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;मौजूदा समय में प्रिवेंशन ऑफ मनी लॉन्ड्रिंग रूल्स के तहत बैंक अकाउंट खोलते समय या हाई वैल्यू वाले ट्रांजैक्शन के लिए बैंक को पैन नंबर या फॉर्म 60 देना ज़रूरी होता है.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-जो कंपनियां बैंक खाता खोलना चाहती हैं, उन्हें कंपनी की तरफ से ट्रांजैक्शन करने की अटॉर्नी रखने वाले मैनेजर्स या एंप्लॉयीज का आधार नंबर देना होगा.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;इसके अलावा सरकार ने टेलीकॉम कंपनियों से सभी फोन नंबरों को आधार से री-वैरिफाई करने को कहा है. फोन के री-वैरिफाई और आधार से लिंक न होने पर फरवरी 2018 से आपका फोन डीएक्टिवेट हो जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ब्लैक मनी: स्विस बैंकों में खाता रखने वालों की जानकारी सीधे भारत को मिलेगी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/black-money-crackdown-switzerland-ratifies-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/black-money-crackdown-switzerland-ratifies-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;स्विसबैंक में कालाधन रखने वालों के लिए अब मुसीबत खड़ी होने वाली है। दरअसल स्विट्जरलैंड ने भारत और 40 अन्य देशों के साथ अपने यहां संबंधित देश के लोगों के वित्तीय खातों, संदिग्ध काले धन से संबंधित सूचनाओं के आदान प्रदान की व्यवस्था को शुक्रवार को मंजूरी दे दी है। अब इन देशों को गोपनीयता और सूचना की सुरक्षा के कडे़ नियमों का अनुपालन&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;करना होगा। टैक्स संबंधी सूचनाओं के स्वत: आदान-प्रदान (ऑटोमैटिक एक्सचेंज ऑफ इन्फर्मेशन) पर वैश्विक संधि को मंजूरी के प्रस्ताव पर स्विट्जरलैंड की संघीय परिषद (मंत्रिमंडल) की मुहर लग गई है। स्विट्जरलैंड सरकार ने इस व्यवस्था को साल 2018 से संबंधित सूचनाओं के साथ शुरू करने का निर्णय लिया है यानी आंकड़ों के आदन प्रदान की शुरूआत 2019 में होगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्विट्जरलैंड की संघीय परिषद सूचनाओं के आदान प्रदान की व्यवस्था शुरू करने की तारीख की सूचना भारत को जल्द ही देगी। परिषद द्वारा इस संबंध में स्वीकृत प्रस्ताव के मसौदे के अनुसार, इसके लिए वहां अब कोई जनमत संग्रह नहीं कराया जाना है। इसलिए इसे लागू करने में देरी की आशंका नहीं है। कालेधन का मुद्दा भारत में सार्वजनिक चर्चा का&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मुद्दा है। लंबे समय से ऐसा माना जाता है कि बहुत से भारतीयों ने अपना काला धन स्विट्जरलैंड के बैंक-खातों में जमा कर रखा है। भारत विदेशी सरकारों, स्विट्जरलैंड जैसे देशों के साथ अपने देश के नागरिकों के बैंकिंग सौदों के बारे में सूचनाओं के आदान प्रदान की व्यवस्था के लिए द्विपक्षीय और बहुपक्षीय मंचों पर जोरदार प्रयास करता आ रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्विट्जरलैंड ने शुक्रवार को जिस बहुपक्षीय एईओआई (ऑटोमैटिक एक्सचेंज ऑफ इन्फर्मेशन) सिस्टम को अप्रूव किया है, वह ऐसे प्रयासों का ही नतीजा है ताकि विदेश के रास्ते कालेधन को खपाने और मनी लॉन्ड्रिंग पर कारगर अंकुश लगाया जा सके। सूचनाओं के आदान-प्रदान के नियम पेरिस स्थित संगठन आर्थिक सहयोग एवं विकास संगठन (ओईसीडी) ने तैयार किए हैं। स्विस&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैंक इस दावे के साथ नए सुरक्षा उपायों की मांग कर रहे हैं जो कि बैंक के डेटा को दुरुपयोग से बचाएगा। डेटा अपहरण या ब्लैकमेल जैसे अपराधों में इस्तेमाल किया जा सकता है। स्विस के प्राइवेट बैंकों की एसोसिएशन के चेयरमैन यूस मिराबाउड ने कहा कि इस डेटा को बेचा जा सकता है या इसका इस्तेमाल क्लाइंट्स या उनके परिवार पर दवाब बनाने के लिए किया जा सकता है। उन्होंने कहा कि यहां मैं उन देशों का जिक्र कर रहा हूं जहां हम यह नहीं जानते हैं कि लोकतांत्रिक प्रक्रिया हमारे जैसी है, या वहां भ्रष्टाचार बहुत ज्यादा है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>