<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs. 333: BSNL&#39;s New Plan To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 333, Rs. 339, Rs. 349 and Rs. 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL or Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited has announced three new data plans priced from Rs 333, the latest offering from the telecom operator seen as aimed at Jio&amp;rsquo;s Dhan Dhana Dhan plans. BSNL is offering up to 270 GB of 3G mobile data along with unlimited voice calls for a period of 90 days. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs 333 includes 3 GB per day of unlimited data, beyond which the speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps, the operator said. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing is causing intense competition in Indian telecom industry, forcing incumbent operators to offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attractive mobile data and unlimited voice calls plans, according to analysts. BSNL has also revised its existing Rs 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of data per day, instead of 2 GB earlier, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s revised Rs 339 pack, valid for 28 days, also includes unlimited local and inter-circle BSNL-to-BSNL calls. Calls to other networks are allowed with a limit of 25 minutes per day, beyond which BSNL customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 349 and Rs 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL had earlier launched yearly packs starting from Rs 1,498 and going up to Rs 4,498, which include 18 GB and 80 GB of data for 365 days, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-based payment modes work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government is planning to utilise the Aadhaar database to give shape to a digital future and utilise it for payments, and authentication of transactions is the key to its success. While Unified Payments Interface and BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) are processes for peer-to-peer transactions using smartphones, the government is promoting Aadhaar-enabled payment systems for the non-smartphone savvy. As per sources it is planning to launch Aadhaar Pay on April 14. ET looks into the different forms of Aadhaar payment modes being developed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems?
Payments that can be done with the help of au thentication and identi fication through the Aadhaar database is referred to as the Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems (AEPS). This is the new form of pay ment that is being pro moted by the govern ment to push for digital payments instead of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the major types of Aadhaar Enabled Payments?
The first type of payment is Aadhaar Bridge Payment System which is meant for direct bene fit transfer and subsidy payments from the gov ernment to the benefi ciaries. The second is AEPS which is used at the level of the business correspondent or `bank mitras’ where bank customers can use Aadhaar to access various services like cash withdrawal, account opening and fund transfer even without going to a bank branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is Aadhaar Pay wherein merchants can accept payments through Aadhaar identification of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we need Aadhaar Enabled payments?
These forms of payments are be ing promoted by the government specifically for the under privileged sections of the society and the rural poor who are not comfortable using cards or mobile wallets for payments.Instead of a mobile phone or a plastic card, in these forms of payments, the mode of authentication becomes the Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who runs the systems?
National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is the nodal authority for all Aadhaar-enabled payments in collaboration with banks. The payment company is trying to get as many banks to seed their customers’ accounts with their Aadhaar number so that payments can flow smoothly .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do the different forms of payments work?
Aahdaar Bridge Payment (ABPS):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant for recur ring payments done by the government to its customers for various subsidies as well as direct benefit transfer. Here the beneficiary is identified through an Aadhaar number, then NPCI manages an Aadhaar Mapper where the Aadhaar number is mapped to a specific bank account and the money flows to the connected bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-enabled-payment-aeps&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Payment (AEPS):&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the customer has to approach a business correspondent (BC), use his Aadhaar number and biometrics which the BC shares with NPCI, which checks the ID with UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India) to confirm the customer’s identity . It also checks the funds in the connected account and allows the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for merchant payments where the merchant will download the merchant payments app of his bank, authenticate the customer through his biometrics and Aadhaar number and initiate a pull transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICICI, Axis, SBI Gain, RBI To Get Power To Act Against Loan Defaulters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Union Cabinet cleared an ordinance empowering the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to act against wilful defaulters. The ordinance has been sent to the president for approval. The ordinance is aimed at empowering RBI to deal more effectively with stressed assets than earlier. A senior finance ministry official said &amp;ldquo;It is part of a broader plan to resolve bad loans with banks&amp;rsquo; issue that has been a major hurdle in the economy from achieving its full potential.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking sub-index on the NSE Nifty Bank index rose to its record high following this development. The index advanced as much as 2 per cent to hit record high of 22,743.70. Sub-index of the public-sector banks Nifty PSU index also rallied over 3 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance may enable RBI to direct banks on how to deal with stressed assets. Moving an amendment to the banking regulation act may take time as the next session of parliament starts sometime after second week of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amended law will also empower RBI to set up oversight panels that will shield bankers from later action by probe agencies looking into loan recasts as a lot of discretion will be involved in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By December 2016, non-performing assets (NPAs) or bad loans with Indian banks rose to Rs. 6.07 lakh crore, of which the share of Public sector banks was Rs. 5.02 lakh crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysts say the ordinance is a positive step towards banks recovering their dues from the defaulters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kishor Ostwal of CNI Research, says &amp;ldquo;Because of this ordinance there will be more and more recovery of bad loans and wilful defaulters which have money will come out and repay their debts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the individual banking shares, ICICI Bank was the top gainer, rose 9.18 per cent to Rs 297.8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canara Bank, Bank of Baroda, State Bank of India, IDFC Bank, Punjab National Bank and Axis Bank were also among the other gainer in the banking sun-index rising between 1-3.5 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the state-run lenders, Union Bank, Andhra Bank, IDBI Bank and  Allahabad Bank also rallied up to 4 per cent each.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Bank Account:Here Are More Ways To Transfer Your Money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-transfer-money-using-sbi-mingle-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-transfer-money-using-sbi-mingle-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India had in July 2016 launched the SBI Mingle app, allowing its customers access various banking services via social media sites Facebook and Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is offering a new facility that helps customers transfer money using their accounts on social media sites Facebook and Twitter. Users can &amp;ldquo;conveniently transfer funds&amp;rdquo; by logging on to SBI&amp;rsquo;s app &amp;lsquo;Mingle&amp;rsquo;. This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on microblogging site Twitter. SBI had in July 2016 launched the SBI Mingle app, allowing its customers access various banking services via these social media platforms. The SBI Mingle app is available on Google Play for Android mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about the SBI Mingle app:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is SBI Mingle?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Mingle is a social banking application that enables SBI customers to perform basic banking activities through the bank&amp;rsquo;s official Facebook page, the bank said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-mingle-650-400_650x287_51494382504.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The SBI Mingle app is available on Google Play for Android mobile users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to use Mingle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI customers need to register through a simple one-time process using either their account number or their ATM/Debit Card details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who can use Mingle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using SBI Mingle, SBI customers can do a host of banking services on their preferred social platform (i.e. Facebook and Twitter) at their own convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which all tasks can I perform using SBI&amp;rsquo;s Mingle app?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon completing the registration process, the SBI customers can perform a variety of tasks using the Mingle app. Some of them include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance enquiry of accounts
Obtaining a mini statement
Transfer money - within and outside SBI
Request for cheque book
Blocking of ATM Cards&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-mingle-services_650x400_61494383417.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Savings Account Minimum Balance Requirement. Read Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. The minimum balance requirement for SBI customers varies depending on geographies such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural. If the minimum balance drops below a particular threshold, SBI will charge a fee from the account holder. SBI says the minimum balance in your savings bank account is the monthly average balance - the average of daily balances in the account during the month. SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holders of SBI&amp;rsquo;s savings bank account in urban areas need to maintain a monthly average balance (MAB) of Rs 3,000, Rs 2,000 in case of those in semi-urban areas and Rs 1,000 in rural areas. This was said on Thursday by SBI - which recently merged its operations with six other banks - on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting 31 crore depositors, SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For metropolitan areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Under 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For rural areas, the penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance ranges from Rs 20 to Rs 50 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI offers other types of accounts where it customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. Small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products offered SBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1. After the merger, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Tickets Delivered To Home, Cash On Delivery</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-get-train-tickets-delivered-to-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-get-train-tickets-delivered-to-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IRCTC has now introduced pay-on-delivery as one of the payment options for its customers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has offered delivery of rail tickets allowing passengers to make payment through any payment mode, including cash. Broad-basing the customer service, the Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation has now introduced pay-on-delivery service allowing passengers to book train tickets online and pay at the time of delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC through its website and mobile app has now introduced pay-on-delivery as one of the payment options for its customers, said a senior IRCTC official. Delivering tickets at the consumer&amp;rsquo;s doorstep by offering the pay-on-delivery (PoD) option will facilitate those consumers who book through travel agents to move to online medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also encourage people who book at railway reservation counters to move to online medium as there is a cost and effort to reach the reservation counters. The customer will have to do a one-time registration for availing PoD as a payment option. He or she will have to tender either Aadhaar or Pan card to avail this payment option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PoD charges shall be Rs. 90 plus sales tax for transactions up to Rs. 5,000 and Rs. 120 plus tax for transactions over Rs. 5,000. In case of refusal or cancellation before delivery, the customer will be liable to pay the cancellation and delivery charges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very soon, you can do “iris” Aadhaar authentication from your smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheap in-built iris scanners will eradicate use of costly ones for mass adoption of Aadhaar verification.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID Inc., a consumer-grade iris scanning technology provider for mobile phones, proposed the introduction of iris integrated mobile phones as a cost-effective way of reducing the failure rates in Aadhaar biometric authentication, as recently reported in MGNREGA tests in Telangana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe iris integrated smartphones and tablets will address the issues reported with Aadhaar biometric authentication. The UIDAI and the worldwide biometric community have tested and found iris to have better reliability. We are confident the failure rates will be drastically lower once the cheaper iris integrated mobile devices are adopted in the market,” said Dr. Salil Prabhakar, President and CEO, Delta ID Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the government mandating the use of Aadhaar biometric authentication in more spheres of the society, the need for a biometric modality that works reliably is critical. Unlike fingerprints that are being reported to show high failure rates due to wear and tear, the iris, being a protected internal organ, is expected to be significantly more reliable. Additionally, since the iris is not affected with age, it works reliably across all age groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key impediments in the large-scale roll out of iris for Aadhaar has been the high cost of iris devices. This is being addressed with the rollout of iris integrated mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this regard, Samsung partnered with Delta ID to launch India’s first iris integrated tablet in May 2016. The technology is arriving in smartphones too, and not only in high end devices such as Samsung Galaxy S8, but also in low cost smartphones developed by Indian manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID’s ActiveIRIS technology passed the Standardisation Testing and Quality Certification’s (STQC) FRR test with better than 99 percent accuracy, and has been certified by the STQC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active IRIS and a combination of STQC-certified hardware components can be integrated by any mobile device to expeditiously introduce iris integrated mobile devices in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आयकर विभाग करेगा 60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों की जांच</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-operation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; के दूसरे चरण में आयकर विभाग 60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों की जांच करेगा। शुक्रवार को दोबारा लॉन्च हुए इस ऑपरेशन का मकसद नोटबंदी के बाद पैदा हुए ब्लैक मनी का पता लगाना है। विभाग ने इससे पहले ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के पहले चरण में नोटबंदी के दौरान संदिग्ध लेन-देन करने वाले 18 लाख लोगों को नोटिस भेजा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग की नीति निर्माता ईकाइ केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (CBDT) का कहना है कि वह पिछले साल 9 नवंबर से इस साल की 28 फरवरी तक 9,332 करोड़ रुपए की अघोषित आय का पता लगा चुका है। बता दें कि 8 नवंबर को पीएम मोदी ने 500 और 1000 के नोटबंदी की घोषणा की थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;60 हजार से ज्यादा लोगों (जिसमें 1300 हाइ रिस्क लोग भी शामिल हैं) की जांच में पहचान हो चुकी है। नोटबंदी के दौरान अधिकतर बड़े लेन-देन कैश में करने वाले लोग नजर में थे। हाइ वैल्यू प्रॉपर्टी खरीद के 6000 मामले और विदेश के शेयर बाजार में पैसा लगाने या विदेश पैसा भेजने के 6,600 मामलों में बारीकी से जांच-पड़ताल होगी। अगर जवाब संतोषजनक नहीं माना गया तो विस्तृत पूछताछ की जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ITR में देनी होगी नोटबंदी के दौरान जमा रकम की जानकारी!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने बताया कि आधुनिक डेटा विश्लेषण का इस्तेमाल करते हुए संदिग्ध कैश डिपॉजिट का पता लगाया है। इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने इस साल 31 जनवरी को &amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; लॉन्च किया गया था। जिसके तहत 17.92 लाख लोगों को ऑनलाइन नोटिस भेजा गया था जिसमें से 9.46 लाख लोगों ने विभाग के प्रश्नों का जवाब दिया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बैंक, डाकघर से निकासी पर नकदी लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर दो लाख रुपये की नकद लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी। आयकर विभाग ने बुधवार को यह स्पष्ट किया। वित्त अधिनियम 2017 के तहत सरकार ने दो लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध लगा दिया है। इससे अधिक के लेनदेन में राशि प्राप्त करने वाले पर उतनी की राशि का जुर्माना लगाया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर कानून में नई शामिल धारा 269 एसटी के बारे में स्पष्टीकरण जारी करते हुए केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ने कहा कि यह प्रतिबंध बैंकों और डाकघरों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा। बयान में कहा गया है कि यह फैसला किया गया है कि नकद लेनदेन पर अंकुश बैंकों, सहकारी बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सीबीडीटी ने कहा कि इस बारे में आवश्यक अधिसूचना जारी की जाएगी। वित्त मंत्री अरण जेटली ने 2017-18 के बजट में 3 लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध का प्रस्ताव किया था। इस सीमा को वित्त विधेयक में संशोधन के जरिए दो लाख रुपये कर दिया गया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prasad also said 4.47 crore bank accounts have been opened with Aadhaar eKYC as compared to only one lakh accounts opened as of May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the government has linked the BHIM app with Aadhaar so that transactions through the app happens in a transparent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>200 Airports To Be Brought Under UDAN Scheme: Jayanta Sinha</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jayanta Sinha said government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central government has embarked upon a plan to bring 200 airports under the regional air connectivity scheme, Union Minister of State for Aviation Jayanta Sinha said here today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Under the UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) regional air connectivity scheme, 33 airports have been already included since its launch last year in addition to 75 taking the total to 108. We intend to take the number to 200,&amp;rdquo; Mr Sinha said at an interaction at Bharat Chamber of Commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this, we will have multiple rounds of bidding, he said, adding the government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Sinha said so far the subsidy burden was only Rs 200 crore and 13 lakh seats have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pointing out that regional air connectivity was both pro-poor and pro-markets, he said that this twin objective had been met by offering seats at Rs 2,500 per seat per hour of flying and reducing the cost of flying by bringing down the costs of ATF and service charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding Bagdogra airport in West Bengal, he said talks were on for getting land with the state government for building a new modern terminal. He said that all greenfield airports would be built through the PPP route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding unruly behaviour while flying it is expected that both passengers and the cabin crew would adhere with the laid-down guidelines, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks vs e-wallets: Who is winning in cashless India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When two of the biggest banks in the country resist wallets from fintech start-ups, you know a few things are simmering. First, SBI disallowed its net banking users to top up third party wallets and next, ICICI blocked transactions on PhonePe, a Flipkart managed wallet that was launched in partnership with YES Bank – PhonePe allows users to link bank accounts to the smartphone through the National Payments Corporation of India’s encrypted software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While SBI cited security concerns, ICICI said PhonePe was “following restrictive practices allowing users to make payments with only its UPI handle which is in contravention to the UPI guidelines of interoperability…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While security concerns could be real, there is more to it than meets the eye. There is an imminent threat from fintech start-ups to the Indian financial services industry as we see growing disintermediation in mobile payments, financial product comparison/aggregation, lending, and remittances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report by consulting firm Zinnov released mid-2016, investments in the fintech sector crossed $1.3 billion.  Mobile wallet start-ups have received the most funding – they have been using this capital to both aggressively market as well as improve the ease of using their technology. Compared to say a Paytm, SBI’s wallet ‘SBI Buddy’ and ICICI’s ‘Pockets’ have much less brand recall. These privately funded start-ups are now threatening the banks from three sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, banks are worried about relationship with their customers being upended. Banks had failed to notice India’s demographic shift; the young did not want complicated KYC norms even for small transactions such as mobile recharges. They love the app economy and the convenience it provides. Wallets stepped in to provide a better payments experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was a slipping market scenario for traditional banks.  The banking industry’s business model majorly centres around retail as well as corporate lending and not small value transactions. However, according to some estimates, the payments market is a mammoth $500 billion opportunity today when domestic and international remittances, government, utility bills as well as merchant payments are included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New payment categories have come into being as well — taxi payments were always in cash a couple of years ago. Today, tech savvy customers are paying their maid or a driver through money transfers. Many more new categories could emerge.  If these start-ups, armed with private equity money, were to garner a major share of this pie, it would be more than an opportunity lost for traditional banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third threat, and a more serious one, is about data. What happens when users start trusting payment companies? The fallout of such a scenario – where both trust and transactions move to wallet companies – would reflect in a bank’s visibility of customer data or their behaviour patterns. That, in turn, would reduce a bank’s ability to cross sell or up sell other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may, in fact, become reliant on wallet companies for such data. Payment companies, for instance, will be in a better position to judge the credit worthiness of many retail customers the banks are after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, the margins of many banks could slip due to competition. As smart phones become more affordable and pervasive, experts see fintech start-ups scale massively. And if traditional banks don’t align their cost structures with current realities — especially the public sector ones — they can find themselves in a quagmire with only “restrictive practices” as aid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>