<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Now Pay Later: IRCTC To Offer Train Tickets On Credit</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potential passengers can book a ticket and pay for it online within 14 days, IRCTC said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation or IRCTC has decided to make booking tickets a hassle-free affair by providing a &amp;lsquo;buy tickets now and pay later&amp;rsquo; service for regular travelers. Soon passengers would be able to buy tickets from the IRCTC website and pay later, an IRCTC official told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential passengers can book a ticket five days prior to the journey with a service charge of 3.5 per cent and pay it in the next 14 days, IRCTC spokesperson Sandip Dutta said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has collaborated with a Mumbai-based firm ePayLater for adding the new service option. The ePayLater platform allows persons to log out immediately after booking tickets and make payments later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The railway agency had earlier introduced &amp;lsquo;pay on delivery&amp;rsquo; category for train tickets booked using its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be applicable for new &amp;ldquo;Buy Now Pay Later&amp;rdquo; feature, users will have fill in basic details including Aadhaar and PAN card details after which they will be able to use the feature with a One Time Password (OTP), ePayLater said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your NPS Account With Aadhaar Number</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPS subscribers have the facility to add their Aadhaar numbers online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPS or National Pension Scheme subscribers have been advised to add Aadhaar number to their accounts. Aadhaar is a 12-digit number issued by Unique Identification Authority of India or UIDAI based on the demographic and biometric information of the person. NPS subscribers can add their Aadhaar numbers online. The Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority (PFRDA), the body which manages NPS, been taking a number of measures to simplify the processes. For example, the Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority has done away with the requirement of submission of a physical application form for opening of an NPS account if done through Aadhaar verification and e-signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to add Aadhaar to your NPS account online:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Log-in to your NPS account (www.cra-nsdl.com)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Click on &amp;ldquo;Update Details&amp;rdquo; tab and then select the option &amp;ldquo;Add/Update Aadhaar Number&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Submit your Aadhaar number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Enter the OTP received from UIDAI on your registered mobile number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) After authentication through OTP, Aadhaar will be linked to your PRAN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PRAN or Permanent Retirement Account Number is a unique number allotted to NPS subscribers that remains the same for the rest of subscriber&amp;rsquo;s life)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NPS body has said that a subscriber is required to seed the Aadhaar in his or her PRAN through this process even if Aadhaar was provided earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: PFRDA has said that the name registered against your PRAN should exactly match the name as registered with &amp;ldquo;UIDAI&amp;rdquo; in Aadhaar. If the correction is required on PRAN card, then the NPS subscriber has to submit a self-attested PRAN card copy and a self-attested Aadhaar card copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For government subscribers, the Aadhaar seeding process will be completed once the request initiated by a subscriber is authorised online by his /her respective Nodal Office, PFRDA said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No PAN Card Without Aadhaar From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-pan-card-without-aadhaar-from-july-1-says-taxman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-pan-card-without-aadhaar-from-july-1-says-taxman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT), The policy-making body of the Income Tax Department made it clear that Aadhaar will be a &amp;ldquo;must&amp;rdquo; for filing of Income Tax Returns or for obtaining a new PAN from July 1. CBDT issued the statements after the Supreme Court offered a temporary relief ruling that those who already possess the Aadhaar number will have to link it with PAN to file I-T returns, but it cannot be insisted upon in case of people not possessing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT issued a three-point &amp;ldquo;effect of the judgement&amp;rdquo; of the apex court statement saying that From July 1, 2017 onwards every person eligible to obtain Aadhaar must quote their Aadhaar number or their Aadhaar enrolment ID number for filing of income tax returns as well as for applications for PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the I-T department maintained that in keeping with the Supreme Court ruling, those who do not have Aadhaar and who do not wish to obtain Aadhaar for the time being, that their PAN will not be cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the PAN is cancelled, then a person cannot do his normal banking and financial operations and hence this relief is given, income tax authorities said adding that for filing of income tax returns or to obtain a new PAN, Aadhaar will be mandatory from July 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The I-T Department also urged taxpayers to link the two numbers - PAN and Aadhaar - as soon as possible saying it will be useful for E-Verification of Income Tax returns using Aadhaar OTP (One-Time Password).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also bear logo of 125th anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year &amp;ldquo;1891&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in English shall be written on the upper and lower periphery of the coin respectively. The year &amp;ldquo;1916&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in international numerals shall be written respectively on left and right top of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI said the existing coins in this denomination shall also continue to be legal tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 5 coin, the RBI said the coin&amp;rsquo;s face will bear an image depicting centre facade of Allahabad High Court Building emerging from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 1866-2016 in English numerals shall be written at the bottom of the image, the RBI said in a release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches. From the fifth transaction onwards, the customers will have to pay a minimum of Rs 150 per transaction (plus taxes and cess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Earlier, HDFC Bank savings account customers were offered five free transactions and the sixth transaction was charged at Rs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) HDFC Bank after December 30, 2016 reintroduced charges on cash transactions at branches after the deadline to deposit old currency notes ended. The charges were waived off after the government had announced a ban on high value currency notes on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) According to the revised norms which came into effect from March 1, from non-home branch, HDFC Bank customers can deposit/withdraw up to Rs 25,000 per day without any charge but any deposit/withdrawal from non-home branch above Rs 25,000 will attract charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess), whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) At the home branch of HDFC Bank, if the cumulative cash transactions (deposit/withdrawal) exceed Rs 2 lakh, a transaction charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess) whichever is higher will be levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For example, if a customer withdraws Rs 2 lakh from an account in four transactions and goes for another fifth transaction of Rs 50,000 from the home branch, then the customer will have to pay a charge of Rs 250. Thus, the charges apply only on the fifth transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) However, the charges for withdrawing money from automatic teller machines (ATMs) remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For senior citizens and minor accounts, the limit of Rs 25,000 per day will be applicable but the accounts will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) India&amp;rsquo;s biggest private sector bank ICICI Bank had reintroduced the cash transaction charges at bank branches from January 1, 2017. There will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while thereafter Rs 5 per Rs 1,000 would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150. The third party limit is Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Meanwhile, news agency Press Trust of India reported that another private sector lender Axis Bank has also started charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp scam alert! how to be safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-be-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-be-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A WhatsApp scam is going viral all around the world where users could be tricked into paying a fake subscription fee. WhatsApp users are being targeted by a fake message which falsely claims their current &amp;lsquo;subscription&amp;rsquo; has expired.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A WhatsApp scam is going viral all around the world where users could be tricked into paying a fake subscription fee. WhatsApp users are being targeted by a fake message which falsely claims their current ‘subscription’ has expired. It encourages the users to tap on a weird link. While WhatsApp is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a hugely popular messaging app with more than a billion global users, it also is a prime target for malware and scammers. The new malicious link has been telling WhatsApp users that their ‘subscription has expired’. This message is being circulated all around WhatsApp. Additionally, the message asks its users for a verification of their accounts. It also asks the users to buy a lifetime subscription for 0.99 British pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that WhatsApp is a free messaging service, and it does not charge its users at all. There was a time, long back, when it used to charge a small annual amount from its users, but now it does not. The link which is going viral is essentially a scam and you should refrain from clicking on it. If you click on the malicious link, it might give access of your personal data including your bank details to hackers. The fake WhatsApp message reads as: “Your subscription has expired. To verify your account and purchase a lifetime subscription for just 0.99 GBP simply tap on this link.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, several users have taken to Twitter where they are warning others about the new scam. You have been advised to delete the message immediately, if you get it, and also block the sender. In order to block a contact which is not saved to your device, open the WhatsApp conversation and click on ‘Block’. Users may also report the user under ‘Spam’ category. In case you received the fake message from one of your contacts, you can block them too, by clicking on the menu button present on the WhatsApp home screen. Just select Settings, Go to Account, Go to Privacy, Select ‘Blocked contacts’. Then add that contact to your Blocked list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users who have already clicked on the link can safeguard themselves by running an antivirus software on their smartphones to make sure they are not infected with malware.
There have been many such instances where hackers have made use of WhatsApp to circulate dangerous links. Earlier, a spam message was circulated on the messaging app, where it invited users to a WhatsApp Gold version, an invite-only club with special features where they could be able to meet movie stars. There have been cases where links were circulated inviting users to download video-calling. These messages also claimed that PM Narendra Modi wanted to give everyone in India, ‘Rs 500 balance’ free for their mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how you can link PAN with Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-you-can-link-pan-with-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-you-can-link-pan-with-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per the recent amendments made in income-tax laws, Aadhaar card and PAN must be linked, failing which PAN shall be cancelled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-order-to-link-pan-and-aadhaar-card-following-steps-are-to-be-followed&#34;&gt;In order to link PAN and Aadhaar card, following steps are to be followed:-&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a) First register on the Income tax e-filing portal (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://incometax&#34;&gt;http://incometax&lt;/a&gt; indiaefiling.gov.in”) if you are not already registered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b) Log-in to the e-filing portal of the income tax department by entering the log-in ID, password and date of birth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c) On logging in to the site, a pop up window will appear, prompting you to link your PAN card with Aadhaar card. If it doesn’t come, then click on “profile settings” and then “Link Aadhaar”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d) Details regarding name, date of birth and gender will already be mentioned as per the details submitted at the time of registration on the e-filing portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e) Verify the details on screen with the ones mentioned on your Aadhaar card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f) If the details match, enter your Aadhaar card number and click on the “Link Aadhaar” button. If the details do not match, it may pose a problem and the person is advised to get the details amended in his Aadhaar or PAN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;g) A pop-up message will display that your Aadhaar card has been successfully linked to your PAN card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अनाज और दूध पर टैक्स नहीं, एसी-फ्रिज भी होगा सस्ता</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-slabs-finalised-foodgrains-and-milk-exempted-from-levy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-slabs-finalised-foodgrains-and-milk-exempted-from-levy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;गुड्स ऐंड सर्विसेज टैक्स (जीएसटी) के तहत अधिकतर वस्तुओं की टैक्स दरों को लेकर केंद्र और राज्यों के बीच सहमति बन गई है। श्रीनगर में गुरुवार को शुरू हुई दो दिवसीय जीएसटी काउंसिल की बैठक में रोजमर्रा की चीजों पर टैक्स रेट घटाने का फैसला लिया गया। नए टैक्स सिस्टम के तहत कई जरूरी चीजों की कीमतें कम हो सकती हैं। अनाज और दूध को टैक्स मुक्त कर दिया गया है। प्रोसेस्ड फूड भी सस्ते हो जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;काउंसिल ने पहले दिन 6 चीजों को छोड़ अन्य सभी वस्तुओं पर 5, 12, 18 और 28 प्रतिशत की टैक्स दर तय कर दी है। मिठाई, खाद्य तेल, चीनी, चायपत्ती, कॉफी को 5% टैक्स स्लैब में रखा गया है। हेयर ऑइल, टूथपेस्ट और साबुन पर 18 फीसदी टैक्स लगाया जाएगा। अभी इन पर 28 फीसदी टैक्स लगता है। कोयले और मसालों पर भी 5% टैक्स लगेगा। एंटरटेनमेंट पर 18 पर्सेंट टैक्स लगेगा। जीवनरक्षक दवाओं को 5 प्रतिशत के टैक्स स्लैब में रखा गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कोयले पर टैक्स की दर 5 प्रतिशत होगी, जबकि अभी इस पर 11.69 प्रतिशत का कर लगता है। इससे बिजली उत्पादन सस्ता होगा। जेटली ने संवाददाताओं से कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमने (आज की बैठक में) ज्यादातर वस्तुओं के लिए कर दरों और छूट सूची को अंतिम रूप दे दिया है।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि बैठक के पहले दिन 1211 में से छह को छोड़कर बाकी सभी वस्तुओं के लिए जीएसटी दर तय कर ली गई।&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/gst1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;सूत्रों के मुताबिक छोटी कारों पर 28 फीसदी टैक्स के अलावा सेस लगाया जाएगा। लग्जरी कारों पर टैक्स के अलावा 15% सेस जोड़ा जाएगा। एसी और फ्रिज को भी 28 फीसदी टैक्स दायरे में रखा गया है। हालांकि अभी इन पर अभी 30-31 फीसदी टैक्स लगता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने मीडियाकर्मियों से कहा, &amp;lsquo;किसी भी वस्तु पर बढ़ोतरी नहीं की गई है। कई चीजों पर टैक्स की दरें कम हो जाएंगी। विचार यह है कि जीएसटी का असर महंगाई बढ़ाने वाला ना हो।&amp;rsquo; वहीं राजस्व सेक्रटरी हसमुख अधिया ने रिपोटर्स को बताया कि 1211 आइटम्स में से 7% को छूट के दायरे में रखा गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14% वस्तुओं को 5% के दायरे में रखा गया है। 17% पर 12% टैक्स लगेगा। 43% आइटम्स को 18 पर्सेंट टैक्स लिया जाएगा। अन्य 19% वस्तुओं पर 28 फीसदी टैक्स देना होगा। सोने और बीड़ी पर टैक्स स्लैब का फैसला शुक्रवार को होगा। सर्विस टैक्स की दरें भी दूसरे दिन ही तय की जाएंगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विज्ञापन में कहा गया है कि आयकर विभाग के पास आपकी जमाओं की जानकारी है। विभाग ने कहा है कि इस योजना के तहत कालेधन की घोषणा करने वालों की गोपनीयता सुनिश्चित की जाएगी। विज्ञापन में स्पष्ट चेतावनी दी गई है कि योजना के तहत काले धन की जानकारी नहीं देने वालों को बेनाम कानून के तहत कठोर कार्रवाई का सामना करना होगा। यहां तक कि उनके नाम ईडी और सीबीआई जैसी केंद्रीय जांच एजेंसियों के साथ साझा कर दिए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा कि जो लोग प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना का लाभ लेते हुए अपनी काली कमाई उजागर नहीं करेंगे, उन्हें जमा राशि पर 137% तक जुर्माना लगाया जा सकता है। उनके मुताबिक, विभाग ऐसे डिफॉल्टरों पर नए बेनामी लेनदेन कानून के तहत कार्रवाई करने से भी नहीं हिचकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत काला धन की जानकारी देने वालों को 49.9 प्रतिशत टैक्स देना होगा, जबकि ऐसा नहीं कर इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न में इस धन का जिक्र करने वालों को टैक्स के साथ-साथ 77.25 प्रतिशत जुर्माना देना होगा। साथ ही, जो लोग योजना के तहत काले धन का खुलासा नहीं करते हैं और जांच आकलन में इसका पता चलता है तो उन्हें 83.25 प्रतिशत की दर से टैक्स वसूला जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो लोग योजना का फायदा लेते हुए काले धन की जानकारी सरकार को नहीं देते हैं और छापेमारी के दौरान छिपा हुआ धन सरेंडर करते हैं तो उन्हें 107.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना होगा। लेकिन, जो लोग छापेमारी में भी काला धन खुद निकाल कर नहीं देते हैं, उन्हें 137.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना पड़ सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बेनामी कानून में दोषियों को 7 साल तक की कैद से दंडित करने का प्रावधान है। इसके अलावा, उस पर आयकर कानून के तहत भी मुकदमा चल सकता है। साथ ही, उस पर बेनामी संपत्ति के उचित बाजार मूल्य का 25 प्रतिशत और दूसरे जुर्माने भी भरने होंगे। गौरतलब है कि सरकार ने नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना की घोषणा की थी। इस योजना के तहत कुल घोषित काले धन का एक चौथाई हिस्सा चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज के सरकार के पास जमा रखने की बाध्यता है। यह योजना पिछले साल 17 दिसंबर को शुरू हुई।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जानें- 2500 रुपये में हवाई सफर को हरी झंडी,  इसकी 10 बड़ी बातें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने हिमाचल प्रदेश में सस्ती उड़ान की शुरुआत की. शिमला से दिल्ली के बीच की पहली उड़ान फ्लाइट को हरी झंडी दिखाने के अलावा पीएम मोदी ने दो और फ्लाइट्स को हरी झंडी दिखाई. इस अवसर पर मोदी ने कहा कि पहले एयरलाइंस में राजा महाराजा ही सफर करते थे. देश का गरीब हवाई चप्पल पहनता है, मैं चाहता था कि हवाई चप्पल वाला व्यक्ति हवाई जहाज में बैठे. आज वो बात सच हो रही है. मोदी ने कहा कि भारत में हवाई सेवा के विस्तार के लिए काफी अवसर है. उन्होंने कहा कि हवाई सर्कुलर रुट बनेगा तो ही सभी यात्री इसका लाभ उठा सकेंगे.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;उड़ान स्कीम की 10 बड़ी बातें-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत हवाई यात्रा के लिए 500 किलोमीटर या 1 घंटे के सफर की कीमत ज्यादा से ज्यादा 2,500 रुपया रखी गई है. इसी आधार पर अन्य रुटों का भी किराया निर्धारित किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 128 रूट्स और 5 ऑपरेटरों को उड़ान स्कीम में शामिल किया है. एयर इंडिया की क्षेत्रीय इकाई अलायंस एयर के तहत इन फ्लाइट्स को ऑपरेट किया जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 45 ऐसे एयरपोर्ट्स जो सेवा में नहीं हैं, उन्हें एयर नेटवर्क में कनेक्ट किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;छोटे शहर टियर-2 और टियर-3 के 13 एयरपोर्ट्स, जहां ज्यादा फ्लाइट्स नहीं चलती थीं वहां अब अधिक फ्लाइट्स होंगी. इन शहरों के लोगों को उड़ान स्कीम का फायदा मिल सकें.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान के तहत 5 ऑपरेटर्स का चयन हुआ है जो एयर इंडिया की सब्सिडियरी अलाइड सर्विसेज, स्पाइसजेट, एयर डेक्कन, एयर ओडिशा, टर्बो मेघा हैं.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;कानपुर से दिल्ली के लिए स्पाइसेजट की सेवा अगस्त में शुरू होगी, जबकि कानपुर से वाराणसी और दिल्ली के बीच सितम्बर में एयर ओडिशा के विमान उड़ान भरेंगे.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;अलायंस एय़र आगरा से जयपुर की उड़ान जून में शुरू करेगी, जबकि अगस्त में एय़र डेक्कन ने आगरा और दिल्ली के बीच उड़ान सेवा शुरु करने की तैयारी कर रखी है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;दिल्ली से शिमला के बीच अलायंस एय़र और एयर डेक्कन, दोनों ने ही अगले महीने सेवा शुरु करने का लक्ष्य रखा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;मध्य प्रदेश-छत्तीसगढ़ में अंबिकापुर से विलासपुर और बिलासपुर से रायपुर के बीच सितम्बर में एय़र ओडिशा अपनी सेवा शुरू करेगी. सितम्बर में ही जगदलपुर से रायपुर और विशाखापत्तनम के बीच सेवाएं शुरू हो जाएंगी.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 जून 2016 को शुरु हुई नैशनल सिविल एविएशन पॉलिसी का उड़ान अहम हिस्सा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>नक्सलवाद की कमर तोड़ने के लिए मोदी सरकार ने की ये प्लानिंग, पढ़ें पूरा मामला</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-plans-to-get-foliage-penetration-radar-for-naxal-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-plans-to-get-foliage-penetration-radar-for-naxal-areas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;खास बातें&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ये रडार जल्द ही नक्‍सलियों के खिलाफ ऑपरेशंस में इस्तेमाल किए जाएंगे.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;इन रडारों का इस्तेमाल पश्चिमी देशों में और इजरायल में काफी कामयाब रहा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;अजीत डोभाल ने इस बारे में जानकारी गृह मंत्री को भी दी.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार जल्द ही नक्सल ऑपरेशनों के लिए फोलिएज पैनिट्रेटिंग रडार यानि ऐसा रडारयुक्त कैमरा जो घने जंगलों में छिपे हुए नक्सलियों की गतिविधियों के बारे में जानकारी सुरक्षा बलों दे सकेगा, ख़रीदने जा रही है. एनडीटीवी इंडिया को मिली हुई जानकारी के मुताबिक़, ये रडार जल्द ही ऑपरेशंस में इस्तेमाल किए जाएंगे. इनके ज़रिए सुरक्षा बलों को घने जंगलों की तस्वीरें भी साफ़ तरह से दिखेंगी, जिसके चलते उन्हें नक्‍सलियों के खिलाफ ऑपरेशंस में मदद मिलेगी.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक सीनियर अफ़सर ने एनडीटीवी को बताया कि &amp;ldquo;आतंकियों के खिलाफ इस तरह के रडार का इस्तेमाल पश्चिमी देशों में और इजरायल में काफी कामयाब रहा है.&amp;rdquo;  बुधवार को हुई उच्चस्तरीय बैठक में राष्ट्रीय सुरक्षा सलाहकार अजीत डोभाल ने इस बारे में जानकारी गृह मंत्री को भी दी. गुरुवार को सीआरपीएफ़ सुकमा हादसे की रिपोर्ट केंद्रीय गृह मंत्रालय को सौंपने जा रहा है.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कैसे काम करेगा ये रडार&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार को अलग-अलग लोकेशन पर फिट किया जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार को एक सेन्ट्रल मॉनिटरिंग कंट्रोल रूम से जोड़ा जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;रडार किसी भी मूवमेंट को पकड़ने के साथ ही उस जगह की इमेज और वीडियो बनाकर सीधा कंट्रोल रूम तक पहुंचाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;इस तकनीक के सहारे नक्सलियों की लोकेशन और संख्या के साथ-साथ उनके पास मौजूद हथियार और गोला-बारूद की जानकारी भी कंट्रोल रूम को देगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>स्मार्ट सिटीज के शहरी गरीबों के घर का किरया भी चुकाएगी मोदी सरकार!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-may-pay-your-rent-through-vouchers-soon-in-100-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-may-pay-your-rent-through-vouchers-soon-in-100-cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मोदी सरकार अब आपके फ्लैट, कमरे का किराया चुका सकती है। केंद्र सरकार 100 स्मार्ट सिटीज में जल्द ही 2700 करोड़ रुपए की नई कल्याणकारी योजना की शुरुआत करने जा रही है, जिसके तहत शहरी गरीबों को घर का किराया चुकाने के लिए वाउचर्स दिए जाएंगे। सरकार रेंट वाउचर्स के साथ नई रेंटल हाउजिंग पॉलिसी को गरीबी रेखा से नीचे वाले लोगों के लिए पेश कर सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्मार्ट सिटीज में गरीबों का किराया देने वाली पॉलिसी पर वैसे तो तीन साल से काम चल रहा है, लेकिन इसका पहला कंपोनेंट वित्त वर्ष 2017-18 में लागू किया जा सकता है। स्मार्ट सिटीज में स्कीम को शुरू करने पर हर साल 2,713 करोड़ रुपए की लागत आने की उम्मीद है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस स्कीम को अर्बन पूअर यानी शहरों में रहने वाले गरीबों के लिए लिया जा रहा है, जिससे वहां मजदूरी करने के लिए आने वाले लोगों को मदद मिलेगी। रेंट वाउचर्स को शहरी निकायों की मदद से गरीबों में बांटा जाएगा। किरायेदार इन वाउचर्स को मकान मालिक को देगा, जो उसे किसी सिटीजन सर्विस ब्यूरो से अपने अकाउंट में ट्रांसफर करा सकेंगे। अगर रेंट वाउचर की वैल्यू से अधिक होता है तो किरायेदार को उसका भुगतान अपनी जेब से करना होगा। रेंट वाउचर की वैल्यू शहर और कमरे के साइज के हिसाब से निकाय तय करेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार इस वाउचर स्कीम के लिए डायरेक्ट बेनेफिट ट्रांसफर (DBT) की संभावना भी तलाश रही है। 2011 की जनगणना के मुताबिक, शहरों में करीब 27.5 प्रतिशत आबादी किराए के घरों में रहती है। हालांकि, नैशनल सैंपल सर्वे (NSS) के आंकड़ों के मुताबिक 2009 में शहरों में 35 प्रतिशत लोग किराए के घरों में रहते हैं। इसके अलावा, NSS से यह बात भी सामने आई थी कि यह रेशियो 1991 के बाद से इतना ही बना हुआ है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आवास और शहरी गरीबी उन्मूलन मंत्रालय के एक अधिकारी ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, &amp;lsquo;प्रधानमंत्री की हाउजिंग फॉर ऑल स्कीम के पूरक के तौर पर वाउचर स्कीम को देखा जा रहा है।&amp;rsquo; केंद्र जब्त की गई बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी का इस्तेमाल किफायती घर बनाने के लिए करेगी। इससे घरों की कमी दूर करने में मदद मिलेगी। एक अधिकारी ने&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बताया, &amp;lsquo;हाल में बेनामी प्रॉपर्टीज ऐक्ट को लागू किया गया है। इससे रेंटल हाउजिंग के लिए एक और रास्ता खुल गया है। इन रूल्स में एक ऐसी शर्त डाली जा सकती है कि जो घर केंद्र सरकार जब्त करेगी, उन्हें नीलाम नहीं किया जाएगा बल्कि उन्हें राज्य सरकारों के जरिये केंद्र मिडल इनकम ग्रुप (MIG), लो इनकम ग्रुप (LIG) और गरीबों को रेंटल हाउजिंग के लिए दे सकता है।&amp;rsquo; यह फैसला प्रॉपर्टी की लोकेशन और योग्यता के आधार पर लिया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>