<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs. 333: BSNL&#39;s New Plan To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 333, Rs. 339, Rs. 349 and Rs. 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL or Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited has announced three new data plans priced from Rs 333, the latest offering from the telecom operator seen as aimed at Jio&amp;rsquo;s Dhan Dhana Dhan plans. BSNL is offering up to 270 GB of 3G mobile data along with unlimited voice calls for a period of 90 days. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs 333 includes 3 GB per day of unlimited data, beyond which the speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps, the operator said. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing is causing intense competition in Indian telecom industry, forcing incumbent operators to offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attractive mobile data and unlimited voice calls plans, according to analysts. BSNL has also revised its existing Rs 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of data per day, instead of 2 GB earlier, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s revised Rs 339 pack, valid for 28 days, also includes unlimited local and inter-circle BSNL-to-BSNL calls. Calls to other networks are allowed with a limit of 25 minutes per day, beyond which BSNL customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 349 and Rs 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL had earlier launched yearly packs starting from Rs 1,498 and going up to Rs 4,498, which include 18 GB and 80 GB of data for 365 days, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Banks Cut Home Loans Rates, Special Discounts for Women</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ICICI and HDFC&amp;rsquo;s decision comes close on the heels of the State Bank of India and LIC Housing Finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICICI Bank cut home loan rates by 0.3% for loans up to Rs 30 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDFC lowers rate to 8.35% for new home loan up to 30 lakh for women&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest private sector lender ICICI Bank cut its home loan rates by 0.3 per cent for loans up to Rs 30 lakh, a move that was matched by HDFC Bank on Monday bringing them in line with the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India. SBI is the biggest player in the home loan segment with around 26 per cent market share, followed by HDFC. With the cut in interest rates, salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40 per cent while salaried women borrowers will get home loans at 8.35 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the move, ICICI Bank managing director Chanda Kochhar said the bank is committed to supporting the government&amp;rsquo;s vision to provide housing for all by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In line with this commitment, we have reduced the home loan interest rates for the affordable housing segment. With this announcement, customers of Economically Weaker Section (EWS) and Low Income Group (LIG) can avail the dual benefit of low interest rates from us and the Credit Linked Subsidy under the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICICI Bank also said that its customers taking home loans in the affordable segment will also have the option to select the type of interest rate. In both these cases, the reduction in interest rates is 30 basis points from the previous rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can enjoy the benefit of floating interest rate or a fixed interest rate for the initial two/three years followed by floating rate, ICICI Bank said, claiming to be the first to offer such flexibility to customers. &amp;ldquo;The reduced rate will be effective from May 15, 2017 for new borrowers,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI and LIC Housing Finance had dialed back interest rates on housing loans last week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EPFO Reduces Wait For Pension, Provident Fund Withdrawal To 10 days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-reduces-wait-for-pension-provident-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-reduces-wait-for-pension-provident-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The retirement fund manager had launched an online claim settlement facility on May 1, 2017.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund manager EPFO has reduced the stipulated period for settlement of various claims such PF withdrawal, pension and insurance to 10 days from 20 at present. In July 2015, the Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had reduced the timeline for settling various claims to 20 day to improve the service delivery for its over four crore subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body has launched the online claim settlement facility on May 1, 2017. It has planned to eventually settle claims of all Aadhaar and bank account seeded EPF accounts within three hours of receipt of an application. &amp;ldquo;The timeline in case of claim settlements is 10 days and 15 days in case of grievance redressal management,&amp;rdquo; an EPFO statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are new provisions in the EPFO&amp;rsquo;s Citizens&amp;rsquo; Charter 2017 launched in Bangalore today by Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said the Charter is an attempt to bring transparency and accountability on the part of EPFO and make service delivery system and grievance redressal mechanism more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO e-court Management System has also been launched which is in tune with the vision of Prime Minister Narendra Modi of digital India. The objective of the project is a transparent and electronic case management system which will cater to aspirations of all stakeholders - the employers, the employees, litigants and CBT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a step towards paperless court system wherein court procedure of EPF &amp;amp; MP Act, 1952 and EPFAT (tribunal) will take place in a digital environment. Further, in order to facilitate easy access to the tribunal, automated messages will be sent to the litigants on their registered mobile numbers on the status of their cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stakeholders can also track the individual cases online, it said. Now the parties can file all their paper/evidence/ documents online and all the details alongwith status can be accessed online. Updation is an important part of e-court management system in which digital case record will create a digital database which can be utilised to generate meaningful and accurate reports, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST impact: here’s how much it may cost you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-impact-services-set-to-get-costlier-heres-how-much-it-may-cost-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-impact-services-set-to-get-costlier-heres-how-much-it-may-cost-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the 120 services that are currently being taxed, a vast majority is likely to come under the goods and services tax (GST) slab of 18%, while a clutch of them including air travel services, renting of hotels, restaurants and other “bundled” food supply services could get taxed at 12%. A handful of services including transport of goods by road (trucks) and rail and financial leasing including hire purchase could fall under the lowest GST rate of 5%. While the principle that underlies the GST rates fitment, recommended by a committee of officials, is to minimise rate shocks, services would still be the category to witness rate hikes the most as the country adopts the new indirect tax structure, official sources said. Since the current service tax rate is 15% (including the 0.5% Swachh Bharat Cess and an equal Krishi Kalyan cess), levy of GST at 18% would mean a significant increase in the tax liability of consumers of most services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even for the relatively smaller number of services to be taxed at 12% in the GST regime, the tax incidence could actually increase in some cases. This is because taxes paid after the abatements permitted by the government work out to be lower than 12% in many such cases at present. For example, restaurant services are currently taxed with 30% abatement, which means actual tax incidence of 10.5%. This could increase to 12% in the GST regime, rather than decrease to 5%. The sources added that all the 60-odd exempt services, which are on the negative list now, would be outside the GST net too. These include services provided by educational institutions, healthcare services, EPFO- Irdai-Sebi services, non-A/c restaurants etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since the service providers will get greater opportunity to avail of input tax credit in the GST regime, their tax liability could soften if a rate hike is big enough to offset it. Transport of goods by rail is now taxed after 70% abatement on the condition that CENVAT credit has not been taken by the businesses concerned. Since the credit flows will be more efficient in the GST regime, the tax rate is likely to be fixed taking into account the abatements being given now for the new regime to be rate-neutral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at least in some cases, this principle might not be followed and the tax liability of businesses and consumers could rise, analysts said. However, the instances of GST leading to higher tax liabilities and price increases will be very few in the case of goods. Items constituting half of the consumer price index (CPI) basket including food grain will be exempt from GST; many other goods of mass consumption, together another tenth of the basket, will be taxed at a benign 5%; a quarter of the basket will come under either 12% or 18%, the two “standard rates.
The government has maintained that rate fitment will be a “mechanical (rather than discretionary) exercise” as the process has taken into account the real tax incidence at present rather than the nominal rate. For instance, if the nominal tax rate on an item with maximum retail price of Rs 150 and ex-factory price of Rs 100 is 26.5% (12.5% excise and 14% VAT), the real tax incidence on the price to the consumer is just 22%, as the excise duty is virtually levied on the ex-factory price, with abatement for post-manufacturing value addition. Chances are that the item will come under 18% GST, rather than the highest rate of 28%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The committee of officials has prepared a detailed document on the fitment of GST rates for the consideration of the GST Council. The 800-page document is likely to be vetted by the council as it meets in Srinagar on May 18-19. Source told FE that even after the GST Council approval, the rates will be notified and made public only closer to the July 1 roll-out to avoid market distortion and hoarding. Experts said that the reason for delaying announcement of rates could be to negate the possibility that a manufacturer may ramp up or slow down production till July 1 if it’s known that a commodity will be taxed at a lower/ higher rate under GST.
Apart from final approval to the rates, the GST Council is expected to okay the five draft rules related to accounts and records, advance ruling, appeals and revision, assessment and audit and e-way bill. So far, the Council has approved nine GST rules in its earlier meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian-Origin Techie Links Ransomware Attack To North Korea</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-origin-techie-links-ransomware-attack-to-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-origin-techie-links-ransomware-attack-to-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About 200,000 machines have been infected worldwide by the ransomware &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Indian-origin security researcher with Google has found evidence suggesting that North Korean hackers may have carried out the &amp;ldquo;unprecedented&amp;rdquo; ransomware cyberattack that hit over 150 countries, including India. Neel Mehta has published a code which a Russian security firm has termed as the &amp;ldquo;most significant clue to date&amp;rdquo;, BBC reported today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code, published on Twitter, is exclusive to North Korean hackers, researchers said. Researchers have said that some of the code used in Friday&amp;rsquo;s ransomware, known as WannaCry software, was nearly identical to the code used by the Lazarus Group, a group of North Korean hackers who used a similar version for the devastating hack of Sony Pictures Entertainment in 2014 and the last year&amp;rsquo;s hack of Bangladesh Central Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security experts are now cautiously linking the Lazarus Group to this latest attack after the discovery by Mehta. Mehta has found similarities between code found within WannaCry and other tools believed to have been created by the Lazarus Group in the past, BBC reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security expert Prof Alan Woodward said that time stamps within the original WannaCry code are set to UTC +9 - China&amp;rsquo;s time zone - and the text demanding the ransom uses what reads like machine-translated English, but a Chinese segment apparently written by a native speaker, the report said.
&amp;ldquo;As you can see it is pretty thin and all circumstantial. However, it is worth further investigation,&amp;rdquo; Woodward said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neel Mehta&amp;rsquo;s discovery is the most significant clue to date regarding the origins of WannaCry,&amp;rdquo; said Russian security firm Kaspersky, but noted a lot more information is needed about earlier versions of WannaCry before any firm conclusion can be reached, it reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We believe it is important that other researchers around the world investigate these similarities and attempt to discover more facts about the origin of WannaCry,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attributing cyberattacks can be notoriously difficult-often relying on consensus rather than confirmation, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Korea has never admitted any involvement in the Sony Pictures hack - and while security researchers, and the US government, have confidence in the theory, neither can rule out the possibility of a false flag, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skilled hackers may have simply made it look like it had origins in North Korea by using similar techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of WannaCry, it is possible that hackers simply copied code from earlier attacks by the Lazarus Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ifs in there. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stand up in court as it is. But it&amp;rsquo;s worth looking deeper, being conscious of confirmation bias now that North Korea has been identified as a possibility,&amp;rdquo; Woodward said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the strongest theory yet as to the origin of WannaCry, but there are also details that arguably point  way from it being the work of North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, China was among the countries worst hit, and not accidentally - the hackers made sure there was a version of the ransom note written in Chinese. It seems unlikely North Korea would want to antagonise its strongest ally. Russia too was badly affected, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, North Korean cyber-attacks have typically been far more targeted, often with a political goal in mind. In the case of Sony Pictures, hackers sought to prevent the release of The Interview, a film that mocked North Korean leader Kim Jong-Un. WannaCry, in contrast, was wildly indiscriminate - it would infect anything and everything it could, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if the plan was simply to make money, it&amp;rsquo;s been pretty unsuccessful on that front too - only around $60,000 has been paid in ransoms, according to analysis of Bitcoin accounts being used by the criminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more than 200,000 machines infected, it&amp;rsquo;s a terrible return, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Europol Director Rob Wainwright said, &amp;ldquo;The global reach is unprecedented. The latest count is over 200,000 victims in at least 150 countries and those victims many of those will be businesses including large corporations&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not happy with bank fixed deposits? Check out 4 alternatives</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/not-happy-with-bank-fixed-deposits-check-out-4-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/not-happy-with-bank-fixed-deposits-check-out-4-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compared to bank deposits or small savings, non-convertible debentures, liquid funds, tax-free bonds and company fixed deposits offer higher returns, albeit with some risks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a time when interest rates on bank deposit and small savings are falling, investors can look at other debt financial instruments to earn some higher returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;non-convertible-debentures&#34;&gt;Non-convertible debentures&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies issue non-convertible debentures (NCDs) to raise long-term funds. These debentures cannot be converted into shares or equities and lenders offer a higher rate of return compared to convertible debentures. Non-convertible debentures are of two types —secured and non-secured. The secured ones are backed by assets, wherein if the company is unable to fulfil its obligations, the assets are liquidated to repay the investors.
So, secured non-convertible debentures pay lower coupons than non-secured ones. Companies issuing non-convertible debentures offer higher rates because they carry default risk compared to bank or postal deposits. Investing in NCDs makes sense for those in the 10% to 20% tax brackets, as those in the lowest tax bracket can get post tax returns around 7% for a 120-month tenure. One should invest in non-convertible debentures only if he can hold them till maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Liquid funds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors can also look at liquid funds offered by asset management companies for short-term investment for up to a year. The fund will yield marginally higher returns than bank deposits. Moreover, they are as liquid as time and demand deposits as the market regulator has allowed fund houses to offer instant redemption facility of up to Rs 50,000. In fact, one aspect where bank deposits scored over liquid funds or any other money market funds was same day redemption.
Now that has been taken care and investors can manage cash flows better. At the time of investing in debt funds, investors must analyse the credit rating of the bonds in which the fund house invests. While debt funds are not rated, their safety can be analysed from the portfolio they invest in. Fund managers may sometimes take higher position in bonds with lower rating for higher returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Tax-free bonds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, tax-free bonds were issued by state-owned companies such as NHAI, IRFC, HUDCO till March 2016. However, investors can now buy these bonds from the secondary market and can earn up to 2% more than bank fixed deposits after tax. Tax-free bonds are an attractive long-term investment as there is no deduction of tax at source from the interest that accrues to bondholders, irrespective of the interest amount or status of the investor.
These bonds score over fixed deposits or other debt investment as investors do not have to pay tax on the returns. Before investing in tax-free bonds, one must look at the issue size as it may impact liquidity. For instance, NHAI’s Rs 10,000-crore bond issue has the highest traded volume on bourses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;company-fixed-deposits&#34;&gt;Company fixed deposits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even by investing in company fixed deposits of top-rated firms, investors can earn up to 150 basis points more than bank fixed deposits. However, investors must exercise utmost caution because while bank deposits provide security for investment up to Rs 1 lakh, this is not the case with corporate fixed deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tenure of company deposits ranges from one to seven years and one can earn compounding interest by reinvesting the principal amount along with the interest earned. Investors can get direct ECS credit facility for interest payments or advance interest warrants for the year. However, unless one needs income regularly, they should prefer cumulative schemes to regular income options since the interest earned gets reinvested at the same coupon rate, resulting in better yields.
Diversify investment in four to five companies and avoid investing in those companies that mention very high interest rates and whose balance sheets show losses. If one invests in a company that is low on ratings, go for a short tenure, which will enable you to opt out if the company is not performing well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Indian companies pay WannaCry ransom</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/despite-legal-implication-some-companies-pay-the-ransom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/despite-legal-implication-some-companies-pay-the-ransom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A top executive working with an Indian conglomerate couldn&amp;rsquo;t fathom how a bill of $300 (Rs 19,000) landed up at his company for using a free Wi-Fi at a five-star hotel coffee shop. The CEO of another New Delhibased manufacturing company clicked on an unknown link — a mistake that would come back to haunt him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laptops of the executive and the CEO were compromised by ransomware WannaCry, the malicious fast-spreading virus that has confounded cyber security experts around the world. The malware demands $300 in bitcoins to release the infected system and its data, causing hundreds of millions of dollars in business damage to corporations and government utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though lawyers and experts have been advising companies to not pay bitcoins, some Indian companies are believed to have gone ahead and paid the ransom to get their systems unlocked. &amp;ldquo;There would be some companies that may have paid the ransom in haste to retrieve their encrypted data. As of Monday morning, the hackers seem to have globally collected 23 bitcoins, which is around $41,400,&amp;rdquo; said Amit Jaju, executive director, Fraud Investigation &amp;amp; Dispute Services (FIDS), EY India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most legal experts and cybercrime experts are cautioning companies not to pay as this could also have legal implications. &amp;ldquo;PwC never recommends paying ransomware ransom — unless there is a threat to life. Doing so fuels the ransomware economy, funding development of additional ransomware techniques and campaigns. In many cases, we have seen that when money is paid, larger attack happens a few days or weeks later,&amp;rdquo; said Sivarama Krishnan, leader -cyber security at PwC India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Twitter handle, @actual_ransom, that describes itself as &amp;ldquo;a bot that is watching the bitcoin wallets tied to WannaCry ransomware attack&amp;rdquo; is also providing live updates of bitcoins paid by companies globally. &amp;ldquo;While we are monitoring this Twitter handle, you can&amp;rsquo;t trust the authenticity of this,&amp;rdquo; said a cybercrime expert with a consultancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports of corporations crippled by the attack are pouring in three days after the hackers stunned the world and showed the impotence of cyber security networks. The ransomware locked about 200 computers of a Mumbai-headquartered company, which did not have any backup for its crucial income tax data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The company worried that the income tax department would come after it if it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the data readily available,&amp;rdquo; said a person in the know. Legal experts are cautioning companies against paying the ransom as this could land them in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While some companies may consider making payment to obtain the decryption key to unlock their computers that have been locked by the WCry virus, one must consider the legal implications of this action,&amp;rdquo; said Tushar Ajinkya, partner, DSK Legal, a law firm. &amp;ldquo;In the event it is concluded that the actions of the ransomware WCry in demanding payment for release of the encrypted data tantamount to extortion, then in addition to a FEMA violation, facilitators and recipients of such payment may also attract provisions of the PMLA,&amp;rdquo; Ajinkya said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies are believed to have paid the bitcoins with the help of third-party service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Typically, the process involves creating a bitcoin wallet and then making the payment. However, this should ideally be done in consultation with legal, forensic and cyber expert advisors as there tends to be little or no guarantee of regaining access to the data once the ransom is paid,&amp;rdquo; said Jaju of EY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time a ransomware has attacked India Inc. ET on January 11 reported that hackers seized control of computers at three banks and a pharmaceutical company and then demanded a ransom in bitcoins for the decryption keys to unfreeze them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases, Indian companies do not wish to report the cases or file a complaint with the investigative authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even Indian banks, which are required to make a mandatory disclosure to the regulator of any cyberattack, seldom do this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want A New Jio SIM? Here&#39;s What You Pay To Get &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in getting a new Reliance Jio SIM and availing the &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer? Rs 408 is the minimum amount you need to spend. For Jio non-Prime and new users, the recharge amount is Rs 309 along with an additional Rs 99. Similarly, to get the Rs 509 plan, the amount needed will be Rs 608.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has extensively provided free data services with unlimited calls for several months and with the telecom operator starting paid services, one can expect the firm to provide the &amp;lsquo;most affordable&amp;rsquo; plans. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rs. 408 is the minimum amount needed to avail Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has provided free services with unlimited calls for last few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has been in the controversy for stretching its free trial run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-dhan.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is WannaCry ransomware? How can it affect India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-is-wannacry-ransomware-how-can-it-affect-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-is-wannacry-ransomware-how-can-it-affect-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware, also known as WannaCrypt, has affected over 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on May 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware, also known as WannaCrypt, has affected over 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on May 12. Termed as one of the biggest ransomware attacks the world has ever seen, this bug has slept open dark signs of vulnerabilities in the digital era. Governments and experts are expecting a possible worsening of the ransomware cyber-attack. The indiscriminate attack began Friday and struck banks, hospitals and government agencies, exploiting known vulnerabilities in older Microsoft computer operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the attack about?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware that is also called WannaCrypt, affected at least 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on Friday. The WanaCrypt0r 2.0 bug basically encrypts data on a computer within seconds and displays a message asking the user to pay a ransom of $ 300 in Bitcoins to restore access to the device and the data inside. Even FedEx, European car factories, Spanish telecoms giant Telefonica, Britain’s health service and Germany’s Deutsche Bahn rail network have been hit. Payment is demanded within three days or the price is doubled, and if none is received within seven days the locked files will be deleted, according to the screen message, agencies reported.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/cZ543_0bjbw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is India safe? Is you Aadhaar card save?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack was specifically targeted at Microsoft Windows devices. Microsoft claims it “released a security update which addresses the vulnerability that these attacks are exploiting” in March itself, and advised users to update their systems in order to deploy the latest patches. However, Indians usually have the Windows running on office desktops, which makes the data vulnerable. A lot of personal data online are now connected to the Aadhaar data of over a billion Indians. “Since the user’s bank account is linked with his Aadhaar number, the ransomware can potentially lock down the account and make it unusable unless a ransom is paid,” Pradipto Chakrabarty, Regional Director, CompTIA India.
F-Secure highlighted the need for a four-phase approach to cybersecurity: Predict, Prevent, Detect, and Respond; and detect by monitoring infrastructure for signs of intrusion or suspicious behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ने पर अवैध हो जाएगा PAN,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) को आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ा तो संभव है कि 31 दिसंबर के बाद यह अवैध हो जाए। दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के सरकार के फैसले के बाद इसे वित्तीय लेनदेन (फाइनैंशल ट्रांजैक्शंज) के लिए जरूरी नंबर बनाने की दिशा में एक और कदम बढ़ा दिया गया है। सरकार पूरे फाइनैंशल सेक्टर में आधार आधारित नो योर कस्टमर (KYC) को इंटीग्रेट करने पर विचार कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इसकी पुष्टि करते हुए कहा कि सरकार रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) सहित सभी रेग्युलेटर्स के साथ विचार-विमर्श कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार KYC एक तुरंत, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक और मजबूत प्रमाण उपलब्ध कराता है, जिससे सेवा उद्योग की प्रक्रिया बेहतर बनाने में मदद मिलेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने फाइनैंस बिल में एक संशोधन के जरिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के लिए आवेदन पर आधार को अनिवार्य बना दिया है। अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन लोगों के पास पहले से आधार मौजूद है, उन्हें किसी भी वित्तीय मध्यस्थ (फाइनैंशल इंटरमीडियरी) को अपने अंगूठे का निशान उपलब्ध कराना होगा। इसे संबंधित सेक्टर की रिपोर्टिंग एंटिटि को दिया जाएगा, जो इसे UIDAI डेटाबेस से वैलिडेट करेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस डेटा के आधार पर सेंट्रल रजिस्ट्री ऑफ सिक्यॉरिटाइजेशन ऐंड ऐसेट रिकंस्ट्रक्शन ऐंड सिक्यॉरिटी इंट्रेस्ट ऑफ इंडिया (CERSAI) की ओर से एक यूनीक C-KYC नंबर जेनरेट किया जाएगा। इस नंबर का इस्तेमाल बैंक अकाउंट, म्यूचुअल फंड इन्वेस्टमेंट, डीमैट अकाउंट और इंश्योरेंस पॉलिसी सहित सभी फाइनैंशल प्रॉडक्ट्स में किया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा था कि देश में 98 प्रतिशत व्यस्कों या 108 करोड़ से अधिक लोगों को आधार नंबर जारी किया जा चुका है और इसी वजह से सरकार इसका इस्तेमाल बढ़ा रही है। उन्होंने इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के प्रस्ताव पर दोबारा विचार करने की संसद की मांग को खारिज कर दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC सुविधा से PAN के आवेदन के लिए जन्मतिथि या पते जैसी जानकारियों की पुष्टि का इंतजार कर रहे व्यक्ति और एंटिटि अंगूठे के निशान से बायोमेट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन कर सकेंगे। CERSAI ने पिछले वर्ष सभी वित्तीय संस्थानों में एक समान KYC प्रोसेस सुनिश्चित करने के लिए e-KYC की कोशिश शुरू की थी। 2016 में मार्केट रेग्युलेटर सेबी ने आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC को स्वेच्छा से अपनाने पर सहमति दी थी। सभी सरकारी बैंकों से भी इस तरह का अपडेटेड डेटा अथॉरिटी को उपलब्ध कराने का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विज्ञापन में कहा गया है कि आयकर विभाग के पास आपकी जमाओं की जानकारी है। विभाग ने कहा है कि इस योजना के तहत कालेधन की घोषणा करने वालों की गोपनीयता सुनिश्चित की जाएगी। विज्ञापन में स्पष्ट चेतावनी दी गई है कि योजना के तहत काले धन की जानकारी नहीं देने वालों को बेनाम कानून के तहत कठोर कार्रवाई का सामना करना होगा। यहां तक कि उनके नाम ईडी और सीबीआई जैसी केंद्रीय जांच एजेंसियों के साथ साझा कर दिए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा कि जो लोग प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना का लाभ लेते हुए अपनी काली कमाई उजागर नहीं करेंगे, उन्हें जमा राशि पर 137% तक जुर्माना लगाया जा सकता है। उनके मुताबिक, विभाग ऐसे डिफॉल्टरों पर नए बेनामी लेनदेन कानून के तहत कार्रवाई करने से भी नहीं हिचकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत काला धन की जानकारी देने वालों को 49.9 प्रतिशत टैक्स देना होगा, जबकि ऐसा नहीं कर इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न में इस धन का जिक्र करने वालों को टैक्स के साथ-साथ 77.25 प्रतिशत जुर्माना देना होगा। साथ ही, जो लोग योजना के तहत काले धन का खुलासा नहीं करते हैं और जांच आकलन में इसका पता चलता है तो उन्हें 83.25 प्रतिशत की दर से टैक्स वसूला जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो लोग योजना का फायदा लेते हुए काले धन की जानकारी सरकार को नहीं देते हैं और छापेमारी के दौरान छिपा हुआ धन सरेंडर करते हैं तो उन्हें 107.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना होगा। लेकिन, जो लोग छापेमारी में भी काला धन खुद निकाल कर नहीं देते हैं, उन्हें 137.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना पड़ सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बेनामी कानून में दोषियों को 7 साल तक की कैद से दंडित करने का प्रावधान है। इसके अलावा, उस पर आयकर कानून के तहत भी मुकदमा चल सकता है। साथ ही, उस पर बेनामी संपत्ति के उचित बाजार मूल्य का 25 प्रतिशत और दूसरे जुर्माने भी भरने होंगे। गौरतलब है कि सरकार ने नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना की घोषणा की थी। इस योजना के तहत कुल घोषित काले धन का एक चौथाई हिस्सा चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज के सरकार के पास जमा रखने की बाध्यता है। यह योजना पिछले साल 17 दिसंबर को शुरू हुई।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>खातों की कम जानकारी देने वाले करदाता जांच के दायरे में</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने सत्यापन के लिए 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान की है, जिसमें 1.58 लाख करदाता ऐसे शामिल हैं, जिन्होंने पिछले दिनों अपने खातों की आंशिक घोषणा की थी। नोटबंदी के बाद इंकम टैक्स विभाग को बैंकों द्वारा दायर वित्तीय लेनदेन के बयान (एसएफटी) सहित विभिन्न स्रोतों से कई अहम जानकारी मिली। आईटी विभाग ने कहा कि इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने 1.58 लाख करदाताओं से संबंधित 3.71 लाख नए खातों की पहचान की है, जिन्होंने पहले अपने अकाउंट के बारे में जानकारी दी थी। पहले 18 लाख मामलों के अलावा, 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान ई-वेरिफेकेशन से की गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट पहले से उप्लब्ध डेटा की मदद से विश्लेषण कर रहा है। इस डेटा की मदद से ई-वेरिफिकेशन के लिए नए मामलों की पहचान हो चुकी है। 31 जनवरी को आई-टी विभाग द्वारा शुरू किए गए &amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; के तहत 17.92 लाख लोगों को एसएमएस और ई-मेल भेजे गए हैं, जिन्होंने 10 नवंबर से 30 दिसंबर के बीच 5 लाख और उससे ज्यादा पैसे जमा किए हैं। इनमें से 9 .72 लाख लोगों ने नकदी जमा के स्रोतों पर जवाब दिया है। विभाग ने उन मामलों में वेरिफिकेशन बंद करने का निर्णय लिया है, जहां नकदी के स्रोत का पूरा ब्यौरा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;करदाताओं ने करीब 2.8 9 लाख करोड़ रुपये के नकदी जमा से जुड़े 13.33 लाख खातों के लिए जवाब दे दिए हैं। ऑनलाइन प्रतिक्रियाओं का आंकलन कर खातों की सही जानकारी देने वालों के मामलों में आगे कोई कार्रवाई नहीं की जाएगी। विभाग ने दो विशेष डेटा ऐनालिटिकल एजेंसियों और एक व्यावसायिक प्रक्रिया प्रबंधन एजेंसी को बड़ी मात्रा में नकद जमा के डेटा का विश्लेषण करने, करदाताओं की अनुपालन स्थिति और रिपोर्टिंग संस्थाओं का पता लगाने की जिम्मेदारी दी है। नकदी जमा के सोर्स के रूप में नकद बिक्री का दावा करने वाले पेट्रोल पंप व्यापारियों और संपत्ति खरीददारों जैसे व्यापारों की विस्तृत जांच की जाएगी, जिनका कैश सेल उनके नकद जमा की तुलना में ज्यादा पाया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जानें- 2500 रुपये में हवाई सफर को हरी झंडी,  इसकी 10 बड़ी बातें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने हिमाचल प्रदेश में सस्ती उड़ान की शुरुआत की. शिमला से दिल्ली के बीच की पहली उड़ान फ्लाइट को हरी झंडी दिखाने के अलावा पीएम मोदी ने दो और फ्लाइट्स को हरी झंडी दिखाई. इस अवसर पर मोदी ने कहा कि पहले एयरलाइंस में राजा महाराजा ही सफर करते थे. देश का गरीब हवाई चप्पल पहनता है, मैं चाहता था कि हवाई चप्पल वाला व्यक्ति हवाई जहाज में बैठे. आज वो बात सच हो रही है. मोदी ने कहा कि भारत में हवाई सेवा के विस्तार के लिए काफी अवसर है. उन्होंने कहा कि हवाई सर्कुलर रुट बनेगा तो ही सभी यात्री इसका लाभ उठा सकेंगे.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;उड़ान स्कीम की 10 बड़ी बातें-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत हवाई यात्रा के लिए 500 किलोमीटर या 1 घंटे के सफर की कीमत ज्यादा से ज्यादा 2,500 रुपया रखी गई है. इसी आधार पर अन्य रुटों का भी किराया निर्धारित किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 128 रूट्स और 5 ऑपरेटरों को उड़ान स्कीम में शामिल किया है. एयर इंडिया की क्षेत्रीय इकाई अलायंस एयर के तहत इन फ्लाइट्स को ऑपरेट किया जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 45 ऐसे एयरपोर्ट्स जो सेवा में नहीं हैं, उन्हें एयर नेटवर्क में कनेक्ट किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;छोटे शहर टियर-2 और टियर-3 के 13 एयरपोर्ट्स, जहां ज्यादा फ्लाइट्स नहीं चलती थीं वहां अब अधिक फ्लाइट्स होंगी. इन शहरों के लोगों को उड़ान स्कीम का फायदा मिल सकें.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान के तहत 5 ऑपरेटर्स का चयन हुआ है जो एयर इंडिया की सब्सिडियरी अलाइड सर्विसेज, स्पाइसजेट, एयर डेक्कन, एयर ओडिशा, टर्बो मेघा हैं.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;कानपुर से दिल्ली के लिए स्पाइसेजट की सेवा अगस्त में शुरू होगी, जबकि कानपुर से वाराणसी और दिल्ली के बीच सितम्बर में एयर ओडिशा के विमान उड़ान भरेंगे.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;अलायंस एय़र आगरा से जयपुर की उड़ान जून में शुरू करेगी, जबकि अगस्त में एय़र डेक्कन ने आगरा और दिल्ली के बीच उड़ान सेवा शुरु करने की तैयारी कर रखी है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;दिल्ली से शिमला के बीच अलायंस एय़र और एयर डेक्कन, दोनों ने ही अगले महीने सेवा शुरु करने का लक्ष्य रखा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;मध्य प्रदेश-छत्तीसगढ़ में अंबिकापुर से विलासपुर और बिलासपुर से रायपुर के बीच सितम्बर में एय़र ओडिशा अपनी सेवा शुरू करेगी. सितम्बर में ही जगदलपुर से रायपुर और विशाखापत्तनम के बीच सेवाएं शुरू हो जाएंगी.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 जून 2016 को शुरु हुई नैशनल सिविल एविएशन पॉलिसी का उड़ान अहम हिस्सा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>हकीकत 1,500 रुपये का 4G फीचर फोन जल्द बन सकता है </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4G फीचर फोन या बेसिक मोबाइल फोन, जिसकी कीमत 1,500 रुपये हो, जल्द ही हकीकत बन सकता है। चाइनीज मोबाइल चिप मेकर स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस ने कहा है कि वह मौजूदा लेवल्स से शुरुआती कीमत कम से कम आधा करने पर काम कर रही है। एक डिवेलपमेंट एक्सपर्ट ने कहा कि यह कई कन्ज्यूमर को स्मार्टफोन की ओर शिफ्टिंग से रोक सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस के कंट्री हेड नीरज शर्मा ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, ‘हम एक ऐसी टेक्नॉलजी पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो कि 1,500 रुपये के 4G फीचर फोन को व्यावहारिक बनाती है। हमने अपने पार्टनर्स के लिए कॉन्सेप्ट प्रमोशन पहले ही शुरू कर दिया है।’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लावा और माइक्रोमैक्स जैसी घरेलू मोबाइल फोन कंपनियों के 4G फीचर फोन की कीमतें करीब 3,000 रुपये से शुरू होती हैं। कॉर्बन के अलावा, यह दोनों हैंडसेट मेकर कंपनियां आगे ऐसे फोन की कीमतें घटाना चाहती हैं। इस मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले इंडस्ट्री एग्जिक्यूटिव्स के मुताबिक, रिलायंस जियो इंफोकॉम भी अपनी सहयोगी रिटेल फर्म के जरिए किफायती 4G VoLTE फीचर फोन लाने की योजना बना रही है, इस फोन की कीमत 1,500 रुपये से कम हो सकती है। शंघाई बेस्ड स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस बेसबैंड चिप सेगमेंट में सधी ग्रोथ हासिल कर रही है और यह मीडियाटेक, क्वॉलकॉम जैसे मोबाइल चिप मेकर्स के साथ मुकाबला कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चिपसेट, किसी भी मोबाइल हैंडसेट का एक अहम हिस्सा है और डिवाइस की कीमत में इसकी बड़ी हिस्सेदारी होती है। स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस की रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज के साथ दो साल पुरानी पार्टनरशिप है और इसने RIL के अफोर्डेबल LYF फ्लेम 5 स्मार्टफोन को तैयार किया है। कंपनी ने लावा M1 4G फीचर फोन को भी पावर्ड किया है, जिसकी कीमत 3,599 रुपये है। कंपनी का कहना है कि उसे टेक्नॉलजी ईजाद करने और डिवाइसेज को मार्केट तक पहुंचाने में करीब छह महीने लगते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फाइनेंशल सर्विसेज फर्म जेपी मॉर्गन ने अपनी एक हालिया रिपोर्ट में कहा है कि 2017 में 4G कैपेबिलिटी वाले फीचर फोन पॉपुलर होंगे। इन्हें उम्मीद से कहीं ज्यादा तेजी से आने वाले 4G नेटवर्क से मजबूती मिलेगी। शर्मा ने कहा कि यह देखना काफी रोचक होगा कि ऐसे समय में जबकि मार्केट का झुकाव डेटा प्ले की तरफ है और वॉयस सेगमेंट स्थिर हो गया है, तब ऑपरेटर्स अपनी स्ट्रैटिजी को कैसे पुख्ता बनाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, ‘पिछले छह महीने में मार्केट पूरी तरह से 3G से 4G में शिफ्ट हो गया है और दमदार टेक्नॉलजी के बीच वेंडर्स को अपनी मार्केट स्ट्रैटेजी को दुरुस्त करना होगा।’ उन्होंने कहा कि अडिशनल वैल्यू ऑफर करने वाले LTE फीचर फोन को और आकर्षक तरीके में पैक्ड किया जाना चाहिए। साथ ही उन्हें बढ़ते डेटा मार्केट के हिसाब से टियर-III लोकेशंस और रूरल एरिया में बेचा जाना चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>