<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>12,000 cows in BJP-ruled Jharkhand get Aadhaar-like ID tags with details of horn, tail</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/12000-cows-bjp-ruled-jharkhand-get-aadhaar-like-id-tags-details-horn-tail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/12000-cows-bjp-ruled-jharkhand-get-aadhaar-like-id-tags-details-horn-tail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over 18 lakh cattle will be given Aadhaar-like UID numbers in a year that will prevent their illegal transportation and help improve their health and milk yield, officials said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jharkhand has tagged over 12,000 cows with Aadhaar-like 12-digit unique identification (UID) number to prevent illegal transportation of cattle, improve their milk yield and monitor their health, officials said, amid a nationwide debate on cow vigilantism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre told the Supreme Court on Monday that it will soon approve tamper-proof identity tags for all cattle in the country that will document a range of data, including a unique number and the type of their horn and tail, as part of efforts to prevent illegal transportation of cattle and livestock to Bangladesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jharkhand State Implement Agency for Cattle and Buffalo (JSIACB), a wing of the government of India, has been working on a pilot project to tag its cattle with Aadhaar-like details in eight districts — Ranchi, Hazaribagh, Dhanbad, Bokaro, Jamshedpur, Deoghar, Giridih and Lohardaga — much before the Centre’s proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pilot project is being carried under the Centre’s INAPH (information network for animal productivity and health) scheme for the last one year in Jharkhand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The information will be uploaded on the master data within a week,” INAPH’s Jharkhand nodal in-charge KK Tiwary said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/hindustan-number-ranchi-punching-aadhar-government-officials_c91e35c0-2988-11e7-b189-41b029cdb6ad.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Government officials punch the tag of the UID number on a cow in Ranchi. (HT Photo)
Tiwary said each animal has been tagged with 12-digit UID numbers, which is fixed around its ears, with records of identification details such as age, breed, sex, lactation, height, body, colour, horn type, tail switch, special mark and others. In Jharkhand, there is around 42 lakh head of cattle, and 70% of them are cows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Centre has recently directed us to extend the programme to all 24 districts and tag at least 18 lakh cattle in a year,” Tiwary said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSIACB chief executive officer Dr Govind Prasad said tracking of the breeding programme is one of the aims of the project. He said the unique ID would also help Society for Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, constituted in each district of Jharkhand, to monitor and check illegal trade of cattle in their respective districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to check illegal trade of cattle and their slaughtering, the Jharkhand government issued an order on March 27 for the closure of all illegal slaughterhouses across the state. The state administration has closed more than 1,000 illegal slaughterhouses so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jharkhand is one of the few states in the country where the Prevention of Cow Slaughter Act, 2005, is in place. The act imposes a penalty of Rs 5,000 and imprisonment of up to 5 years or both for offenders. However, despite the law, cow slaughter continues unabated in the several illegal slaughter houses across many districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prasad said after compilation of the information to the database, details of each animal could be accessed anywhere and anytime. “The animal details could also be tracked through smartphones,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on cow protection, especially by vigilante groups, has risen since the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP)-led government under Prime Minister Narendra Modi took power at the Centre 3 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been a string of cow-related violence but many state governments, particularly those ruled by the BJP, have defended the action on the grounds that the animal is considered holy by many Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not compulsory for obtaining marriage certificate: CIC to Govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Chief Information Commission has asked the government and marriage registration authorities to raise awareness and provide publicity through various media that Aadhaar is not compulsory for the purpose of marriage registration scheme, reports LiveLaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commission ruled that the compulsory registration of marriages helps tackle various issues like child marriage, marriage without consent, bigamous marriages, etc., and as such, the government should make it easier and more convenient to facilitate the registration, by not requiring other documents like Aadhaar and making changes for online application for marriage under the Special Marriage Act etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CIC cited Supreme Court’s order from 2014, which ruled that the government should not restrict social benefits to those who are yet to receive their Aadhaar card. Last year, the SC had also said that the card scheme is purely voluntary and cannot be made mandatory for scholarships. However, contrary to its prior stance, the SC asked the Government to link all mobile numbers with Aadhaar card details within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;centre-s-push-to-increase-aadhaar-saturation&#34;&gt;Centre’s push to increase Aadhaar saturation?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usage of Aadhaar as a verification system has been on the rise where multiple services including the IIT JEE, employee provident funds, PDS food grain purchases, RTE admissions and Jharkhand’s food and public distribution systems also using it. Private companies have also started using Aadhaar for verification purposes, such as iris scans by DCB Bank for eKYC, Microsoft’s Skype Lite which supports Aadhaar based verification, etc. However, use of Aadhaar by making it compulsory to avail some services, has come under heavy criticism for not respecting user privacy or being very secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM gives E-Wallets a run for money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BHIM — or the Bharat Interface For Money — is quickly becoming the favoured mobile payment solution for crores of Indians. Since its launch on December 31 till the end of February, the app had been downloaded 17 million times. Following its Android launch, BHIM is now also available on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is an extension of the Unified Payment System. It allows users to send and receive money through a mobile app that is linked to their bank savings account. This is an elegant solution compared to e-wallets that need to maintain a cash balance in order to be functional. Naturally, the question then arises: Should users switch to BHIM and simply spend from their banks, and stop using e-wallets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences between BHIM and e-wallets, and we’ll examine them here in order to help you understand the pros and cons of both ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bhim-vs-wallets-where-bhim-wins&#34;&gt;BHIM vs Wallets: Where BHIM Wins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Balance, loading &amp;amp; unloading:&lt;/em&gt; The first major difference between BHIM and UPI apps and e-wallets is how you maintain your spending balance. BHIM and UPI apps allow you to send and receive money with your bank account. You do not have to maintain a balance with the app. The app is your bank account, in a sense. But in e-wallets, you must maintain a balance in order to spend from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just that, returning your wallet balance back to your bank account will come with limitations and charges. But with BHIM and UPI, there is no need to send the money back from the app to the bank, since the money has been sitting in your account all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/em&gt; Another aspect where BHIM and UPI apps trump e-wallets. E-wallets do not have interoperability, meaning that if you are using Wallet X, you can only transfer money to another user on Wallet X, and not to a user operating Wallet Y. This isn’t a problem with BHIM, since you may move money between accounts with any bank on the BHIM platform. For example, you may be using an SBI account but you can send and receive money from users on ICICI or HDFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spending limits:&lt;/em&gt; BHIM and UPI score heavily here as well. E-wallets have a monthly spending limit of Rs 10,000 which can be raised to Rs 100,000 after the KYC process wherein users need to submit proof of ID and address in order to become authenticated. But BHIM allows a limit of Rs 10,000 per transaction and Rs 20,000 as the total worth of transactions in a 24-hour cycle. UPI apps go further, allowing you to spend up to Rs 100,000 per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-bhim-lags&#34;&gt;Where BHIM Lags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly two areas where e-wallets have an edge over UPI and BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marketing gimmicks:&lt;/em&gt; E-wallets have been around for a few years and they have had the time to build relationships with merchants and businesses. As a result, e-wallets are useful not just for money transfers but also for earning cashbacks and discounts. Not just that, some e-wallets also operate as e-commerce platforms allowing users to buy merchandise, electronics, tickets, etc. UPI and BHIM, on the other hand, are recent innovations and have some catching up to do in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit usage:* E-wallets allow you to link and spend from your credit card, allowing you to leverage the power of the credit available to you. BHIM works on simpler principles: you get to spend only if you have a bank balance, and you cannot link BHIM and UPI apps to your credit card account yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-bhim-is-catching-up&#34;&gt;How BHIM Is Catching Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest Union Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced a referral bonus and cashback scheme for BHIM users. “The government will launch two new schemes — a referral bonus for consumers and a cash-back scheme for merchants — to promote the use of BHIM,” Jaitley said during his budget speech. With these inclusions, BHIM will become a little more attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
Both e-wallets and UPI-based apps such as BHIM have a long way to go and a big role to play in India where internet penetration and smartphone usage are increasing by leaps and bounds every year. Both need to evolve in order to accommodate the changing needs of the Indian consumer in an increasingly less cash-dependent economy. However, at this point, you may want to have both BHIM and e-wallets installed on your smartphones. They both have some unique services to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Fixed Deposit Rates Lowest In Many Years. What Are Your Options?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fixed-deposit-rates-are-at-multi-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fixed-deposit-rates-are-at-multi-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the interest rates on bank fixed deposits are at multi-year lows. For example, State Bank of India is offering interest rate between 5.50 per cent and 6.90 per cent across different maturities on retail deposits (below Rs 1 crore), according to its website. Though the Reserve Bank of India has held its repo rate steady for some time, the 175-basis-point cut in its key lending rate since January 2015 has led to a broad decline in overall interest rate in the financial system. And the surge in deposits after demonetisation has forced banks to bring down interest rates on fixed deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;With bank fixed deposits at around 7 per cent and offering a post-tax return of 5-7 per cent depending on one&amp;rsquo;s tax slab, clearly for people in higher tax slab this will only help them match inflation and be at best a value protector,&amp;rdquo; says Manoj Nagpal, CEO, Outlook Asia Capital. But conservative investors should maintain their asset allocation based on their risk profile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some newer private banks offer higher rates, Mr Nagpal added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given that most asset classes that replace debt like gold, real estate etc have also not been giving returns in the short term, equity seems to be emerging as the only alternative. However investors should not over-allocate to equities just in the chase of higher returns. If being safe is the objective, then one should surely remember that equities are volatile by nature,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says small savings schemes like 5-year NSC (National Savings Certificates) offer a superior alternative for investors though with a slightly longer lock-in and could also be considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For senior citizens, Mr Nagpal recommends the Senior Citizen Savings Scheme and the to-be-launched Varishtha Pension Bima Yojana from LIC. The Varishtha Pension Bima Yojana 2017 is a pension scheme for senior citizens, which was earlier approved by the Union Cabinet. The Varishtha Pension Bima scheme 2017, which will be implemented through Life Insurance Corporation of India (LIC), assures pension based on a guaranteed rate of return of 8 per cent for 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among debt mutual funds, Mr Nagpal suggests accrual funds with a high quality of underlying portfolio for conservative investors. Given that the Reserve Bank of India has once again cautioned on the higher risks to inflation, conservative investors should reduce allocation to long duration debt funds, he added. Accrual funds mainly focus on earning interest income from the coupon offered by underlying bonds while debt funds based on duration try to gain from the upward or downward movement of interest rate in the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidya Bala, head of mutual fund research at Fundsindia.com, also says conservative investors should &amp;ldquo;actively considerer income accrual funds in mutual funds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If investors have a shorter time frame, Ms Bala suggests short-term and ultra short-term debt funds. &amp;ldquo;If they need regular income, they can use systematic withdrawal from short-term debt funds,&amp;rdquo; she adds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Besides generating superior returns, debt funds are more tax efficient&amp;rdquo; than bank fixed deposits, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Vodafone To Airtel To BSNL, Operators Launch New Plans To Take On Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-drags-data-pricing-to-rock-bottom-with-new-prepaid-offers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-drags-data-pricing-to-rock-bottom-with-new-prepaid-offers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under its Rs. 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With tariff war intensifying in Indian telecom sector after Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s low cost data plans under its Summer Surprise and Dhan Dhana Dhan offers, prices of mobile data from other incumbent telecom players like Bharti Airtel, Vodafone, Idea Cellular and BSNL have fallen by nearly 60 per cent. According to domestic research house Crisil, the telecom player which will be able to retain maximum average revenue per user (ARPU) will win the ongoing tariff war and be able to sustain. In a bid to retain existing customers, incumbent telecom players like Airtel, Vodafone, Idea and BSNL are pricing their plans in such a way that they retain maximum of their existing subscribers and also maintain their ARPU. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at various plans launched by incumbent telecom players:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, Reliance Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data per day till end of June on a recharge of Rs 309. Those who recharge with the Rs 509 pack will get 2GB of 4G data every day. Under both the Rs 309 and Rs 509 plans, subscribers will also get free calls, free roaming and 100 SMSs per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs 399 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs. 399 recharge pack, Airtel is offering 1GB of 4G data per day along with free voice calls to any network for 70 days. However, there are some limitations on voice calls. You can make 300 minutes of Airtel-to-Airtel calls per day (1,200 minutes in a week) and for other networks, 3,000 minutes of free local and STD calls for 70 days. If you exhaust the free minutes, Rs 0.10 per minute will be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs 345 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel is offering 2GB of data per day at 4G speed for 28 days under its new Rs 345 recharge pack. Also, now there is no restriction with regard to the timing of data consumption. Under the earlier Rs. 345 recharge pack, users were restricted to use only 500 MB of data daily from 6 am till midnight , and the remaining 500 MB between 12 am and 6 am. Along with the above data, users will also get free voice calls to Airtel and other networks as it is in the Rs. 399 pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs. 244 recharge, users will get 1 GB of 4G data per day for 70 days without any restriction on usage timing. But this pack offers free calls on Airtel networks only (300 minutes of daily Airtel-to-Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for a week for 70 days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs. 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week. If you cross the call limit, a fee of 30 paise per minute will be charged for every call. This offer is not available for every Vodafone users. You can check if the offer is available for you by dialing *121# from your Vodafone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL Rs. 333 plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs. 333 offers 3 GB of 3G data per day for 90 days. After you exhaust the daily data limit of 3GB data, speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL Rs. 349 plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs. 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and offers 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs. 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL Rs. 395 plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Nehle Pe Dehla&amp;rsquo; plan priced at Rs 395 provides 2GB daily data at 3G speed for 71 days. The Rs. 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL Rs. 339 plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL has also revised its existing Rs. 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of 3G data per day, instead of 2 GB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NITI&#39;s 3-Year Agenda Suggests Key Reforms To Bolster Economy</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-3-year-agenda-suggests-key-reforms-to-bolster-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-3-year-agenda-suggests-key-reforms-to-bolster-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The draft agenda, released by Niti Aayog Vice Chairman Arvind Panagariya, also underlined the need for recalibrating the role of the government by limiting its involvement in activities that do not serve a public purpose.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niti Aayog in its three-year draft action agenda today suggested a host of reforms in taxation, agriculture and energy sectors with the objective of accelerating growth and increasing employment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The draft agenda, released by Niti Aayog Vice Chairman Arvind Panagariya today, also underlined the need for recalibrating the role of the government by limiting its involvement in activities that do not serve a public purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other things, the Aayog has also suggested the closure of loss-making CPSEs and strategic disinvestment in 20 state-owned companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three-year agenda (2017-18 to 2019-20) called for steps to check tax evasion, expand tax base and simplify taxation system through reforms. It suggested the government could consider consolidating existing custom duty rates to a unified rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other suggestions include creation of an institutional mechanism to promote competition through comprehensive review and reform of government regulations across all sectors, besides strengthening of the public procurement system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressing the need to bring down land prices to make housing affordable through increased supply of urban land, it suggested the need of reform in the Rent Control Act along the lines of the Model Tenancy Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other suggestions include, more flexible conversion rules from one use to another, release of land held by sick units, release of other urban land potentially available and more generous floor space index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also recommended setting up of dormitory housing for migrants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The draft action agenda on the agriculture sector, which seeks to double the income of farmers by 2022, include reform of the Agriculture Produce Marketing to ensure that farmers receive remunerative prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aayog&amp;rsquo;s three-year agenda also suggested raising productivity through enhanced irrigation, faster seed replacement and precision agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The farmers, it said, should be encouraged to shift to high-value commodities like horticulture, animal husbandry and fisheries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regard to the energy sector, the draft agenda pitched for adopting consumer friendly measures such as provision of electricity to all households by 2022, LPG connection to all BPL households, elimination of black carbon by 2022 and extension of the city gas distribution programme to 100 smart cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also suggested to reduce the cross-subsidy in the power sector to ensure competitive supply of electricity to the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The draft agenda also talked about reforming the coal sector by setting up a regulator, encouraging commercial mining and improving labour productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regard to transport and digital connectivity, the draft action agenda suggested strengthening infrastructure in roadways, railways, shipping and ports, inland waterways and civil aviation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also pitched for ensuring last-mile digital connectivity, particularly for e-governance and financial inclusion, through developing infrastructure, simplifying the payments structure and improving literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitate public-private partnerships, it said, by reorienting the role of the India Infrastructure Finance Company Ltd (IIFCL) and added there is a need to &amp;ldquo;introduce low cost debt instruments and operationalise the National Investment Infrastructure Fund (NIIF)&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referring to job creation, the draft agenda sought creation of coastal employment zones to boost exports and generating high-productivity jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also emphasised on enhancing labour-market flexibility through reforms of key laws and addressing the high and rising share of non-performing assets (NPAs) in India&amp;rsquo;s bank through supporting action of larger assets to private reconstruction companies (ARCs) and strengthening the State Bank of India-led by ARC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Science and Technology, it suggested creating a &amp;lsquo;National Science, Technology &amp;amp; Innovation Foundation&amp;rsquo; to identify and deliberate national issues, recommend priority interventions in S&amp;amp;T and prepare frameworks for their implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also suggested developing guidelines for PPPs in S&amp;amp;T to improve education and industry-academia linkages for demand-driven research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The draft agenda also stressed for streamlining the administration of the patent regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agenda also pitched for enhanced focus on public health through significantly increasing government expenditure on it and suggested establishing a focal point and setting up a dedicated cadre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a need to generate and disseminate periodic, district-level data as per uniform protocols, the draft agenda said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also suggested launching the National Nutrition Mission and developing a comprehensive Nutrition Information System.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The draft agenda also suggested to revisit the policy towards felling of trees on private land and transport of trees.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operation Clean Money 60,000 individuals including 1,300 ‘high-risk’ cases </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-phase-ii-60k-individuals-including-1300-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-phase-ii-60k-individuals-including-1300-high/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over 60,000 individuals, including 1,300 high-risk persons, will be under the scanner of the income tax department in the second phase of ‘Operation Clean Money’. The second phase of the black money detection programme, which was first started by the tax department post demonetisation, will investigate into claims of excessive cash sales during the demonetisation that did not match the previous profiles of the tax assessees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“More than 60,000 persons, including 1,300 high-risk persons, have been identified for investigation into claims of excessive cash sales during the demonetisation period. More than 6,000 transactions of high value property purchase and 6,600 cases of outward remittances shall be subjected to detailed investigations. All the cases where no response is received shall also be subjected to detailed enquiries,” the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) said in a statement.
The tax department has identified the high risk persons through detailed investigations using advanced data analytics, including integration of data sources, relationship clustering and fund tracking, CBDT said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The high risk categories identified include businesses claiming cash sales as the source of cash deposits that has been found to be in excess of their past profile or industry norms, large cash deposits made by government or PSU employees, persons who have undertaken high value purchases, persons who have used shell entities for layering of funds and where no responses were received, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CBDT, the policy-making body of the department, said it has detected undisclosed income over Rs 9,334 crore between the period of November 9, 2016 till February 28 this year. On November 8 last year, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had announced the decision to scrap high-denomination currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the first phase of the ‘Operation Clean Money’, launched on January 31 this year, the department had sent communications to around 18 lakh individuals asking them to respond online to specific queries relating to cash deposits made during November 9-December 30, the time period given for deposit of scrapped currency notes in banks. Out of the 17.92 lakh persons to whom the queries were sent by the tax department under the first phase of operation Clean Money, 9.46 lakh persons responded have responded to the department as per pre-defined parameters of sources of the cash deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Online queries were raised in 35000 cases and on-line verification was completed in more than 7800 cases. It has been decided to close the verification in cases where explanation of source of cash was found to be justified. In cases where the cash deposit has been declared under Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), the verifications would also be closed,” the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post-demonetisation period saw a rise in number of searches and surveys conducted by the tax department. More than 2,362 search, seizure and survey actions were conducted by the tax department during November 9 last year to February 28, leading to seizure of valuables worth more than Rs 818 crore, which includes cash of Rs 622 crore and detection of undisclosed income of more than Rs 9,334 crore. Over 400 cases have been referred by the tax department to the Enforcement Directorate and the CBI. Surveys have been conducted in more than 3400 cases by assessment units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had also launched a compliance window for assesees to come clean with their undisclosed cash and deposits made after demonetisation through the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY). The three-month long PMGKY scheme received lukewarm response, with only Rs 2,300 crore flowing into government coffers as taxes and penalty by declarants in the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,334 cr undisclosed income detected&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CBDT said it has detected undisclosed income over Rs 9,334 crore between the period of November 9, 2016 till February 28 this year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High risk categories include businesses claiming cash sales as the source of cash deposits found to be in excess of their past profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provident Fund Rules Changed. Now, Pay Home Loan EMIs, Buy House From Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-rules-changed-pay-home-loan-emis-buy-house-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-rules-changed-pay-home-loan-emis-buy-house-from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EPFO subscribes will be able withdraw up to 90% of their accumulations in their provident fund accounts for purchase/construction of houses or purchase of land.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has amended the rules of the Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Funds Scheme to enable over four crore subscribers to pay equated monthly instalments (EMIs) of home loans. They can also make payments towards purchase/construction of houses or purchase of land. This is part of the government&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Housing for All&amp;rsquo; agenda. The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) is the retirement fund body that manages provident fund savings on behalf of employees. The government also recently announced other measures like Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana (Urban) for middle-income groups to boost the housing sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) EPFO subscribes will be able withdraw up to 90 per cent of their accumulations in their provident fund accounts for purchase/construction of houses or purchase of land. (Also read: 8.65% interest on PF deposits to be credited soon)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) To purchase a house under this new scheme, the subscriber has to be a member of a cooperative society or a society registered for housing purpose and such society should have at least ten members. The subscriber can also purchase the flat/house or land from the government or any agency under housing scheme or any promoter or builder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The retirement fund body will make the payment for purchase of the property to the housing agency - not to the provident fund subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, only those EPFO subscribers who had completed five years of service were allowed to withdraw provident fund savings for purchase of house/flat/construction including land. They were allowed to withdraw only 36 months of their salary (basic salary and dearness allowance) for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) The new rules also provide that that monthly instalments towards home purchase can also be paid from provident fund deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The monthly instalments will be directly paid to to the government, housing agency, primary lending agency or the bank concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The subscriber has to apply to the EPFO for availing the new scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The withdrawal facility from the provident fund account will be available to only those members who fulfil certain conditions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The member should have contributed to the fund for at least three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The facility will be available only once to every member during his or her lifetime. The rule applies to all those who together with their subscriber spouse have at least Rs 20,000 in their accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) If the member fails to get allotted a flat or in the event of the cancellation of an allotment, the amount so withdrawn has to be refunded in one lump sum within a period not exceeding fifteen days from the date of such cancellation or non-allotment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: How Much Fine You Have To Pay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is charging a fine on savings bank account customers not meeting the average monthly balance requirement. The amount of penalty for non-compliance with monthly average balance or MAB requirement is based on customer location - such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on Twitter while specifying various ranges according to which it will levy the charges. Charges levied for not maintaining the minimum balance depend upon how much the average balance in the account is below the agreed minimum, said SBI, which has&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. SBI also unveiled a new identity after merging its operations with six other banks recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is minimum balance requirement?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI savings bank account customers need to maintain a monthly average balance or MAB, which is the average of daily balances in the account during the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When do SBI savings bank account customers pay this charge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing to maintain the monthly balance as specified by the bank will attract a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What to do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A regular review of your account will help you to ensure the average monthly balance is maintained and avoid the minimal charges,&amp;rdquo; State Bank of India (SBI) said in another tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much fine do I need to pay?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking behemoth SBI has divided its customers into four categories: metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For metro customers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the monthly average balance of an SBI savings bank account holder comes out to be between Rs 2,500 and Rs 5,000 - a shortfall of less than 50 per cent, a charge of Rs 50 plus service tax will be levied, SBI said. For those with a shortfall of between 50 and 75 per cent (MAB from Rs 1,250 to Rs 2,500), a fee of Rs 75 plus service tax will be charged, and Rs 100 plus service tax for those keeping an average less than Rs 749 (more than 75 per cent shortfall).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-semi-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For semi-urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-rural-customers&#34;&gt;For rural customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-minimum.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The charges have been permitted by the Reserve Bank of India and are being levied by banks across the industry &amp;ldquo;and help us in providing better services to the customers&amp;rdquo;, SBI added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides savings bank accounts, SBI offers some other accounts wherein customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After its merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visa, Mastercard Threatened By Meteoric Rise of Aadhaar Pay &amp; UPI;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/visa-mastercard-threatened-meteoric-rise-aadhaar-pay-rs-6000-cr-market-danger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/visa-mastercard-threatened-meteoric-rise-aadhaar-pay-rs-6000-cr-market-danger/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Traditional payment processing and payment card companies, Visa and Mastercard, are feeling threatened now, and the reason is the exponential rise of Govt. backed digital payment platforms: Aadhaar Pay and UPI, which combined with BHIM App is giving these companies sleepless nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports emerging, representatives of these companies are trying to meet with senior Govt. officials, to make sure that they are not ignored in this cashless mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One senior Govt. official said, “Aadhaar Pay will be like India’s own solution to the cashless economy. Lots of players such as Visa, MasterCard are shaken up and there is a big war going on. But the government is very clear and wants to just bulldoze ahead with it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, Rs 6000 crore is at stake here, which is estimated to be Visa and Mastercard’s potential market size in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems that Govt is in no mood to assist private players in this highly competitive niche. Earlier, these companies were threatened with the rise of RuPay cards in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will Visa and Mastercard do now, to protect their territory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visa-mastercard-shaken-stirred-due-to-aadhaar-pay-upi-bhim&#34;&gt;Visa, Mastercard Shaken &amp;amp; Stirred Due To Aadhaar Pay, UPI &amp;amp; BHIM&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;payment-processing-companies-like-visa-and-mastercard-charge-1-on-every-transaction-which-is-happening-on-their-platform-and-currently-rs-6-lakh-crore-is-the-size-of-digital-transactions-as-estimated-by-the-govt&#34;&gt;Payment processing companies like Visa and Mastercard charge 1% on every transaction which is happening on their platform. And currently, Rs 6 lakh crore is the size of digital transactions, as estimated by the Govt.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the market size and potential of revenues for Visa and Mastercard is Rs 6000 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But due to the immense popularity of UPI-based transactions, and the recent launch of Aadhaar-based BHIM Appfor merchants have induced fear among these traditional payment processing companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the reason is that UPI and Aadhaar Pay doesn’t give any transactions fees to Visa or Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Govt. official said, “Card companies get 1% commission is which is around Rs 6,000 crore market for the likes of Visa, MasterCard and Rupay. Since UPI, BHIM and Aadhaar Pay don’t give this commission to them, they think it’s a big loss to them of the potential business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, these companies are feeling ignored, and out of the digital ecosystem of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports coming in, officials from these companies are making rounds of Niti Ayog office, and Finance Department for seeking more collaboration and partnerships. But Govt. is in no mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One official from Niti Aayog said, “We are not in the process of protecting the revenue of private players. The government will continue to provide alternate and cheaper options to end users to enable them to board our digital payment drive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note here, that earlier this month, Amitabh Kant, CEO of Niti Aayog had declared that in future, ATMs and Credit/Debit cards will disappear; and only mobile wallets and Aadhaar based payment mechanism will survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that Aadhaar Pay is supported by 27 banks and 715,000 merchants within weeks of its launch, 19 million people are already using BHIM App is not good news for Visa and Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visa-mastercard-puts-up-a-brave-face&#34;&gt;Visa, Mastercard Puts Up A Brave Face&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;meanwhile-both-mastercard-and-visa-officials-in-india-have-put-up-a-brave-face-and-have-assured-that-there-is-nothing-to-worry-despite-the-fact-that-aadhaar-already-covers-99-of-indian-population-40-banks-are-already-linked-with-aadhaar&#34;&gt;Meanwhile, both Mastercard and Visa officials in India have put up a brave face and have assured that there is nothing to worry, despite the fact that Aadhaar already covers 99% of Indian population, 40 banks are already linked with Aadhaar.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porush Singh, divisional president for MasterCard in South Asia said, “We don’t see it as a loss of business. There is enough opportunity for multiple players. Otherwise, you wouldn’t have had more banks in the ecosystem or wallet operators or payment solutions. We haven’t seen it yet (possible impact), but yes if the consumer finds it more relevant, then we will have to start evaluating.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Visa is devising plans to work with the Govt., in order to take the digital story forward. TR Ramachandran, group country manager, India and South Asia said, “We will continue working with the government, our clients and merchants to expand access to electronic payments in support of India’s drive to a less-cash society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to stay relevant in the market, both of these companies have launched innovative schemes, such as QR Code based payments, and contactless payment interface. Last year, talks were on regarding a massive collaboration to combine forces of Visa, Mastercard and BharatQR code into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Govt. estimates, cashless payment ecosystem will increase from Rs 6 lakh to Rs 90 lakh crore in few years. But, will Visa and Mastercard be relevant then?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can Now Pay Home Loan EMIs From Provident Fund Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-pay-home-loan-emis-from-provident-fund-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-pay-home-loan-emis-from-provident-fund-deposits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The withdrawal facility from the PF account will be available to only those PF members who fulfil the conditions prescribed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over four crore subscribers of the retirement fund body EPFO can now make down payment and pay EMIs from their EPF accounts to buy homes. The subscribers of the Employees Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) will be able to withdraw up to 90 per cent of their accumulations in their PF account for purchase of homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO has amended the scheme by inserting a new paragraph - 68 BD - to the Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Funds (EPF) Scheme, 1952, to enable a subscriber to make down payment to buy homes and pay EMIs through the EPF account, a senior official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official said, &amp;ldquo;Since the labour ministry has issued a notification for the purpose, the scheme stands amended.&amp;rdquo; Under the new provision, an EPF subscriber being a member of a co-operative or housing society with at least 10 members can withdraw up to 90 per cent from the fund for purchase of a dwelling house or flat or construction of a dwelling house and acquisition of site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also provides that monthly instalments for repayments of any outstanding payment or interest may also be paid from the amount to the government, housing agency, primary lending agency and banks concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the withdrawal facility from the PF account will be available to only those PF members who fulfil the conditions prescribed. One, the member applying under this window should have contributed to the fund for at least three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facility will be available only once to every member during his or her lifetime. The rule applies to all those who together with their subscriber spouse have at least Rs 20,000 in their accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विज्ञापन में कहा गया है कि आयकर विभाग के पास आपकी जमाओं की जानकारी है। विभाग ने कहा है कि इस योजना के तहत कालेधन की घोषणा करने वालों की गोपनीयता सुनिश्चित की जाएगी। विज्ञापन में स्पष्ट चेतावनी दी गई है कि योजना के तहत काले धन की जानकारी नहीं देने वालों को बेनाम कानून के तहत कठोर कार्रवाई का सामना करना होगा। यहां तक कि उनके नाम ईडी और सीबीआई जैसी केंद्रीय जांच एजेंसियों के साथ साझा कर दिए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा कि जो लोग प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना का लाभ लेते हुए अपनी काली कमाई उजागर नहीं करेंगे, उन्हें जमा राशि पर 137% तक जुर्माना लगाया जा सकता है। उनके मुताबिक, विभाग ऐसे डिफॉल्टरों पर नए बेनामी लेनदेन कानून के तहत कार्रवाई करने से भी नहीं हिचकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत काला धन की जानकारी देने वालों को 49.9 प्रतिशत टैक्स देना होगा, जबकि ऐसा नहीं कर इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न में इस धन का जिक्र करने वालों को टैक्स के साथ-साथ 77.25 प्रतिशत जुर्माना देना होगा। साथ ही, जो लोग योजना के तहत काले धन का खुलासा नहीं करते हैं और जांच आकलन में इसका पता चलता है तो उन्हें 83.25 प्रतिशत की दर से टैक्स वसूला जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो लोग योजना का फायदा लेते हुए काले धन की जानकारी सरकार को नहीं देते हैं और छापेमारी के दौरान छिपा हुआ धन सरेंडर करते हैं तो उन्हें 107.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना होगा। लेकिन, जो लोग छापेमारी में भी काला धन खुद निकाल कर नहीं देते हैं, उन्हें 137.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना पड़ सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बेनामी कानून में दोषियों को 7 साल तक की कैद से दंडित करने का प्रावधान है। इसके अलावा, उस पर आयकर कानून के तहत भी मुकदमा चल सकता है। साथ ही, उस पर बेनामी संपत्ति के उचित बाजार मूल्य का 25 प्रतिशत और दूसरे जुर्माने भी भरने होंगे। गौरतलब है कि सरकार ने नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना की घोषणा की थी। इस योजना के तहत कुल घोषित काले धन का एक चौथाई हिस्सा चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज के सरकार के पास जमा रखने की बाध्यता है। यह योजना पिछले साल 17 दिसंबर को शुरू हुई।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पीएम ने किया नई इनसेंटिव स्कीम का ऐलान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modi-announced-new-incentive-scheme-to-promote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modi-announced-new-incentive-scheme-to-promote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;डिजिधन योजना के 100 दिन पूरे होने पर पीएम मोदी ने कैशलेस स्कीम को बढ़ावा देने के लिए शुक्रवार को नई इनसेंटिव स्कीम का ऐलान किया। नागपुर में एक कार्यक्रम में पीएम ने बताया कि इस प्लान के तहत किसी भी शख्स को भीम ऐप के बारे में सिखाने पर जब वह तीन ट्रांजेक्शन कर लेगा, तो आपके खाते में 10 रुपये आ जाएंगे। इसी तरह यदि कोई व्यापारी अपनी दुकान पर निश्चित संख्या में ग्राहकों से भीम ऐप के जरिए ट्रांजेक्शन कराएगा तो उसके खाते में 25 रुपये आएंगे। पीएम मोदी ने बताया कि यह योजना अक्टूबर तक चलेगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2022 तक सबको घर&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पीएम मोदी ने इस दौरान 2022 तक देश में सभी लोगों को अपना घर देने की बात कही। पीएम ने कहा कि क्या ऐसा संभव नहीं है कि जब देश अपनी आजादी के 75 साल पूरे कर रहा हो तो देश के गरीब से गरीब आदमी के पास अपना घर हो। डॉ. आंबेडकर ने जो सपने देखें हैं, उन्हें पूरा करने का समय आ गया है। बड़ी संख्या में घर बन रहे हैं। गरीब को घर मिलेगा और घर बनाने वालों को रोजगार मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;देश के शहीदों के सपने को साकार करें&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2022 में देश को आजाद हुए 75 साल पूरे हो रहे हैं, आप कल्पना कीजिए की इससे पहले का समय कैसा रहा होगा। उस समय लोग देश के लिए जान की बाजी लगा देते थे और तिरंगा लहराने के लिए फांसी पर चढ़ जाते थे। लेकिन, उन लोगों को आजादी में सांस लेने का मौका नहीं मिला। हमें देश के लिए मरने का सौभाग्य भले ही न मिला हो, लेकिन जीने का मौका मिला है। क्या हम शहीदों के सपने को साकार नहीं कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>