<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2500 रुपये में हवाई सफर को हरी झंडी, जानें- इसकी 10 बड़ी बातें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने हिमाचल प्रदेश में सस्ती उड़ान की शुरुआत की. शिमला से दिल्ली के बीच की पहली उड़ान फ्लाइट को हरी झंडी दिखाने के अलावा पीएम मोदी ने दो और फ्लाइट्स को हरी झंडी दिखाई. इस अवसर पर मोदी ने कहा कि पहले एयरलाइंस में राजा महाराजा ही सफर करते थे. देश का गरीब हवाई चप्पल पहनता है, मैं चाहता था कि हवाई चप्पल वाला व्यक्ति हवाई जहाज में बैठे. आज वो बात सच हो रही है. मोदी ने कहा कि भारत में हवाई सेवा के विस्तार के लिए काफी अवसर है. उन्होंने कहा कि हवाई सर्कुलर रुट बनेगा तो ही सभी यात्री इसका लाभ उठा सकेंगे.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;उड़ान स्कीम की 10 बड़ी बातें-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत हवाई यात्रा के लिए 500 किलोमीटर या 1 घंटे के सफर की कीमत ज्यादा से ज्यादा 2,500 रुपया रखी गई है. इसी आधार पर अन्य रुटों का भी किराया निर्धारित किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 128 रूट्स और 5 ऑपरेटरों को उड़ान स्कीम में शामिल किया है. एयर इंडिया की क्षेत्रीय इकाई अलायंस एयर के तहत इन फ्लाइट्स को ऑपरेट किया जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 45 ऐसे एयरपोर्ट्स जो सेवा में नहीं हैं, उन्हें एयर नेटवर्क में कनेक्ट किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;छोटे शहर टियर-2 और टियर-3 के 13 एयरपोर्ट्स, जहां ज्यादा फ्लाइट्स नहीं चलती थीं वहां अब अधिक फ्लाइट्स होंगी. इन शहरों के लोगों को उड़ान स्कीम का फायदा मिल सकें.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान के तहत 5 ऑपरेटर्स का चयन हुआ है जो एयर इंडिया की सब्सिडियरी अलाइड सर्विसेज, स्पाइसजेट, एयर डेक्कन, एयर ओडिशा, टर्बो मेघा हैं.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;कानपुर से दिल्ली के लिए स्पाइसेजट की सेवा अगस्त में शुरू होगी, जबकि कानपुर से वाराणसी और दिल्ली के बीच सितम्बर में एयर ओडिशा के विमान उड़ान भरेंगे.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;अलायंस एय़र आगरा से जयपुर की उड़ान जून में शुरू करेगी, जबकि अगस्त में एय़र डेक्कन ने आगरा और दिल्ली के बीच उड़ान सेवा शुरु करने की तैयारी कर रखी है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;दिल्ली से शिमला के बीच अलायंस एय़र और एयर डेक्कन, दोनों ने ही अगले महीने सेवा शुरु करने का लक्ष्य रखा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;मध्य प्रदेश-छत्तीसगढ़ में अंबिकापुर से विलासपुर और बिलासपुर से रायपुर के बीच सितम्बर में एय़र ओडिशा अपनी सेवा शुरू करेगी. सितम्बर में ही जगदलपुर से रायपुर और विशाखापत्तनम के बीच सेवाएं शुरू हो जाएंगी.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 जून 2016 को शुरु हुई नैशनल सिविल एविएशन पॉलिसी का उड़ान अहम हिस्सा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar mandatory to avoid fake PAN cards: Government tells Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government today defended in the Supreme Court its decisionto make Aadhaar mandatory for issuing of PAN cards, saying it was done to curb the use of fake PAN cards across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi told a bench comprising Justices A K Sikri and Ashok Bhushan that the programme of PAN had become suspect as it could be faked while Aadhaar is a &amp;ldquo;secure and robust&amp;rdquo; system by which the identity of an individual cannot be faked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AG said that due to Aadhaar, government has saved over Rs 50,000 crore on the schemes to benefit the poor as well as the pension schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that around 10 lakh PAN cards have been cancelled, while out of the 113.7 crore Aadhaar cards issued, no case of duplication has been found by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that Aadhaar was an effective tool to check the menace of terror funding and circulation of black money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The idea behind Aadhaar is to make a secure and robust system by which the identity of a person cannot be faked,&amp;rdquo; the Attorney General told the court, which would continue hearing the arguments tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court is hearing three petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Section 139 AA of the Income Tax Act which was introduced through the latest budget and the Finance Act 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Section 139AA provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns and making an application for allotment of PAN number with effect from July 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior counsel Shyam Divan, representing the petitioners, had earlier argued that section 139AA was unconstitutional and was in &amp;ldquo;direct collision&amp;rdquo; with the Aadhaar Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had also contended that there was no question of forcing a person to give his consent for Aadhaar and this was an issue which &amp;ldquo;alters the relationship of Republic of India with its citizens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The petitioner had also argued that a law-abiding tax payer cannot be forced to give his Aadhaar number while filing income tax returns and this was like an &amp;ldquo;electronic leash&amp;rdquo; as government would be able to keep a tab on its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nowhere in the world there is such a biometric system which can track a person 24X7. They (government) are doing it even before the age of consent,&amp;rdquo; he had said during the arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had earlier put a poser as to why there was no objection from the lawmakers on the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for making PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rohatgi had also clarified that nowhere in section 139AA of IT Act, was it mentioned that it would be effective with retrospective effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had earlier told the apex court that fake PAN cards were being used to &amp;ldquo;divert funds&amp;rdquo; to shell companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Call Drop Problem: No More Tricks, Telecom Minister Warns Operators</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refusing to lower his guard on the issue of call drops, Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement, which leaves no room for any manipulation. &amp;ldquo;We are looking at every aspect of call drop. No trick will work in this case,&amp;rdquo; Sinha told Press Trust of India in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent report from the Department of Telecom (DoT) had said call drops had come down by seven per cent in three months between December 2016 to March 2017. The minister was responding to a query on whether the DoT has taken into account the prolonged use of &amp;lsquo;radio link timeout&amp;rsquo;, a technology that prevents disconnection of calls even if there is no or weak signal. Usually, in such cases, the customer ends up disconnecting the call without it showing up as a call drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not only the DoT report, but even Trai releases official report every quarter&amp;hellip; they clearly show that there is a significant reduction in call drop. However, it is a matter of continuous monitoring. Also, the manner in which BTS (Base Transceiver Stations) have been installed in last 8-9 months is a record,&amp;rdquo; Sinha noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom operators had informed the government that they installed more than 1.60 lakh additional BTS or mobile sites across the country between June 15 and December 31, 2016 and another 1.1 lakh additional mobile sites were committed by March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per a report of the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India, all operators have met call drop standard norms in the three months ended June and September. In October-December 2016, Trai found performance of Aircel below par for call drops in most circles. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha said the IVRS is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones. &amp;ldquo;The IVRS system makes an average 2600-2700 calls everyday. It is helping us in identifying those blind spots where there are regular call drops and telecom service providers are informed about it. They (telecom operators) are trying to sort it out,&amp;rdquo; Sinha added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister emphasised that the government is boosting telecom connectivity across the country, including optical fibre rollout in village panchayats, the North-East and even in Left wing extremism-affected areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have been successful in connecting 91,000 panchayats. In coming 15-20 days, we will meet our target of connecting one lakh panchayats. There was problem of equipment. It was an indigenous technology developed by (state-owned company) C-DOT. Vendors were not available. It took a lot of time in testing,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 50 thousand such equipment have been supplied by Tejas Networks, ITI Ltd and L&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I feel that from next week onwards (optical fibre) in as many as 300 villages per day will be lit. Thereafter, the pace will increase to 400 villages per day. Right now, it is around 100 villages,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar With Your PAN Card Just by Uploading a Scanned Proof</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Individuals struggling to link their Permanent Account Number with Aadhaar because of differently spelt names can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the tax department is planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for a One-Time Password (OTP), provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the linking of PAN with Aadhaar being made mandatory, individuals can log on to e-filing website of the income tax department or NSDL but the seeding cannot happen if the name is differently spelt in the two cards – like use of full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, government has allowed a simple uploading of a scanned copy of PAN on the Aadhaar website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had through amendment to tax proposals in the Finance Bill of the Budget for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-filing portal has already activated a functionality of linking PAN with Aadhaar. Over 1.08 crore assessees have already Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official said that linking of PAN with Aadhaar should not be cumbersome for people whose registered mobile number with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In case the taxpayer is unable to link PAN with Aadhaar because of discrepancy in name, we are advising them to log in to the Aadhaar website, request for a name change and upload a scanned copy of PAN card as supported proof. This is the simplest way to update name in Aadhaar and only the registered mobile number has to be functional,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This option will hold good for people who have given short forms of their name or in some cases there are some spelling errors in the name provided in Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in certain cases, there are people who have got married and changed their surname and updated the same while getting Aadhaar number, but it does not get reflected in PAN documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such and other name change cases, the tax department is planning to give the OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number and the tax department, on its part, would match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are also contemplating that when taxpayers with name discrepancy logs into the e-filing website for linkage, we will send OTP to the Aadhaar registered mobile number. The taxpayer can link PAN using the OTP. While generating the OTP, we will just check if the year of birth of the taxpayer in PAN card matches with the year given in the Aadhaar document,” the official added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want A New Jio SIM? Here&#39;s What You Pay To Get &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in getting a new Reliance Jio SIM and availing the &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer? Rs 408 is the minimum amount you need to spend. For Jio non-Prime and new users, the recharge amount is Rs 309 along with an additional Rs 99. Similarly, to get the Rs 509 plan, the amount needed will be Rs 608.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has extensively provided free data services with unlimited calls for several months and with the telecom operator starting paid services, one can expect the firm to provide the &amp;lsquo;most affordable&amp;rsquo; plans. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rs. 408 is the minimum amount needed to avail Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has provided free services with unlimited calls for last few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has been in the controversy for stretching its free trial run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-dhan.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your PAN card could be invalid without Aadhaar by December. Here’s what to do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar-by-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar-by-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Permanent account numbers (PAN) not linked to Aadhaar cards will likely become invalid after December 31, a government source said on Thursday, as the Centre pushes to widen the use of the 12-digit biometric identity project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permanent account numbers (PAN) not linked to Aadhaar cards will likely become invalid after December 31, a government source said on Thursday, as the Centre pushes to widen the use of the 12-digit biometric identity project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, all taxpayers need to have a PAN number to file income tax return but others, such as students outside the tax bracket, also use the card as a proof of identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government says many of these PAN cards are fraudulently obtained, a practice that can be checked by a unique identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official – who refused to be quoted as he isn’t authorised to talk to media – said the government had arrived at the tentative cutoff date of December 31 as it believed the Aadhaar enrollment process will be complete by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Considering that 98% of the adult population is Aadhaar card holders, a time frame till the end of the year is more than adequate for linking PAN with Aadhaar,” said State Bank of India group’s chief economic adviser Soumya Kanti Ghosh.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/pan-aadhaar.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-facility to link Aadhaar with PAN launched</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I-T Department asks people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched an e-facility to link Aadhaar with Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing IT returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department’s e-filing website &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; has created the link on its homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires the PAN, the Aadhaar number and the “exact name as given in the Aadhaar card”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After verification from the UIDAI [Unique Identification Authority of India], the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in the Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP [one time password] will be required,” the department said in an advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OTP would be sent on the registered mobile number and email of an individual, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department urged people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no need to login or be registered on the e-filing website. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of the Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a 10-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how you can link PAN with Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-you-can-link-pan-with-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-you-can-link-pan-with-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per the recent amendments made in income-tax laws, Aadhaar card and PAN must be linked, failing which PAN shall be cancelled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-order-to-link-pan-and-aadhaar-card-following-steps-are-to-be-followed&#34;&gt;In order to link PAN and Aadhaar card, following steps are to be followed:-&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a) First register on the Income tax e-filing portal (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://incometax&#34;&gt;http://incometax&lt;/a&gt; indiaefiling.gov.in”) if you are not already registered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b) Log-in to the e-filing portal of the income tax department by entering the log-in ID, password and date of birth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c) On logging in to the site, a pop up window will appear, prompting you to link your PAN card with Aadhaar card. If it doesn’t come, then click on “profile settings” and then “Link Aadhaar”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d) Details regarding name, date of birth and gender will already be mentioned as per the details submitted at the time of registration on the e-filing portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e) Verify the details on screen with the ones mentioned on your Aadhaar card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f) If the details match, enter your Aadhaar card number and click on the “Link Aadhaar” button. If the details do not match, it may pose a problem and the person is advised to get the details amended in his Aadhaar or PAN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;g) A pop-up message will display that your Aadhaar card has been successfully linked to your PAN card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>टैरिफ प्लान को लेकर जियो और एयरटेल में फिर टकराव</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/between-reliance-jio-and-airtel-offer-tariff-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/between-reliance-jio-and-airtel-offer-tariff-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;पिछले साल देश के टेलीकॉम मार्केट में प्रवेश करने वाली रिलायंस जियो और देश की सबसे बड़ी टेलिकॉम कंपनी भारती एयरटेल टैरिफ प्लान को लेकर फिर आमने-सामने आ गई हैं। जियो ने एयरटेल पर टैरिफ ऑर्डर का उल्लंघन करने और कुछ टैरिफ प्लान की मार्केटिंग भ्रामक तरीके से करने का आरोप लगयाा है और टेलिकॉम रेग्युलेटर से एयरटेल के खिलाफ कड़ी कार्रवाई करने और भारी पेनाल्टी लगाने को कहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हालांकि, एयरटेल ने इन आरोपों से इनकार करते हुए उल्टा जियो पर टेलीकॉम रेग्युलेटरी अथॉरिटी ऑफ इंडिया (TRAI) के निर्देशों का उल्लंघन करने का आरोप लगाया है। एयरटेल का कहना है कि जियो के ये आरोप नेटवर्क में कमियों सहित उसकी अपनी समस्याओं के लिए दूसरों पर दोष लगाने की पुरानी चाल का हिस्सा हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मुकेश अंबानी के मालिकाना हक वाली जियो ने TRAI को भारती एयरटेल के 293 और 449 रुपये के टैरिफ ऑफर्स के बारे में लेटर लिखकर शिकायत की है कि एयरटेल 4G हैंडसेट रखने वाले नए सब्सक्राइबर्स को ही अधिक बेनेफिट दे रही है और अन्यों को डेटा और वॉयस पर कम बेनेफिट दिए जा रहे हैं। जियो का कहना है कि यह 4G और अन्य सब्सक्राइबर्स के बीच भेदभाव है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जियो के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;इन प्रीपेड फर्स्ट रिचार्ज वाउचर्स के लिए एयरटेल की ओर से दिए गए विज्ञापनों में फ्री डेटा और वॉयस कॉल्स की भ्रामक तरीके से मार्केटिंग की जा रही है जो टेलीकम्युनिकेशन कानूनों का बड़ा उल्लंघन है।&amp;rsquo; जियो ने TRAI से एयरटेल के खिलाफ कड़ी कार्रवाई करने और पेनाल्टी लगाने की मांग की है। जियो ने TRAI से एयरटेल को तुरंत टैरिफ ऑर्डर और प्रमोशनल पैक को वापस लेने का निर्देश देने को कहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एयरटेल के प्रवक्ता ने इन आरोपों से इनकार करते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;टेलीकॉम, ई-कॉमर्स, इंश्योरेंस जैसे किसी भी बिजनेस में डिस्काउंट देना आम बात है और कंपनियां समय-समय पर इन्हें देती रहती हैं।&amp;rsquo; एयरटेल का कहना है कि जियो कई महीनों से फ्री सर्विसेज ऑफर कर रही है और अब यह ऐसे अन्य टेलfकॉम ऑपरेटर्स के खिलाफ उंगली उठा रही है जो अपने यूजर्स को बरकरार रखने के लिए डिस्काउंट की पेशकश कर रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंंपनी के प्रवक्ता ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;वास्तव में जियो TRAI के सभी दिशानिर्देशों का उल्लंघन कर रही है।&amp;rsquo; जियो की दलील है कि एयरटेल भेदभाव करने वाली तरीके से टैरिफ ऑफर कर रही है और उसने टैरिफ से जुड़े दो निर्देशों का उल्लंघन किया है। इनमें से एक ऑर्डर 16 सितंबर 2005 का है, जिसमें कहा गया है कि कस्टमर्स को भ्रमित करने वाले किसी भी टैरिफ प्लान की पेशकश, मार्केटिंग या विज्ञापन नहीं दिया जा सकता। दूसरा टैरिफ ऑर्डर 1999 का है, जिसके तहत एक टेलीकॉम कंपनी मनमाने तरीके से एक क्लास और क्लासिफिकेशन के सब्सक्राइबर्स के बीच भेदभाव नहीं कर सकती।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बिजली बिल: आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को जरूरी सेवाओं के लिए अनिवार्य किए जाने का मामला अभी सुप्रीम कोर्ट में लंबित है। इस बीच बिजली बिल के भुगतान को भी आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी शुरू कर दी गई है। केंद्र सरकार ने राज्यों से बिजली के बिलों का डिजिटल भुगतान आधार से जुड़े बैंक खातों के माध्यम से सुनिश्चित करने को कहा है। केंद्रीय ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा है कि बिजली बिल को आधार से जोड़ना ग्राहकों के लिए फायदेमंद साबित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;राज्यों और केंद्र शासित प्रदेशों के ऊर्जा और खदान मंत्रियों की कॉन्फ्रेंस में गोयल ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह जरूरी नहीं है, लेकिन सभी के हित में है क्योंकि अगर आप बिल का भुगतान डिजिटल माध्यम से करेंगे तो आपके पास यह ठीक-ठीक सबूत होगा कि आपने बिल का भुगतान किया है। यह पहल जनता को मदद करेगी और इस संबंध में कोशिश की जानी चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि इसका फैसला राज्यों को लेना है कि वे बिजली बिलों के भुगतान की प्रणाली को आधार से जुड़े खातों से जोड़ें या नहीं, लेकिन निश्चित तौर पर यह कहा जा सकता है कि यह ग्राहकों के हित में है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि सरकार ने हाल में आयकर रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को जरूरी कर दिया है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट में भी सरकार ने अपनी तरफ से साफ किया है कि पैन नंबर के जरिए होने वाले फ्रॉड को रोकने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य किया जाना जरूरी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गोयल ने यह भी कहा कि सरकार राज्यों को बिजली आवंटन के मसौदे को फिर तैयार कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम फॉर्म्युले पर काम कर रहे हैं। हम इस बात पर फिर से विचार कर रहे हैं कि हम इसे (पावर आवंटन पॉलिसी) किस तरह मजबूत बना सकते हैं। फिलहाल गाडगिल फॉर्म्युले पर बिजली का बंटवारा होता है। इसके तहत राज्यों के प्लान के लिए केंद्रीय मदद के लिए नियम और शर्तों को तय किया जाता है। उनका यह भी कहना था कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा बिजली उन को दी जाएगी, जो न्यूक्लियर प्लांट्स स्थापित करने को बढ़ावा देंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिजली के कमर्शल नुकसान में गिरावट और कॉस्ट की बेहतर कवरेज से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन कंपनियों में मामूली बेहतरी से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रिब्यूशन कंपनियों के ऑपरेशनल परफॉर्मेंस में सुधार हुआ है। पावर फाइनेंस कॉर्पोरेशन (PFC) की एक रिपोर्ट में यह बात कही गई है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>99 देशों पर साइबर अटैक: चपेट में ये देसी कंपनियां एवं सरकारी संस्थान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;दुनियाभर के 99 देशों पर हुए साइबर अटैक की चपेट में देश की कई कंपनियां भी आ गईं। रैनसमवेअर वानाक्राइ से प्रभावित हुईं कंपनियों में दो दक्षिण भारतीय बैंक, दिल्ली की दो मैन्युफैक्चरिंग कंपनियां, बहुराष्ट्रीय कंपनी (एमएनसी) की एक मैन्युफैक्चरिंग यूनिट, मुंबई की एक दिग्गज कंपनी और एक एफएमसीजी कंपनी के मुख्यालय शामिल हैं। इनके अलावा, आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के 100 से ज्यादा कंप्यूटर भी इस भयावह हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुरक्षा विशेषज्ञों का मानना है कि इस हमले से हुआ नुकसान और ज्यादा हो सकता है और प्रभावित कंपनियों की तादाद बढ़ सकती है। चूंकि यह हमला वीकेंड में (शुक्रवार को) हुआ है, इसलिए नुकसान का सही-सही आकलन सोमवार को ही किया जा सकता है जब सारे पर्सनल कंप्यूटर्स स्टार्ट किए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EY इंडिया में पाटर्नर (फ्रॉड इन्वेस्टिगेशन ऐंड डिस्प्यूट सर्विसेज) मुकुल श्रीवास्तव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;भारतीय कंपनियां हालिया हमले की चपेट में आई हैं। पिछले एक साल में रैनसमवेअर के मामले बहुत बढ़ गए हैं। अब साइबर क्रिमिनल्स बेहद टेक सेवी हो चुके हैं और हरेक रैनसमवेअर की अपनी यूनीक एन्क्रिप्टिंग मशीनें हैं। ये हमले लगातार बाधा पहुंचाने और फिरौती वसूलने के मकसद से हो रहे हैं। इसलिए संगठनों को ऐसे खतरों का सामना करने के लिए गंभीर उपाय करने होंगे। हम साइबरक्राइम और रैनसमवेअर के खिलाफ समाधान प्रक्रिया में कई देसी एवं वैश्विक कंपनियों के साथ काम कर रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जाल में ऐसे फंसाते हैं हैकर्स, रहें सावधान&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;शुक्रवार को मैलवेअर बड़ी तेजी से फैल गया और दुनियाभर की कंपनियों एवं सरकारी संगठनों में कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए। दरअसल, रैनसमवेअर के डाउनलोड होते ही सभी कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए और उनमें पड़े डेटा एन्क्रिप्ट कर लिए गए। हमलावर ने इन डेटा को रीस्टोर करने के लिए फिरौती की मांग की।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनियां ऐसे हमलों से निपटने के लिए देश के जिन साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर कर रही हैं, उनके मुताबिक ऐसे कई मामले सामने आए हैं जब भारतीय कंपनियों ने अपने प्रभावित कंप्यूटरों को दुबारा ऐक्सेस करने के एवज में फिरौती दी। यूके की नैशनल हेल्थ सर्विसेज (एनएसएस) जैसे वैश्विक संस्थान और रेनॉ, फेडेक्स एवं टेलिफोनिका जैसी कंपनियों ने हमले से प्रभावित होने की जानकारी दी, लेकिन देश की एक भी कंपनी ने नहीं बताया कि उनके कंप्यूटर हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के कंप्यूटरों पर साइबर हमले, फिरौती मांग रहे हैकर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक्सपर्ट्स का कहना है कि शुक्रवार को फैलाया गया मैलवेअर अमेरिका की नैशनल सिक्यॉरिटी एजेंसी का वही इटरनलब्लू टूल है जिसे अप्रैल महीने में द शैडो ब्रॉकर्स नाम के हैकर ग्रुप ने चुरा लिया था। दिग्गज साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी कंपनी अवास्ट ने कहा कि उसने रैनसमवेअर और इसके विभिन्न रूपों के 75,000 मामले देखे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी एक्सपर्ट ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इस हमला कुछ अलग है। इससे कोई एक बार इन्फेक्ट हो गया तो हो गया। इसे हटाने के लिए तीन से चार घंटे लगेंगे और पीसी रीबूट करना पड़ेगा। हालांकि, इसमें कोई नुकसान या कोई डेटा खत्म नहीं होता।&amp;rsquo; साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स के मुताबिक, भारतीय कंपनियों पर रैनसमवेअर अटैक्स के मामले में एक सिलिसला सा जुड़ रहा है। पिछले तीन महीनों में 25 से 30 ऐसे मामले सामने आ चुके हैं जब कंपनियां मैलवेअर का शिकार हुई हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>