<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>At SBI, You Don&#39;t Need To Maintain Minimum Balance In These Accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India is offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has said it is exempting its customers holding certain account types from maintenance of average monthly balance. Such accounts include small savings bank accounts, basic savings bank accounts and Jan Dhan accounts, or the accounts opened under the government&amp;rsquo;s financial inclusion scheme Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana or PMJDY. This was said in a tweet by SBI, which recently adopted a new brand identity after merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank. SBI had earlier decided to increase the minimum balance required for maintaining savings accounts from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, State Bank of India is also offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.
Account holders of the following types of accounts are exempt from requiring to maintain an average monthly balance: pic.twitter.com/61U8QNu7xR
— State Bank of India (@TheOfficialSBI) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement was increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros. In case of non-compliance, savings bank account holders will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs. 100 (in metro cities), as per the bank&amp;rsquo;s website. (Read more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other features SBI offers under these accounts, according to its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-savings-bank-account&#34;&gt;Small savings bank account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account has a maximum balance limit of Rs 50,000 and offers a rate of interest applicable to savings bank accounts. Account holders get an ATM-cum-Debit card, issued free of cost and without any annual maintenance charge, as per the SBI website. All credits in a financial year should not aggregate to more than Rs 1 lakh and Rs 10,000 in case of withdrawals and transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-savings-account&#34;&gt;Basic savings account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s basic savings account has no minimum balance or maximum balance limits. Holders of this account type &amp;ldquo;will not be eligible to open any other Savings Bank Account&amp;rdquo; at the bank. Such an account - in case the customer already holds one - will have to be closed within 30 days of opening the basic savings bank deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;corporate-salary-package&#34;&gt;Corporate salary package&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s salary account under corporate salary package offers many benefits to the employer and the employee alike. This account type reduces employer&amp;rsquo;s paperwork and salary administration cost. Employees get free internet banking and mobile banking services, among other features, as per the SBI website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Fixed Deposit Rates Lowest In Many Years. What Are Your Options?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fixed-deposit-rates-are-at-multi-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fixed-deposit-rates-are-at-multi-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the interest rates on bank fixed deposits are at multi-year lows. For example, State Bank of India is offering interest rate between 5.50 per cent and 6.90 per cent across different maturities on retail deposits (below Rs 1 crore), according to its website. Though the Reserve Bank of India has held its repo rate steady for some time, the 175-basis-point cut in its key lending rate since January 2015 has led to a broad decline in overall interest rate in the financial system. And the surge in deposits after demonetisation has forced banks to bring down interest rates on fixed deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;With bank fixed deposits at around 7 per cent and offering a post-tax return of 5-7 per cent depending on one&amp;rsquo;s tax slab, clearly for people in higher tax slab this will only help them match inflation and be at best a value protector,&amp;rdquo; says Manoj Nagpal, CEO, Outlook Asia Capital. But conservative investors should maintain their asset allocation based on their risk profile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some newer private banks offer higher rates, Mr Nagpal added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given that most asset classes that replace debt like gold, real estate etc have also not been giving returns in the short term, equity seems to be emerging as the only alternative. However investors should not over-allocate to equities just in the chase of higher returns. If being safe is the objective, then one should surely remember that equities are volatile by nature,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says small savings schemes like 5-year NSC (National Savings Certificates) offer a superior alternative for investors though with a slightly longer lock-in and could also be considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For senior citizens, Mr Nagpal recommends the Senior Citizen Savings Scheme and the to-be-launched Varishtha Pension Bima Yojana from LIC. The Varishtha Pension Bima Yojana 2017 is a pension scheme for senior citizens, which was earlier approved by the Union Cabinet. The Varishtha Pension Bima scheme 2017, which will be implemented through Life Insurance Corporation of India (LIC), assures pension based on a guaranteed rate of return of 8 per cent for 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among debt mutual funds, Mr Nagpal suggests accrual funds with a high quality of underlying portfolio for conservative investors. Given that the Reserve Bank of India has once again cautioned on the higher risks to inflation, conservative investors should reduce allocation to long duration debt funds, he added. Accrual funds mainly focus on earning interest income from the coupon offered by underlying bonds while debt funds based on duration try to gain from the upward or downward movement of interest rate in the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidya Bala, head of mutual fund research at Fundsindia.com, also says conservative investors should &amp;ldquo;actively considerer income accrual funds in mutual funds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If investors have a shorter time frame, Ms Bala suggests short-term and ultra short-term debt funds. &amp;ldquo;If they need regular income, they can use systematic withdrawal from short-term debt funds,&amp;rdquo; she adds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Besides generating superior returns, debt funds are more tax efficient&amp;rdquo; than bank fixed deposits, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Get Time Till June 30 To Obtain PAN From Account Holders</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department has given banks three more months till June 30 to obtain permanent account number (PAN) or Form-60 from all account holders as it looks to tighten the noose around evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the notification, the Income Tax Department said that in Income-Tax Rules 114B, in the fourth proviso, &amp;ldquo;for the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;28th day of February&amp;rsquo; the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;30th day of June&amp;rsquo; shall be substituted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 114B lists various transactions for which quoting PAN is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had in January asked banks, post offices and cooperative banks to document PAN or declaration of Form 60 received from account holders and maintain all records for transactions under Rule 114B of I-T Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had said that persons who have not quoted PAN, or did not furnish Form 60 at the time of opening account, will have to provide the same by February 28. Form 60 is a declaration form filed by an individual without PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the demonetisation move effective November 9, the tax department had asked banks and post offices to report to it all deposits above Rs 2.5 lakh in savings accounts and more than Rs 12.50 lakh in current accounts made between November 10 and December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cash deposits exceeding Rs 50,000 in a single day had to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an estimated Rs 15 lakh crore in junked currency notes coming back into the banking system post demonetisation, the tax department has started analysing the bank deposit trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-based payment modes work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government is planning to utilise the Aadhaar database to give shape to a digital future and utilise it for payments, and authentication of transactions is the key to its success. While Unified Payments Interface and BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) are processes for peer-to-peer transactions using smartphones, the government is promoting Aadhaar-enabled payment systems for the non-smartphone savvy. As per sources it is planning to launch Aadhaar Pay on April 14. ET looks into the different forms of Aadhaar payment modes being developed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems?
Payments that can be done with the help of au thentication and identi fication through the Aadhaar database is referred to as the Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems (AEPS). This is the new form of pay ment that is being pro moted by the govern ment to push for digital payments instead of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the major types of Aadhaar Enabled Payments?
The first type of payment is Aadhaar Bridge Payment System which is meant for direct bene fit transfer and subsidy payments from the gov ernment to the benefi ciaries. The second is AEPS which is used at the level of the business correspondent or `bank mitras’ where bank customers can use Aadhaar to access various services like cash withdrawal, account opening and fund transfer even without going to a bank branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is Aadhaar Pay wherein merchants can accept payments through Aadhaar identification of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we need Aadhaar Enabled payments?
These forms of payments are be ing promoted by the government specifically for the under privileged sections of the society and the rural poor who are not comfortable using cards or mobile wallets for payments.Instead of a mobile phone or a plastic card, in these forms of payments, the mode of authentication becomes the Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who runs the systems?
National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is the nodal authority for all Aadhaar-enabled payments in collaboration with banks. The payment company is trying to get as many banks to seed their customers’ accounts with their Aadhaar number so that payments can flow smoothly .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do the different forms of payments work?
Aahdaar Bridge Payment (ABPS):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant for recur ring payments done by the government to its customers for various subsidies as well as direct benefit transfer. Here the beneficiary is identified through an Aadhaar number, then NPCI manages an Aadhaar Mapper where the Aadhaar number is mapped to a specific bank account and the money flows to the connected bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-enabled-payment-aeps&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Payment (AEPS):&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the customer has to approach a business correspondent (BC), use his Aadhaar number and biometrics which the BC shares with NPCI, which checks the ID with UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India) to confirm the customer’s identity . It also checks the funds in the connected account and allows the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for merchant payments where the merchant will download the merchant payments app of his bank, authenticate the customer through his biometrics and Aadhaar number and initiate a pull transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Aadhaar With PAN Made Mandatory: How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the government insists that one&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar account and Permanent Account Number (PAN) should be linked by July 31 this year to pay income taxes, millions of Indians have faced issues with syncing the two accounts due to small differences in how their names are spelt. This problem can happen even if there are minor differences in how the name is recorded &amp;ndash; like the use of one&amp;rsquo;s full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar. Issues have also cropped up due to use of special characters in the initials and punctuation that often form a person&amp;rsquo;s name as Aadhaar doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize such characters but PAN does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, while one solution is to apply for a name correction in either Aadhaar or PAN card - both time consuming procedures - the government has stepped in to provide a simple solution for frustrated potential taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If an individual&amp;rsquo;s name on the Aadhaar does not match his/her name on the PAN card, the person can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A taxpayer can also log in to the Aadhaar website and request for a change in the name which will be verified using a one-time password on the phone number registered with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One-Time Passwords (OTP) will be used in cases where there are people who have gotten married and changed their surname. In such instances the tax department will give an OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number. The tax department, on its part, would&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department is also planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for OTP, provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told news agency Press Trust of India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.08 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN, but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people. As per statistics with the tax department, only six crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, You Can Get A PAN Or TAN Within A Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax department today said it has issued Permanent Account Number (PAN) within a day to 19,704 newly incorporated companies till March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Applicant would be benefited by having a digitally signed E-PAN card which they can submit as proof of identity to other agency electronically directly or by storing in the Digital Locker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; CBDT, the apex policy making body of the Income Tax department, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said that newly incorporated companies have also been issued Tax Deduction Account Number (TAN) simultaneously with PAN as the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) has tied up with the Ministry of Corporate Affairs (MCA) under which companies can submit a common application form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicant companies submit a common application form SPICe (INC 32) on MCA portal and once the data of incorporation is sent to CBDT by the MCA, PAN and TAN are issued immediately without any further intervention of the applicant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Certificate of Incorporation (COI) of newly incorporated companies includes the PAN in addition to the Corporate Identity Number (CIN). TAN is also allotted simultaneously and communicated to the company,&amp;rdquo; the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till March 31, 2017, 19,704 newly incorporated companies were allotted PAN in this manner. During March 2017, of the 10,894 newly incorporated companies, PAN was allotted within 4 hours in 95.63 per cent cases and within one day in all cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, TAN was allotted to all such companies within 4 hrs in 94.7 per cent cases and within 1 day in 99.73 per cent cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;CBDT&amp;rsquo;s initiative in starting of a business is expected to significantly improve the ranking of India in the Ease of Doing Business Study conducted by World Bank by reducing the number of processes of registration before various authorities under law, reducing the time taken for allotment of the registration number (CIN, PAN, TAN) and making the entire registration process for new companies much simpler,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बैंक, डाकघर से निकासी पर नकदी लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर दो लाख रुपये की नकद लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी। आयकर विभाग ने बुधवार को यह स्पष्ट किया। वित्त अधिनियम 2017 के तहत सरकार ने दो लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध लगा दिया है। इससे अधिक के लेनदेन में राशि प्राप्त करने वाले पर उतनी की राशि का जुर्माना लगाया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर कानून में नई शामिल धारा 269 एसटी के बारे में स्पष्टीकरण जारी करते हुए केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ने कहा कि यह प्रतिबंध बैंकों और डाकघरों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा। बयान में कहा गया है कि यह फैसला किया गया है कि नकद लेनदेन पर अंकुश बैंकों, सहकारी बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सीबीडीटी ने कहा कि इस बारे में आवश्यक अधिसूचना जारी की जाएगी। वित्त मंत्री अरण जेटली ने 2017-18 के बजट में 3 लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध का प्रस्ताव किया था। इस सीमा को वित्त विधेयक में संशोधन के जरिए दो लाख रुपये कर दिया गया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar. To further incentivize Indians to make the switch to using the BHIM app for transacting business, PM Modi also launched two schemes - cash back for merchants and referral bonus for individual owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Are Some Of The Key Features Of BHIM:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BHIM, short for Bharat Interface for Money, enables its users to transfer money using their mobile phone. The app created a world record by registering 10 million downloads in just four months since its launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. For every successful referral, users can earn Rs. 10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;PM Modi declared on Friday that incentives totalling Rs. 495 crore will be given to merchants for accepting payments through BHIM and existing users for referring it to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 2 MB in size, the latest version of the app enables payments through a fingerprint scanner by authenticating biometric details of the user against the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is available in 12 languages with three new languages (Marathi, Punjabi and Assamese) added in BHIM 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, now allows users to transfer money to contacts saved on the phone. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a cap of Rs. 10,000 for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present account holders of around 30 banks can transact on BHIM 1.3. The app will add Punjab And Maharashtra Co-Operative Bank Ltd, Punjab &amp;amp; Sind Bank and Jammu and Kashmir Bank soon, according to its Google Play Store page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the United Payments Interface (UPI), BHIM users do not need to download mobile applications of multiple banks to transact with different banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the government&amp;rsquo;s move on November 8 last year to demonetise Rs. 500 and Rs. 1,000 currency notes, the number of digital payment apps have logged a nearly 23-fold increase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed by National Payments Corporation of India, BHIM aims pave the way for making payments using fingerprints or iris scanners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Accounts To Be Blocked If Not Self-Certified By April 30. What To Do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions, without which the accounts would be blocked, the income tax department said. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Account holders are informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till 30.4.2017,A/Cs would be blocked : pic.twitter.com/YICvRHqfPm
— Income Tax India (@IncomeTaxIndia) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Investors are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed, the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014-August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016, extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The financial institutions were advised to continue to work on completing the required due diligence, including obtaining self-certifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them. (With agency inputs)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucky Grahak: Student Wins Rs. 1 Crore For Paying Smartphone EMI Through Rupay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lucky-grahak-student-wins-rs-1-crore-for-paying-smartphone-emi-through-rupay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lucky-grahak-student-wins-rs-1-crore-for-paying-smartphone-emi-through-rupay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s schemes to incentivize digital payments &amp;ndash; Lucky Grahak Yojana and DigiDhan Vyapar Yojana &amp;ndash; has awarded 16 lakh winners till now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An EMI payment of Rs. 1,590 for a newly bought mobile phone has earned a mega lottery of Rs. 1 crore for 20 year-old engineering student Shradha Mohan Mengshette under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak Yojana. Mengshette, a second year student of Electrical Engineering from Latur district in Maharashtra, received the cash prize from Prime Minister Narendra Modi at a function in Nagpur today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She won the mega prize for making a transaction of Rs. 1,590 through her Rupay card online.
The second prize of Rs. 50 lakh under the Lucky Grahak Yojana, an official statement said, was won by Hardik Kumar from Khambhat in Gujarat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 29-year-old is a primary school teacher who used his Rupay card for making a transaction of Rs. 1,100. Under the Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana category for merchants, the first prize of Rs. 50 lakh was won by Anand Ananthapadmanabhan for accepting a payment of Rs. 300 at GRT Jewellers in Tambaram, Tamil Nadu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second prize of Rs. 25 lakh was won by Ragini Rajendra Uttekar, owner of a small beauty parlour in Thane, Maharashtra, the statement said. She accepted a payment of Rs. 510 which won her the amount, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s two schemes to incentivize digital payments &amp;ndash; Lucky Grahak Yojana and DigiDhan Vyapar Yojana &amp;ndash; was launched on December 25 last year. According to the statement, Rs. 258 crore of prize money was won by 16 lakh winners, including customers and merchants belonging to different corners of the country and from varied walks of life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operation Clean Money 60,000 individuals including 1,300 ‘high-risk’ cases </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-phase-ii-60k-individuals-including-1300-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-phase-ii-60k-individuals-including-1300-high/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over 60,000 individuals, including 1,300 high-risk persons, will be under the scanner of the income tax department in the second phase of ‘Operation Clean Money’. The second phase of the black money detection programme, which was first started by the tax department post demonetisation, will investigate into claims of excessive cash sales during the demonetisation that did not match the previous profiles of the tax assessees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“More than 60,000 persons, including 1,300 high-risk persons, have been identified for investigation into claims of excessive cash sales during the demonetisation period. More than 6,000 transactions of high value property purchase and 6,600 cases of outward remittances shall be subjected to detailed investigations. All the cases where no response is received shall also be subjected to detailed enquiries,” the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) said in a statement.
The tax department has identified the high risk persons through detailed investigations using advanced data analytics, including integration of data sources, relationship clustering and fund tracking, CBDT said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The high risk categories identified include businesses claiming cash sales as the source of cash deposits that has been found to be in excess of their past profile or industry norms, large cash deposits made by government or PSU employees, persons who have undertaken high value purchases, persons who have used shell entities for layering of funds and where no responses were received, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CBDT, the policy-making body of the department, said it has detected undisclosed income over Rs 9,334 crore between the period of November 9, 2016 till February 28 this year. On November 8 last year, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had announced the decision to scrap high-denomination currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the first phase of the ‘Operation Clean Money’, launched on January 31 this year, the department had sent communications to around 18 lakh individuals asking them to respond online to specific queries relating to cash deposits made during November 9-December 30, the time period given for deposit of scrapped currency notes in banks. Out of the 17.92 lakh persons to whom the queries were sent by the tax department under the first phase of operation Clean Money, 9.46 lakh persons responded have responded to the department as per pre-defined parameters of sources of the cash deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Online queries were raised in 35000 cases and on-line verification was completed in more than 7800 cases. It has been decided to close the verification in cases where explanation of source of cash was found to be justified. In cases where the cash deposit has been declared under Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), the verifications would also be closed,” the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post-demonetisation period saw a rise in number of searches and surveys conducted by the tax department. More than 2,362 search, seizure and survey actions were conducted by the tax department during November 9 last year to February 28, leading to seizure of valuables worth more than Rs 818 crore, which includes cash of Rs 622 crore and detection of undisclosed income of more than Rs 9,334 crore. Over 400 cases have been referred by the tax department to the Enforcement Directorate and the CBI. Surveys have been conducted in more than 3400 cases by assessment units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had also launched a compliance window for assesees to come clean with their undisclosed cash and deposits made after demonetisation through the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY). The three-month long PMGKY scheme received lukewarm response, with only Rs 2,300 crore flowing into government coffers as taxes and penalty by declarants in the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,334 cr undisclosed income detected&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CBDT said it has detected undisclosed income over Rs 9,334 crore between the period of November 9, 2016 till February 28 this year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High risk categories include businesses claiming cash sales as the source of cash deposits found to be in excess of their past profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>