<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper published under Creative Commons is titled ‘Information Security Practices of Aadhaar (or lack thereof): A documentation of public availability of Aadhaar Numbers with sensitive personal financial information’ and was released on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha and Kodali looked at databases on four government portals — National Social Assistance Programme, National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme, Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh and Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We chose major government programmes that use Aadhaar for payments and banking transactions. We found sensitive and personal data and information accessible on these portals,” the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaked through portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Based on the numbers available on the websites, estimated number of Aadhaar numbers leaked through these 4 portals could be around 130-135 million and the number of bank account numbers leaked at around 100 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these numbers are only from two major government programmes of pensions and rural employment schemes, other major schemes, that have also used Aadhaar for DBT, could have leaked PII similarly due to lack of information security practices,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They fear that data of over 23 crore beneficiaries under DBT of LPG subsidies could be leaked also. Identity theft and financial fraud “risks increase multifold in India…,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar payments unsafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case a financial fraud takes place through Aadhaar enabled Payment System (AePS), the consumer may not be able to assert his claims for compensation due to the terms and conditions around liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These terms force the consumer to take liabilities onto oneself than the payment provider….. Regulations and standards around Aadhaar are at a very early and nascent stage causing (an) increase in financial risk for both consumers and banks to venture into AePS,” they added. The authors also pulled up UIDAI for their inability in providing strong legislation against such leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaky govt portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Social Assistance Programme&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII available – Access to Aadhaar no., name, bank account number, account frozen status  94,32,605&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bank accounts linked with Aadhaar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14,98,919  post office accounts linked with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though total Aadhaar number is 1,56,42,083, not all are linked to bank accounts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NREGA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII Details available: Job card no., Aadhaar number, bank/postal account number, no. of days worked, registration no., account frozen status&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;78,74,315  post office accounts of individual workers seeded with Aadhaar numbers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8,24,22,161 bank accounts of individual workers with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10,96,41,502 total number of Aadhaar numbers stored by portal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other websites&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to media, the senior Congress leader said there was a need to upgrade all post offices in the country with latest infrastructure since there was &amp;ldquo;vast availability of post offices&amp;hellip;one can find it in every nook and corner of the country, even in remote villages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said passports could be applied from post offices shortly, adding around 86 post offices have already started work in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation, including eight MPs, paid obeisance at the sanctum sanctorum of the Golden Temple here. They also visited the historic Jallianwala Bagh, where they paid tributes to the martyrs who had sacrificed their lives for the freedom of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation thereafter visited the Integrated Check Post (ICP) Attari/Wagah border where they held a meeting with the Custom and BSF officials in order to have a &amp;ldquo;first hand information with regard to the required infrastructure at ICP, import/export activities with Pakistan and problems faced by the officials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members also witnessed the evening beating retreat ceremony at Wagah border.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been reported that a new ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; is spreading widely, the RBI advisory to the banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wannacry encrypts the files on infected Windows system and spreads by exploiting vulnerabilities, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI also asked all banks to put in place a software update at ATMs to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate malware attack last year, 3.2 lakh debit cards were compromised in the country. Data of the users who transacted from ATM machines of Hitachi were compromised during May, June and July last year. The Hitachi ATMs deployed by many White Label ATM players and Yes Bank were impacted by the malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, ATMs or automated teller machines are highly vulnerable to such malware attacks as they currently run on old version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, making a software security patch update a necessary exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a total of 2.2 lakh ATMs in India, of which many old ones run on Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, the ransomware has hit systems in more than 150 countries, including Russia and the UK, in one of the most widespread cyber attacks in history. It infected computers running on older versions of Microsoft operating systems like XP, locking access to files on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cyber criminals have demanded a fee of about $300 in crypto-currencies like Bitcoin for unlocking the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has introduced a security patch to tackle the situation, and consumers across the globe have been advised to download the solution at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CERT-In on Monday said it has not received any formal report of cyber attack on India&amp;rsquo;s vital networks by the crippling global ransomware, &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) had said on Sunday that a few systems of the Police Department in Andhra Pradesh were impacted and that the state government has been informed to follow the advisory by the CERT-In.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the Maharashtra Police department said it was partially hit by the ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the alert, the Gujarat government began equipping its state computer systems with anti-virus software and upgrading its Microsoft operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the advisory issued by CERT-In, the ransomware infects other computers on the same network and is also spreading through malicious attachments to e-mails. Security firms have suggested that users immediately disconnect the infected device from the local network to contain the spread of infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, major companies including telecommunications firm Telefonica have been infected. The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avoid Queue At SBI Branches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is offering a virtual queue ticket or &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo; service through its newly-launched app No Queue, which enables customers to avail select banking services at its select branches without having to stand in queues. SBI customers &amp;ldquo;can book a virtual token&amp;hellip;and skip the queue,&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI said on Twitter. SBI&amp;rsquo;s No Queue app was launched by the bank&amp;rsquo;s chairperson Arundhati Bhattacharya in March this year. The mobile-based virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores. &amp;ldquo;The Application is designed to save customers&amp;rsquo; valuable time, avoid queue for Banking services and aims to provide the customers with a better customer service experience,&amp;rdquo; SBI had said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user can select a minimum of one and maximum five services in virtual ticket using No queueapp, as per the SBI website. Here are few other things to know about the No Queue app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers a variety of services under the &amp;lsquo;no queue&amp;rsquo; facility. Some of these include cheque deposit, cash deposit/withdrawal, demand draft, NEFT/RTGS and loan account opening/maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The No Queue app empowers those interested in SBI&amp;rsquo;s banking services to efficiently book a virtual token without being physically present in the branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app provides &amp;ldquo;real time status notification of your position in the queue&amp;rdquo;, as per its description on Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers can generate an e-token before being physically present in the branch. This way, he or she avoids waiting in a queue and saves time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app conveys the estimated waiting time, the number of customers ahead in the queue and the distance to the branch from the point of booking, SBI has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers will be updated about their position in the queue through alerts, according to the app&amp;rsquo;s description on Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-book-e-token&#34;&gt;Who can book &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals - SBI and non-SBI customers - registered on the No Queue app installed on their devices can avail this facility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-use&#34;&gt;How to use&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user can register on the No Queue app by entering basic information such as name and mobile number to start using the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a virtual ticket is generated through the No Queue app, the customer will receive a notification about his or her position in the queue. A button that says &amp;lsquo;Activate&amp;rsquo; will be available on the app when the customer reaches the fifth position in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reaching the branch, a customer activating the queue ticket will be &amp;ldquo;serviced immediately, thus avoiding waiting time at the Branch&amp;rdquo;, the press release added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;can-i-reschedule-my-visit&#34;&gt;Can I reschedule my visit?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After booking a virtual ticket, customers also have the facility of rescheduling or renewing the ticket in case they are running late. The rescheduling option will be available only until when the customer is within the first five positions in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department has launched a massive hunt for black money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The massive hunt for undeclared cash launched across the country post demonetisation has revealed that these was either converted into gold or routed through shell companies to make it legal tender, IT sleuths have told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income Tax officials said black money holders avoided the bank-deposit route because they wanted to conceal their identities and somehow had &amp;ldquo;managed to get many jewellers&amp;rdquo; to convert their unaudited cash into gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They bought gold and jewellery from jewellers across the cities on November 8 (the night Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced the demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 currency notes from midnight) and, thereafter. Jewellers camouflaged the identities of the actual buyers and offered split bills,&amp;rdquo; an Income Tax official, who was part of the investigations, told IANS on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to him, jewellers saw in demonetisation an opportunity to ramp up their sales and thought &amp;ldquo;they could get away&amp;rdquo; by showing these amounts as sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jewellers offered a platform to convert unreported cash into gold,&amp;rdquo; the official said, adding that split bills were below the value of Rs 2 lakh, the threshold above which buyers have to provide the permanent account number (PAN) issued by the income tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The buyers&amp;rsquo; lists provided by the jewellers were false. After verification, it emerged that many of the buyers were financially weak and not in a position to spend such huge amounts shown in the invoices,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen tried to find an answer to a common question: How did jewellers meet the huge spurt in demand following the announcement of demonetisation, particularly after the festival season?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We found many of these sales were booked as advance collection for future sales. Due to preceding sales during Dhanteras and Diwali, jewellers had a stock crunch and they delivered gold later,&amp;rdquo; another IT official told IANS, asking not to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen said they have stumbled upon records which suggested many shops &amp;ndash; as many as 90 per cent across cities &amp;ndash; were closed at the time of the demonetisation announcement and sales at the day&amp;rsquo;s closing had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Still, we found sales were registered in the accounting system either on November 8 or a date prior to that after the closing sales were reported. These sales were manipulated,&amp;rdquo; another IT official said, also requesting anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sankar Sen, Chairman and MD, Senco Gold Ltd, which was one of the jewellery houses under the I-T department scanner, told IANS: &amp;ldquo;We keep records of all buyers on the basis of the names and contacts provided by the customers. We cooperated with officials and provided all the documents, including the CCTV footage that we had.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is difficult for jewellers to verify whether the customers have provided a legitimate identity or not, particularly when the sale value is less than Rs 2 lakh,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hunt for black money by the IT officials picked up after November 29 as they waited for some time to collect information from the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) or other agencies about the movement of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked how taxmen identified jewellers, an official told IANS: &amp;ldquo;The first set of information showed that jewellers deposited huge amounts of money into banks. Then, we went after jewellers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IT sleuths were able to identify legitimate transactions, easily. &amp;ldquo;We also had given options to the jewellers to disclose the name of actual buyers or declare that the amount is your money,&amp;rdquo; the official said, pointing out that such moves proved successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many actual buyers and jewellers contributed to the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY), an amnesty scheme to declare unreported wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a robust and quick information-sharing system among state and central agencies been in place, the hunt for black money would have been more effective, the officials lamented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A compilation of unique features found in transactions post-demonetisation across states is expected soon,&amp;rdquo; an IT official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Union Finance Ministry, the CBDT has detected undisclosed income of over Rs 9,334 crore between November 9, 2016, and February 28 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under Operation Clean Money (OCM), more than 60,000 persons, including 1,300 high-risk persons, have been identified for investigation into claims of excessive cash sales after demonetisation was announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to officials, shell companies provided a strong support system for black money after demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials found dummy directors of these companies included a cancer patient who signed documents for a Rs 10,000 monthly fee or charges of Rs 200 for every signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials said reporting of cash seizures was relatively less in Kolkata because of the existence of the shell companies as an established channel to stash ill-gotten money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining how active the channel was, the official said: &amp;ldquo;Many cash handlers with whom we interacted told us that the money does not stay for more than half-an-hour at a particular point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shell companies were also used as instruments to buy bullion. &amp;ldquo;We found invoices for bullion sales were generated against such companies while actual beneficiaries received the bullion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Luxurious Maharajas&#39; Express Offers Free Seats On New Routes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Railways and IRCTC have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian Railways’ super-luxury trains, which cater to various tourist circuits throughout India have long been in demand with travellers with deep pockets looking to explore the cities, towns, villages and regional areas, while travelling in style along the world’s fourth largest rail network. Expanding the network of its super-luxury trains, the Indian Railways and Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation Ltd (IRCTC) have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of their promotional campaign, the Railways are offering one free ticket on the booking of first adult on twin sharing at full cost, for the newly-introduced Maharajas’ Express circuits during monsoon period of June-July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, for a ‘Deluxe Cabin’, you can get a chance to upgrade it to a ‘Junior Suite’ by paying 50 per cent of the difference in tariff, the Railways said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the new Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express routes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two new routes have been named as ‘Southern Sojourn’ and ‘Southern Jewels’ which will cover prominent destinations in West and South India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ‘Southern Sojourn’ will cover Goa, Hampi, Mysore, Ernakulam, Kumarakom and Trivandrum. And, the ‘Southern Jewels’ will cover Chettinad, Mahabalipuram, Mysore, Hampi and Goa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both the journeys will take about 8 Days and 7 Nights and IRCTC will organize visits to monuments and sight-seeing at each destination under these trips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regular trip of ‘Southern Sojourn’ will start from Mumbai on September 9 and ‘Southern Jewels’ will start from Trivandrum on September 16.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guests on the Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express shall also have an opportunity to enjoy traditional cultural performances at Cochin, visit a Coir Factory and enjoy a cruise with lunch at Alleppey, savour traditional Chettinad Cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trains will be equipped with two restaurants, two bars, lounge, LCD TVs, direct dial phone, internet, individual temperature controls and in suite bathroom as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 23 coach long Maharajas’ Express carries only 88 guests in one trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maharajas’ Express commenced its operations in 2010, and is the recipient of the coveted Leading Luxury Train of the World Award for the last five years in a row since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indian Railways also operates a number of other luxury trains such as Fairy Queen, Heritage on Wheels, The Indian Maharaja and Splendor of South&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The booking and other details for the super-luxury trains can either be done online on the official website of Maharajas’ Express or on the official website of IRCTC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why SBI Cut Its Fixed Deposit Rates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-sbi-cut-its-fixed-deposit-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-sbi-cut-its-fixed-deposit-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;According to SBI&amp;rsquo;s new rates, for two to less than three-year deposits, the bank will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank, cut its term deposit rates in select maturities from April 29, 2017. The government&amp;rsquo;s move in November last year to withdraw Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 bank notes from the financial system led to a &amp;ldquo;huge inflow of current account and savings bank deposits&amp;rdquo;, State Bank of India (SBI) chief financial officer Anshula Kant told NDTV Profit, while explaining the rationale behind her bank&amp;rsquo;s decision to lower its deposit rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Post-demonetisation gradually some of the deposits have started to go out of the system and roughly for us about 40 per cent of the deposits have gone out from the bank. We still have 60 per cent. That is one thing,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were not very keen to increase the MCLR (marginal cost of funds-based lending rates) at this point. As cost of deposit goes up, it has an upward pressure on the MCLR as well. To maintain MCLR for our borrower customers where it is, we have tweaked the rates in certain longer deposit buckets.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marginal cost of funds-based rate is a new benchmark which banks are using for pricing their home and car loans. They add a margin above their MCLR to price retail loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to SBI&amp;rsquo;s new rates, for two to less than three-year deposits, the bank will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has not changed its marginal cost of funds-based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She further said that &amp;ldquo;there has been a slight uptick in the cost of deposits&amp;rdquo; since its mega merger last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the merger, SBI entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मोदी की &#39;कड़वी दवाइयों&#39; के लिए रहें तैयार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/result-get-ready-for-big-economic-reforms-by-modi-governemnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/result-get-ready-for-big-economic-reforms-by-modi-governemnt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;यूपी में बीजेपी की प्रचंड जीत से प्रभावित मोदी सरकार सुधारों की दिशा में अपने कदम और तेज कर सकती है। विदेशी निवेश के मामले में सरकार और उदारवादी रुख अपना सकती है वहीं, भारत में उत्पादन बढ़ाना, कर्ज में डूबे बैंकों का उबारना, सोशल सेक्टर में डिलिवरी सिस्टम को मजबूत करना सरकार के सुधारवादी अजेंडा में शामिल रह सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यूपी में बीजेपी अपनी &amp;lsquo;ट्रिपल सेंचुरी&amp;rsquo; को नोटबंदी पर जनता के ग्रीन सिग्नल के रूप में देख रही है। दो सालों से &amp;lsquo;सबसे बड़ा&amp;rsquo; आर्थिक सुधार माने जाने वाले जीएसटी को पास कराने की कोशिशों में लगी बीजेपी अब अन्य सुधारों की ओर तेज कदम बढ़ाएगी जिससे जीएसटी को लागू करने में भी फायदा होगा। वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने विधानसभा चुनावों में बीजेपी के प्रदर्शन पर ट्वीट किया, &amp;lsquo;विधानसभा चुनावों में बीजेपी की बेहतरीन जीत से फिर यह साबित होता है कि जनता पीएम मोदी के विकास के साथ हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;इन-स-ध-र-म-आएग-त-ज&#34;&gt;इन सुधारों में आएगी तेजी&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बीजेपी के प्रदर्शन का असर संसद में जीएसटी के पास होने को आसान बनाने में मदद करेगा। लागू होने की कई डेटलाइन मिस कर चुके जीएसटी को सरकार 1 जुलाई से लागू करना चाहती है। श्रम सुधारों पर सरकार पहले से ही काम कर रही है। इसके अलावा सरकार विदेशी निवेश के और रास्ते खोल सकती है और रिटेल में FDI की अनुमति भी दे सकती है। सरकार के सामने सबसे बड़ी समस्या बैंकिंग सेक्टर को ट्रैक पर लाने का है। एनपीए से जूझ रहे बैंकों को बचाने के लिए सरकार बड़े कदम उठा सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;आन-व-ल-स-ध-र&#34;&gt;आने वाले सुधार&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी एक ऐसा कदम था जिसका अंदाजा भी लगाना आसान नहीं था। सरकार आने वाले समय में इन्फ्रास्ट्रकचर पर जोर देते हुए भूमि सुधार की दिशा में आगे बढ़ सकती है। भूमि अधिग्रहण बिल को पास कराने की असफल कोशिशों के बाद सरकार अब कोई और रास्ता निकाल सकती है। डायरेक्ट बेनिफिट ट्रांसफर की सफलता को और डिजिटल इंडिया के सपने के साथ सरकरा सब्सिडी के क्षेत्र में भी बड़े सुधार ला सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;न-टब-द-पर-फ-सल&#34;&gt;नोटबंदी पर फैसला?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक्सपर्ट्स का मानना है कि चुनावी नतीजे ने साफ कर दिया कि वह नोटबंदी पर क्या राय रखते हैं। नोटंबदी जिसमें 86 प्रतिशत करंसी को अमान्य घोषित कर दिया गया हो वह एक साहसी कदम था। जनता पर नोटबंदी का प्रभाव जानने के बाद सरकार, बड़े और कठोर कदम उठाने में अब हिचकेगी नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जानें, क्रेडिट कार्ड के बेहद &#39;खास&#39; फायदे</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड रखना यानी उधार की जिंदगी जीना, अरे यह हम नहीं कह रहे बल्कि आमतौर पर इस तरह की बातें हमारे आसपास के लोग बोलते दिख जाते हैं। अगर आप भी ऐसा ही सोचते हैं तो अगले कुछ मिनट्स में आपके यह सोच बदलने वाली है। जी हां, आज हम आपको बता रहे हैं क्रेडिट कार्ड रखने के कुछ बेहद खास फायदे&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-ब-क&#34;&gt;कैश बैक&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कई क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां कुछ खास ब्रैंड्स के साथ 10 से 20 प्रतिशत तक का कैश बैक ऑफर देती हैं। यानी कैशलेश पेमेंट भी करिए और बचत भी पाइए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;र-व-र-ड-प-इ-ट&#34;&gt;रिवॉर्ड पॉइंट&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कैैश बैक के अलावा सभी क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां प्रत्येक ट्रांजैक्शन के वेट के अनुसार पॉइंट्स देती हैं। पॉइंट्स आपके खाते में जुड़ते जाते हैं और बाद में आप इन्हें रिडीम कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-र-ड-ट-ह-स-ट-र&#34;&gt;क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड के प्रयोग से आप अपनी क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री अपने साथ रख सकते हैं। यानि आपको पता रहता है कि आपने कब कहां कितना पैसा खर्च किया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-क-झ-झट-नह&#34;&gt;कैश का झंझट नहीं&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड का सबसे बड़ा फायदा यह है कि आपको इस बात की चिंता करने की नहीं जरूरत होती है कि बैंक में बैलेंस है या नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;emi-क-व-कल-प&#34;&gt;EMI का विकल्प&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अगर आपका मन कोई बड़ी चीज खरीदने का है, लेकिन पैसे नहीं, तो क्रेडिट कार्ड से खरीद कर आप उस पैसे को ईएमआई यानि किश्तों में बदल सकते हैं। कई बार क्रेडिट कार्ड जीरो प्रतिशत ब्याज पर ईएमआई देते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भविष्य में सभी कार्डों की जगह ले लेगा आधार कार्ड: अरुण जेटली</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लोकसभा ने बुधवार को वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली की ओर से पेश वित्त विधेयक को चर्चा के बाद पारित कर दिया। चर्चा के दौरान अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि आने वाले दिनों में आधार ही एकमात्र कार्ड होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि भविष्य में यह वोटर आईडी कार्ड और पैन कार्ड जैसे दस्तावेजों की जगह ले लेगा। इन सभी के मुकाबले एक आधार कार्ड ही किसी भी व्यक्ति की पहचान के लिए काफी होगा। लोकसभा में एक सांसद की ओर से पूछा गया था कि आधार कार्ड जारी किए जाने के बाद भी कई कार्डों की व्यवस्था क्यों लागू है। इसके जवाब में जेटली ने यह बात कही। उन्होंने कहा कि आने वाले वक्त में आधार ही व्यक्तिगत पहचान और पते के लिए पुख्ता सबूत होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाए जाने के सवाल पर जेटली ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;तमाम लोगों को कई पैन नंबर इस्तेमाल करते हुए पाया गया है। इसलिए सरकार ने इस व्यवस्था को लागू करने का फैसला लिया है।&amp;rsquo; जेटली ने एक सवाल के जवाब में कहा, &amp;lsquo;आज 98 फीसदी नागरिकों के पास आधार कार्ड है। टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के दौरान व्यक्ति आधार नंबर दे सकता है या यह बता सकता है कि उसने आवेदन कर दिया है, लेकिन टैक्स चोरी की अनुमति नहीं दी जा सकती है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा लोगों को टैक्स की व्यवस्था से जोड़ने की जरूरत है। इसीलिए सरकार ने इस साल टैक्स स्लैब को नीचे लाने का प्रयास किया है। चर्चा के दौरान जेटली ने नोटबंदी को सही फैसला करार देते हुए इकॉनमिस्ट मार्टिन वॉल्फ के एक आर्टिकल का उदाहरण देते हुए कहा कि उन्होंने इसकी सराहना की है। जेटली ने लेख का हवाला देते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;इससे सरकार को ब्लैक मनी पर टैक्स लगाने का मौका मिला है। बड़े पैमाने पर कैश रखने वाले लोगों के लिए रिस्क पैदा हुआ है। इसके अलावा क्रिमिनल्स के पास जमा संपत्ति सरकार के पास आई है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भारत के हाइटेक टैलंट को नजरअंदाज कर चीन ने की गलती: चीनी मीडिया</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/china-made-mistake-of-ignoring-indias-high-tech-talent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/china-made-mistake-of-ignoring-indias-high-tech-talent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;चीन ने भारत के विज्ञान एवं तकनीकी एक्सपर्ट्स को नजरअंदाज कर गलती की है। यह बात किसी भारतीय नेता या कारोबारी ने नहीं कही है, बल्कि खुद चीन मीडिया ने कही है। चीन के सरकारी अखबार ग्लोबल टाइम्स ने लिखा है कि कम्युनिस्ट देश को भारत के हाइटेक टैलंट को अपनी ओर आकर्षित करना चाहिए ताकि वह आविष्कारों के मामले में अपनी क्षमता को बरकरार रख सके। ग्लोबल टाइम्स में लिखे लेख के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;चीन ने भारतीय टैलंट को नजरअंदाज कर गलती की है। इसकी बजाय हम अमेरिका और यूरोप से आने वाले टैलंट पर निर्भर रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चीनी अखबार ने लिखा, &amp;lsquo;चीन ने भारत के साइंस ऐंड टेक्नॉलजी से जुड़े टैलंट को अपनी ओर आकर्षित करने के लिए बहुत प्रयास नहीं किए हैं।&amp;rsquo; अखबार के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;बीते कुछ सालों में चीन ने तकनीकी जगत से जुड़ी नौकरियां का बूम देखा है। इसके चलते चीन दुनिया भर के देशों के लिए रिसर्च ऐंड डिवेलपमेंट सेंटर के तौर पर उभरा है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हालांकि अब हाईटेक फर्म्स चीन की बजाय भारत की ओर देखने लगी हैं। इसकी वजह भारत में कम कीमत पर श्रम की उपलब्धता है। अखबार के मुताबिक भारत के हाइटेक टैलंट को आकर्षित करके हम अपनी इनोवेशन की क्षमता को बनाए रख सकते हैं। अमेरिकी स्थित सॉफ्टवेयर फर्म सीए टेक्नॉलजीज ने अपनी 300 लोगों की टीम को चीन जाने से रोक दिया था, जबकि भारत में 2,000 टेक्निकल प्रफेशनल्स की टीम का गठन किया था। अखबार ने कहा कि बीते कुछ सालों में भारत ने चीन के मुकाबले यंग टैलंट पूल के तौर पर बड़ी जगह बनाई है। अखबार ने कहा कि चीन हाईटेक निवेशकों के प्रति आकर्षण खत्म होने को सहन नहीं कर सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>हर स्कीम के लिए अनिवार्य न हो आधार: SC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-cant-be-mandatory-for-social-welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-cant-be-mandatory-for-social-welfare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने सोमवार को कहा कि सरकार की समाज कल्याण योजनाओं का लाभ उठाने के लिए आधार बायोमीट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन को अनिवार्य नहीं बनाया जा सकता। देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत ने कहा कि सरकार चाहे तो दूसरे क्षेत्रों में आधार को अनिवार्य बना सकती है, जो समाज कल्याण के कार्यक्रमों से नहीं जुड़े हैं। बैंक खाता खोलना ऐसा एक काम हो सकता है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट की जिस बेंच ने यह बात कही, उसमें चीफ जस्टिस जे एस खेहर, जस्टिस डी वाई चंद्रचूड़ और जस्टिस संजय किशन कौल शामिल थे। सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने पहले भी आधार को सभी समाज कल्याण योजनाओं के लिए लाभुकों की पहचान के लिए आधार को अकेला मानक बनाने के खिलाफ आदेश दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चीफ जस्टिस ने कहा कि आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने का मामला महत्वपूर्ण है और इसकी सुनवाई सात जजों की संवैधानिक बेंच के सामने होनी चाहिए, लेकिन उन्होंने तुरंत यह बेंच बनाने में असमर्थता जताई। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह बेंच बनाई जाएगी।&amp;rsquo; अभी सात सदस्यों वाली बेंच के लिए जज ढूंढना मुश्किल हो सकता है। इस महीने के अंत तक तीन जजों की नियुक्ति होने की उम्मीद है। चीफ जस्टिस ने उनके जॉइन करने के बाद अहम मामलों पर विचार करने के लिए संवैधानिक बेंच बनाने का वादा किया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुप्रीम कोर्ट के सोमवार के आदेश का मतलब यह है कि सरकार कल्याणकारी योजनाओं के लाभुकों की पहचान के लिए आधार का इस्तेमाल कर सकती है, लेकिन इसके न होने पर वह लाभ देने से इनकार नहीं कर सकती। सार्वजनिक वितरण प्रणाली या एलपीजी सब्सिडी कल्याणकारी योजना के दायरे में आते हैं। मान लीजिए कि किसी शख्स के पास आधार नंबर नहीं है तो वह इन फायदों को हासिल करने के लिए पहचान के दूसरे सबूतों का इस्तेमाल कर सकता है। देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत पहले भी यह बात कह चुकी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वकील श्याम दीवान ने कई पक्षों की तरफ से आधार बेस्ड आइडेंटिफिकेशन को अनिवार्य बनाने का विरोध किया था। उन्होंने कहा था कि इससे किसी शख्स की प्राइवेसी के लिए खतरा पैदा हो सकता है। इसके बाद सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने मामले पर त्वरित सुनवाई का निर्णय लिया। आधार का इस्तेमाल अभी पेंशन स्कीम के लाभुकों की पहचान, प्रविडेंट फंड और प्रधानमंत्री जन धन योजना के लिए किया जा रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 जुलाई से इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए भी इसे अनिवार्य बनाया गया है। आधार को स्कॉलरशिप स्कीम्स और स्कूलों में मिड डे मील स्कीम्स से भी जोड़ा जा रहा है। श्याम दीवान ने यह आरोप भी लगाया था कि केंद्र सरकार आधार के मामले में देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत के कई आदेशों की अवहेलना कर रही है। इस मामले में उन्होंने ड्राइविंग लाइसेंस के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने जैसे मामलों का जिक्र किया। उन्होंने कहा था कि इस तरह से सरकार अदालत की अवमानना कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>