<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.
A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26 Chartered Accountants Under Watch In Crackdown On Shell Companies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26-chartered-accountants-under-watch-in-crackdown-on-shell-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26-chartered-accountants-under-watch-in-crackdown-on-shell-companies/</guid>
      <description>At least 26 chartered accountants have come under the scanner of the ICAI for allegedly helping shell companies, a senior official said. The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (ICAI) is the regulator for accountancy professionals and can initiate disciplinary action against erring members.
&amp;ldquo;The role of (around) 26 chartered accountants with respect to their alleged links with shell companies are being looked into by the institute,&amp;rdquo; ICAI President Nilesh Shivji Vikamsey told PTI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 smart tips which can help you save more &amp; become rich</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t want to become rich? However, getting wealthy isn’t that easy. It begins with determined consciousness to get wealthy. We all know that to become rich you need to spend less than what you earn. That is because the less you spend, the more you will be able to save. You should save and invest what you have into investments (assets) that appreciate over time. Apart from these, here we are taking a look at a few really easy and ‘anyone can do it’ strategies or DIY tips that can make you a crorepati:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt makes Aadhaar mandatory for students</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</guid>
      <description>The move is aimed at checking the drop-out rate and ensuring quality education
The Yogi Adityanath government in Uttar Pradesh has made Aadhaar Card mandatory for students from Class 1 to 8 in government schools. The Basic Education department has been entrusted with this task involving over 1.75 crore students.
The Basic Education Minister Anupama Jaiswal said that directions have been issued in this regard. “The main aim of the government is to link their Aadhaar Card number with different welfare schemes, including mid-day meal, run by the state for the welfare of primary students,” she said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Of Rs 200 Note To Fill The Missing Middle, Says SBI Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launch-of-rs-200-note-to-fill-the-missing-middle-says-sbi-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launch-of-rs-200-note-to-fill-the-missing-middle-says-sbi-report/</guid>
      <description>Introduction of Rs 200 note will fill in the &amp;ldquo;missing middle&amp;rdquo; even as the new currency in circulation (CIC) has already reached 84 per cent of the pre demonetisation level, says a report. Cash with banks, a CIC component, has however witnessed a decline over November 2016 level, said the State Bank of India Ecowrap report.
The data for June 23, 2017 shows cash in hand with banks declining to 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.
The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either 567678 or 56161.
It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Aadhaar With PAN Made Mandatory: How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>As the government insists that one&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar account and Permanent Account Number (PAN) should be linked by July 31 this year to pay income taxes, millions of Indians have faced issues with syncing the two accounts due to small differences in how their names are spelt. This problem can happen even if there are minor differences in how the name is recorded &amp;ndash; like the use of one&amp;rsquo;s full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.
Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI- Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fee-on-imps-transactions-under-rs-1000-removed-by-sbi/</guid>
      <description>HomeIndustry Banking financeFee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI Fee on IMPS transactions under Rs 1000 removed by SBI
State Bank of India (SBI) on Wednesday waived charges on all money transfers of less than Rs 1,000 made through the Immediate Payment System (IMPS) channel, in a bid “to promote small ticket size transactions”.
By: FE Bureau | Mumbai | Updated: July 13, 2017 5:02 AM imps, sbi, state bank of india, sbi news, sbi latest news, imps transaction fee SBI’s decision to waive charges on some IMPS transactions may have been the result of more than a nudge from the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सभी बैंकों को आधार एनरॉलमेंट और अपडेट फसिलटी देनी होगी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-banks-to-facilitate-aadhaar-enrolment-update-facility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-banks-to-facilitate-aadhaar-enrolment-update-facility/</guid>
      <description>एचडीएफसी, आईसीआईसीआई, कोटक, ऐक्सिस जैसे प्राइवेट सेक्टर के बैंकों के साथ उन सारे बैंकों को अपने ग्राहकों को आधार एनरॉलमेंट और अपडेट फसिलटी देनी होगी, जिन्हें सरकार ने इस साल 31 दिसंबर तक अपने बैंक अकाउंट्स से आधार को लिंक करने के लिए कहा है। केंद्र ने कहा है कि अगर बैंक खातों को आधार से लिंक नहीं किया जाता तो संचालित नहीं किए जा सकेंगे।
इससे पहले 1 जुलाई के नोटिफिकेशन में सरकार ने वेरिफिकेशन के बाद सभी बैंक खातों को आधार से लिंक करने का आदेश दिया था। इस नोटिफिकेशन के लिए प्रिवेंशन ऑफ मनी लॉन्ड्रिंग (पीएमएलए) में संशोधन भी किया गया था। अधिकतर बैंक आधार और बैंक खाते को लिंक करने की ऑनलाइन फसिलटी दे रहे हैं, लेकिन माना जा रहा है कि कई लोगों के पास अब तक आधार नहीं है या उनका पता या फोटोग्राफ, उनके बैंक रिकॉर्ड के ऐसे डेटा से मेल ना खाते हों। ऐसे में बैंक आधार से उनके खाते को लिंक करने की रिक्वेस्ट ठुकरा सकते हैं। यह गंभीर मसला है क्योंकि जो लोग बैंक खातों को आधार से लिंक नहीं करेंगे, वो 31 दिसंबर के बाद कोई ट्रांजैक्शन नहीं कर पाएंगे।</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>