<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2500 रुपये में हवाई सफर को हरी झंडी, जानें- इसकी 10 बड़ी बातें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-big-things-about-udaan-flights-of-2500-rupees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने हिमाचल प्रदेश में सस्ती उड़ान की शुरुआत की. शिमला से दिल्ली के बीच की पहली उड़ान फ्लाइट को हरी झंडी दिखाने के अलावा पीएम मोदी ने दो और फ्लाइट्स को हरी झंडी दिखाई. इस अवसर पर मोदी ने कहा कि पहले एयरलाइंस में राजा महाराजा ही सफर करते थे. देश का गरीब हवाई चप्पल पहनता है, मैं चाहता था कि हवाई चप्पल वाला व्यक्ति हवाई जहाज में बैठे. आज वो बात सच हो रही है. मोदी ने कहा कि भारत में हवाई सेवा के विस्तार के लिए काफी अवसर है. उन्होंने कहा कि हवाई सर्कुलर रुट बनेगा तो ही सभी यात्री इसका लाभ उठा सकेंगे.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;उड़ान स्कीम की 10 बड़ी बातें-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत हवाई यात्रा के लिए 500 किलोमीटर या 1 घंटे के सफर की कीमत ज्यादा से ज्यादा 2,500 रुपया रखी गई है. इसी आधार पर अन्य रुटों का भी किराया निर्धारित किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 128 रूट्स और 5 ऑपरेटरों को उड़ान स्कीम में शामिल किया है. एयर इंडिया की क्षेत्रीय इकाई अलायंस एयर के तहत इन फ्लाइट्स को ऑपरेट किया जाएगा.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान स्कीम के तहत 45 ऐसे एयरपोर्ट्स जो सेवा में नहीं हैं, उन्हें एयर नेटवर्क में कनेक्ट किया गया है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;छोटे शहर टियर-2 और टियर-3 के 13 एयरपोर्ट्स, जहां ज्यादा फ्लाइट्स नहीं चलती थीं वहां अब अधिक फ्लाइट्स होंगी. इन शहरों के लोगों को उड़ान स्कीम का फायदा मिल सकें.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;उड़ान के तहत 5 ऑपरेटर्स का चयन हुआ है जो एयर इंडिया की सब्सिडियरी अलाइड सर्विसेज, स्पाइसजेट, एयर डेक्कन, एयर ओडिशा, टर्बो मेघा हैं.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;कानपुर से दिल्ली के लिए स्पाइसेजट की सेवा अगस्त में शुरू होगी, जबकि कानपुर से वाराणसी और दिल्ली के बीच सितम्बर में एयर ओडिशा के विमान उड़ान भरेंगे.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;अलायंस एय़र आगरा से जयपुर की उड़ान जून में शुरू करेगी, जबकि अगस्त में एय़र डेक्कन ने आगरा और दिल्ली के बीच उड़ान सेवा शुरु करने की तैयारी कर रखी है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;दिल्ली से शिमला के बीच अलायंस एय़र और एयर डेक्कन, दोनों ने ही अगले महीने सेवा शुरु करने का लक्ष्य रखा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;मध्य प्रदेश-छत्तीसगढ़ में अंबिकापुर से विलासपुर और बिलासपुर से रायपुर के बीच सितम्बर में एय़र ओडिशा अपनी सेवा शुरू करेगी. सितम्बर में ही जगदलपुर से रायपुर और विशाखापत्तनम के बीच सेवाएं शुरू हो जाएंगी.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 जून 2016 को शुरु हुई नैशनल सिविल एविएशन पॉलिसी का उड़ान अहम हिस्सा है.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 जून से ही आधार अनिवार्य</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tells-supreme-court-aadhar-deadline-not-to-be-extended/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tells-supreme-court-aadhar-deadline-not-to-be-extended/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट में साफ कर दिया है कि 30 जून से आधार को अनिवार्य कर दिया जाएगा। केंद्र सरकार ने शुक्रवार को कोर्ट को बताया कि अलग-अलग समाज कल्याण योजनाओं का लाभ लेने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने संबंधी 30 जून की समय सीमा आगे नहीं बढ़ाई जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जस्टिस ए एम खानविलकर और जस्टिस नवीन सिन्हा की पीठ के सामने अटॉर्नी जनरल मुकुल रोहतगी ने कहा कि वेलफेयर स्कीम के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने का मकसद यही है कि इसका लाभ उन लोगों तक नहीं पहुंचे जो अस्तित्व में ही नहीं हैं, जैसा कि सार्वजनिक वितरण प्रणाली जैसी योजनाओं के मामले में पाया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने केंद्र सरकार की विभिन्न अधिसूचनाओं को चुनौती देने और अंतरिम राहत का अनुरोध किए जाने पर भी आपत्ति की और कहा कि इस मामले को 5 सदस्यीय संविधान पीठ के सामने सुनवाई के लिए सूचीबद्ध किया जाना चाहिए। रोहतगी ने कहा कि इससे पहले भी इसी तरह की अंतरिम राहत के लिए याचिकाएं दायर की गईं थीं और वे मामले सुप्रीम कोर्ट के पास लंबित हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पीठ ने कहा कि अंतरिम राहत के लिए दायर सभी याचिकाओं पर वह एक साथ सुनवाई करेगी ताकि दोहराव से बचा जा सके। कोर्ट ने इसके साथ ही इस मामले को 27 जून के लिए सूचीबद्ध करने का निर्देश दिया। सुप्रीम कोर्ट जब इस सवाल पर विचार कर रही थी कि क्या इन मामलों को गर्मी की छुट्टियों के दौरान ही सुनवाई के लिए सूचीबद्ध किया जाए, तभी एक याचिकाकर्ता की ओर से वरिष्ठ अधिवक्ता श्याम दीवान ने कहा कि इसमें शीघ्र सुनवाइ की आवश्यकता है। यदि इस पर 30 जून से पहले सुनवाई नहीं होती है तो फिर केंद्र को इसकी समय सीमा आगे बढ़ानी चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस पर रोहतगी ने कहा कि इसका कोई सवाल ही नहीं उठता। कोर्ट ने अंतरिम राहत का अनुरोध करने वाली सभी याचिकाओं को 27 जून को सूचीबद्ध करने का आदेश दिया है। साथ ही सरकार को तीन सप्ताह के अंदर जवाबी हलफनामा दाखिल करने का आदेश दिया है। शुक्रवार को सुनवाई शुरू होते ही अटॉर्नी जनरल ने कहा कि इसी तरह की अंतरिम राहत के अनुरोध के साथ करीब 6 महीने पहले याचिकाएं दायर की थीं। इन याचिकाओं को मुख्य मामले के साथ जोड़ दिया गया था, जिन पर संविधान पीठ सुनवाई करेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 30 Aadhaar Deadline Not To Be Extended, Government Tells Top Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of the Unique Identity programme Aadhaar are pending in the Supreme Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is &amp;ldquo;no question&amp;rdquo; of extending the June 30 deadline for making Aadhaar mandatory for availing benefits of various social welfare schemes, the centre today told the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General Mukul Rohatgi told the top court that the idea behind making Aadhaar mandatory for welfare schemes was that the benefit should not go to &amp;ldquo;ghosts&amp;rdquo; as was noticed in schemes like the public distribution system (PDS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also raised preliminary objection to the plea seeking interim relief and challenging various notifications issued by the centre and told a bench, comprising Justices A M Khanwilkar and Navin Sinha, that this matter should be listed for hearing before a five-judge constitution bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Rohatgi said that earlier, some pleas seeking identical interim reliefs were also filed and those matters were pending before the top court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bench said it would be appropriate to hear all these pleas seeking interim relief together to &amp;ldquo;avoid multiplicity&amp;rdquo; and fixed the matter for hearing on June 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the bench was considering whether to list the matter for hearing during the summer vacation, senior advocate Shyam Divan, appearing for the petitioner, said there was urgency involved in it and if the matter was not heard before June 30, &amp;ldquo;the other way was if they (centre) extend the deadline&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;There is no question of that,&amp;rdquo; Mr Rohatgi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Aadhaar are pending in the top court and would be heard by a five-judge constitution bench, which is yet to be set up by the Chief Justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Supreme Court had passed a slew of orders asking the government and its agencies not to make Aadhaar mandatory for extending benefits of their welfare schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top court, however, had allowed the Centre to seek Aadhaar card voluntarily from citizens for extending benefits of schemes like LPG subsidy, Jan Dhan scheme and Public Distribution System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said.
The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report also says that both prepaid and postpaid customers will have to be re-verified by the telecom companies. It can be done by SMSes. Telecom companies will send verification codes to its customers.
Aadhaar may become the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future, he added.
Recently, Supreme Court has also asked the Central government to link all mobile numbers to Aadhaar within a period of one year. The Apex Court urged Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led government to frame policies regarding rules and regulations to ensure the fact that the SIMs (Subscriber
Identification Module) are not misused by anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apex court has said that its mandatory for all mobile subscribers including pre-paid SIM card users to link their SIM cards to Aadhaar cards. The Court asked the Centre to devise a plan for pre-paid SIM card users so that each person will have to fill and deposit a form whenever he or she recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh. In the present scenario where bank interest rates are on a falling trend, financial planners say that equity mutual funds are one of the best instruments to accumulate long-term savings through systematic investment plan (SIP). Gains from equity mutual funds after a year are tax-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, fund selection is one of the most difficult things to do for a retail investor as it needs lot of research. Financial planners say diversified equity funds are the best to invest through SIP for long term. Here are some funds which have generates over 20 per cent CAGR return in past 20 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Equity Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on January 1, 1995, it is one of the oldest and best performing funds in India. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.95 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 23.56 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This fund has generated a CAGR return of 23.68 per cent since its inception. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998 would have helped you accumulate a corpus of Rs. 2.12 crore by April 1, 2017 implying 17.66 times return in 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;Franklin India Prima Fund:&lt;/em&gt; It is one of the flagship fund of Franklin Templeton India. Since its inception in December 1993, it has generated a CAGR return of 21.04 per cent till now. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 2.38 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 25.11 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Vision Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on October 8, 1995, it has generated a CAGR return of 19.92 per cent till now. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998, would have become Rs. 1.46 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Top 200 Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This flagship fund of HDFC Mutual Fund has generated a CAGR return of 20.88 per cent since its inception in September 1996. If you would have started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.43 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With falling return on bank fixed deposits, equity mutual funds are witnessing increased investment from retail investors now. Equity and equity-linked schemes have seen inflows of more than Rs. 70,000 crore in last financial year according to Association of Mutual Funds in India data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how you can link PAN with Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-you-can-link-pan-with-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-you-can-link-pan-with-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per the recent amendments made in income-tax laws, Aadhaar card and PAN must be linked, failing which PAN shall be cancelled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-order-to-link-pan-and-aadhaar-card-following-steps-are-to-be-followed&#34;&gt;In order to link PAN and Aadhaar card, following steps are to be followed:-&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a) First register on the Income tax e-filing portal (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://incometax&#34;&gt;http://incometax&lt;/a&gt; indiaefiling.gov.in”) if you are not already registered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b) Log-in to the e-filing portal of the income tax department by entering the log-in ID, password and date of birth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c) On logging in to the site, a pop up window will appear, prompting you to link your PAN card with Aadhaar card. If it doesn’t come, then click on “profile settings” and then “Link Aadhaar”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d) Details regarding name, date of birth and gender will already be mentioned as per the details submitted at the time of registration on the e-filing portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e) Verify the details on screen with the ones mentioned on your Aadhaar card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f) If the details match, enter your Aadhaar card number and click on the “Link Aadhaar” button. If the details do not match, it may pose a problem and the person is advised to get the details amended in his Aadhaar or PAN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;g) A pop-up message will display that your Aadhaar card has been successfully linked to your PAN card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एक करोड़ बैंक खातों का डेटा लीक, 20 पैसे प्रति कस्टमर के हिसाब से बेचा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/20-paise-each-bank-data-of-1-crore-indians-was/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/20-paise-each-bank-data-of-1-crore-indians-was/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;देश के एक करोड़ लोगों के बैंक खातों की जानकारी &amp;lsquo;ऑन सेल&amp;rsquo; है। बैंक अकाउंट्स से जुड़ी सभी जानकारी सेल वाले रेट से भी सस्ते में उपलब्ध है। पुलिस जांच में पता चला है कि 10 या 20 पैसे में आपके बैंक खाते से जुड़ी जानकारियां बेची जा रही हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दिल्ली के ग्रेटर कैलाश में रहने वाली एक 80 साल की महिला के केस की जांच करते हुए पुलिस को यह जानकारी मिली है। महिला के क्रेडिट कार्ड से 1.46 लाख रुपए उड़ा लिए गए थे। इसी केस की जांच करते हुए पुलिस ने बैंक अकाउंट्स की जानकारी बेचने वाले मॉड्यूल का पर्दाफाश किया। पुलिस को पता चला कि इस मॉड्यूल में बैंक में काम करने वालों और कॉल सेंटर्स से जानकारी निकलवाई जाती थी और फिर उसे बेच दिया जाता था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दक्षिण-पूर्वी दिल्ली के डीसीपी ने दावा किया कि मॉड्यूल के मास्टरमाइंड को गिरफ्तार करने के बाद पुलिस ने एक करोड़ लोगों के बैंक अकाउंट्स की जानकारी रिकवर की। सस्ते रेट में बेची जाने वाली जानकारी में आपका कार्ड नंबर, कार्ड होल्डर का नाम, जन्मतिथि और मोबाइल नंबर है। यह सारा डेटा कई कैटिगरीज में बंटा हुआ है, जिसका कुल साइज 20 जीबी से ज्यादा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गिरफ्तार किया गए पूरन गुप्ता ने बताया कि वह डेटा बल्क में बेचता था। 50 हजार लोगों का डेटा बेचने के वह 10 से 20 हजार लेता था। बताया जा रहा है कि आरोपी ने डेटा मुंबई के एक सप्लायर से खरीदा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डेटा खरीदने वाले इसकी मदद से बैंक के कर्मचारी बन लोगों को फोन करते थे और उनको CVV नंबर और OTP शेयर करने को कहते थे। जिसकी मदद से वह बैंक अकाउंट से पैसे निकालने में सफल हो जाते थे। किसी भी बैंक अकाउंट होल्डर की सारी डिटेल्स होने के कारण लोग इस जाल में फंस जाते थे। इसके अलावा वह रिवॉर्ड पॉइंट्स, कार्ड ब्लॉक जैसे बहाने बना कर पासवर्ड निकलवा लेते थे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हमारे सहयोगी अखबार टाइम्स ऑफ इंडिया ने 6 अप्रैल को रिपोर्ट किया था कि एक 80 साल की महिला के साथ ठगी के आरोप में आशीष कुमार को पुलिस ने गिरफ्तार किया है। आशीष इससे पहले बैंक और वित्तीय संस्थानों सेल्स एग्जिक्यूटिव के पद पर काम कर चुका है। उसने 2013 में हेल्थ इंश्योरेंस बेचने के लिए टेलिकॉलिंग का काम शुरू किया था।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विज्ञापन में कहा गया है कि आयकर विभाग के पास आपकी जमाओं की जानकारी है। विभाग ने कहा है कि इस योजना के तहत कालेधन की घोषणा करने वालों की गोपनीयता सुनिश्चित की जाएगी। विज्ञापन में स्पष्ट चेतावनी दी गई है कि योजना के तहत काले धन की जानकारी नहीं देने वालों को बेनाम कानून के तहत कठोर कार्रवाई का सामना करना होगा। यहां तक कि उनके नाम ईडी और सीबीआई जैसी केंद्रीय जांच एजेंसियों के साथ साझा कर दिए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा कि जो लोग प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना का लाभ लेते हुए अपनी काली कमाई उजागर नहीं करेंगे, उन्हें जमा राशि पर 137% तक जुर्माना लगाया जा सकता है। उनके मुताबिक, विभाग ऐसे डिफॉल्टरों पर नए बेनामी लेनदेन कानून के तहत कार्रवाई करने से भी नहीं हिचकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत काला धन की जानकारी देने वालों को 49.9 प्रतिशत टैक्स देना होगा, जबकि ऐसा नहीं कर इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न में इस धन का जिक्र करने वालों को टैक्स के साथ-साथ 77.25 प्रतिशत जुर्माना देना होगा। साथ ही, जो लोग योजना के तहत काले धन का खुलासा नहीं करते हैं और जांच आकलन में इसका पता चलता है तो उन्हें 83.25 प्रतिशत की दर से टैक्स वसूला जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो लोग योजना का फायदा लेते हुए काले धन की जानकारी सरकार को नहीं देते हैं और छापेमारी के दौरान छिपा हुआ धन सरेंडर करते हैं तो उन्हें 107.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना होगा। लेकिन, जो लोग छापेमारी में भी काला धन खुद निकाल कर नहीं देते हैं, उन्हें 137.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना पड़ सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बेनामी कानून में दोषियों को 7 साल तक की कैद से दंडित करने का प्रावधान है। इसके अलावा, उस पर आयकर कानून के तहत भी मुकदमा चल सकता है। साथ ही, उस पर बेनामी संपत्ति के उचित बाजार मूल्य का 25 प्रतिशत और दूसरे जुर्माने भी भरने होंगे। गौरतलब है कि सरकार ने नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना की घोषणा की थी। इस योजना के तहत कुल घोषित काले धन का एक चौथाई हिस्सा चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज के सरकार के पास जमा रखने की बाध्यता है। यह योजना पिछले साल 17 दिसंबर को शुरू हुई।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भविष्य में सभी कार्डों की जगह ले लेगा आधार कार्ड: अरुण जेटली</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लोकसभा ने बुधवार को वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली की ओर से पेश वित्त विधेयक को चर्चा के बाद पारित कर दिया। चर्चा के दौरान अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि आने वाले दिनों में आधार ही एकमात्र कार्ड होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि भविष्य में यह वोटर आईडी कार्ड और पैन कार्ड जैसे दस्तावेजों की जगह ले लेगा। इन सभी के मुकाबले एक आधार कार्ड ही किसी भी व्यक्ति की पहचान के लिए काफी होगा। लोकसभा में एक सांसद की ओर से पूछा गया था कि आधार कार्ड जारी किए जाने के बाद भी कई कार्डों की व्यवस्था क्यों लागू है। इसके जवाब में जेटली ने यह बात कही। उन्होंने कहा कि आने वाले वक्त में आधार ही व्यक्तिगत पहचान और पते के लिए पुख्ता सबूत होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाए जाने के सवाल पर जेटली ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;तमाम लोगों को कई पैन नंबर इस्तेमाल करते हुए पाया गया है। इसलिए सरकार ने इस व्यवस्था को लागू करने का फैसला लिया है।&amp;rsquo; जेटली ने एक सवाल के जवाब में कहा, &amp;lsquo;आज 98 फीसदी नागरिकों के पास आधार कार्ड है। टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के दौरान व्यक्ति आधार नंबर दे सकता है या यह बता सकता है कि उसने आवेदन कर दिया है, लेकिन टैक्स चोरी की अनुमति नहीं दी जा सकती है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा लोगों को टैक्स की व्यवस्था से जोड़ने की जरूरत है। इसीलिए सरकार ने इस साल टैक्स स्लैब को नीचे लाने का प्रयास किया है। चर्चा के दौरान जेटली ने नोटबंदी को सही फैसला करार देते हुए इकॉनमिस्ट मार्टिन वॉल्फ के एक आर्टिकल का उदाहरण देते हुए कहा कि उन्होंने इसकी सराहना की है। जेटली ने लेख का हवाला देते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;इससे सरकार को ब्लैक मनी पर टैक्स लगाने का मौका मिला है। बड़े पैमाने पर कैश रखने वाले लोगों के लिए रिस्क पैदा हुआ है। इसके अलावा क्रिमिनल्स के पास जमा संपत्ति सरकार के पास आई है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>