<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar. To further incentivize Indians to make the switch to using the BHIM app for transacting business, PM Modi also launched two schemes - cash back for merchants and referral bonus for individual owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Are Some Of The Key Features Of BHIM:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BHIM, short for Bharat Interface for Money, enables its users to transfer money using their mobile phone. The app created a world record by registering 10 million downloads in just four months since its launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. For every successful referral, users can earn Rs. 10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;PM Modi declared on Friday that incentives totalling Rs. 495 crore will be given to merchants for accepting payments through BHIM and existing users for referring it to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 2 MB in size, the latest version of the app enables payments through a fingerprint scanner by authenticating biometric details of the user against the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is available in 12 languages with three new languages (Marathi, Punjabi and Assamese) added in BHIM 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, now allows users to transfer money to contacts saved on the phone. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a cap of Rs. 10,000 for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present account holders of around 30 banks can transact on BHIM 1.3. The app will add Punjab And Maharashtra Co-Operative Bank Ltd, Punjab &amp;amp; Sind Bank and Jammu and Kashmir Bank soon, according to its Google Play Store page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the United Payments Interface (UPI), BHIM users do not need to download mobile applications of multiple banks to transact with different banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the government&amp;rsquo;s move on November 8 last year to demonetise Rs. 500 and Rs. 1,000 currency notes, the number of digital payment apps have logged a nearly 23-fold increase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed by National Payments Corporation of India, BHIM aims pave the way for making payments using fingerprints or iris scanners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either &lt;em&gt;567678 or 56161.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said linking the two numbers is the key to &amp;ldquo;seamlessly avail online, a world of income tax facilities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar can also be seeded into PAN database by quoting Aadhaar in PAN application form for new PAN allotment or by quoting Aadhaar in change request form used for reprint of PAN card,&amp;rdquo; it said in the advertisement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income-Tax-department had early this month launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing I-T returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has hosted a new link on its homepage to link the two unique identities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires a person to punch in his PAN number, Aadhaar number and the exact name as given in the Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department had said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number in the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of Income-Tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the I-T department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAN से आधार कार्ड जोड़ने के लिए आयकर विभाग ने शुरू की नई सुविधा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-introduces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-introduces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने पैन नंबर को आधार कार्ड से जोड़ने के लिए एक नई ई-सुविधा शुरू की है। बता दें कि सरकार ने आयकर रिटर्न दाखिल करने के लिए पैन नंबर के साथ ही आधार कार्ड संख्या को भी अनिवार्य कर दिया है। आयकर विभाग ने ई-फाइलिंग वेबसाइट इनकमटैक्सइंडियाईफाइलिंग डॉट जीओवी डॉट इन पर एक नया लिंक शुरू किया है। इससे लोगों को अपने दोनों विशिष्ट पहचान पत्रों को जोड़ने में आसानी होगी। इस लिंक पर जाने के बाद किसी व्यक्ति को अपनी पैन संख्या और आधार संख्या देने के बाद आधार कार्ड में उल्लेखित नाम को दर्ज करना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारतीय विशिष्ट पहचान प्राधिकरण की ओर से पुष्टि होने के बाद यह जुड़ जाएंगे। यदि कोई गड़बड़ होती है तो UIDAI द्वारा भेजे जाने वाले वनटाइम पासवर्ड की जरूरत होगी, जो आधार पर पंजीकृत मोबाइल नंबर पर भेजा जाएगा। इस सुविधा का प्रयोग करने के लिए आयकर विभाग की ई-फाइलिंग वेबसाइट पर पंजीकरण की आवश्यकता नहीं होगी। इसे कोई भी उपयोग कर सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;किसी प्रकार की विफलता से बचने के लिए दोनों पहचान कार्डों पर उल्लेखित जन्मतिथि एक समान होना जरूरी है। गौरतलब है कि सरकार ने वित्त अधिनियम 2017 के तहत पैन और आधार को आपस में जोड़ना अनिवार्य कर दिया है। यह एक जुलाई 2017 से प्रभावी होगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio’s new plans offer 100% cashback on JioFi on exchange of old dongle, datacard, routers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio has launched a 100% cashback offer with JioFi 4G router, as the Mukesh Ambani-owned tries to attract users of dongles, datacard and wifi routers offered by rival telcos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has come up with two plans where as part of the first plan, users will get a 100% exchange offer where they’ll be required to exchange their existing datacard, dongle or hotspot router at any Jio Digital store or Jio Care store and will get 4G data worth Rs 2010 against the device exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customers will have to pay Rs 1999 to get the JioFi router and will have to do a mandatory first recharge of Rs 408 which is Rs309 for the plan – which ensures freebies for 84 days - and Rs99 for a Jio Prime membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the customer pays Rs 1999 minus the Rs 2010 worth 4G data which translates into zero cost for the customer and the device with internet connection becomes almost free. However, the Rs 408 mandatory recharge is the additional cost which the user will have to pay in order to avail the services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the second plan, users get JioFi at Rs 1999 after a first mandatory recharge of Rs 408 (Rs309 + Rs99) but they get 4G data worth Rs 1005 which translates to the effective cost of Rs 994 (Rs1999 - Rs1005). Users need not exchange their existing data connections for this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first plan is ideal for all existing dongle users whereas the second plan is ideal for laptop users, 2G/3G phone users and tablet users, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Queries addressed to Jio for the new plans went unanswered till the press time. Reliance Retail currently has four JioFi devices running in the market namely JioFi 1 Router, JioFi 2 Router, JioFi 3 Router, JioFi 4 Dongle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the first plan, the telco is trying to capture the market of rival telcos offering dongles, datacard and wifi routers, since the exchange scheme will encourage existing dongle users to shift to Jio’s services, say experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They added that by offering free data in the second plan to the first time users or users that are willing to keep multiple connections, the telco is looking to expand the subscriber-base for its JioFi routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIL’s retail arm namely Reliance Retail sold 2.6 million LYF and JioFi devices during the last quarter and nearly 10 million units in the financial year, and is further looking to accelerate the sales with the launch of new JioFi plans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Reliance-Jio-VoLTE-feature-phone.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen. It also has a dedicated button for torchlight. Maker of this feature phone is not known yet. Currently we don’t have any specifications of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to recent reports, Jio will launch these VoLTE-enabled feature phones starting at Rs. 999 that will run on Android operating system. Earlier reports said that capability to make VoLTE calls in these feature phones will be enabled by Spreadtrum chips, and Jio is in talks with Qualcomm and MediaTek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Jio plans start as low as Rs. 149 per month offering unlimited calls, this will be useful for those who make a lot of calls and need a cheap phone with a keypad. We should know more details about more upcoming VoLTE-enabled feature phones from Jio soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh. In the present scenario where bank interest rates are on a falling trend, financial planners say that equity mutual funds are one of the best instruments to accumulate long-term savings through systematic investment plan (SIP). Gains from equity mutual funds after a year are tax-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, fund selection is one of the most difficult things to do for a retail investor as it needs lot of research. Financial planners say diversified equity funds are the best to invest through SIP for long term. Here are some funds which have generates over 20 per cent CAGR return in past 20 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Equity Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on January 1, 1995, it is one of the oldest and best performing funds in India. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.95 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 23.56 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This fund has generated a CAGR return of 23.68 per cent since its inception. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998 would have helped you accumulate a corpus of Rs. 2.12 crore by April 1, 2017 implying 17.66 times return in 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;Franklin India Prima Fund:&lt;/em&gt; It is one of the flagship fund of Franklin Templeton India. Since its inception in December 1993, it has generated a CAGR return of 21.04 per cent till now. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 2.38 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 25.11 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Vision Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on October 8, 1995, it has generated a CAGR return of 19.92 per cent till now. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998, would have become Rs. 1.46 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Top 200 Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This flagship fund of HDFC Mutual Fund has generated a CAGR return of 20.88 per cent since its inception in September 1996. If you would have started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.43 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With falling return on bank fixed deposits, equity mutual funds are witnessing increased investment from retail investors now. Equity and equity-linked schemes have seen inflows of more than Rs. 70,000 crore in last financial year according to Association of Mutual Funds in India data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon,Bank Account number portability</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-soon-you-may-be-able-to-port-your-bank-account-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-soon-you-may-be-able-to-port-your-bank-account-number/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;From linking Aadhaar numbers to bank accounts to the increase in digital payments, the days are not far when people can port their account numbers too. Reserve Bank of India&amp;rsquo;s (RBI) deputy governor SS Mundra on Tuesday batted for the need of account number portability and said that &amp;ldquo;the prospect of an aggrieved customer moving his/her account to another bank in the near future is very real.&amp;rdquo; He also spoke about the security issues involved in the electronic banking as the use of technology is being increasing over the recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account number portability has come within the realms of possibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SS Mundra first advocated the idea a couple of years ago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He also spoke on the security issues involved in the electronic banking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At an event organised by the Banking Codes and Standards Board of India (BCSBI) in Mumbai, Mr Mundra said, &amp;ldquo;I first advocated the idea of &amp;lsquo;account number portability&amp;rsquo; a couple of years ago. Back then the concept might have appeared somewhat abstract but with technological advancements in the field of payment system such as UPI etc. coupled with massive enrolments under Aadhaar and their linkage to individual bank accounts, it has come within the realms of possibility.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BCSBI is an independent body set up by RBI, Indian Banks Association (IBA) and scheduled commercial banks with the specific objective of ensuring that customers get fair treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the security risks involved in the online banking, he said, &amp;ldquo;There have been several incidents of theft of personal information, fraudulent use of ATMs, net banking frauds, ATM/Debit card incidents or cases of unauthorized access to bank servers. Hence, there is an immediate need for plugging all the gaps and vulnerabilities in tech-enabled service delivery.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While banks have been granted autonomy in fixing minimum average balance or for charging for premium services, it should not be used as an excuse to deny service or to drive away common man,&amp;rdquo; Mr Mundra said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank is also in the process of reiterating its guidelines to the banks for providing essential minimum relevant details in respect of various transactions in the passbook or statement, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trai Releases An App Which Lets You Rate Call Quality</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sector regulator Trai today said it will soon roll-out an app that enables subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call. The &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app would be available by the end of this month, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) chairman RS Sharma said at &amp;lsquo;Digital Broadcasting in India - Way Forward&amp;rsquo;, a seminar to commemorate the completion of 20 years of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We would like the consumers to assess the quality of calls, through &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app, which will be rolled out by this month end,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, once downloaded, the new app would give the subscribers the choice of assessing the quality of all or a portion of calls. When the call is completed, the users will be able to rate it, and the data will thereafter be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The application will pop up a window and enquire about the quality of the call. The subscriber can give it one star to five stars. There will also be assessment parameters like whether the call was indoors or outside or while travelling,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government and the regulator have refused to lower their guard on the issue of call drops, and have kept a close watch on call quality through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.
Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops. The system is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trai through its analytics portal has also rolled out initiatives that measure data speeds and maps call drops in India, which is the world&amp;rsquo;s second largest telecom market with 1.12 billion mobile subscribers.
Sharma today said that Trai also plans to &amp;ldquo;strengthen&amp;rdquo; the &amp;lsquo;Do Not Disturb&amp;rsquo; or DND service aimed at blocking pesky calls by telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already done a lot of work in this,&amp;rdquo; Sharma said, but refused to elaborate on the upcoming plans. At present, there is a framework for DND registry that allows telecom subscribers to block unwanted communication from telemarketers. Reaching out to such subscribers can result in a heavy fine for telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source familiar with the initiative said that the regulator may look at building specific intelligence features into the system such that pesky messages with certain key words could automatically generate a prompt on whether the users wishes to report the message as a spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the occasion, Communications Minister Manoj Sinha said TRAI&amp;rsquo;s regulatory framework has provided a conducive environment for the sector&amp;rsquo;s growth. It has made the sector more competitive and enhanced accessibility of services at affordable tariffs, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awareness of the some of the main challenges faced by the sector and regulatory framework of today - ranging from convergence to the persisting issue of the digital divide - is therefore necessary to be better equipped to handle these challenges in future,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your PAN card could be invalid without Aadhaar by December. Here’s what to do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar-by-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar-by-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Permanent account numbers (PAN) not linked to Aadhaar cards will likely become invalid after December 31, a government source said on Thursday, as the Centre pushes to widen the use of the 12-digit biometric identity project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permanent account numbers (PAN) not linked to Aadhaar cards will likely become invalid after December 31, a government source said on Thursday, as the Centre pushes to widen the use of the 12-digit biometric identity project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, all taxpayers need to have a PAN number to file income tax return but others, such as students outside the tax bracket, also use the card as a proof of identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government says many of these PAN cards are fraudulently obtained, a practice that can be checked by a unique identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official – who refused to be quoted as he isn’t authorised to talk to media – said the government had arrived at the tentative cutoff date of December 31 as it believed the Aadhaar enrollment process will be complete by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Considering that 98% of the adult population is Aadhaar card holders, a time frame till the end of the year is more than adequate for linking PAN with Aadhaar,” said State Bank of India group’s chief economic adviser Soumya Kanti Ghosh.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/pan-aadhaar.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>करोड़पति शेयर: 14.3 लाख के निवेश पर तीन साल में 1 करोड़ रुपये का रिटर्न</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/crorepati-stock-rs-14-3-lakh-invested-in-this-stock-became-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/crorepati-stock-rs-14-3-lakh-invested-in-this-stock-became-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मोदी सरकार ने अपने कार्यकाल के तीन साल पूरे कर लिए। इस दौरान सरकार ने कई महत्वपूर्ण आर्थिक सुधारों को अंजाम दिया और यह प्रक्रिया जारी है। इधर, अर्थव्यवस्था के मौलिक मापदंडों में मजबूती देखी जा रही है। इनके अलावा, देश में राजनीतिक स्थिरता एवं सरकार के स्तर पर सक्रियता की वजह से शेयर बाजार नित नई ऊंचाइयां छू रहा है। इसी क्रम में पिछले तीन सालों में बॉम्बे स्टॉक एक्सचेंज (बीएसई) में लिस्टेड कंपनियों का मार्केट वैल्यू 40 लाख करोड़ रुपये बढ़ गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मार्केट वैल्यू में वृद्धि के मामले में मारुति सुजुकी, आईओसी, एचडीएफसी और रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज जैसी बड़ी कंपनियों ने नेतृत्वकारी प्रदर्शन किया। लेकिन, बेस्ट परफॉर्मर्स की टॉप 10 लिस्ट में जगह बनाने वाली एक नई कंपनी ने सबको चकित कर रखा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जिन निवेशकों ने तीन साल पहले इस कंपनी के शेयर में 14.27 लाख रुपये निवेश किए होंगे, वह आज करोड़पति बन चुके हैं। पिछले तीन साल में यह शेयर 538 प्रतिशत उछला है और अब कंपनी दिग्गजों की सूची में शुमार हो चुकी है। यह कंपनी है बजाज फाइनैंस।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस स्टॉक का मार्केट कैप शुक्रवार को 71,000 करोड़ रुपये तक पहुंच गया जो महज तीन साल पहले 10,000 करोड़ रुपये था। आंकड़े बताते हैं कि कंपनी ने पिछले तीन साल से वित्त वर्ष 2016 तक 29.31 प्रतिशत की दर से ऐनुअल प्रॉफिट ग्रोथ दर्ज की है। इस अवधि में कंपनी की बिक्री में सालाना 33.64 प्रतिशत की वृद्धि हुई। विश्लेषक अब भी इस स्टॉक में निवेश की सलाह दे रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ब्रोकरेज फर्म शेयरखान ने बजाज फाइनैंस के शेयर की रेटिंग अपग्रेड कर दी और उसे होल्ड से बाय कैटिगरी में ला दिया। फर्म में इसका रिवाज्ड प्राइस टार्गेट 1,550 रुपये रखा है। सोमवार को बीएसई में यह स्टॉक 1,282 रुपये पर ट्रेड कर रहा था। मार्केट वैल्यू के लिहाज से शानदार प्रदर्शन करने वाली टॉप 10 कंपनियों ने पिछले तीन साल में बीएसई के मार्केट कैप में 9 लाख करोड़ रुपये का इजाफा किया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>नोटबंदी के बाद सोने और फर्जी कंपनियों में खपाई गई थी ब्लैक मनी: IT सूत्र</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/black-money-converted-into-gold-stored-in-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/black-money-converted-into-gold-stored-in-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी के बाद ब्लैक मनी से बड़े पैमाने पर सोने की खरीदारी की गई थी या फिर इन अज्ञात पैसों को फर्जी कंपनियां बनाकर उसमें खपाया गया था। नोटबंदी के बाद देशभर में पड़े छापों के दौरान यह जानकारी सामने आई थी। आयकर विभाग के सूत्रों ने बताया कि ब्लैक मनी रखने वाले लोगों ने ये पैसे बैंकों में डिपॉजिट नहीं किए क्योंकि वे अपनी पहचान गुप्त रखना चाहते थे। नोटबंदी के दौरान कई जूलर्स ने लोगों की ब्लैक मनी को सोने में बदल दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जांच में शामिल रहे एक अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo; पिछले साल 8 नवंबर को पीएम नरेंद्र मोदी की नोटबंदी की घोषणा के बाद लोगों ने अपनी ब्लैक मनी को सोने और जूलरी खरीदने में लगा दी। जूलर्स ने इसके बाद अलग-अलग बिल देकर लोगों की असली पहचान छिपा ली।&amp;rsquo; बता दें कि 8 नवंबर को ही पीएम मोदी ने 500 और 1000 रुपये के नोट को चलन से बाहर करने की घोषणा की थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सूत्र ने बताया कि नोटबंदी को जूलर्स ने अपनी बिक्री बढ़ाने का जरिया माना और वे ऐसे पैसों को गहनों की बिक्री दिखाकर बच गए। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जूलर्स ने अज्ञात आय को सोने में बदलने का प्लैटफ़ॉर्म उपलब्ध कराया।&amp;rsquo; जो बिल दिए गए वो अलग-अलग थे और दो लाख रुपये से कम के थे। इसके अलावा खरीदारों की सूची भी फर्जी थी। जांच के बाद पता चला कि कई खरीदार तो वित्तीय तौर पर काफी कमजोर थे और वे बिल में दिखाई गई राशि इतना पैसा खर्च करने की स्थिति में ही नहीं थे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने जूलर्स से सवाल पूछा था कि कैसे नोटबंदी के बाद उनके पास इतनी मांग बढ़ी, खासतौर पर त्योहारी सीजन बीत जाने के बाद। आयकर रेडार के निशाने पर आए सेंको गोल्ड लिमिटेड के चेयरमैन शंकर सेन ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;हमने सभी खरीदारों द्वारा दिए गए नाम और कॉन्टैक्टस के आधार पर सारा रेकॉर्ड रखा है। हम इस मामले में विभाग की जांच में मदद कर रहे हैं और उन्हें सभी दस्तावेज मुहैया करा रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जूलर्स के लिए यह जांच पाना काफी मुश्किल है कि खरीदार ने सही जानकारी दी है या नहीं। खासकर तब जब खरीदारी दो लाख रुपये से कम की हो। गौरतलब है कि आयकर विभाग ने 29 नवंबर के बाद ब्लैक मनी वालों के खिलाफ जांच तेज कर दी थी। दरअसल इस समय तक विभाग सीबीडीटी और अन्य एजेंसियों से पैसों के मूवमेंट पर सूचनाएं एकत्र कर रहा था।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पांच साल और, पेट्रोल मिलेगा 30 रुपये लीटर, पढ़िये पूरी खबर</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-to-go-cheaper-due-to-low-oil-demand-and-technology-change-rs-30-per-liter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-to-go-cheaper-due-to-low-oil-demand-and-technology-change-rs-30-per-liter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;टोनी कहते हैं कि सेल्फ ड्राइव कारों की वजह से दुनिया भर में पेट्रोलियम पदार्थों की कीमतों में जबर्दस्त गिरावट दर्ज की जाएगी। और तेल की कीमतें 25 डॉलर प्रति बैरल तक आ जाएगीं।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पेट्रोल की कीमतें हर भारतीय के बजट का मोटा हिस्सा हजम कर जाती हैं। आपके पास बाइक अथवा कार हो या ना हो लेकिन आप पेट्रोल की कीमतों से प्रभावित होते हैं। लेकिन अगर हम आपको कहेंगे कि अगले 5 साल के बाद आप पेट्रोल 30 रुपये प्रति लीटर खरीद पाएंगे तो आप इसे मजाक ही समझेंगे। लेकिन ऐसा संभव हो सकता है। और ऐसा संभव है विज्ञान और बदलती प्रोद्योगिकी की वजह से। ऐसा दावा किया है तकनीकी और इसके प्रभाव का अध्ययन करने वाले अमेरिका के मशहूर फ्यूचरिस्ट यानी की भविष्यवादी टोनी सीबा ने। बता दें कि अमेरिका के ही इस प्रोफेशनल ने दावा किया था कि दुनिया में सोलर पावर का बूम होगा। टोनी ने ये दावा तब किया था जब आज के मुकाबले सोलर पावर की कीमतें 10 गुणा थी। टोनी का आकलन सही साबित हुआ और सोलर पावर की कीमतों में गिरावट हुआ और आज दुनिया भर में सोलर पावर पेट्रोलियम पदार्थों का विकल्प बन चुका है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अंग्रेजी वेबसाइट इकोनॉमिक टाइम्स के मुताबिक टोनी सीबा सिलिकन वैली के एक बड़े बिजनेसमैन हैं साथ ही स्टैनफोर्ड यूनिवर्सिटी में भी क्लीन एनर्जी से जुड़े अध्ययन में शामिल हैं। टोनी कहते हैं कि सेल्फ ड्राइव कारों की वजह से दुनिया भर में पेट्रोलियम पदार्थों की कीमतों में जबर्दस्त गिरावट दर्ज की जाएगी। और तेल की कीमतें 25 डॉलर प्रति बैरल तक आ जाएगीं। यूं तो एक भारतीय के लिए उनकी इस भविष्यवाणी पर यकीन करना मुश्किल लगता है। लेकिन उनके आंकड़ों में दम और तर्क नजर आता है। टोनी का कहना है कि 2020-21 तक दुनिया में तेल की मांग उच्चतम स्तर पर होगी और ये 100 मिलियन बैरल तक पहुंच जाएगा। लेकिन इसके बाद तेल की कीमतें गिरने लगेंगी। 10 साल में तेल की मांग घटकर 70 मिलियन डॉलर हो जाएगीष इसका मतलब होगा कि दुनिया में तेल 25 डॉलर प्रति बैरल बिकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;टोनी सीबा का कहना है कि आने वाले सालों में इलेक्ट्रिक कार ऑयल इंडस्ट्री पर गहरा प्रभाव डालने वाली है। कुछ सालों में लोगों के लिए इलेक्ट्रिक कार खरीदना और चलाना दोनों सस्ता पड़ेगा। इसका असर तेल की कीमतों पर भी पड़ेगा। हाल ही में ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा था कि 2030 तक भारत में भी सारी कारें इलेक्ट्रिक कार से चलने वाली होंगी। इसका ये भी मतलब लगाया जा सकता है कि अगले 15 से 20 सालों में देश में पेट्रोल डीजल से चलने वाली कारें ना के बराबर रह जाएंगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>राष्ट्रीय औषधि मूल्य प्राधिकरण (एनपीपीए) ने और 30 दवाओं (फार्मूलेशन) का अधिकतम खुदरा मूल्य तय किया</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nppa-decided-maximum-retail-price-of-30-more-medicines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nppa-decided-maximum-retail-price-of-30-more-medicines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;राष्ट्रीय औषधि मूल्य प्राधिकरण (एनपीपीए) ने और 30 दवाओं (फार्मूलेशन) का अधिकतम खुदरा मूल्य तय किया है। इन दवाओं का इस्तेमाल हेपेटाइटिस, ह्दय रोग, संक्रमण, बुखार और दर्द के इलाज के लिए होता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दवा मूल्य नियामक ने कहा कि जहां 19 अनिवार्य दवाओं के लिए एमआरपी तय किया गया है, वहीं 11 के मूल्य में संशोधन किया गया है। एनपीपीए ने अधिसूचना में कहा,&amp;lsquo;सात दवाओं का खुदरा मूल्य तय किया गया है।&amp;rsquo; ताजा मूल्य संशोधन से अप्रैल, 2016 से मूल्य नियंत्रण के दायरे में आने वाली दवाओं की संख्या 760 पर पहुंच गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह कदम सरकार की देशभर में मरीजों को उचित मूल्य पर गुणवत्ता वाली सस्ती दवाएं उपलब्ध कराने की प्रक्रिया का हिस्सा है। एनपीपीए नियंत्रित थोक दवाओं और फार्मूलेशन का मूल्य तय और संशोधित करता है। वह देश में दवाओं की उपलब्धता सुनिश्चित करने के साथ ही बिना नियंत्रण वाली दवाओं के दाम उचित स्तर पर रखने के लिए मूल्य की निगरानी भी करता है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>