<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Govt:Over Rs 153cr awarded to 10lk people to promote e-payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;check if you are winner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dev.digidhanlucky&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px;padding:4px&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/logoapp.png&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on start button in Digi Dhan Lucky Yojana App.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on whether you are a Consumer or a Merchant, click on the corresponding button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box that appears next, provide the mobile phone number registered with your UPI/ USSD/ RuPay/ AEPS account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive an OTP, which you must enter in the box that appears in the middle of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Try Your Luck button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next message will show if you have won under the Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi Dhan Vyapar Yojana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been awarded over Rs 153.5 crore in the last 58 days under Niti Aayog’s schemes to promote digital payments, its CEO Amitabh Kant said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It has been 58 days since the launch of Niti Aayog’s two incentive schemes – Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana to promote digital payments and the public response has been quite encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the latest figures released by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), which has been executing the schemes, nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been disbursed over Rs 153.5 crore as reward money till February 20, 2017,” Kant said at a press conference here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s think-tank said in a statement that among the 9.8 lakh winners are more than 9.2 lakh consumers and 56,000 merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners belong to diverse socio-economic backgrounds, including farmers, merchants, small entrepreneurs, professionals, housewives, students and retired persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Uttar Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh and Delhi have emerged as the top five states/Union Territories with maximum number of winners,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While majority of the winners are in the age group of 21 to 30, Niti Aayog pointed out that a significant number are also above 60 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The diversity in age of winners is from 15 to 66 years, challenging the notion that the old find it difficult to embrace technology to adopt digital payments,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government on December 25 had launched two schemes — Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana — to boost digital transactions post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associate Bank Branches To Become SBI Branches From April 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branches of all five associate banks, which are merging with parent State Bank of India, will begin functioning as SBI branches from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customers, including depositors of State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore will be treated as customers of State Bank of India with effect from April 1, 2017,&amp;rdquo; the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) said in a notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officers and employees, with the exception of the board of directors and executive trustees of the associate banks, will become employees of SBI following the merger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI alone has nearly 20,000 branches, including 191 foreign offices spread across 36 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the five subsidiary banks, only SBBJ, SBM and SBT are listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the government on Monday announced that Bharatiya Mahila Bank will also be merged with SBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation Says No Vulnerability In BHIM App</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-says-no-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-says-no-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPCI significant downloads have been witnessed since the BHIM app was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;National Payments Corporation of India&lt;/em&gt; (NPCI) on Monday said there is no vulnerability or loopholes reported in the Bharat Interface for Money or BHIM application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI has done intensive testing, robust design of security controls and continuous monitoring of its Unified Payments Interface (UPI) infrastructure, the corporation said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The environment in which BHIM or UPI is run by NPCI is highly secure and certified with best global practices,&amp;rdquo; it said, adding that the packages have also been audited by reputed IT security firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI has put in place adequate governance mechanism for banks to report any fraud or system issues and its redressal, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, it said that since BHIM was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, significant downloads have been witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Out of the 19.16 million downloads, 5.1 million customers have been able to link their bank accounts. In many cases customers downloaded the application to see that they have not linked their mobile number to the bank account,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks are expected to reach out to all their customers by various means and ensure universal acceptance of mobile banking services at the earliest,&amp;rdquo; NPCI managing director and CEO A P Hota said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI के सहयोगी बैंकों का 1 अप्रैल को विलय होना तय, महिला बैंक भी बनेगा हिस्सा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/branches-of-associate-banks-will-be-work-as-sbi-branches-from-1st-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/branches-of-associate-banks-will-be-work-as-sbi-branches-from-1st-april/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;यदि आपका बैंक खाता स्टेट बैंक ऑफ बीकानेर ऐंड जयपुर, स्टेट बैंक ऑफ हैदराबाद, स्टेट बैंक ऑफ मैसूर, स्टेट बैंक ऑफ त्रावणकोर और स्टेट बैंक ऑफ पटियाला में है तो यह खबर आपके लिए बेहद जरूरी है। इन बैंकों की देश भर में मौजूद सभी शाखाएं 1 अप्रैल से देश के सबसे बड़े सार्वजनिक बैंक एसबीआई की ब्रांच के तौर पर काम कर शुरू कर देंगी। सरकार इससे पहले ही एसबीआई के सभी असोसिएट बैंकों के विलय का ऐलान कर चुकी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यही नहीं केंद्र सरकार ने भारतीय महिला बैंक के भी स्टेट बैंक में ही विलय का ऐलान किया है। सरकार का कहना है कि इससे महिलाओं तक बेहतर बैंकिंग सुविधाओं को पहुंचाने में मदद मिल सकेगी। स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया के असोसिएट बैंकों की ओर से जारी किए जाने वाले डेबिट और क्रेडिट कार्ड पहले से ही एसबीआई के नेटवर्क के तहत ही काम करते थे। माना जा रहा है कि असोसिएट बैंकों के मर्जर से एसबीआई मजबूत होगा और उसकी वित्तीय स्थिति में बड़ा इजाफा होने की उम्मीद है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पिछले ही दिनों स्टेट बैंक की चेयरपर्सन अरुंधति भट्टाचार्य ने कहा था कि मर्जर के साथ पैरेंट बैंक असोसिएट बैंकों और महिला बैंक से 5,000 करोड़ रुपये की फिक्स्ड पूंजी हासिल करेगा। रिपोर्ट्स के मुताबिक, अगर मर्जर योजनाएं पूरी होती हैं तो एसबीआई के पास 21 लाख करोड़ रुपये से ज्यादा के डिपॉजिट्स होंगे और लोन बुक भी 17.5 लाख करोड़ रुपये के करीब पहुंच जाएगी। भट्टाचार्य ने कहा था, &amp;lsquo;इस सबसे ग्लोबल बैंकों में हमारी रैंकिंग भी सुधरेगी। बैलेंस शीट साइज के हिसाब से हमारी रैंकिंग 59 से सुधरकर 55 पर आ जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can now lock your Aadhaar data to keep it safe from hackers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now, you can lock your Aadhaar biometric details to keep it safe and unlock it whenever you want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With digital payments using Aadhaar data on the rise and cases of misuse being reported, officials of the &lt;em&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India&lt;/em&gt; (UIDAI) have come out with the new security feature to lock the biometric details (fingerprint and retinal scan data).The UIDAI introduced the lock and unlock facility following an uproar that Aadhaar deprived people of their right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric data of citizens is being collected on various platforms for government schemes, often without much safeguards. Aadhaar identification has become almost compulsory in some cases. Banks, mobile phone operators and others have access to it. “People can hack into this data and access individuals’ details, including bank accounts,” a UIDAI official warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Each time you shop and pay using your fingerprint, the data processed by POS machines can be hacked. Fingerprint details can be captured as well,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lock and unlock facility is purely voluntary. “If a person wants to lock his data, he or she can do it. No other person can unlock it. One can keep it locked as long as one wishes,” the official said Once the Aadhaar data is locked, even banks cannot access the biometric information stored in the main server.This will lead to failed transactions due to non-verification or non-authentication of the Aadhaar. The UIDAI is also planning to introduce a mobile application to lockunlock biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब भी लोन पर दे रहे हैं ज्यादा ब्याज? जानें, कैसे करा सकते हैं कम</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/still-paying-interest-on-home-loan-at-old-rates-cut-emi-by-switching-to-mcls-linked-rate-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/still-paying-interest-on-home-loan-at-old-rates-cut-emi-by-switching-to-mcls-linked-rate-now/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;बैंक में राशि जमा करने वालों के साथ ही कर्जधारकों को भी ब्याज दरों में बदलाव को लेकर सचेत रहना चाहिए। कई बार नियमों की जानकारी न होने के चलते कर्जधारकों को कई बार गैरजरूरी चार्ज चुकाने पड़ते हैं। जानें, आखिर किन वजहों से कस्टमर्स को बैंकों के ओवरचार्ज चुकाने पड़ते हैं। यदि आप अपने बैंक लोन की ब्याज दर का मित्रों, रिश्तेदारों और अन्य लोगों के इंटरेस्ट रेट से तुलना करते हैं तो पता लगता है कि आपको बड़ी राशि बेवजह चुकानी पड़ रही है। अलग-अलग बैंकों की ब्याज दर अलग होती है, लेकिन एक ही बैंक में भी अलग-अलग ग्राहकों के लिए यह अलग होती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इसकी वजह कस्टमर्स का क्रेडिट स्कोर नहीं होता। कुछ बैंक नए ग्राहकों को तो सस्ते दाम पर लोन उपलब्ध करता हैं, जबकि पुराने कस्टमर्स पर अधिक रेट ही चार्ज करते रहते हैं। फिज्डम के को-फाउंजर रामगणेश अय्यर ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;बैंक अब भी लगातार भेदभावपूर्ण नीति अपनाते हुए मौजूदा ग्राहकों और नए कस्टमर्स के लिए अलग-अलग रेट पर लोन मुहैया कराते हैं। इसे रोका जाना चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; बैंकिंग रेग्युलेटर रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया को इस तरह की गलत नीति पर लगाम कसनी चाहिए। आरबीआई ने मार्जिनल कॉस्ट लेंडिंग रेट मेथड को अप्रैल, 2016 से लागू किया था। इसका मकसद यह था कि रेट कट को तेजी से लागू किया जा सके। इससे पहले प्राइम लेंडिंग रेट के आधार पर ही कर्ज की ब्याज दर तय की जाती थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जिन कर्जधारकों ने 4 या 5 साल पहले लोन लिया था और उन्होंने बैंक से नई व्यवस्था के तहत जोड़ने का आग्रह नहीं किया है, उन्हें आज भी प्राइम लेडिंग रेट सिस्टम के तहत बेस रेट पर ही इंटरेस्ट चुकाना पड़ रहा है। ऐसे में अब जबकि बैंक नए कस्टमर्स को एमसीएलआर के तहत लोन मुहैया करा रहे हैं तो पुराने ग्राहकों को अब भी अधिक ब्याज ही चुकाना पड़ रहा है। आईसर्व फाइनैंशल के सीईओ दीपक सामंत ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;बैंक यदि अलग-अलग रेट ऑफर कर रहे हों तो सबसे सही होता है कि ऐग्रिगेटर्स से संपर्क किया जाए। इससे आपको लोन के इंटरेस्ट रेट पर बारगेन करने का मौका मिलेगा।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यदि आप अपने पुराने लोन पर इंटरेस्ट कम कराना चाहते हैं तो इसके लिए आपको इसे बेस रेट से एमसीएलआर पर शिफ्ट कराना होगा। एक्सपर्ट्स के मुताबिक एमसीएलआर में शिफ्ट कराना अच्छा कदम होगा। इन्वेस्टमेंट एक्सपर्ट बलवंत जैन का कहना है, &amp;lsquo;आरबीआई फिलहाल स्थिर नीतियां अपना रहा है। ब्याज दर में मौजूदा रेट्स से अधिक का इजाफा नहीं होगा। इसेक अलावा आने वाले एक साल के बाद इसमें कमी भी हो सकती है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ल-न-र-स-ट-कर-न-क-च-र-ज&#34;&gt;लोन रीसेट कराने के चार्ज&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैंकों की ओर से दो तरह के लोन मुहैया कराए जाते हैं: फ्लोटिंग और फिक्स्ड रेट। फ्लोटिंग रेट लोन में आरबीआई की ओर से ब्याज दरों में कमी और इजाफे के अनुसार बदलाव होता रहता है, जबकि फिक्स्ड रेट लोन की किस्त समान रहती है। हालांकि बैंक ब्याज दर बढ़ाने में तो जल्दी दिखाते हैं, लेकिन कटौती करने में नहीं। यही नहीं पुराने बेंचमार्क से नए बेंचमार्क में लोन ट्रांसफर के लिए भी बैंक चार्ज वसूलते हैं। बैंक यह चार्ज नए अग्रीमेंट्स के रजिस्ट्रेशन और स्टांप ड्यूटी के लिए भी वसूलते हैं, इसके अलावा अन्य खर्च भी इसमें शामिल होते हैं। हालांकि यह चार्ज बकाया राशि के 0.2% से अधिक नहीं होता है। हालांकि कुछ बैंक 0.5 पर्सेंट तक की राशि वसूलते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>मच्योर हो चुके फिक्स्ड डिपॉजिट को रीन्यू न करें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/do-not-renew-matured-fixed-deposit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/do-not-renew-matured-fixed-deposit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने बैंक फिक्स्ड डिपॉजिट में पांच साल पहले निवेश किया था तो आपने इसे करीब 9 प्रतिशत के रेट पर लॉक किया होगा। अब आप इस रेट के करीब 7.5 फीसदी पर रहने की उम्मीद कर सकते हैं। अगर आप 30 फीसदी टैक्स ब्रैकेट में आते हैं तो इसका मतलब होगा कि आपको टैक्स के बाद रिटर्न के तौर पर महज 5 फीसदी का रेट मिलेगा। यहां कुछ ऐसे विकल्प दिए जा रहे हैं, जो &lt;em&gt;बैंक एफडी&lt;/em&gt; के मुकाबले बेहतर रिटर्न ऑफर कर रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;सरक-र-स-व-ग-स-ब-न-ड-स&#34;&gt;सरकारी सेविंग्स बॉन्ड्स&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;येे बॉन्ड 8 फीसदी इंट्रेस्ट और सबसे ऊंचे लेवल की सेफ्टी यानी भारत सरकार की ओर से गारंटी ऑफर करते हैं। हालांकि, इस पर मिलने वाला ब्याज आपके स्लैब के हिसाब से टैक्सेबल होगा। इसके साथ ही इसमें 6 साल का लॉक-इन भी है। आप इन बॉन्ड्स को बैंकों और फाइनैंशल इंस्टीट्यूशंस के जरिए ले सकते हैं और इसमें आपके अधिकतम निवेश की कोई सीमा नहीं है। प्लानरुपी इन्वेस्टमेंट सर्विसेज के फाउंडर अमोल जोशी के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;अपने लिक्विडिटी पार्ट को लेकर सतर्क रहिए क्योंकि ये बॉन्ड न तो ट्रेडेबल हैं और न ही ट्रांसफरेबल।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-र-प-र-ट-फ-क-स-ड-ड-प-ज-ट-स&#34;&gt;कॉर्पोरेट फिक्स्ड डिपॉजिट्स&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कॉर्पोरेट एफडी पर मिलने वाला इंट्रेस्ट रेट बैंक एफडी के मुकाबले 1-2 फीसदी ज्यादा होता है। हालांकि, इन्वेस्टर्स को केवल एएए रेटेड डिपॉजिट्स पर गौर करना चाहिए ताकि पूंजी सुरक्षित रहे। सीनियर सिटीजंस को अक्सर इन एफडी में 25 बेसिस पॉइंट्स अतिरिक्त इंट्रेस्ट मिलता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;स-म-ल-स-व-ग-स-स-क-म-स&#34;&gt;स्मॉल सेविंग्स स्कीम्स&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्मॉल सेविंग्स या पोस्ट ऑफिस स्कीमों में कई तरह के इंस्ट्रूमेंट्स शामिल होते हैं। ये बैंक एफडी के मुकाबले ज्यादा बेहतर रिटर्न देते हैं। नैशनल सेविंग्स सर्टिफिकेट्स (एनएससी) एक अच्छा विकल्प है, अगर आपके इन्वेस्टमेंट की अवधि पांच साल की है। ये 8 फीसदी का आकर्षक रिटर्न देते हैं। सबसे ऊंचे टैक्स ब्रैकेट वालों के लिए नेट आफ्टर टैक्स रिटर्न करीब 5.6 फीसदी रहता है। किसान विकास पत्र भी एक लॉन्ग-टर्म ऑप्शन है। इसमें आपका इन्वेस्टमेंट 9 साल 4 महीने में दोगुना हो जाता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_पब्लिक प्रविडेंट फंड _(पीपीएफ) एक ऑल सीजन प्रॉडक्ट है जिसमें इग्जेंप्ट-इग्जेंप्ट-इग्जेंप्ट स्टेटस रहता है। जोशी के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;यह एक बेस्ट ऑप्शन बना हुआ है, हालांकि, इसके रेट्स गिरकर 8 फीसदी पर आ गए हैं।&amp;rsquo; 10 साल से कम उम्र वाली बेटी के माता-पिता 8.5 फीसदी इंट्रेस्ट वाली सुकन्या समृद्धि योजना में इन्वेस्ट कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#डेट फंड्स&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डेट फंड्स में बैंक एफडी से बेहतर रिटर्न मिलता है और ये बढ़िया लिक्विडिटी भी देते हैं। हालांकि, इनमें रिटर्न मार्केट लिंक्ड है, ऐसे में इसमें कुछ रिस्क शामिल होते हैं। इडलवाइज म्यूचुअल फंड के फिक्स्ड इनकम के सीआईओ धवल दलाल के मुताबिक, &amp;lsquo;अनुभवी फंड मैनेजमेंट टीम वाले एक मजबूत रिस्क मैनेजमेंट सिस्टम वाले स्थापित फंड हाउसों का चुनाव करें।&amp;rsquo; डेट फंड्स की सबसे अच्छी बात यह है कि आपको इंडेक्सेशन बेनेफिट मिलते हैं, अगर आप कम-से-कम तीन साल के लिए इन्वेस्ट करते हैं। हकीकत यह है कि अगर आप 31 मार्च को खत्म होने वाले फाइनैंशल इयर से पहले इन्वेस्ट करते हैं तो आपको चार साल के लिए इंडेक्सेशन का फायदा होगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रुपये की मजबूती से 3% से ज्यादा लुढ़केगा गोल्ड</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-rate-would-fall-more-than-3-percent-due-to-strong-rupee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-rate-would-fall-more-than-3-percent-due-to-strong-rupee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगले महीने शुरू होने वाले शादी के सीजन से पहले गोल्ड की कीमतों को लेकर बुलियन डीलर्स और जानकारों की राय बंटी हुई दिख रही है। कुछ बुलियन डीलर्स और जानकारों का मानना है कि अगर डॉलर के मुकाबले रुपये में मजबूती जारी रहती है तो आने वाले दिनों में गोल्ड की कीमत 3 प्रतिशत से अधिक गिरकर 27,800 रुपये प्रति 10 ग्राम पर जा सकती है। दूसरों का कहना है कि आने वाले सप्ताहों में गोल्ड प्राइसेज मजबूत हो सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अमेरिका में फेडरल ओपन मार्केट कमिटी (FOMC) की पिछले सप्ताह के मध्य में हुई मीटिंग से पहले गोल्ड प्राइसेज में गिरावट आई थी, लेकिन शुक्रवार को इसमें रिकवरी दर्ज की गई थी। डॉलर के मुकाबले भारतीय रुपये के मजबूत होने के कारण गोल्ड महंगा होने का असर रुपये के लिहाज से महसूस नहीं किया गया था। ऋद्धिसिद्धि बुलियन के मैनेजिंग डायरेक्टर पृथ्वीराज कोठारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;अगर रुपया और मजबूत होता है तो प्राइसेज गिरकर 27,800 रुपये प्रति 10 ग्राम पर आ सकते हैं। इससे कस्टमर्स को शादी के सीजन से पहले गोल्ड खरीदने का मौका मिलेगा।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने बताया कि इन्वेस्टर्स के पोर्टफोलियो में गोल्ड और अन्य कीमती मेटल्स का आकर्षण कम हो सकता है, लेकिन वैश्विक स्तर पर अनिश्चितताओं की आशंका होने से निवेश के एक सुरक्षित जरिए के तौर पर इसका महत्व बरकरार रहेगा। मुंबई के झवेरी बाजार में गुरुवार को गोल्ड का स्पॉट प्राइस लगभग 28,710 रुपये प्रति 10 ग्राम पर था। उन्होंने कहा कि अगर प्राइसेज में तेजी आती है तो गोल्ड 29,000 रुपये प्रति 10 ग्राम पर पहुंच सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इंडिया बुलियन ऐंड जूलर्स असोसिएशन के नैशनल सेक्रेटरी सुरेन्द्र मेहता ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;ऐसा सुना जा रहा है कि मोदी सरकार रुपये की रि-रेटिंग करने की कोशिश कर रही है। हमें देखना होगा कि इसका गोल्ड पर क्या असर होता है। पिछले एक महीने में रुपये में काफी मजबूती आई है और अगर यह जारी रहती है तो गोल्ड प्राइसेज गिरकर 28,000 रुपये प्रति 10 ग्राम के स्तर पर जा सकते हैं। हालांकि, इंटरनैशनल मार्केट में हम गोल्ड प्राइसेज को लेकर बुलिश हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कोटक महिंद्रा बैंक के हेड (ग्लोबल ट्रांजैक्शन, बैंकिंग ऐंड प्रेशियस मेटल्स) शेखर भंडारी ने बताया कि मौजूदा लेवल से गोल्ड प्राइसेज से नीचे जाने का कोई संकेत नहीं है। उनका कहना था, &amp;lsquo;रुपये के इस स्तर से और ऊपर जाने की संभावना नहीं है। गोल्ड प्राइसेज आने वाले सप्ताहों में चढ़ सकते हैं। अक्षय तृतीया के करीब आने के साथ अगले छह सप्ताह गोल्ड प्राइसेज के मूवमेंट के लिए महत्वपूर्ण हैं।&amp;rsquo; अक्षय तृतीया को देश में गोल्ड खरीदने के लिए पवित्र दिन माना जाता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हालांकि, पिछले कुछ दिनों में गोल्ड प्राइसेज गिरने के कारण शादी के सीजन से पहले इसकी डिमांड बढ़ी है। ऑल इंडिया जेम्स ऐंड जूलरी ट्रेड फेडरेशन के चेयरमैन, नितिन खंडेलवाल ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;प्राइसेज के नीचे आने के कारण पिछले कुछ दिनों में डिमांड अच्छी रही है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 में इन 5 कंपनियों ने भारत में की छंटनी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-tech-companies-in-india-that-cut-jobs-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-tech-companies-in-india-that-cut-jobs-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;2017 भारत के टेक्नॉलजी सेक्टर के लिए शुभ संकेत लेकर नहीं आया। वैश्विक राजनीतिक बदलावों और कम होती फंडिंग के कारण कई स्टार्टअप्स और कंपनियां छंटनी की घोषणा कर चुके हैं। देखिए किन कंपनियों में हुई छंटनी.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;yepme&#34;&gt;YepMe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फैैशन रिटेलर येपमी ने अपनी वेयरहाउसिंग और क्विलिटी कंट्रोल टीम से छंटनी की है। कंपनी के फाउंडर विवेक गौर ने बताया कि नोटंबदी से कंपनी की सेल्स पर काफी असर पड़ा और वह भारत के बाहर कंपनी को बढ़ाने पर फोकस कर रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;snapdeal&#34;&gt;Snapdeal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पिछले महीने स्नैपडील में भारतीय ई-कॉमर्स कंपनी स्नैपडील ने साफ किया था कि वह छंटनी करने वाली है। हालांकि कंपनी ने साफ नहीं किया था कि वह कितने एंप्लॉयीज को निकालेगा। कंपनी की फाइनैंशल हालत का अंदाजा इसी से लगाया जा सकता है कि स्नैपडील के फाउंडर्स कुणाल बहल और रोहित बंसल ने अनिश्चितकाल के लिए सैलरी न लेने का फैसला किया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;leeco&#34;&gt;LeEco&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चार महीने पहले इस चीनी कंपनी ने बताया कि उसके पास कैश की कमी है। कंपनी ने भारत में अपने 85 प्रतिशत स्टाफ को बाहर का रास्ता दिखा दिया। इंडस्ट्री एक्सपर्ट्स का मानना है कि कंपनी की पेरेंट फर्म घाटे में है और वह अब केवल चीन और अमेरिका पर फोकस करना चाहती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aircel&#34;&gt;Aircel&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस साल फरवरी में टेलिकॉम कंपनी एयरसेल ने 700 एंप्लॉयीज को नौकरी से निकाल दिया। कंपनी ने अपने 10 प्रतिशत वर्कफोर्स को कम कर दिया है। कंपनी के भारत में करीब 8000 कर्मचारी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;craftsvilla&#34;&gt;Craftsvilla&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पारंपरिक परिधानों की कंपनी क्राफ्ट्सविला ने अपने सैकड़ों एंप्लॉयीज को नौकरी से निकाल दिया है। इसमें प्रॉडक्ट टीम और टेक्नॉलजी टीम में छंटनी की है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hacker can access your information via a UPI-based app</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/startup-identified-291-ways-hacker-can-access-information-via-upi-based-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/startup-identified-291-ways-hacker-can-access-information-via-upi-based-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As digitisation picks up steam with Indians expected to transact Rs 4 crore digitally every day this year, privacy of their data has become a paramount concern. The government is caught between encouraging digitisation and ensuring secure platforms. This is where startups like Appknox come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specialising in mobile apps security, Appknox recently identified 291 critical vulnerabilities (181 were accorded the status of high ctitical vulnerabilities) in Unified Payments Interface (UPI) based mobile applications developed by banks and other fintech companies. These vulnerabilities had the potential of exposing a user’s entire bank details to the eyes of any hacker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There were issues where we could bypass the entire security gamut and get access to user’s bank account details and even download those details easily. We found hackers can easily manipulate these loopholes to misuse the data,” says Appknox cofounder and CEO, Harshit Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team at Appknox, driven by Agarwal and cofounders Subho Halder and Prateek Panda was hired by NPCI in July 2016 and has been scanning UPI-based apps since November. These apps, developed and launched by banks and other fintech companies, have already seen heavy downloads and have lakhs of users transacting online.
The team found 181 high, 83 medium and 27 low critical vulnerabilities in the 35 plus apps evaluated by it. The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) then advised the banks to quickly work on the suggestions provided by Appknox in order to negate these threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other threats, the team was particularly concerned about basic security steps which the hackers at Appknox were easily able to contravene. The login password step was easily bypassed by the team in a number of UPI-based apps which could lead any hacker directly into a user’s account and access that user’s information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of apps depend on OTP (One Time Password) system to provide an extra layer of security to its users. The team shares it was able to easily brute force its way to login into a user’s account.
Given these apps were developed by banks which are considered the safest mode financial platforms, the team was surprised at the ease with which it was able to hack into the apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These banks have internal audits and we expected their apps to be pretty secure. Banks are the most important sector in fintech sector and have to be pretty ahead of the curve of security. Thus, we were surprised at how easily we could find loopholes in these apps. Whatever these banks are doing is not enough for mobile app security,” said Agarwal.
While banks are still the most secure way of transferring money digitally when it comes to platforms like NEFT however, mobile apps, shares Agarwal, are a different ball game altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mobiles can be hacked in very different ways and the internal team at these banking institutions is not that great with mobile apps. The whole security landscape is very different when it comes to mobiles,” says Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A worrying statement indeed when the financial transactions are increasingly moving from websites to mobile apps with the proliferation of e-wallets and other payments systems.
Several mobile apps have sprung in the last couple of years providing users with ease of transacting online however, to prevent this ease from metamorphosing into a security disaster, the government is working keenly on regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The government is getting very strict when it comes to security. The central government recently made empanelment mandatory for any mobile app in bank payment gateway. Regulators have been proactive in ensuring that companies follow certain standards,” shares Agarwal.
NPCI, shares Agarwal, was quick to get banks to plug the loopholes found by the team at Appknox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about their experience with Appknox NPCI, Head of Risk Management, Bharat Panchal, said in a statement, “Appknox has been a crucial partner with us to ensure utmost security of our UPI-based application. We have had good early detection of vulnerabilities with the help of very energetic and brilliant security professionals. ”
The threat however, is persistent and transformative and both the government and the fintech institutions would need all the help they can find to keep hackers from digging into sensitive user information and thereby, to drive its digitisation push further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a never-ending race where hackers look for more loopholes and banking companies innovate to keep ahead. The problem is that banks and other fintech institutions rely on a single vendor for all their security concerns. What they do not realise is that there could be many brains working to break the system and relying on a single brain for security is really dangerous,” says Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appknox specialises in providing security to mobile apps and currently services 100 plus companies in the fintech sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM gives E-Wallets a run for money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BHIM — or the Bharat Interface For Money — is quickly becoming the favoured mobile payment solution for crores of Indians. Since its launch on December 31 till the end of February, the app had been downloaded 17 million times. Following its Android launch, BHIM is now also available on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is an extension of the Unified Payment System. It allows users to send and receive money through a mobile app that is linked to their bank savings account. This is an elegant solution compared to e-wallets that need to maintain a cash balance in order to be functional. Naturally, the question then arises: Should users switch to BHIM and simply spend from their banks, and stop using e-wallets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences between BHIM and e-wallets, and we’ll examine them here in order to help you understand the pros and cons of both ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bhim-vs-wallets-where-bhim-wins&#34;&gt;BHIM vs Wallets: Where BHIM Wins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Balance, loading &amp;amp; unloading:&lt;/em&gt; The first major difference between BHIM and UPI apps and e-wallets is how you maintain your spending balance. BHIM and UPI apps allow you to send and receive money with your bank account. You do not have to maintain a balance with the app. The app is your bank account, in a sense. But in e-wallets, you must maintain a balance in order to spend from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just that, returning your wallet balance back to your bank account will come with limitations and charges. But with BHIM and UPI, there is no need to send the money back from the app to the bank, since the money has been sitting in your account all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/em&gt; Another aspect where BHIM and UPI apps trump e-wallets. E-wallets do not have interoperability, meaning that if you are using Wallet X, you can only transfer money to another user on Wallet X, and not to a user operating Wallet Y. This isn’t a problem with BHIM, since you may move money between accounts with any bank on the BHIM platform. For example, you may be using an SBI account but you can send and receive money from users on ICICI or HDFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spending limits:&lt;/em&gt; BHIM and UPI score heavily here as well. E-wallets have a monthly spending limit of Rs 10,000 which can be raised to Rs 100,000 after the KYC process wherein users need to submit proof of ID and address in order to become authenticated. But BHIM allows a limit of Rs 10,000 per transaction and Rs 20,000 as the total worth of transactions in a 24-hour cycle. UPI apps go further, allowing you to spend up to Rs 100,000 per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-bhim-lags&#34;&gt;Where BHIM Lags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly two areas where e-wallets have an edge over UPI and BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marketing gimmicks:&lt;/em&gt; E-wallets have been around for a few years and they have had the time to build relationships with merchants and businesses. As a result, e-wallets are useful not just for money transfers but also for earning cashbacks and discounts. Not just that, some e-wallets also operate as e-commerce platforms allowing users to buy merchandise, electronics, tickets, etc. UPI and BHIM, on the other hand, are recent innovations and have some catching up to do in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit usage:* E-wallets allow you to link and spend from your credit card, allowing you to leverage the power of the credit available to you. BHIM works on simpler principles: you get to spend only if you have a bank balance, and you cannot link BHIM and UPI apps to your credit card account yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-bhim-is-catching-up&#34;&gt;How BHIM Is Catching Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest Union Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced a referral bonus and cashback scheme for BHIM users. “The government will launch two new schemes — a referral bonus for consumers and a cash-back scheme for merchants — to promote the use of BHIM,” Jaitley said during his budget speech. With these inclusions, BHIM will become a little more attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
Both e-wallets and UPI-based apps such as BHIM have a long way to go and a big role to play in India where internet penetration and smartphone usage are increasing by leaps and bounds every year. Both need to evolve in order to accommodate the changing needs of the Indian consumer in an increasingly less cash-dependent economy. However, at this point, you may want to have both BHIM and e-wallets installed on your smartphones. They both have some unique services to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BSNL Is Planning To Counter Reliance Jio, Airtel, Others</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new plan gives 2GB of 3G data per day at Rs 339&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlimited calling within its network is also applicable under the plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-run &lt;em&gt;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited&lt;/em&gt; (BSNL) announced a new plan which offers 2GB of 3G data per day with unlimited calling within its network for Rs 339. In an effort to take on the service providers like Reliance Jio, Airtel and others, BSNL will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks and after that the users will be charged 25 paise per minute. The company further said that the data of 2GB per day is one of the best in the industry. The limited offer for prepaid services comes with a validity of 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are committed to providing affordable and efficient services to all segment of our loyal mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL Director for Consumer Mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data and unlimited calling to all network till March 31. From April 1, users opting for Jio Prime service will get unlimited data and calls till March 31, 2018, for one time registration fee of Rs 99 and Rs 303 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharti Airtel has also introduced its &amp;lsquo;Surprise offer&amp;rsquo; which will give free 30GB data for three months, starting March 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers from Airtel or other operators comes in wake of the telecom war started by the new entrant Reliance Jio in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea To Sell 1GB 2G, 3G, 4G Mobile Data At Same Price From March End</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present, Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision in the wake of stiff competition in the market&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with a month validity for Rs 170&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular will start selling 1GB and above mobile data plans across its 2G, 3G and 4G network at same price by the end of this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Idea has now announced that it will allow open market data recharges of 1GB and above to work on Idea&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G or 4G network without any differential prices and this will be rolled out nationally by March 31, 2017,&amp;rdquo; Idea said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates. Due to stiff competition in the market from Reliance Jio, the 4G mobile data service of Idea is significantly cheaper than 2G service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the high speed data plans were priced higher based on their download speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customer can choose the recharge price basis usage and volume available in pack, without having to worry about the platform the customer&amp;rsquo;s device is logged in,&amp;rdquo; Idea Cellular Chief Marketing Officer Sashi Shankar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea will bring all data product categories like sachets, freedom packs to unified pricing and will be rolled out nationally in phases by May 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Idea&amp;rsquo;s pan India broadband coverage continues to expand and reduces gap with existing 2G coverage which covers 4 lakh towns and villages, customers can now seamlessly migrate services between technology &amp;amp; platform without worrying about differential costs,&amp;rdquo; Shankar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data limit in high speed internet plans gets exhausted in less time compared to that on slow speed network like 2G.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: BSNL Offers 2GB Data Per Day On Rs 339 Recharge</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-2gb-data-per-day-on-rs-339-recharge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-2gb-data-per-day-on-rs-339-recharge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analysts say incumbent telecom operators are coming up with attractive calling plans and lucrative data packs to counter additional competition triggered by Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry in the market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL is offering 2GB of 3G data per day and unlimited voice calling within its network under a special scheme priced at Rs 339. The &amp;ldquo;Combo STV&amp;rdquo; plan by state-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited or BSNL - for its prepaid customers - comes with a validity of 28 days, the telecom operator said in a statement. Analysts say incumbent telecom operators are coming up with attractive calling plans and lucrative data packs to counter additional competition triggered by Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSNL is offering 2GB of 3G data per day under a special recharge plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plan also offers unlimited voice calls on BSNL network&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telcos in India are giving attractive plans after Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special offer under its prepaid mobile services is in effect from March 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) The offer is limited for 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The &amp;ldquo;unlimited data&amp;rdquo; on offer will come with a &amp;ldquo;fair use policy&amp;rdquo; of 2 GB per day with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) BSNL is offering unlimited voice calls within its network. Calls outside the BSNL network will be for 25 minutes per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) After exhausting the 25-minute limit, the customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) &amp;ldquo;The data of 2GB per day is one of the best in the industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL added in its statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) &amp;ldquo;We are committed to providing affordable and efficient services to all segments of our loyal mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL director for consumer mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Religare analysts Rumit Dugar and Saumya Shrivastava believe the market could remain competitive for an extended period considering Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive revenue market share expectations. (Also read: 28 GB data for Rs 345: Airtel&amp;rsquo;s latest offer to counter Jio)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Reliance Industries&amp;rsquo; telecom arm - Reliance Jio Infocomm - is offering 1GB of 4G data per day and unlimited calling to all networks for free till March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) From April 1, Jio customers opting for its Prime service will continue to enjoy the unlimited calls and data benefits under its New Year Offer for a full year, till March 31, 2018. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime subscription will come at a one-time enrolment fee of Rs. 99 and &amp;ldquo;a rock-bottom introductory price” of only Rs 10 per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Proposal To Withdraw New 2,000 Rupee Notes: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday said there is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 notes that were introduced post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 denomination banknote,&amp;rdquo; the minister said in a written reply in the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley further said the Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes returned to currency chests of the RBI amounted to Rs 12.44 lakh crore (as on December 10, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data obtained in this regard would need to be reconciled with the physical cash balances to eliminate counterfeit notes, accounting errors and possible double counts after which only the final figures will be arrived at, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added that as on March 3, 2017 the currency in circulation was Rs 12 lakh crore and as on January 27, it was Rs 9.921 lakh crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley said the cash recall seeks to create a new &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; wherein the GDP will be bigger, cleaner and real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This exercise is part of the government&amp;rsquo;s resolve to eliminate corruption, blackmoney, counterfeit currency and terror funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This exercise has resulted in an increase in deposits with banks. This will facilitate reduction of interest rates and provide more headroom to banks to expand their credit base,&amp;rdquo; the minister said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation, several restrictions were imposed on withdrawal from banks as well as ATMs. The restrictions have been gradually removed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>