<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data hack: IIT Kharagpur graduate arrested, earns Rs 40 lakh a year at Ola</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</guid>
      <description>An IIT Kharagpur graduate, Abhinav Srivastava, who allegedly hacked Aadhaar data has been arrested by Bengaluru Police. According to investigation, Srivastava had gained access to the repository of the Unique Identification Development Authority of India’s (UIDAI) Aadhaar project through the Digital India e-hospital portal. The 31-year-old hails from Uttar Pradesh and was arrested in connection with a complaint filed by the UIDAI on July 26, according to Indian Express.
Police said the complaint against Srivastava stated that he accessed UIDAI data without authorisation between January 1 and July 26 for an app called ‘eKYC Verification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSNL Expects To Start 5G Service Trials By March 2018</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-expects-to-start-5g-service-trials-by-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-expects-to-start-5g-service-trials-by-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>The state-owned telecom firm BSNL expects to start field trial of 5G services by the end of this financial year, company&amp;rsquo;s chairman and MD Anupam Shrivastava said today.
&amp;ldquo;We had interaction with Nokia last week (on 5G). Next we are going to present about our requirements after which field trail concept is there. It should start before the end of this financial year,&amp;rdquo; Shrivastava told reporters today.
The state-run firm has started discussion with Larsen &amp;amp; Toubro and HP for end devices that will be required for 5G services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Without Aadhaar Enrolment Centres To Face Fine From October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-without-aadhaar-enrolment-centres-to-face-fine-from-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-without-aadhaar-enrolment-centres-to-face-fine-from-october/</guid>
      <description>The UIDAI has given banks one more month to open Aadhaar enrolment centres in a stipulated 10 per cent of branches and will impose Rs. 20,000 as fine per uncovered branch after September 30, CEO Ajay Bhushan Pandey said today.
The Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), in July, had asked private as well as public banks to open Aadhaar enrolment and updation facility in one out of 10 branches by August-end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customers’ consent must for use of Aadhaar-based e-KYC: IRDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-consent-must-use-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-irdai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-consent-must-use-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-irdai/</guid>
      <description>The use of Aadhaar and accessing of personal information of Unique Identity Authority of India (UIDAI) for e-Know Your Customer (e-KYC) purposes can only be done only on the voluntary consent of customer, the insurance regulator has said.
In a clarification on the existing circulars issued on the matter, the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (IRDAI) said that insurers can use the e-authentication facility being provided by UIDAI either through the fingerprint or iris scanning) or through one time password (OTP) received on client’s mobile number or on e-mail address registered with UIDAI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Attack Could Affect 143 Million Americans: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/equifax-hacked-massive-data-breach-could-affect-143-million-americans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/equifax-hacked-massive-data-breach-could-affect-143-million-americans/</guid>
      <description>US-based credit reporting agency Equifax Inc announced on Friday that hackers had gained access to the company&amp;rsquo;s data, potentially impacting approximately 143 million US consumers.
Hackers exploited a vulnerability in the company&amp;rsquo;s website application from mid-May through July and gained access to consumer information including names, Social Security numbers, birth dates, addresses and in some instances, driver&amp;rsquo;s license numbers, the agency said in a statement.
The breach also included credit card numbers of approximately 209,000 consumers and certain dispute documents with personal identifying information of approximately 182,000 consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadline for Linking Aadhaar with Govt Schemes is Now Dec 31</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/deadline-linking-aadhaar-govt-schemes-now-dec-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/deadline-linking-aadhaar-govt-schemes-now-dec-31/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court was informed on Wednesday the deadline for linking Aadhaar to various government schemes for benefits will be extended till December 31.
A bench of Chief Justice Dipak Misra, Justice Amitava Roy and Justice A.M. Khanwilkar said the challenge to the constitutional validity of the Aadhaar scheme would be heard in the first week of November.
Attorney General K.K. Venugopal told the court that the existing deadline of September 30 would be extended by three months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Celebrates One Year: Five Key Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-celebrates-one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-celebrates-one-year/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is celebrating its first birthday on Tuesday. The Mukesh Ambani-led mobile and internet service provider, which was commercially launched on September 5, 2016, keeps unleashing a plethora of offers, which have changed the landscape of the Indian telecom sector. As Jio sparked off an intense price war among the debt-ridden domestic telecom industry, its attractive offers have made key rivals like Bharti Airtel, Idea Cellular, Vodafone and even Mukesh’s younger brother Anil Ambani owned-Reliance Communications up the ante in terms of data and call offerings to retain customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with bank a/c at the earliest else you won’t get scholarship</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-bank-ac-earliest-else-wont-get-scholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-bank-ac-earliest-else-wont-get-scholarship/</guid>
      <description>If you are entitled for “Central Sector Scheme of Scholarship for College and University Students” and have not linked your bank account with Aadhaar, then do it as early as possible else you won’t be able to claim scholarship. This year, the central government has made it clear that scholarships will be disbursed only through Direct Benefit Transfer (DBT) and told state governments to ensure 100 per cent seeding of beneficiaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May Take 3 Months For Rs. 200 Note To Reach ATMs: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/may-take-3-months-for-rs-200-note-to-reach-atms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/may-take-3-months-for-rs-200-note-to-reach-atms/</guid>
      <description>While the RBI launched the 200-rupee note a week ago, it may take up to three months for ATMs to start dispensing the new denomination currency as it will involve a huge exercise of recalibration.
Some banks have even asked the ATM companies to begin testing the new note for recalibration of the machines, though they have not got supplies of the new currency. Only last year, the banks were involved in recalibration of ATM machines after the demonetisation of high-value currency notes in November.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now you can check if your bank account is linked to Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-check-if-your-bank-account-is-linked-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-check-if-your-bank-account-is-linked-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory for financial institutions, including banks, to verify and link Aadhaar of their customers with their accounts. According to a notification dated June 1, 2017, the deadline for doing this is December 31, 2017 (as of now), and accounts where this is not done are to be made inoperable after this date till the details are updated.
To comply with this directive, banks are now asking customers to submit their Aadhaar to link the same with their accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>