<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Mandatory For Filing Tax Returns, PAN Card From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting of Aadhaar has been made mandatory for filing income tax returns with effect from July 1, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, an official statement said on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961 as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017 provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar /Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from July 1,&amp;rdquo; said a Finance Ministry statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or Enrolment ID will apply only to a person who is eligible to obtain Aadhaar number, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act, 2016, only a resident individual is entitled to obtain Aadhaar. Resident as per the said Act means an individual who has resided in India for a period or periods amounting in all to 182 days or more in the 12 months immediately preceding the date of application for enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the requirement to quote Aadhaar as per section 139AA of the Income-tax Act shall not apply to an individual who is not a resident as per the Aadhaar Act, 2016, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar mandatory to avoid fake PAN cards: Government tells Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government today defended in the Supreme Court its decisionto make Aadhaar mandatory for issuing of PAN cards, saying it was done to curb the use of fake PAN cards across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi told a bench comprising Justices A K Sikri and Ashok Bhushan that the programme of PAN had become suspect as it could be faked while Aadhaar is a &amp;ldquo;secure and robust&amp;rdquo; system by which the identity of an individual cannot be faked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AG said that due to Aadhaar, government has saved over Rs 50,000 crore on the schemes to benefit the poor as well as the pension schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that around 10 lakh PAN cards have been cancelled, while out of the 113.7 crore Aadhaar cards issued, no case of duplication has been found by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that Aadhaar was an effective tool to check the menace of terror funding and circulation of black money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The idea behind Aadhaar is to make a secure and robust system by which the identity of a person cannot be faked,&amp;rdquo; the Attorney General told the court, which would continue hearing the arguments tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court is hearing three petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Section 139 AA of the Income Tax Act which was introduced through the latest budget and the Finance Act 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Section 139AA provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns and making an application for allotment of PAN number with effect from July 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior counsel Shyam Divan, representing the petitioners, had earlier argued that section 139AA was unconstitutional and was in &amp;ldquo;direct collision&amp;rdquo; with the Aadhaar Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had also contended that there was no question of forcing a person to give his consent for Aadhaar and this was an issue which &amp;ldquo;alters the relationship of Republic of India with its citizens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The petitioner had also argued that a law-abiding tax payer cannot be forced to give his Aadhaar number while filing income tax returns and this was like an &amp;ldquo;electronic leash&amp;rdquo; as government would be able to keep a tab on its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nowhere in the world there is such a biometric system which can track a person 24X7. They (government) are doing it even before the age of consent,&amp;rdquo; he had said during the arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had earlier put a poser as to why there was no objection from the lawmakers on the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for making PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rohatgi had also clarified that nowhere in section 139AA of IT Act, was it mentioned that it would be effective with retrospective effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had earlier told the apex court that fake PAN cards were being used to &amp;ldquo;divert funds&amp;rdquo; to shell companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Correct Aadhaar, PAN Details Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-aadhaar-pan-details-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-aadhaar-pan-details-online/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tax department has launched facilities to correct errors in PAN, Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has urged taxpayers to link Aadhaar with PAN immediately. This will be useful for e-verification of income tax returns using OTP (one-time password) sent to their mobile registered with Aadhaar, the tax department said. In this regard, the income tax department has launched an online facility to link Aadhaar with PAN, In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided by taxpayer when compared to the actual data in Aadhaar, One Time Password (Aadhaar OTP) will be sent to the mobile registered with Aadhaar. In rare cases where Aadhaar name is completely different from name in PAN, then the linking will fail and taxpayer will be prompted to change the name in either Aadhaar or in PAN database, the tax department said. For the benefit of taxpayers, the income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IT department has launched an online facility to link Aadhaar with PAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor mismatches in Aadhaar name and PAN name can be fixed with an OTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In rare cases a user will be prompted to change name in Aadhaar or PAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website - &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; - one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/graph_650x400_51494824521.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/pan_650x400_41494824562.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;2) The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for correcting data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The income tax department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has a new link on its homepage for connecting Aadhaar with PAN of a taxpayer.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/graph_650x400_51494824644.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;4) There is no need to log in or be registered on e-filing website of the income tax department. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The link requires a person to key in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact&amp;rdquo; name as mentioned on the Aadhaar card. After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR). Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN or permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ITR फाइल करने के लिए सभी फार्म वेबसाइट पर अपलोड, 31 जुलाई है अंतिम तिथि</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-itrs-for-e-filing-business-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-itrs-for-e-filing-business-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्‍स रिटर्न भरने के लिए इनकम टैक्‍स डिपार्टमेंट ने ई-फायलिंग के लिए सभी तरह के फार्म वेबसाइट पर उपलब्‍ध करा दिए हैं। यह फार्म ऐसेसमेंट ईयर 2017-18 के लिए आयकर रिटर्न भरने के लिए इस्‍तेमाल किए जाने हैं। 31 जुलाई तक आईटीआर फाइल किया जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए तैयार रखें यह दस्‍तावेज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्‍स विभाग ने बताया है कि जब ई-फायलिंग करने जा रहे हों कुछ दस्‍तावेज जरूर तैयार रखें। इन दस्‍तावेजों में पिछले साल का आईटीआर, बैंक स्‍टेटमेंट, टीडीएस और सेविंग के प्रमाणपत्र के अलावा फार्म 60 जरूरी दस्‍तावेज शामिल हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;आधार से करें ई-वेरीफिकेशन&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्‍स रिटर्न के ई-वेरीफिकेशन के लिए आधार नम्‍बर का इस्‍तेमाल किया जा सकता है। ऐसा करने से आईटीआर की कॉपी बंगलुरू भेजने की जरूरत नहीं रहती है। इनकम टैक्‍स विभाग के अनुसार अभी तक 2,59,831 लोग आधार से अपने आईटीआर वे‍रीफाई करा चुके हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;फायनेंस बिल में आधार की जानकारी देना किया गया जरूरी&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फायनेंस एक्‍ट 2017 में सरकार ने टैक्‍सपेयर के लिए आधार नम्‍बर की जानकारी देना जरूरी कर दिया है। अगर किसी के पास आधार नम्‍बर न हो तो उसे आधार के इनरोलमेंट की कॉपी लगानी होगी। आगामी 1 जुलाई से पेन नम्‍बर लेने के लिए आधार की जानकारी देना जरूरी होगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Savings Account Minimum Balance Requirement. Read Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. The minimum balance requirement for SBI customers varies depending on geographies such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural. If the minimum balance drops below a particular threshold, SBI will charge a fee from the account holder. SBI says the minimum balance in your savings bank account is the monthly average balance - the average of daily balances in the account during the month. SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holders of SBI&amp;rsquo;s savings bank account in urban areas need to maintain a monthly average balance (MAB) of Rs 3,000, Rs 2,000 in case of those in semi-urban areas and Rs 1,000 in rural areas. This was said on Thursday by SBI - which recently merged its operations with six other banks - on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting 31 crore depositors, SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For metropolitan areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Under 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For rural areas, the penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance ranges from Rs 20 to Rs 50 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI offers other types of accounts where it customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. Small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products offered SBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1. After the merger, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The biggest privacy risk is your smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-privacy-risk-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-privacy-risk-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Former UIDAI chairman Nandan Nilekani dispels privacy concerns surrounding Aadhaar and bats for biometric data protection and privacy laws in India&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks and months have witnessed a steady stream of negative news surrounding Aadhaar, the government’s unique identity number programme, with wide-ranging concerns being raised on the security of the system and the potential leakage of Aadhaar numbers by government departments. The government also received flak for making Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns. Then there are issues with the technology itself—the Aadhaar biometric authentication failure rate in the rural job guarantee scheme was as high as 36% in Telangana, as reported by Mint in April.
In an interview, Infosys co-founder and former Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) chairman Nandan Nilekani, the creator of Aadhaar, dispelled most of the concerns surrounding Aadhaar, especially around the security of the system, but conceded that there are areas where it can improve, while calling for the creation of a data-protection and privacy law. Edited excerpts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How big a problem is the current situation with the lack of a privacy law?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very clear that India needs a very modern privacy and data-protection law. And I’ve been saying this far longer than most people. Sometime in May of 2010, I wrote to Prime Minister Manmohan Singh that we should have a privacy law. And I followed that up. I asked Rahul Matthan (partner at Trilegal and a Mint columnist) and he helped. He worked with the department of administrative reforms and came out with a draft law and subsequently there was a committee under Justice A.P. Shah, and one of my colleagues (at UIDAI) Ashok Pal Singh was a member of that committee. They contributed to the framing of the principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue I have with the current narrative is, why should Aadhaar be singled out as a reason for the law? The biggest privacy risk that you have is your smartphone. A billion people will have smartphones as we go forward, their conversations will be recorded, their messages will be read, their location can be identified with the GPS or the triangulation of the towers on a real-time basis. So, for 24 hours a day, you know where a person is. Using all the accelerometers and gyrometers on the phone, you can actually make out if someone is drunk or not. The kind of intrusion of privacy that the smartphone does is order of magnitudes higher. Aadhaar is a sporadic thing—it is episodic, for instance, when I go and open an account, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second big privacy risk that we have are CCTV cameras—there doesn’t seem to be a law on these things. Every mall, every retailer, every ATM, every bus-stand, every railway station, every airport, every hotel has a CCTV camera. And now, we have CCTV combined with face recognition technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, we have the Internet companies and data collection. Indians are essentially giving data to companies that are essentially unaccountable to Indian law and that data is often shared with foreign governments as we have seen, time and again. There is more risk of Indians sharing data with foreign governments, than their own government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there are drones, or the Internet of Things, with sensors everywhere collecting data on you. So, when you look at it, there is a data tsunami that is coming due to a variety of things—(it has) nothing to do with Aadhaar as such. Given that, we should have a data-protection and privacy law which is an umbrella law, which looks at all these phenomena and certainly Aadhaar and the use of Aadhaar should be part of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s perfectly fine—but people are acting as if Aadhaar is the only reason why we should have a privacy law. That’s where I have a problem. We have a far bigger risk today from a cell-phone than Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why are we witnessing such reluctance from the government in terms of creating this legal framework around Aadhaar?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to have an internal champion in the system who will take it forward. It cuts across everything. There are a lot of stakeholder interests inside the government—so, it requires someone to champion it and lead it. In any case, we need a very modern data-protection law—data generation has become so huge now; all the current constructs of data laws were designed 10-15 years ago. If you look at the work happening in Europe with the generalized data protection regulations which come into effect next year, it was actually designed pre-big data. So, how do we design it (a privacy law) so that it operates in this massive data which is coming out of sensors, phones, etc? We need to rethink the entire concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These (current) laws were designed for a different era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Concerns have been raised around how Aadhaar is facilitating the creation of an Orwellian sort of surveillance state…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, this is another attempt to criticize and (create) this notion that Aadhaar is an instrument of mass surveillance. It’s complete nonsense. Your smartphone is a much better tool for the government to do surveillance than Aadhaar. Because Aadhaar by nature is episodic. I open a bank account once in a while. I buy a SIM card once in a while. If I use it for payments, I’ll use for low-value payments; I’ll use other means of authentication. So, it’s not really surveillance. By definition, a surveillance system is collecting data about you. The Aadhaar system does not collect data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s no limit to the amount of data the system can collect on individuals…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the Aadhaar system is concerned, what enters the system is very limited information and when you do an Aadhaar authentication, the Aadhaar authentication does not even know for what purpose that authentication has happened. It has been deliberately designed like that. Suppose I use it to do a financial transaction in a bank, the bank knows the financial transaction, but the Aadhaar system does not know. It’s deliberately designed like that. Real surveillance happens when data is accumulated which is what is happening in many organizations and that data is a black box. Nobody knows what’s happening with that data. And on top of that, you have black-box algorithms operating, which is what is happening. We have no idea what algorithms are being used today to feed you news or whatever. That is where the risks are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What happens in the event of a data breach? Unlike a credit card, one cannot block the Aadhaar card.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the Aadhaar system is extremely well-designed. It’s not an online system that is exposed to the Internet. When the enrolment happens, the packet is encrypted at source and sent, so that there can’t be a man-in-the-middle attack. And when the authentication happens, that is also encrypted—not compared to the original data, but to a digital minutiae. The point is that the system is very, very secure. So, if the objection is to centralization, then you should not have clouds. Clouds are also centralized. Everything today is centralized—otherwise, let’s all go back to pen and paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s a realization that we have this extraordinary transformation in governance platform—so, there is the willingness to use this platform to achieve more”- Nandan Nilekani
The point is that on Aadhaar authentication, a number of things are happening that make it even more secure because UIDAI has over the past couple of years come out with an architecture that is called registered devices. And registered devices have level-zero and level-one. Level-zero is software-based and level-one is hardware-based. Increasingly what is happening is that biometrics is now becoming common to every phone. When you’re using your phone, you’re giving your biometric to some company. For example, if you look at the latest Samsung Galaxy 8, it has something called Fort Knox—it’s a secure zone. So, secure hardware zones are now going to be standard in most of these—and this is military-grade security. So, in hardware-based registered devices, the biometric authentication details are captured and encrypted there itself. So that makes it even better and more secure. And the government or the Reserve Bank of India can say that all payment transactions should be only on level-one registered devices. So, it’s a continuous game of making things more and more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s also a perception of a general lack of transparency in terms of sharing concrete data from the UIDAI on how the system has done more good than harm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, every RTI (request under the Right to Information law) has been responded to. But I think the Aadhaar authentication with registered devices, especially with hardware-registered devices, will make it even more safe. The Aadhaar law limits what organizations can do when they do an eKYC (electronic Know Your Customer, a process of verifying the identity of customers) with the Aadhaar number. That law has to be rigorously enforced. The Aadhaar law is a very good law—in fact, the Aadhaar law has more privacy kind of details than most laws have. But I agree we need an overall data-protection and privacy law which covers everything, including foreign companies collecting data in India, including drones, Internet of Things, people reading your emails, smartphones, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But doesn’t the system need to be held accountable in the event of a breach of data? That doesn’t seem to be happening—for instance, a lot of things are being done in the name of national security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everywhere in the world national security exceptions are there. Everywhere in the world, the tension is between privacy and security because the security guys feel that if there is a criminal action, they should get access. Now, most countries do provide under national security, the ability to access very specific information—which is provided for in the Aadhaar law… I think instead of attacking Aadhaar which is a negative activity, everyone should get together and get the (privacy) law passed, which is a positive activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Given the developments of the past few weeks and months, is the Aadhaar law in need of an overhaul? Does the legal framework around Aadhaar need to be re-examined to ensure that the scope of the program is not abused?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aadhaar law which was passed in 2016 governs the UIDAI’s authority, which as I said has better privacy protection than any other law that I can think of and it has a lot of checks and balances. That’s one part. Then there’s the use of Aadhaar which is done by other laws. For example, in the Finance Bill, they say Aadhaar should be mandatory for PAN (permanent account number) Card. That’s got nothing to do with Aadhaar, that’s a legal provision in another law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly four purposes to the use of Aadhaar: first, the feature of Aadhaar, which is unique only to Aadhaar and no other system, is that it gives a unique ID across a billion people—you can be sure that somebody does not have more than one ID; second, Aadhaar is used to do direct benefit transfer by sending money to the Aadhaar number which in turn is linked to a bank where your account is; third, Aadhaar is as an online authentication system; and the fourth use of Aadhaar is as an electronic KYC where I give permission to the Aadhaar system to release my name and address to the bank and I get an instant bank account or an instant SIM card. So, four very different uses of one platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first use has a used case in both benefits as well as documents. In benefits, you want to eliminate ghosts and duplicates. You want to make sure there are no fake pensioners, etc. We’ve already seen the value of the savings that the government has got. The government has said that the savings is somewhere around Rs49,000 crore. The total investment in Aadhaar is around Rs8,000-9,000 crore. The impact is there to be seen….a variation of the duplicate problem is in documents. India has 250 million PAN (cards). And only 40 million Indians are paying taxes. Why should there be 250 million PAN (cards) and only 40 million taxpayers? Many people have taken PAN for ID proof. But even when you discount the people who have PAN for ID, there are still many duplicate PAN (cards). The reason is that there are people who want to evade taxes. But having the Aadhaar number de-duplicate PAN numbers you’re actually making sure that a guy has only one PAN number and that will help in eliminating tax evasion, so that’s a good social purpose. Similarly, the mobile phone using Aadhaar-eKYC actually came out of a Supreme Court decision. Now, in the old days, you used to submit a copy of your passport or an ID proof, to get a SIM card. Now, that’s even more unsafe—because that fellow now has all your data. Secondly, 10 other people will get a SIM using your details—you don’t know. Even though we have a billion phones, we have about 600 million unique users, is my estimate. And even in that, how many of them have given a genuine ID to get a phone? I don’t know. The same story is playing out with driving licences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is still concern around all this data being centralized…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, the data is not in one system—that’s the whole point. The data is in respective systems. The Aadhaar number is in the PAN database. The PAN number is not in the Aadhaar database… that’s the point. The Aadhaar database does not have any data. This is a conscious design choice, which is why to say that the system is for surveillance makes no sense. The nature of surveillance requires you to collect data. This does not collect data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But then why is Aadhaar become all-pervasive? Why is Aadhaar being made mandatory for everyone?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, there’s a realization that we have this extraordinary transformation in governance platform—so, there is the willingness to use this platform to achieve more. All the goals that we’ve identified are all the things that improve governance: making sure there’s one PAN card reduces tax evasion; making sure that a person has done a proper KYC reduces criminality and terrorism; making sure that a person has only one driver’s licence makes it easier to enforce the rules of the road, which makes it safer for you and me to travel on the roads… So everything that has been done is being done to ensure that it enhances the quality of governance. Now if the concern is of privacy, I’ve made my position clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Instead of attacking Aadhaar, which is a negative activity, everyone should get together and get the (privacy) law passed, which is a positive activity.”- Nandan Nilekani
In everything in life, there’s always a trade-off between privacy and convenience. There’s no absolute privacy, there’s no absolute convenience. In our view, the benefits of the Aadhaar system to individuals and society far outweigh the inconvenience or the risk. Everything in life is a risk. You always see how you balance these out. But the benefits here are so huge, it’s worth anything—and obviously the obligation of the Aadhaar system is to ensure that things are done properly and nobody is denied benefits. As technology evolves, you make things better and safer. Within seven years of its launch, the Aadhaar system has made a remarkable leap in terms of its security and privacy and it will keep improving. Technology does not come through immaculate conception. It has to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speaking of evolution, what are some of things that still need to be fixed in the system?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, I agree we need a privacy law, covering everything. Secondly, we need to implement (the concept of) registered devices as soon as possible. The first launch is by June… Also, the Aadhaar law already provides that anyone who uses the Aadhaar number cannot display the number or publish it, so that enforcement has to happen. We have to make sure that any user of this, whether it’s the government or the private sector, follows the law of (for?) the protection of the Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protection of numbers and preventing leakages have been a massive issue…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know the government has sent a notice to everyone. If somebody has done it, they ought not to have done it—there’s a law for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even with these kind of checks and balances, why are so many concerns being raised on the security of the system?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very safe. Security is an ongoing thing. You have to keep improving and getting better. You have to keep doing that and I’m sure the guys (at UIDAI) are aware of that. The methods followed here, the architecture, the encryption, the use of HSM (hardware security module)—all these are way above what we’ve seen anywhere. You saw what happened with debit cards in India—there the breach happened and wasn’t noticed for months. In the Aadhaar system, we’ve caught these guys within 24 hours. The point is, as I said, technology will keep getting better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Several experts on security have pointed out flaws in the system and said Aadhaar can be breached. There’s also a general sense that the UIDAI is being reluctant to invite people to help improve security or point out flaws.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to know which government system has been as open as UIDAI has. The kind of documentation that we have put out right from day 1, design documentation, architecture documentation, standards, etc—it’s incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something is built at scale, there will be points of view on that. And if there are any gaps, they have to be addressed. That’s how we move forward. But when it’s a motivated campaign where the agenda is something else, then you have to deal with it differently. I’m all for learning and reforming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-facility to link Aadhaar with PAN launched</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I-T Department asks people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched an e-facility to link Aadhaar with Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing IT returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department’s e-filing website &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; has created the link on its homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires the PAN, the Aadhaar number and the “exact name as given in the Aadhaar card”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After verification from the UIDAI [Unique Identification Authority of India], the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in the Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP [one time password] will be required,” the department said in an advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OTP would be sent on the registered mobile number and email of an individual, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department urged people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no need to login or be registered on the e-filing website. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of the Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a 10-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>keep your computer safe from WannaCry 10 Do’s and Don’ts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-ransomware-scare-10-dos-and-donts-to-keep-your-computer-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-ransomware-scare-10-dos-and-donts-to-keep-your-computer-safe/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-is-a-list-of-do-s-and-don-ts-which-you-should-follow-to-keep-your-computer-safe&#34;&gt;Here is a list of Do’s and Don’ts which you should follow to keep your computer safe:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to immediately install the May Windows Update bundles. Shutting down your system for a few minutes will be worth it, if it enables you to avoid this. If you’re still using Windows XP, you’re out of luck, but the March and April update bundles are available for Windows Vista. Also, Microsoft has released a patch for Windows XP and its server counterpart Windows 2003.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to prevent the infection, users and organisations should apply relevant patches to Windows systems as mentioned in the Microsoft Security Bulletin MS17-010. The malware has been targeting commonly used office file extensions such as .ppt (PowerPoint), .doc and .docx (Word), .xlsx (Excel), and image file extensions such as .tiff, .raw, among various other common file types for archiving, emails, databases, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This attack type may evolve over time, so any additional defense-in-depth strategies will provide additional protections. (For example, to further protect against SMBv1 attacks, customers should consider blocking legacy protocols on their networks).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As part of the best practices to prevent ransomware attacks, users should maintain an updated antivirus software, regularly check for integrity of the information stored on databases, to not open attachments in unsolicited e-mails, restrict users’ ability to install and run unwanted software applications, among various others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals or organisations are not encouraged to pay the ransom, as this does not guarantee files will be released. Report such instances of fraud to CERT-In and law enforcement agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform regular backups of all critical information to limit the impact of data or system loss and to help expedite the recovery process. Ideally, this data should be kept on a separate device, and backups should be stored offline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CERT-In advisory: Block SMB ports on Enterprise Edge/perimeter network devices [UDP 137, 138 and TCP 139, 445] or Disable SMBv1. &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/2696547&#34;&gt;http://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/2696547&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t open attachments in unsolicited e-mails, even if they come from people in your contact list, and never click on a URL contained in an unsolicited e-mail, even if the link seems benign. In cases of genuine URLs close out the e-mail and go to the organisation’s website directly through browser&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deploy web and email filters on the network. Configure these devices to scan for known bad domains, sources, and addresses; block these before receiving and downloading messages. Scan all emails, attachments, and downloads both on the host and at the mail gateway with a reputable antivirus solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;USE THESE TOOLS:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tool (NoMoreCry) to prevent Wannacry Ransomware by CCN-CERT:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sophos: Hitman.Pro&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Malwarebytes Anti-Ransomware(formally Crypto Monitor)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trendmicro Ransomware Screen Unlocker tool&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Enhanced mitigation and experience toolkit(EMET)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>खातों की कम जानकारी देने वाले करदाता जांच के दायरे में</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने सत्यापन के लिए 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान की है, जिसमें 1.58 लाख करदाता ऐसे शामिल हैं, जिन्होंने पिछले दिनों अपने खातों की आंशिक घोषणा की थी। नोटबंदी के बाद इंकम टैक्स विभाग को बैंकों द्वारा दायर वित्तीय लेनदेन के बयान (एसएफटी) सहित विभिन्न स्रोतों से कई अहम जानकारी मिली। आईटी विभाग ने कहा कि इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने 1.58 लाख करदाताओं से संबंधित 3.71 लाख नए खातों की पहचान की है, जिन्होंने पहले अपने अकाउंट के बारे में जानकारी दी थी। पहले 18 लाख मामलों के अलावा, 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान ई-वेरिफेकेशन से की गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट पहले से उप्लब्ध डेटा की मदद से विश्लेषण कर रहा है। इस डेटा की मदद से ई-वेरिफिकेशन के लिए नए मामलों की पहचान हो चुकी है। 31 जनवरी को आई-टी विभाग द्वारा शुरू किए गए &amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; के तहत 17.92 लाख लोगों को एसएमएस और ई-मेल भेजे गए हैं, जिन्होंने 10 नवंबर से 30 दिसंबर के बीच 5 लाख और उससे ज्यादा पैसे जमा किए हैं। इनमें से 9 .72 लाख लोगों ने नकदी जमा के स्रोतों पर जवाब दिया है। विभाग ने उन मामलों में वेरिफिकेशन बंद करने का निर्णय लिया है, जहां नकदी के स्रोत का पूरा ब्यौरा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;करदाताओं ने करीब 2.8 9 लाख करोड़ रुपये के नकदी जमा से जुड़े 13.33 लाख खातों के लिए जवाब दे दिए हैं। ऑनलाइन प्रतिक्रियाओं का आंकलन कर खातों की सही जानकारी देने वालों के मामलों में आगे कोई कार्रवाई नहीं की जाएगी। विभाग ने दो विशेष डेटा ऐनालिटिकल एजेंसियों और एक व्यावसायिक प्रक्रिया प्रबंधन एजेंसी को बड़ी मात्रा में नकद जमा के डेटा का विश्लेषण करने, करदाताओं की अनुपालन स्थिति और रिपोर्टिंग संस्थाओं का पता लगाने की जिम्मेदारी दी है। नकदी जमा के सोर्स के रूप में नकद बिक्री का दावा करने वाले पेट्रोल पंप व्यापारियों और संपत्ति खरीददारों जैसे व्यापारों की विस्तृत जांच की जाएगी, जिनका कैश सेल उनके नकद जमा की तुलना में ज्यादा पाया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जानें, क्रेडिट कार्ड के बेहद &#39;खास&#39; फायदे</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड रखना यानी उधार की जिंदगी जीना, अरे यह हम नहीं कह रहे बल्कि आमतौर पर इस तरह की बातें हमारे आसपास के लोग बोलते दिख जाते हैं। अगर आप भी ऐसा ही सोचते हैं तो अगले कुछ मिनट्स में आपके यह सोच बदलने वाली है। जी हां, आज हम आपको बता रहे हैं क्रेडिट कार्ड रखने के कुछ बेहद खास फायदे&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-ब-क&#34;&gt;कैश बैक&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कई क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां कुछ खास ब्रैंड्स के साथ 10 से 20 प्रतिशत तक का कैश बैक ऑफर देती हैं। यानी कैशलेश पेमेंट भी करिए और बचत भी पाइए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;र-व-र-ड-प-इ-ट&#34;&gt;रिवॉर्ड पॉइंट&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कैैश बैक के अलावा सभी क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां प्रत्येक ट्रांजैक्शन के वेट के अनुसार पॉइंट्स देती हैं। पॉइंट्स आपके खाते में जुड़ते जाते हैं और बाद में आप इन्हें रिडीम कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-र-ड-ट-ह-स-ट-र&#34;&gt;क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड के प्रयोग से आप अपनी क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री अपने साथ रख सकते हैं। यानि आपको पता रहता है कि आपने कब कहां कितना पैसा खर्च किया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-क-झ-झट-नह&#34;&gt;कैश का झंझट नहीं&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड का सबसे बड़ा फायदा यह है कि आपको इस बात की चिंता करने की नहीं जरूरत होती है कि बैंक में बैलेंस है या नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;emi-क-व-कल-प&#34;&gt;EMI का विकल्प&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अगर आपका मन कोई बड़ी चीज खरीदने का है, लेकिन पैसे नहीं, तो क्रेडिट कार्ड से खरीद कर आप उस पैसे को ईएमआई यानि किश्तों में बदल सकते हैं। कई बार क्रेडिट कार्ड जीरो प्रतिशत ब्याज पर ईएमआई देते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पहली बार एक साथ 10 न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर्स के निर्माण को सरकार ने दी मंजूरी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-expansion-of-nuclear-power-industry-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-expansion-of-nuclear-power-industry-union/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वर्तमान में कुल 22 रिएक्टर चलाए जा रहे हैं। नए रिएक्टर्स पुरानों की तुलना में ज्यादा क्षमता वाले हैं।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देश की न्यूक्लियर पावर इंडस्ट्री में अभी तक का सबसे बड़ा विस्तार करते हुए केन्द्रीय मंत्रिमंडल ने बुधवार को 10 नए न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर के निर्माण को मंजूरी दे दी है। यह पहली बार है जब इतनी संख्या में न्यूक्लियर रिएक्टर्स को एक साथ मंजूरी मिली हो। वर्तमान में कुल 22 रिएक्टर चलाए जा रहे हैं। नए&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रिएक्टर्स पुरानों की तुलना में ज्यादा क्षमता वाले हैं। पुराने 20 रिएक्टर्स 220 MWe (मेगा वॉट इलेक्ट्रिक) वाले और 2005 व 2006 में तारापुर में लगाए गए दो रिएक्टर 540 MWe क्षमता वाले हैं। वहीं, नए रिएक्टर्स की क्षमता 700 MWe होगी। यह दस रिएक्टर्स राजस्थान के माही बंसवाड़ा (यूनिट 1, 2, 3, 4), हरियाणा के गोरखपुर (यूनिट 3 और 4), कर्नाटक के कैगा (यूनिट 5 और 6) और मध्य प्रदेश के चुटका (यूनिट 1 और 2) में लगाए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इसके अलावा बिजली घरों को कोयले की पर्याप्त आपूर्ति सुनिश्चित करने के लिये बुधवार को सरकार ने एक नई कोयला आपूर्ति व्यवस्था संबंधी नीति को मंजूरी दे दी। इसके तहत बिजली क्षेत्र को ईंधन की आपूर्ति नीलामी मार्ग या प्रतिस्पर्धी बोली प्रक्रिया पर आधारित बिजली खरीद करार (पीपीए) के तहत होगी। प्रधानमंत्री&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नरेंद्र मोदी की अध्यक्षता में हुई मंत्रिमंडल की आर्थिक मामलों की समिति (सीसीईए) की बैठक में यह फैसला किया गया। इस कदम से बिजली क्षेत्र की परियोजनाओं को कोयले आपूर्ति उपलब्ध न होने की समस्या को दूर किया जा सकेगा।
बिजली घरों के लिये इस नई कोयला आपूर्ति व्यवस्था से उत्पादकों को व्यवस्थित तरीके से ईंधन की आपूर्ति करने में मदद मिलेगी। सूत्रों के अनुसार सरकार के प्रयास और अंतरराष्ट्रीय बाजार की परिस्थितियों से इस शुष्क ईंधन के दाम नीचे लाने में मदद मिली है और घरेलू उत्पादन बढ़ा है। लेकिन बिजली संयंत्रों को प्रतिस्पर्धी दरों पर कोयला संपर्क उपलब्ध कराने के लिये एक प्रणाली की जरूरत है। सूत्रों का कहना है कि नई नीति से यह चिंता दूर होगी और बिजली घरों के लिये उनकी जरूरत के मुताबिक कोयले की आपूर्ति के वास्ते उचित प्रणाली तैयार होगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>हर स्कीम के लिए अनिवार्य न हो आधार: SC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-cant-be-mandatory-for-social-welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-cant-be-mandatory-for-social-welfare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने सोमवार को कहा कि सरकार की समाज कल्याण योजनाओं का लाभ उठाने के लिए आधार बायोमीट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन को अनिवार्य नहीं बनाया जा सकता। देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत ने कहा कि सरकार चाहे तो दूसरे क्षेत्रों में आधार को अनिवार्य बना सकती है, जो समाज कल्याण के कार्यक्रमों से नहीं जुड़े हैं। बैंक खाता खोलना ऐसा एक काम हो सकता है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट की जिस बेंच ने यह बात कही, उसमें चीफ जस्टिस जे एस खेहर, जस्टिस डी वाई चंद्रचूड़ और जस्टिस संजय किशन कौल शामिल थे। सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने पहले भी आधार को सभी समाज कल्याण योजनाओं के लिए लाभुकों की पहचान के लिए आधार को अकेला मानक बनाने के खिलाफ आदेश दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चीफ जस्टिस ने कहा कि आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने का मामला महत्वपूर्ण है और इसकी सुनवाई सात जजों की संवैधानिक बेंच के सामने होनी चाहिए, लेकिन उन्होंने तुरंत यह बेंच बनाने में असमर्थता जताई। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह बेंच बनाई जाएगी।&amp;rsquo; अभी सात सदस्यों वाली बेंच के लिए जज ढूंढना मुश्किल हो सकता है। इस महीने के अंत तक तीन जजों की नियुक्ति होने की उम्मीद है। चीफ जस्टिस ने उनके जॉइन करने के बाद अहम मामलों पर विचार करने के लिए संवैधानिक बेंच बनाने का वादा किया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुप्रीम कोर्ट के सोमवार के आदेश का मतलब यह है कि सरकार कल्याणकारी योजनाओं के लाभुकों की पहचान के लिए आधार का इस्तेमाल कर सकती है, लेकिन इसके न होने पर वह लाभ देने से इनकार नहीं कर सकती। सार्वजनिक वितरण प्रणाली या एलपीजी सब्सिडी कल्याणकारी योजना के दायरे में आते हैं। मान लीजिए कि किसी शख्स के पास आधार नंबर नहीं है तो वह इन फायदों को हासिल करने के लिए पहचान के दूसरे सबूतों का इस्तेमाल कर सकता है। देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत पहले भी यह बात कह चुकी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वकील श्याम दीवान ने कई पक्षों की तरफ से आधार बेस्ड आइडेंटिफिकेशन को अनिवार्य बनाने का विरोध किया था। उन्होंने कहा था कि इससे किसी शख्स की प्राइवेसी के लिए खतरा पैदा हो सकता है। इसके बाद सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने मामले पर त्वरित सुनवाई का निर्णय लिया। आधार का इस्तेमाल अभी पेंशन स्कीम के लाभुकों की पहचान, प्रविडेंट फंड और प्रधानमंत्री जन धन योजना के लिए किया जा रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 जुलाई से इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए भी इसे अनिवार्य बनाया गया है। आधार को स्कॉलरशिप स्कीम्स और स्कूलों में मिड डे मील स्कीम्स से भी जोड़ा जा रहा है। श्याम दीवान ने यह आरोप भी लगाया था कि केंद्र सरकार आधार के मामले में देश की सबसे बड़ी अदालत के कई आदेशों की अवहेलना कर रही है। इस मामले में उन्होंने ड्राइविंग लाइसेंस के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने जैसे मामलों का जिक्र किया। उन्होंने कहा था कि इस तरह से सरकार अदालत की अवमानना कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>