<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी 2.0&#39; के लिए पोर्टल बना रहा I-T विभाग</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/it-department-building-portal-for-operation-clean-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/it-department-building-portal-for-operation-clean-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ऐसे लोगों की जांच के लिए एक खास पोर्टल बना रहा है, जिन्होंने अपनी घोषित आमदनी से कहीं ज्यादा जमा किए हैं या बड़ी खरीदारियां की हैं। सीबीडीटी यह कदम ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत उठा रहा है। उस अभियान को नोटबंदी के मद्देनजर काले धन पर लगाम कसने के लिए शुरू किया गया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह प्रस्ताव प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी के सामने राजस्व विभाग की हालिया समीक्षा बैठक में रखा गया था। चर्चा की जानकारी रखने वाले एक उच्च अधिकारी ने ईटी को बताया, &amp;lsquo;हम एक पोर्टल पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो खास इसी मकसद के लिए होगा।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह उन लोगों के लिहाज से विकसित किया जाएगा, जिनकी पहचान ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत हुई थी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह पोर्टल ऐसे लोगों और टैक्स अथॉरिटीज के बीच संवाद का जरिया बनेगा। यह संवाद PAN के जरिए होगा। डिपार्टमेंट इस प्रोसेस में मानव हस्तक्षेप की गुंजाइश यथासंभव कम रखना चाहता है और जोर ई-असेसमेंट पर है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी का दूसरा चरण हाई-रिस्क लोगों पर केंद्रित होगा, जिन्होंने ज्यादा वैल्यू वाले ट्रांजैक्शंस किए थे। ऐसे लोगों की विस्तृत जांच की जाएगी। डेटा एनालिटिक्स के जरिए ऐसे 60,000 से ज्यादा लोगों की पहचान डिपार्टमेंट कर चुका है। जिन मामलों में गहराई से पड़ताल की तैयारी है, वे ज्यादा डिपॉजिट्स के अलावा ज्यादा कीमत की खरीद-फरोख्त से जुड़े हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने कहा कि इस डेडिकेटेड पोर्टल से टैक्स अथॉरिटीज और संदेह के घेरे में आए लोगों के बीच बिना जोर-जबरदस्ती के संवाद पर फोकस सुनिश्चित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पीएम को ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के बारे में डिटेल्ड रिप्रेजेंटेशन दिया गया था और यह भी बताया गया था कि सीबीडीटी ने कौन से कदम उठाए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी को नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद शुरू किया गया था। इसका मकसद अघोषित आमदनी रखने वालों को टैक्स के दायरे में लाना था। डिपार्टमेंट ने लगभग 18 लाख लोगों की पहचान की थी, जिनसे एसएमएस और ईमेल से संपर्क किया गया था और उनसे उनके डिपॉजिट्स पर सफाई मांगी गई थी। ऐसे लोगों से कहा गया था कि या तो वे टैक्स चुकाएं या प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के जरिए पहले की अघोषित आमदनी का खुलासा करें।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनमें से लगभग 10 लाख लोग ई-वेरिफिकेशन प्रोसेस में शामिल हुए थे। डिपार्टमेंट वित्त वर्ष 2017 में करीब 95 लाख नए करदाताओं को कर के दायरे में लाने में सफल रहा। पिछले साल 8 नवंबर को नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद पैन के लिए ऐप्लिकेशंस की संख्या भी बढ़ी क्योंकि विभाग ने बैंकों को निर्देश दिया था कि सभी खातों को PAN से जोड़ा जाए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डिपार्टमेंट को PAN के लिए रोज करीब 173000 आवेदन मिले, जबकि नोटबंदी के पहले इनकी औसत संख्या 83000 हआ करती थी। कुछ दिनों में इनकी तादाद 300000 तक चली गई। डिपार्टमेंट ने 8 नवंबर 2016 सके 31 मार्च 2017 के बीच 4.65 करोड़ PAN अलॉट किए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 GB Free Data: Vodafone&#39;s Latest Offer In Response To Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September, incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Vodafone is also currently offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone is giving &lt;em&gt;9 GB data&lt;/em&gt; free to customers in a special scheme, its latest offer to counter Reliance Jio which has come up with aggressive tariff plans. &amp;ldquo;Thank you for making us a 200 million strong family! As a token of appreciation, we are happy to delight you with free data on your Vodafone mobile,&amp;rdquo; Vodafone said. A Vodafone customer care executive said the 9 GB free data offer has been made to select customers. The 9 GB free data will be applicable &lt;em&gt;at 3 GB/month&lt;/em&gt; for three billing cycles. Vodafone said this 9GB offer is in addition to &amp;ldquo;existing data quota on your plan/pack at no extra cost&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September,&lt;/em&gt; incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Currently, Vodafone is also offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New entrant Reliance Jio has kept the pressure on other operators to cut tariffs and make special offers to customers. Jio&amp;rsquo;s current &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans offer &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs. 309.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Vodafone said that it will offer free incoming calls during international roaming on its network in 45 countries at a daily rental of Rs. 500 along with all international and local outgoing calls for Rs. 1 a minute. In the countries where Vodafone operates, the customer will get 1 megabyte of mobile internet for Rs. 1 which implies 1 GB of data will cost them Rs. 1,024. &amp;ldquo;Keeping in mind the requirements of international travelers, Vodafone had recently introduced the i-RoamFREE proposition offering free incoming calls, Re 1 for all international and local outgoing calls and data at Re 1 per MB in over 45 countries on a daily basis,&amp;rdquo; Vodafone said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price war for data subscribers has dented the bottom lines of wireless telecom service providers, yet none of them is likely to pull a punch, Crisil said in a report. If anything, competition will only heat up further given that market leadership is all-crucial to the business, it said. The proposed merger between Idea and Vodafone - which marks the biggest consolidation in the Indian telecom sector - is also part of this quest to strengthen market position, alongside lowering investment needs and costs, Crisil added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been reported that a new ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; is spreading widely, the RBI advisory to the banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wannacry encrypts the files on infected Windows system and spreads by exploiting vulnerabilities, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI also asked all banks to put in place a software update at ATMs to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate malware attack last year, 3.2 lakh debit cards were compromised in the country. Data of the users who transacted from ATM machines of Hitachi were compromised during May, June and July last year. The Hitachi ATMs deployed by many White Label ATM players and Yes Bank were impacted by the malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, ATMs or automated teller machines are highly vulnerable to such malware attacks as they currently run on old version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, making a software security patch update a necessary exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a total of 2.2 lakh ATMs in India, of which many old ones run on Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, the ransomware has hit systems in more than 150 countries, including Russia and the UK, in one of the most widespread cyber attacks in history. It infected computers running on older versions of Microsoft operating systems like XP, locking access to files on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cyber criminals have demanded a fee of about $300 in crypto-currencies like Bitcoin for unlocking the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has introduced a security patch to tackle the situation, and consumers across the globe have been advised to download the solution at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CERT-In on Monday said it has not received any formal report of cyber attack on India&amp;rsquo;s vital networks by the crippling global ransomware, &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) had said on Sunday that a few systems of the Police Department in Andhra Pradesh were impacted and that the state government has been informed to follow the advisory by the CERT-In.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the Maharashtra Police department said it was partially hit by the ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the alert, the Gujarat government began equipping its state computer systems with anti-virus software and upgrading its Microsoft operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the advisory issued by CERT-In, the ransomware infects other computers on the same network and is also spreading through malicious attachments to e-mails. Security firms have suggested that users immediately disconnect the infected device from the local network to contain the spread of infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, major companies including telecommunications firm Telefonica have been infected. The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avoid Queue At SBI Branches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is offering a virtual queue ticket or &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo; service through its newly-launched app No Queue, which enables customers to avail select banking services at its select branches without having to stand in queues. SBI customers &amp;ldquo;can book a virtual token&amp;hellip;and skip the queue,&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI said on Twitter. SBI&amp;rsquo;s No Queue app was launched by the bank&amp;rsquo;s chairperson Arundhati Bhattacharya in March this year. The mobile-based virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores. &amp;ldquo;The Application is designed to save customers&amp;rsquo; valuable time, avoid queue for Banking services and aims to provide the customers with a better customer service experience,&amp;rdquo; SBI had said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user can select a minimum of one and maximum five services in virtual ticket using No queueapp, as per the SBI website. Here are few other things to know about the No Queue app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers a variety of services under the &amp;lsquo;no queue&amp;rsquo; facility. Some of these include cheque deposit, cash deposit/withdrawal, demand draft, NEFT/RTGS and loan account opening/maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The No Queue app empowers those interested in SBI&amp;rsquo;s banking services to efficiently book a virtual token without being physically present in the branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app provides &amp;ldquo;real time status notification of your position in the queue&amp;rdquo;, as per its description on Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers can generate an e-token before being physically present in the branch. This way, he or she avoids waiting in a queue and saves time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app conveys the estimated waiting time, the number of customers ahead in the queue and the distance to the branch from the point of booking, SBI has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers will be updated about their position in the queue through alerts, according to the app&amp;rsquo;s description on Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-book-e-token&#34;&gt;Who can book &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals - SBI and non-SBI customers - registered on the No Queue app installed on their devices can avail this facility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-use&#34;&gt;How to use&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user can register on the No Queue app by entering basic information such as name and mobile number to start using the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a virtual ticket is generated through the No Queue app, the customer will receive a notification about his or her position in the queue. A button that says &amp;lsquo;Activate&amp;rsquo; will be available on the app when the customer reaches the fifth position in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reaching the branch, a customer activating the queue ticket will be &amp;ldquo;serviced immediately, thus avoiding waiting time at the Branch&amp;rdquo;, the press release added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;can-i-reschedule-my-visit&#34;&gt;Can I reschedule my visit?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After booking a virtual ticket, customers also have the facility of rescheduling or renewing the ticket in case they are running late. The rescheduling option will be available only until when the customer is within the first five positions in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile number will be deactivated if not linked with Aadhaar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mobile-number-will-deactivated-not-linked-aadhaar-card-heres-can-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mobile-number-will-deactivated-not-linked-aadhaar-card-heres-can-link/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government had in March 2017, had announced that Aadhaar-based e-KYC (know your customer) will be made mandatory for mobile phone connections. The department of telecommunications (DoT) had then ordered all mobile operators to verify the details of the existing customers by using their unique Aadhaar identity number and biometric details by early 2018. Aadhaar-based e-KYC will also be made compulsory for customers who have to get new SIM cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Airtel and Idea have begun the process of completing this verification. The two service providers are sending messages to their customers to initiate the KYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A message in Airtel store reads: “Link your Aadhaar card to your number now to stay active! As per the Government of India, this is mandatory to enjoy continued services”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To save yourself from getting your services discontinued, here is your guide to link your Aadhaar card with your mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to link the phone number to your Aadhaar card?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• As soon as you receive the SMS, go to the nearby store of your operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Take your Aadhaar card along and give the details there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• After this, you will receive a 4 digit verification code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Once the code is confirmed, fingerprint verification will be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Within 24 hours, you will get another message for “Final verify”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Reply to that message with “Y”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• You will get an SMS that your number is linked to the Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;clear-your-doubts-with-these-answers&#34;&gt;Clear your doubts with these answers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do I need to pay any charges?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is free and you need to get it done through an operator’s store only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can I do online registration?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, don’t go behind any online registration sites, as they are fake. The process is manual and as of now, only offline registration facility is available. Telecom operators haven’t started online registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s the last date?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last date is 6th of February 2018. Do it as soon as possible as it is rightly said, “Sooner the better”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can the Aadhaar card be linked to multiple SIM cards?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you can link it. However, a limit has been set for maximum connections. You need to find it out from your operator store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions mentioned above and get your card linked as soon as possible. It is better to be safe than sorry; following the rule at the earliest will not only benefit you, but will also ensure that you don’t face any issues later on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI&#39;s New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1. SBI has clarified that the Rs. 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through its mobile wallet app. SBI’s app Bank Buddy is a new facility that enables withdrawal of cash through ATMs using the bank&amp;rsquo;s mobile wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal saving bank accounts in a month will continue to get eight free ATM transactions (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks) in metros and 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks), the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applies to the Basic Savings Banks Deposit Accounts, SBI further said. SBI’s basic savings account is a limited-services bank account aimed at poorer sections of society to encourage them to start saving without any burden of charges or fees. This type of bank account comes with an ATM-cum-debit free of cost and no annual maintenance charges. A basic savings bank deposit account holder is not eligible to open any other savings bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective June 1. Here are some of the other key changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS or Immediate Payment Service will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh; Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh; and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; If a customer wishes to exchange of more than 20 soiled notes or if the total value of soiled notes is above Rs. 5,000, SBI said it will charge Rs. 2 plus service charge for every soiled note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customer with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs. 30 plus service tax for a 10-leaf cheque book, Rs. 75 with service tax for 25-leaf cheque book and Rs. 150 plus service tax for a 50-leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issuance of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only RuPay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs. 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs. 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI acts against 50 illegal websites</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It came to the notice of UIDAI that websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) has ensured that 12 websites and 12 mobile applications available on the Google Playstore are shut down and has directed to close down 26 more such fraudulent and illegal websites/applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came to the notice of UIDAI that these websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services such as downloading online Aadhaar card, providing status of Aadhaar generation, PVC Aadhaar Card, etc. and in that process they were illegally obtaining the Aadhaar number/enrolment details.
“UIDAI has not authorised the owners of these mobile applications or websites to extend any Aadhaar related services on its behalf,” said UIDAI CEO Ajay Bhushan Pandey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, “Any Aadhaar-related demographic information can only be shared following the procedures laid down in the Aadhaar Act, 2016. Any such violation is punishable under Section 38 and Chapter VII of the Aadhaar Act.”
Warning unauthorised websites and mobile applications providers against illegal use of Aadhaar logo, Pandey said, “We are contemplating stern action against them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He cautioned people to be aware against all such unscrupulous entities that provide unauthorized Aadhaar related services and asked them to remain vigilant. “www.uidai.gov.in is the only authorised website of UIDAI. Any other website with Aadhaar in its name and providing Aadhaar related services is not authorized by us and hence, illegal. We are taking stern action against all such illegal sites,” said Pandey.
In case a person loses his Aadhaar card, he/she can download his Aadhaar card free of cost from the UIDAI’s official website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ATMs Are Going Dry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1: The ATM expansion era is over. ATM extensions will no longer be part of future banking growth, and future ATMs may well be of the mobile kind focused only on rural cash deliveries. But even here, the growth will be limited. Standalone ATM companies may have a future, but only because banks may choose to outsource all their existing networks to them so that they can focus on growing the digital business themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: The phenomenon of business correspondents will rise in the short run, and then collapse as rural and unbanked sectors accept digital cash as the way to transfer money. The limiting factors are the absence of reliable power supplies in remote areas, and the gap in the spread of mobile phones to the poor. These shortcomings will be addressed over the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3: Once ATMs and cash start falling in terms of importance, the cash logistics business will, perforce, have to shrink. It is already in trouble after a few months of glory during the peak weeks of demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4: Many banking services may be outsourced. As ATMs shrink, branch rationalisation will also be the order of the day. Banks may outsource one-time customer-acquisition operations and use Aadhaar-based-eKYC to grow their customer bases, as Kotak Mahindra Bank’s 811 account is trying to do. E-KYC will soon become the standard way of acquiring new customers, both for regular banks and payment banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5: Cyber security will see a boom. As digital cash becomes the norm, the real growth in financial sector jobs will be in cyber security, since digital currency systems are vulnerable to hacking and fraud. For example, the unified payments interface (UPI) which allows for peer-to-peer payments using mobile phone numbers could be vulnerable to fraudsters who manage to clone your SIM card. In the past, fraudsters have cloned ATM magnetic strips; next they will target SIMs. Since smartphones will essentially become your digital banking interface, technologies to protect you from losses when you misplace or lose your phone will become paramount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6: Credit cards and payments systems will move out of the physical category and turn virtual. In future, credit and debit cards may be embedded in your phone, as the new Samsung Pay product indicates. Samsung Pay uses finger-print authorisation and PIN for payment at merchant nodes without any physical card having to be swiped. Kotak’s 811 app-based bank account offers virtual debit cards and scan-and-pay options. Once the Bharat QR Code becomes widely adopted by merchants, e-wallets too will become interoperable like credit cards issued by various banks are now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7: Phishing and fraud insurance will become big business. Once the smartphone becomes your wallet, you have to buy insurance to cover yourself against the possibility of fraud. Credit card fraud insurance is not big in India, but digital cash fraud may need better insurance than cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8: The biggest business of them all will be data analytics. As bank charges and payment usage fees fall to low levels, both due to regulation and high-volume usage, banks, virtual banks, card companies, and e-wallets will have to make money from the customer data they now own, as Aadhaar man Nandan Nilekani has repeatedly emphasised. This means financial companies must understand customers better from their spending and payments habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9: Bank employment will fall, as banks hollow out in terms of physical infrastructure and some jobs get outsourced. But they will pay top dollar to techies, since banking is being taken over by technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India is on the cusp of a huge shift in its financial sector. The old certainties are gone. The jobs market is shifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reassuring face of Gandhi on the currency note, with all its certainties, will be replaced with the virtual face of Bhimrao Ambedkar, the Modi government’s mascot for digital cash, with all its exciting uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>इस साल 20000 लोगों को नौकरी देंगे: इन्फोसिस</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/only-400-people-asked-to-leave-will-hire-20000-this-year-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/only-400-people-asked-to-leave-will-hire-20000-this-year-says/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;इन्फोसिस के सीओओ यूबी प्रवीण राव ने कहा कि भारी पैमाने पर नौकरियां कम होने की बात अतिश्योक्ति है। उन्होंने कहा कि कंपनी की योजना इस साल 20,000 लोगों को नौकरी देने की है। राव ने कहा कि इन्फोसिस काफी नौकरियां पैदा कर रहा है और टेक्नॉलजी आधारित परिवर्तनों से इन्फोसिस जैसी कंपनियों के लिए नए अवसर पैदा हो रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;छंटनी को लेकर फैली अफवाहों पर अगर बात करें तो यह परफॉर्मेंस आधारित है और हम हर साल ऐसा करते हैं। ऐसे लोगों की संख्या 300-400 होगी जो कि बीते वर्षों की तरह ही है।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने हालांकि इन्फोसिस के सह-संस्थापक एनआर नारायणमूर्ति की उस बात पर प्रतिक्रिया देने से मना कर दिया जिसमें उन्होंने कहा था कि अगर कंपनियों के सीनियर एग्जिक्यूटिव्स अपनी कटी सैलरी लें और ट्रेनिंग एंप्लॉयी में निवेश करें तो नौकरियों को सुरक्षित रखना संभव है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस मामले में विभिन्न एंप्लॉयी यूनियनों ने लेबर कमिशन और राज्यों सरकारों से मामले में हस्तक्षेप करने की गुहार लगाई है। राव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;मुझे लगता है कि छंटनी की खबरें बहुत बढ़ाचढ़ाकर पेश की जा रही हैं। इन्फोसिस ने पिछले साल 20,000 लोगों को नौकरी दी थी और इस साल भी कंपनी इतने ही लोगों को रोजगार देगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>कालेधन के खिलाफ सरकार का नया अभियान, ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी वेबसाइट लॉन्च</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-website-launched-tax-defaulters-to-be-rated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-website-launched-tax-defaulters-to-be-rated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;कालेधन के खिलाफ सरकार एक नया अभियान चला रही है। वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने इसके लिए आज (16 मई) ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी वेबसाइट लॉन्च कर दी है। इस पर सरकार छापेमारी की रिपोर्ट पेश करेगी। साथ ही वेबसाइट पर डिफॉल्टर्स को ज्यादा रिस्क से लेकर बहुत कम रिस्क की अलग अलग श्रेणियों में रखा जाएगा। सेंट्रल बोर्ड ऑफ डायरेक्ट टैक्स (सीबीडीटी) के चैयरमेन सुशील चंद्र ने बताया कि हम लोगों की टैक्स नहीं देने की आदत को बदलना चाहते हैं। उन्होंने कहा कि वेबसाइट पर उस प्रक्रिया के बारे में भी जानकारी दी जाएगी, जिसके द्वारा टैक्स डिफॉल्टर की पहचान की गई होगी।
हाई रिस्क, मीडियम रिस्क, कम रिस्क और बहुत कम रिस्क की श्रेणी के मुताबिक ही डिफॉल्टर पर कार्रवाई की जाएगी। सूत्रों के मुताबिक हाई रिस्क वाले लोगों और ग्रुप पर सर्च, जब्ती और सीधे जांच जैसी कार्रवाई का सामना करेंगे। वहीं मीडियम रिस्क वालों को मैसेज और ईमेल से सूचित किया जाएगा। इसके अलावा कम रिस्क और&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बहुत कम रिस्क वाले डिफॉल्टरों पर नजर रखी जाएगी। जिन लोगों और ग्रुप्स की जांच चल रही होगी उनकी पहचान को उजागर नहीं किया जाएगा। इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट रेड की रिपोर्ट इस वेबसाइट पर डालेगा।
आपको बता दें कि आयकर विभाग डेटा जुटाने के लिए जिन स्रोतों का इस्तेमाल करता है, उनमें दूसरे देशों की टैक्स अथॉरिटीज और इंडिया में हाई-वैल्यू ट्रांजेक्शंस शामिल हैं। डिपार्टमेंट के ऑपरेशन ‘क्लीन मनी’ के तहत चिन्हित किए गए लोगों ने नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद बैंकों में जमा किए ज्यादा पैसे और महंगी खरीदारी के बारे में अगर उचित जवाब नहीं दिए तो उन्हें भी जांच का सामना करना पड़ सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रिपोर्ट्स के मुताबिक डिपार्टमेंट के नोटबंदी के बाद चलाए गए ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत काफी डेटा जुटाया है। विभाग अब टैक्स चोरी की कोशिशों का पता लगाने का प्रयास कर रहा है। उसने 60,000 लोगों की पहचान कर ली है, जिनकी अब गहराई से जांच की जाएगी। हालांकि संख्या के बजाय गुणवत्ता का ध्यान रखा जा रहा है ताकि यह पूरा अभियान ज्यादा प्रभावी हो। डायरेक्ट टैक्स के मामले में शीर्ष संस्था सीबीडीटी ने पहले ही तय किया था कि वह उन मामलों की जांच नहीं करेगी जिनमें बिना व्यवसाय के 5 लाख रुपये तक की इनकम होगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जून से SBI इन सेवाओं के लिए वसूलेगा एक्‍स्‍ट्रा चार्ज, ये होंगे बदलाव</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-customers-bank-will-charge-extra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-customers-bank-will-charge-extra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;देश का सबसे बड़ा बैंक एसबीआई 1 जून से अपनी कई सेवाओं के शुल्‍क में बढ़ोतरी करने जा रहा है। पहली जून से अगर आप एसबीआई जाकर कटे-फटे नोट बदलवाते हैं या एक सीमा से अधिक बार पैसे निकालते हैं तो एसबीआई आपसे चार्ज वसूलेगा। बेसिक सेविंग बैंक डिपॉजिट अकाउंट के ग्राहकों को पैसे निकालने, नए कार्ड इश्यू करवाने जैसी सुविधाएं के लिए भी 1 जून से चार्ज देना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कैश विड्रॉल पर लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एसबीआई से कैश विड्रॉल सिर्फ 4 बार तक के लिए ही मुफ्त रहेगी। इसमें एटीएम ट्रांजैक्शंस भी शामिल हैं। 4 बार से ज्यादा एसबीआई की ब्रांच से भी कैश विड्रॉल करेंगे तो हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 50 रुपए का सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लगेगा। एसबीआई के एटीएम से 4 बार से ज्यादा विड्रॉल करेंगे तो हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 10 रुपए सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स देना होगा। दूसरे बैंक के एटीएम से 4 बार से ज्यादा कैश विड्रॉल पर हर ट्रांजैक्शन पर 20 रुपए सर्विस चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लगेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;आरबीआई ने दिए कटे-फटे नोट को लेकर दिए थे ये निर्देश&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30 अप्रैल को ही आरबीआई ने बैंकों को कटे, लिखे, पुराने व फटे नोटों को लेने के लिए कहा था. रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (आरबीआई) ने बैंकों को साफ निर्देश दिया है कि उन्हें गंदे नोट लेने ही होंगे और इसे लेने से वे इनकार नहीं कर सकते। लेकिन अगर आप एसबीआई में कटे-फटे या गले-गीले नोट जमा कराएंगे तो आपके ऊपर अतिरिक्त चार्ज देना होर्गा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;पुराने कटे-फटे नोट बदलने पर भी लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एसबीआई 20 से ज्यादा या 5,000 रुपए से ज्यादा कटे-फटे नोट बदलवाने पर अब 2 से लेकर 5 रुपए तक का चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स वसूलेगा। इसके तहत हर नोट पर 2 रुपये या हरेक 1,000 रुपये पर 5 रुपये चार्ज, जो भी ज्यादा होगा, वह वसूला जाएगा। 5,000 रुपए तक कीमत होने पर हर नोट पर 2 रुपये चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स वसूला जाएगा और 5000 रुपये से ज्यादा कीमत होने पर हर नोट पर 5 रुपये चार्ज+सर्विस टैक्स लिया जाएगा। कटे-फटे 20 नोट जिनकी कुल कीमत 5,000 रुपये से ज्यादा नहीं होगी तक बदलने पर एसबीआई कोई सर्विस चार्ज नहीं लगेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बेसिक बैंक डिपॉजिट अकाउंट के नए कार्ड पर भी लगेगा चार्ज&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 जून से एसबीआई एक्स्ट्रा डेबिट कार्ड इश्यू करने पर भी चार्ज लेने की तैयारी कर रहा है। एक जून से बैंक सिर्फ रुपे डेबिट कार्ड ही मुफ्त में जारी करेगा। बाकी सभी कार्ड जारी करने पर बैंक ने सर्विस चार्ज लेने का ऐलान कर दिया है। 1 जून से बैंक मास्टर और वीजा कार्ड इश्यू करने पर सर्विस चार्ज लेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रूपे क्रेडिट कार्ड करेगा जारी, मेट्रो-बस का पेमेंट भी कार्ड से</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupay-credit-cards-soon-says-chief-hota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupay-credit-cards-soon-says-chief-hota/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;नैशनल पेमेंट कॉर्पोरेशन ऑफ इंडिया (NPCI) जल्द ही रूपे क्रेडिट कार्ड जारी करेगा। NPCI ने इसके लिए कुछ बैंकों के साथ हाथ मिलाया है। नैशनल पेमेंट कॉर्पोरेशन ऑफ इंडिया देश में डिजिटल ट्रांजैक्शंस की नोडल एजेंसी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI के प्रबंध निदेशक और मुख्य कार्यकारी अधिकारी एपी होता ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमारे क्रेडिट कार्ड जल्द ही जारी किए जाएंगे। ये रूपे क्रेडिट कार्ड होंगे। कुछ बैंकों के साथ प्रयोग के तौर पर यह काम चल रहा है। प्रायोगिक तौर पर करीब 7200 लेन-देन हुए हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पंजाब नैशनल बैंक, सेंट्रल बैंक, IDBI बैंक, आंध्रा बैंक और यूनियन बैंक इस प्रायोगिक परियोजना पर काम कर रहे हैं। इसके अलावा नोडल एजेंसी ऐसे कार्ड भी लाएगी जिसे मेट्रो और बस के किराए में पेमेंट के लिए यूज किया जा सके। इसकी शुरुआत बेंगलुरु से की जाएगी। होता ने बताया कि इस सर्विस को जून से कोच्चि और अहमदाबाद में भी शुरू किया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारत में डिजिटल पेमेंट के विस्तार का जिक्र करते हुए उन्होंने बताया कि NPCI अब तक 2.30 लाख बैंक ATM खोल चुका है और 3 करोड़ से अधिक पॉइंट ऑफ सेल (POS) मशीनों के जरिए कैश लेस पेमेंट को बढ़ावा दे रहा है। जिसे जल्द ही और विस्तार दिया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data leak: Now govt agencies will safeguard your personal info</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The linking of Aadhaar — the 12-digit unique identification number for Indian residents is about to become safer as new rules put the onus on government departments and agencies to safeguard personal data or information held by them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Departments handling the data will have to ensure that end-users are made aware of the data usage and collection and their consent is taken either in writing or electronically, according to new guidelines issued by the government for security of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sensitive personal data such as passwords, financial information (bank account, credit card, debit card and other payment instrument details), medical records and history, sexual orientation, physical and mental health, and biometric information cannot be stored by agencies without encryption, say the guidelines issued by the Ministry of electronics and information technology (IT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure, the Information Technology Act 2000 and Aadhaar Act 2016 have laid down most of these rules. The new guidelines seek answers to questions being asked on data protection under the Aadhaar Act, according to Press Trust of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;uidai-warns-government-departments&#34;&gt;UIDAI warns government departments:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publishing identity information, i.e. Aadhaar number along with demographic information is in clear contravention of the provisions of the Aadhaar Act 2016 and constitutes an offence punishable with imprisonment up to 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publishing of financial information including bank details, being sensitive personal data, is also in contravention of provision under IT Act 2000 with violations liable to pay damages by way of compensation to persons affected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move to protect personal data comes after reports that data of 130 million Aadhaar cardholders has been leaked from four government websites. Reports, based on a study conducted by the Centre for Internet and Society (CIS) said Aadhaar numbers and details have been leaked.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM will now allow you to make payments via Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app will now allow users to send and receive money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes shortly after the government announced the Aadhaar Pay which would allow any person with their Aadhaar number linked to a bank account, can make and receive payment electronically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, IT minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said that BHIM would be able to make Aadhar Payments any biometric authentication, as indicated by this Economic Times report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the government has 14 banks onboard to facilitate payments via Aadhaar Pay, with more to join soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The updated BHIM app now has options where it will allow users to pay with Aadhar number in addition to virtual payment addresses (VPA) and bank account and IFSC codes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>