<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>45GB Free Data On Amazon Exclusive Smartphones:Vodafone Offers </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-45gb-free-data-on-amazon-exclusive-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-45gb-free-data-on-amazon-exclusive-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the purchase of 1GB or above 4G data pack, users will get 9GB additional free 4G data for five recharges with maximum validity of five months from Vodafone, Amazon stated on its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major telecom players in India, Vodafone is offering 45GB of free data on the purchase of Amazon exclusive 4G smartphones. For the purchase of 1GB or above 4G data pack, users will get 9GB additional free 4G data for five recharges with maximum validity of five months from Vodafone, e-commerce firm Amazon stated on its website. The offer is only available on select smartphones. To avail the offer from Vodafone, one must purchase the Amazon exclusive handset till June 30. According to the website, the offer was started on May 11. (Click here to see the full list of smartphones which are applicable under the offer)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the smartphones included under the offer are Samsung On5 Pro, OnePlus 3T, Honor 6X and Moto G Play (4th Gen), among others. This free data offer cannot be cumulated with any other special discounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-how-users-can-avail-the-vodafone-offer&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how users can avail the Vodafone offer:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Insert Vodafone SIM in the new Amazon exclusive handset. You will get an activation message saying &amp;ldquo;You are eligible for Vodafone Amazon Buy 1GB or above pack and Get 9 GB for 5 Recharges with maximum validity of 5 months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For prepaid connections, recharge with 1GB or above pack, 9GB free data will get credited automatically. The 9GB free data is valid for 28 days only and a user can avail the offer up to five times or five months, whatever comes first. No special recharges and prices are applicable to get the free 9GB data offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For postpaid connections, user need to have 1GB or above rental plan, then 9GB free data will get attached within 48 hours. The 9GB Offer is valid for five billing cycles with a condition that the user has 1 GB or higher pack throughout the promotional period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea Cellular is also providing a similar offer in collaboration with Flipkart. It has announced 4G data offer with no daily limit and unlimited voice calling. Users purchasing a new 4G-enabled smartphone through Flipkart can avail up to 30GB of 4G data per month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBSE affiliated schools to be made Aadhaar centres</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to ensure that all students have unique identification number to be enrolled, the Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) recently directed all its affiliated schools to set up Aadhaar enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To implement this, the board has collaborated with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) to collect demographic and biometric data of residents directly or through enrolment agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-on-the-report&#34;&gt;More on the report:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, schools are free to decide whether or not to set up the centres&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if a school wishes to set up an Aadhaar centre, then they can do so by signing a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with either the Board or UIDAI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, the board has asked schools to procure equipment for the purpose as per the UIDAI check list&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reasons-behind-this-step&#34;&gt;Reasons behind this step:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As reported, this move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-cbse-said-in-its-notice&#34;&gt;Here’s what CBSE said in its notice:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools shall set up enrolment centres to facilitate their bonafide students, teachers, staff and their family members to to enrol for Aadhar and make any updation or corrections,” it said in a communication to schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Equipment such as computer, printer, biometric devices and other such things will have to be procured by the school themselves and should be as per the UIDAI specifications,” as reported in a recent PTI report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to encourage students to enroll themselves, the schools will not be charging any fees for the Aadhaar enrolment; but CBSE will pay them Rs 30 for every enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the February 2017 data of the board, there are 18,546 CBSE affiliated schools in India and 210 schools in 25 foreign countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, the schools will also be required to adhere to all code of conducts applicable to other enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICICI, Axis, SBI Gain, RBI To Get Power To Act Against Loan Defaulters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Union Cabinet cleared an ordinance empowering the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to act against wilful defaulters. The ordinance has been sent to the president for approval. The ordinance is aimed at empowering RBI to deal more effectively with stressed assets than earlier. A senior finance ministry official said &amp;ldquo;It is part of a broader plan to resolve bad loans with banks&amp;rsquo; issue that has been a major hurdle in the economy from achieving its full potential.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking sub-index on the NSE Nifty Bank index rose to its record high following this development. The index advanced as much as 2 per cent to hit record high of 22,743.70. Sub-index of the public-sector banks Nifty PSU index also rallied over 3 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance may enable RBI to direct banks on how to deal with stressed assets. Moving an amendment to the banking regulation act may take time as the next session of parliament starts sometime after second week of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amended law will also empower RBI to set up oversight panels that will shield bankers from later action by probe agencies looking into loan recasts as a lot of discretion will be involved in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By December 2016, non-performing assets (NPAs) or bad loans with Indian banks rose to Rs. 6.07 lakh crore, of which the share of Public sector banks was Rs. 5.02 lakh crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysts say the ordinance is a positive step towards banks recovering their dues from the defaulters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kishor Ostwal of CNI Research, says &amp;ldquo;Because of this ordinance there will be more and more recovery of bad loans and wilful defaulters which have money will come out and repay their debts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the individual banking shares, ICICI Bank was the top gainer, rose 9.18 per cent to Rs 297.8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canara Bank, Bank of Baroda, State Bank of India, IDFC Bank, Punjab National Bank and Axis Bank were also among the other gainer in the banking sun-index rising between 1-3.5 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the state-run lenders, Union Bank, Andhra Bank, IDBI Bank and  Allahabad Bank also rallied up to 4 per cent each.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: Aircel Offers 1 GB Of 3G Data At Rs. 76</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-aircel-offers-1-gb-of-3g-data-at-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-aircel-offers-1-gb-of-3g-data-at-rs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aircel is also offering full talk time or FTT benefits on a recharge of Rs. 86. It is also offering 100MB of data with the download of its Aircel App.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is offering its customers 1GB of 3G data at a price of Rs. 76 on its mobile app. Aircel, which last month announced free incoming calls on national roaming on its network across the country, is also offering additional 100MB of free data on recharges above Rs. 50, the telecom company said in a press release on Wednesday. &amp;ldquo;Tapping the increasing trend of customers choosing to recharge their phones online or through apps, Aircel&amp;hellip;has launched special Data and Calling packs on its mobile application,&amp;rdquo; the press release by Aircel noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1gb-rs-76&#34;&gt;1GB @ Rs. 76&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel&amp;rsquo;s 1GB of 3G data on offer in a recharge of Rs. 76 will come with a validity of 10 days, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The exciting offers are designed keeping the customer demands at the forefront and giving them best value offers with Aircel,&amp;rdquo; the company said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aircel has always worked to delight its customers and present them with value for money offers. Through apps, we know our customers, their plans, usage, and the services they are interested in, and hence have curated these products basis the trends observed,&amp;rdquo; Aircel chief marketing officer Anupam Vasudev said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some analysts say the aggressive pricing by Reliance Jio has led to high competition in the Indian telecom industry, forcing existing players to come up with lower tariffs and lucrative schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full talk time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is also offering full talk time or FTT benefits on a recharge of Rs. 86. It is also offering 100MB of data with the download of its Aircel App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel&amp;rsquo;s app - Aircel App-Recharge &amp;amp; BillPay - is available on Google Play (for Android users) and App Store (for iPhone users).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app successfully caters to the growing customer base and increasing data consumption, offering benefits like data loan and main balance recharge options which are industry&amp;rsquo;s first features on the app, Aircel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen great success in the past with such products and we feel that these App exclusive products will suit the convenience of our customers and assist them to stay seamlessly connected,&amp;rdquo; Mr Vasudev added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is a pan-India operator with 3G spectrum in 13 circles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 30 Aadhaar Deadline Not To Be Extended, Government Tells Top Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/june-30-aadhaar-deadline-not-to-be-extended-government-tells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of the Unique Identity programme Aadhaar are pending in the Supreme Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is &amp;ldquo;no question&amp;rdquo; of extending the June 30 deadline for making Aadhaar mandatory for availing benefits of various social welfare schemes, the centre today told the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General Mukul Rohatgi told the top court that the idea behind making Aadhaar mandatory for welfare schemes was that the benefit should not go to &amp;ldquo;ghosts&amp;rdquo; as was noticed in schemes like the public distribution system (PDS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also raised preliminary objection to the plea seeking interim relief and challenging various notifications issued by the centre and told a bench, comprising Justices A M Khanwilkar and Navin Sinha, that this matter should be listed for hearing before a five-judge constitution bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Rohatgi said that earlier, some pleas seeking identical interim reliefs were also filed and those matters were pending before the top court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bench said it would be appropriate to hear all these pleas seeking interim relief together to &amp;ldquo;avoid multiplicity&amp;rdquo; and fixed the matter for hearing on June 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the bench was considering whether to list the matter for hearing during the summer vacation, senior advocate Shyam Divan, appearing for the petitioner, said there was urgency involved in it and if the matter was not heard before June 30, &amp;ldquo;the other way was if they (centre) extend the deadline&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;There is no question of that,&amp;rdquo; Mr Rohatgi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Aadhaar are pending in the top court and would be heard by a five-judge constitution bench, which is yet to be set up by the Chief Justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Supreme Court had passed a slew of orders asking the government and its agencies not to make Aadhaar mandatory for extending benefits of their welfare schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top court, however, had allowed the Centre to seek Aadhaar card voluntarily from citizens for extending benefits of schemes like LPG subsidy, Jan Dhan scheme and Public Distribution System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar With Your PAN Card Just by Uploading a Scanned Proof</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Individuals struggling to link their Permanent Account Number with Aadhaar because of differently spelt names can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the tax department is planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for a One-Time Password (OTP), provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the linking of PAN with Aadhaar being made mandatory, individuals can log on to e-filing website of the income tax department or NSDL but the seeding cannot happen if the name is differently spelt in the two cards – like use of full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, government has allowed a simple uploading of a scanned copy of PAN on the Aadhaar website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had through amendment to tax proposals in the Finance Bill of the Budget for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-filing portal has already activated a functionality of linking PAN with Aadhaar. Over 1.08 crore assessees have already Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official said that linking of PAN with Aadhaar should not be cumbersome for people whose registered mobile number with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In case the taxpayer is unable to link PAN with Aadhaar because of discrepancy in name, we are advising them to log in to the Aadhaar website, request for a name change and upload a scanned copy of PAN card as supported proof. This is the simplest way to update name in Aadhaar and only the registered mobile number has to be functional,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This option will hold good for people who have given short forms of their name or in some cases there are some spelling errors in the name provided in Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in certain cases, there are people who have got married and changed their surname and updated the same while getting Aadhaar number, but it does not get reflected in PAN documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such and other name change cases, the tax department is planning to give the OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number and the tax department, on its part, would match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are also contemplating that when taxpayers with name discrepancy logs into the e-filing website for linkage, we will send OTP to the Aadhaar registered mobile number. The taxpayer can link PAN using the OTP. While generating the OTP, we will just check if the year of birth of the taxpayer in PAN card matches with the year given in the Aadhaar document,” the official added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI में है आपका अकाउंट, अब इन खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-are-now-exempt-from-keeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-are-now-exempt-from-keeping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;एसबीआई ने सरकारी नौकरी करने वालों को भी राहत दी है। और ऐसे अकाउंट होल्डर्स को अब न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस नहीं रखना होगा।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देश के सबसे बड़े सरकारी बैंक स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (SBI) ने अपने यहां खाता रखने वाले ग्राहकों को बड़ी राहत दी है। SBI ने कई प्रकार के खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस ना रखने पर वसूलने वाले चार्ज को हटा दिया है। अब ग्राहक इन खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस नहीं भी रखेंगे तो उन्हें किसी भी प्रकार का शुल्क नहीं देना पड़ेगा। एसबीआई ने ट्वीट कर इस फैसले की जानकारी दी है। एसबीआई के ट्वीट के मुताबिक अब छोटी बचत खातों, बेसिक बचत खातों में मंथली एवरेज बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं है। इसके अलावा प्रधानमंत्री जन धन अकाउंट योजना के तहत खोले गये खातों में भी न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं है। एसबीआई ने सरकारी नौकरी करने वालों को भी राहत दी है। और ऐसे अकाउंट होल्डर्स को अब न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस नहीं रखना होगा। एसबीआई ने सभी कॉरपोरेट सैलरी रखने वालों को भी ये सुविधा दी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;मिनिमम बैलेंस की क्या है सीमा&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि SBI ने एक अप्रैल से अपने बैंकिंग नियमों में बदलाव किया है और कई तरह के खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस ना रखने पर चार्ज लगाया है। एसबीआई का नया नियम देश के 6 मेट्रो शहरों में बचत खातों में 5 हजार रुपये रखने अनिवार्य कर दिये हैं, जबकि शहरी क्षेत्र के खाताधारकों को अपने खाते में 3 हजार रुपये रखने जरुरी होंगे, अर्ध शहरी क्षेत्र के अकाउंट होल्डर्स के लिए ये सीमा 2 हज़ार रुपये हैं, हालांकि ग्रामीण खाताधारकों को थोड़ी राहत दी गई है और उनके लिए हज़ार रुपये ही अपने खाते में रखने जरूरी किये गये हैं। एसबीआई के नये नियमों के मुताबिक ऐसा ना करने पर ग्राहक से 20 से 100 रुपये तक का जुर्माना वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कैसे करें अपने खाते की पहचान&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बड़ा सवाल ये है कि आप इस बात की पहचान कैसे करेंगे कि आपका खाता किस कैटेगरी में आता है। एसबीआई ने स्मॉल और बेसिक सेविंग्स अकाउंट का मतलब बताते हुए लिखा है कि छोटी बचत खाते ढील दिये गये केवाईसी नियमों के तहत खोले जा सकते हैं। लेकिन इन खातों में अधिकत्तम बैलेंस और अधिकत्तम लेनदेन की सीमा तय की गई है। बेसिक सेविग्स अकाउंट केवाईसी नियमों के तहत खोला गया खाता है। बेसिक सेविंग्स खाताधारी दूसरा सेविंग अकाउंट नहीं खोल सकता है। जबकि सभी तरह के सरकारी नौकरियों में सैलरी पाने के लिए खोले गये खाते कॉरपोरेट सैलरी पैकेज के तहत आते हैं। जन-धन खातों के पासबुक में ही लिखा होता है कि ये खाते प्रधानमंत्री जन धन योजना के तहत खोले गये हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब पीएफ के पैसे का 10 दिन में होगा निपटारा, EPFO का दावा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-provident-fund-can-withdraw-in-10-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-provident-fund-can-withdraw-in-10-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;कर्मचारी भविष्य निधि संगठन (EPFO) ने पीएफ निकासी, पेंशन और बीमा जैसे विभिन्न दावों के निपटान के लिए निर्धारित समयसीमा मौजूदा 20 दिन से घटाकर 10 दिन कर दिया है। उल्लेखनीय है कि ईपीएफओ ने जुलाई 2015 में विभिन्न दावों के निपटान के लिए समयसीमा घटाकर 20 दिन कर दिया था। अपने चार करोड़ अंशधारकों को दी जाने वाली सेवा में सुधार के मकसद से यह कदम उठाया गया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;निकाय ने एक मई 2017 से ऑनलाइन दावा निपटान शुरू किया। उसकी सभी आधार और बैंक खाते से जुडे़ ईपीएफ खातों के संदर्भ में आवेदन प्राप्त होने के तीन घंटे के भीतर दावों के निपटान की योजना है। ईपीएफओ ने एक बयान में कहा, &amp;lsquo;दावों के निपटान के लिए समयसीमा 10 दिन तथा शिकायतों के निपटान के लिए समयसीमा 15 दिन होगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;श्रम मंत्री बंडारु दत्तात्रेय ने मंगलवार को बैंगलोर में ईपीएफओ के &amp;lsquo;सिटिजन चार्टर&amp;rsquo; 207 पेश किया। बयान के अनुसार चार्टर ईपीएफओ की तरफ से पारदर्शिता और जवाबदेही लाने का प्रयास है और सेवा डिलीवरी प्रणाली तथा शिकायत निपटान प्रणाली को और कुशल बनाना है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार के बिना नहीं मिलेगा सिम कार्ड</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card-said/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;यदि आपके पास आधार कार्ड नहीं है तो जल्दी से बनवा लें। टेलिकॉम रेग्युलेटरी अथॉरिटी ऑफ इंडिया (TRAI) ने आधार कार्ड के बगैर सिम कार्ड देने पर रोक लगा दी है। ट्राई की तरफ से जारी गाइडलाइन में कहा गया है कि मोबाइल सिम कार्ड, ब्रॉडबैंड और फिक्स लाइन फोन के लिए आधार कार्ड अनिवार्य होगा। बता दें कि फरवरी में केंद्र सरकार ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट को बताया था लगभग एक साल में देश के सभी सिम कार्डों को आधार कार्ड से जोड़ दिया जाएगा। केंद्र सरकार ने कहा था कि ऐसा मैकेनिज्म लाया जा रहा है, जिससे इन मोबाइल सिम को भी आधार से जोड़ा जा सके।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देश में डिजिटल ट्रांजेक्शन को बढ़ावा देने की बात पर चीफ जस्टिस ऑफ इंडिया खेहर ने कहा था कि मोबाइल सिम कार्ड रखने वालों की पहचान बेहद जरूरी है, ऐसा न होने पर यह धोखाधड़ी से रुपये निकालने के काम में इस्तेमाल हो सकता है। सरकार को जल्द ही पहचान करने की प्रक्रिया करनी चाहिए, वहीं केंद्र की ओर से कहा गया था कि इस मामले में उसे हलफनामा दाखिल करने के लिए वक्त चाहिए। इसके बाद सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने दो हफ्ते का वक्त दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ट्राई के नियम के मुताबिक अब हर सिमकार्ड के लिए ई-केवाईसी जरूरी होगा। ट्राई की ओर से प्रस्तावित नियमों के तहत न सिर्फ नई मोबाइल सिम बल्कि मौजूदा सभी मोबाइल सब्सक्राइबर्स का ई-केवाईसी वेरिफिकेशन जरूरी होगा। किसी दूसरे सर्कल में जाकर मोबाइल फोन कनेक्शन को लेकर काफी दिक्कते आती हैं। लोगों को एड्रेस प्रूफ देने में परेशानी होती है, लेकिन ईकेवाईसी के बाद ये समस्या खत्म हो जाएगी। अब ईकेवाई से एक ही अड्रेस पर पूरे देश में सिम हासिल किया जा सकेगा। इतना ही नहीं ईकेवाईसी की मदद से सिम कार्ड में फर्जीवाड़े को भी रोका जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>तो क्‍या 1 जून से हर एटीएम न‍िकासी पर 25 रुपए वसूलेगा एसबीआई? दूर हुई गफलत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-will-not-be-charged-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-will-not-be-charged-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;एटीएम से पैसे निकालने के नियमों में कोई बदलाव नहीं किया गया है, और पुराने नियम ही लागू रहेंगे।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया के ग्राहकों के लिए एक जरूरी खबर है। मीडिया में चल रही खबरों के विपरीत स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया एटीएम से हर बार पैसे निकालने के लिए 25 रुपये चार्ज नहीं करेगी। स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया की बेबसाइट पर एक सर्कुलर डाला गया है, जिसके मुताबिक एक जून 2017 से एटीएम से हर बार पैसे की निकासी पर 25 रुपये चार्ज लिया जाएगा। एसबीआई के अधिकारी ने इस सर्कुलर के बारे में सफाई देते हुए कहा कि बैंक ऐसी कोई भी रकम नहीं लेने वाला है, क्योंकि ये सर्कुलर एसबीआई मोबाइल वैलेट, जिसे बड्डी भी कहा जाता है, से जुड़ा है। अंग्रेजी वेबसाइट बिजनेस टुडे के मुताबिक एसबीआई जल्द ही नया सर्कुलर जारी करने वाला है। इस&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि एटीएम से पैसे निकालने के नियमों में कोई बदलाव नहीं किया गया है, और पुराने नियम ही लागू रहेंगे।
बता दें कि एसबीआई के इसी सर्कुलर में बताया गया है कि एक महीने में चार निकासी जिसमें की एटीएम से निकाले गये पैसे भी शामिल हैं मुफ़्त होंगे। सर्कुलर में आगे लिखा है कि अगर किसी को चार बार से ज्यादा पैसे निकालने हैं तो 50 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स चार्ज करेगा। ये चार्ज बैंक की शाखा से पैसे निकालने के लिए
रखे गये हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अगर कस्टमर ने दूसरे बैंक के एटीएम का इस्तेमाल किया है तो 20 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स चार्ज किया जाएगा, और अगर एसबीआई की एटीएम से पैसे निकाले जाएंगे तो 10 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स लिया जाएगा।
इस आदेश के मुताबिक अब चेकबुक लेने के लिए भी जेब ढीली करनी पड़ेगी। 1 जून से अगर आप 10 चेक वाला चेकबुक लेते हैं तो आपको 30 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स देना पड़ेगा, 25 चेक वाला चेकबुक लेने पर 75 रुपये और चेकबुक देना पड़ेगा, जबकि 50 चेक वाला चेकबुक लेने पर 150 रुपये और सर्विस टैक्स भुगतान करना पड़ेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बिजली बिल: आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को जरूरी सेवाओं के लिए अनिवार्य किए जाने का मामला अभी सुप्रीम कोर्ट में लंबित है। इस बीच बिजली बिल के भुगतान को भी आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी शुरू कर दी गई है। केंद्र सरकार ने राज्यों से बिजली के बिलों का डिजिटल भुगतान आधार से जुड़े बैंक खातों के माध्यम से सुनिश्चित करने को कहा है। केंद्रीय ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा है कि बिजली बिल को आधार से जोड़ना ग्राहकों के लिए फायदेमंद साबित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;राज्यों और केंद्र शासित प्रदेशों के ऊर्जा और खदान मंत्रियों की कॉन्फ्रेंस में गोयल ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह जरूरी नहीं है, लेकिन सभी के हित में है क्योंकि अगर आप बिल का भुगतान डिजिटल माध्यम से करेंगे तो आपके पास यह ठीक-ठीक सबूत होगा कि आपने बिल का भुगतान किया है। यह पहल जनता को मदद करेगी और इस संबंध में कोशिश की जानी चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि इसका फैसला राज्यों को लेना है कि वे बिजली बिलों के भुगतान की प्रणाली को आधार से जुड़े खातों से जोड़ें या नहीं, लेकिन निश्चित तौर पर यह कहा जा सकता है कि यह ग्राहकों के हित में है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि सरकार ने हाल में आयकर रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को जरूरी कर दिया है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट में भी सरकार ने अपनी तरफ से साफ किया है कि पैन नंबर के जरिए होने वाले फ्रॉड को रोकने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य किया जाना जरूरी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गोयल ने यह भी कहा कि सरकार राज्यों को बिजली आवंटन के मसौदे को फिर तैयार कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम फॉर्म्युले पर काम कर रहे हैं। हम इस बात पर फिर से विचार कर रहे हैं कि हम इसे (पावर आवंटन पॉलिसी) किस तरह मजबूत बना सकते हैं। फिलहाल गाडगिल फॉर्म्युले पर बिजली का बंटवारा होता है। इसके तहत राज्यों के प्लान के लिए केंद्रीय मदद के लिए नियम और शर्तों को तय किया जाता है। उनका यह भी कहना था कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा बिजली उन को दी जाएगी, जो न्यूक्लियर प्लांट्स स्थापित करने को बढ़ावा देंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिजली के कमर्शल नुकसान में गिरावट और कॉस्ट की बेहतर कवरेज से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन कंपनियों में मामूली बेहतरी से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रिब्यूशन कंपनियों के ऑपरेशनल परफॉर्मेंस में सुधार हुआ है। पावर फाइनेंस कॉर्पोरेशन (PFC) की एक रिपोर्ट में यह बात कही गई है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>