<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>400 Benami Transactions Crackdown by Income Tax Department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/i-t-department-crackdown-yeilds-400-benami-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/i-t-department-crackdown-yeilds-400-benami-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Benami property includes movable or immovable assets and property which is in name of someone other than the beneficial owner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department today said it has identified over 400 benami transactions and attached properties worth Rs 600 crore in about 240 cases. Keen to implement the new Benami Act to ensure &amp;ldquo;visible outcomes on the ground&amp;rdquo;, the tax department last week set up 24 dedicated Benami Prohibition Units (BPUs) all over India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department started initiating actions under the new Benami Transactions (Prohibition) Amendment Act, 2016 from November 1 last year. The law provides for a maximum punishment of seven years in jail and a fine. Benami property includes movable or immovable, tangible or intangible, corporeal or incorporeal property which is in name of someone other than the beneficial owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Income-tax Directorates of Investigation have identified more than 400 benami transactions up to May 23, 2017. These include deposits in bank accounts, plots of land, flat and jewellery,&amp;rdquo; said an official release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provisional attachment of properties under the law has been done in more than 240 cases. The market value of properties under attachment is more than Rs 600 crore, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Immovable properties have been attached in 40 cases with total value of more than Rs 530 crore in Kolkata, Mumbai, Delhi, Gujarat, Rajasthan and Madhya Pradesh,&amp;rdquo; the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also undertaken searches on 10 &amp;ldquo;senior government officials&amp;rdquo; during the past one month, in line with its policy to &amp;ldquo;unearth black money earned through corrupt practices and introduce accountability and probity in public life&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving details, the department said in one case in Jabalpur, the &amp;ldquo;benamidar&amp;rdquo;, a driver, was found to be owner of land worth Rs 7.7 crore. The beneficial owner was a Madhya Pradesh based listed company, his employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mumbai, a professional was found to be holding several immovable properties in the name of shell companies which exist only on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another case in Sanganer, Rajasthan, a jeweller was found to be the beneficial owner of nine immovable properties in the name of his former employee, a man of no means. Certain properties purchased through shell companies have also been attached by the department in Kolkata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crackdown on all forms of illicit wealth is being spearheaded by the department to ensure that any economic misdeed is immediately identified and actions as per law follow, the release added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 24 dedicated units are under the overall supervision of the Principal Directors of Investigation in the Income-tax Department to enable swift action and follow up, especially in cases where criminality has been detected.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATM hacks are less about losing a few lakhs &amp; more about erosion of reputation.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bankers-atm-hacks-are-less-about-losing-a-few-lakhs-more-about-erosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bankers-atm-hacks-are-less-about-losing-a-few-lakhs-more-about-erosion/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last year, Vijay Kumar, an Indian Army sepoy, got the shock of his life when he discovered a shortfall of Rs 2 lakh in his SBI salary account. Subsequently drawing out of transaction details and CCTV footage revealed Kumar’s card was “cloned” by fraudsters several kilometers from his base in Delhi Cantonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kumar had never even travelled to Connaught Place where his card was used (or misused). Miscreants managed to get his bank details using a Malaysian-make card reader and a hidden camera (affixed to the ceiling of the rigged ATM, focused on the keypad) to capture the PIN. Card skimming – an old trick – is common in India, but on a waning curve as swindlers have moved on to more sophisticated technologies. Daring raids on ATM switches and payment gateways, in rising numbers, have turned fraudsters of yore into new-age hackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to India Forensic, an educational &amp;amp; research organisation specialising in banking frauds, roughly 37,000 ATM fraud cases have been reported in the country since 2014. Industry experts estimate over 8,000 ATMs got infected by bugs last year – a good number on account of mishandling by third party handlers. Most banks outsource ‘ATM management’ (software updates, hardware service and others) to external agencies. ATMs get infected when third party service engineers use (virus) infected pen drives. Eight dacoity cases were reported in 2014, according to the National Crime Records Bureau, a couple of which included uprooting ATM machines and trucking them into the woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ransomware-rears-up&#34;&gt;RANSOMWARE REARS UP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a response to the recent ‘WannaCry Ransomware’ malware attack, the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) asked banks to update software systems. There are unconfirmed reports of two south India based banks being infected, The Times of India stated recently. “Ample security measures have to be employed across all banks as customers use non-home ATMs as well. So only one bank with strong system or network may not really help. ATMs are easy targets,” explains Mahesh Patel, group CTO, AGS Transact Technologies, an ATM manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bankers, it appears, are not overly worried about individual ATMs as these hold only “a few lakhs of rupees” at any given time. But they are concerned about reputational risk associated with their ATMs getting hacked and plundered. Beyond that, banks are focused on securing pricier installations such as the ‘ATM or core banking switch,’ which link core accounts and clusters of ATMs. “Hackers are not interested in individual customers or ATMs anymore… they’re looking for larger gains and bigger play,” admits Johnson K Jose, head of IT at Federal Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Most ATM attacks happen at the (ATM) switch level these days… precisely for this reason, we don’t outsource switch-level operations to outsiders. But then securing individual ATMs is also important for banks… customers should feel safe when they transact on a particular bank’s ATM,” Johnson adds. ATM/debit card fraud complaints shot up 23% to 13,081 in 2015-16, as per the latest Banking Ombudsman Report. Of the 22,000 card-related complaints received, 8,300 pertain to failed ATM withdrawal transactions, short/non-dispensation and fraudulent removal of cash from customer accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;physical-attacks&#34;&gt;PHYSICAL ATTACKS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 2016, four youths uprooted an SBI ‘pass book updating machine’ thinking it was an ATM kiosk. Such instances of ‘ATM ramming’ are fairly common in Australia, where miscreants use tractors to pull out cash dispensers bolted to the ground. Physical attacks on ATMs are also on a rising curve in India. AnG India, an electronic security solutions company, receives over 100 alerts of “force” being exerted on ATMs every day. Of this, around 10 pertain to breakage or forced entry. “Not many ATMs have guards anymore… Banks mostly use e-surveillance systems,” says Pulkit Punj, director of AnG India. “Some kind of access restriction has to be there to keep away undesirable elements (near ATMs),” feels Mukul Shrivastava, partner – fraud investigation &amp;amp; dispute services, EY. “Also, there’s a lot of hardware (wires, connecting cables) lying around openly in ATMs. These have to be concealed properly… Such inlet points come handy for expert hackers to get through,” he warns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;defence-countermeasures&#34;&gt;DEFENCE, COUNTERMEASURES&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, when banks requisitioned for new ATMs, they did not ask for security packages that came at extra cost. This has changed now. Banks have started demanding whitelisting modules, antiskimming devices and hard disk encryption software along with new ATMs. “Multiple banking touchpoints — from net banking to mobile banking and ewallets — are vulnerable to cyber attacks. So banks should not look at security in a piecemeal fashion,” says Navroze Dastur, MD of NCR Corporation, an ATM manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operating system updation would go a long way to secure ATMs from minor hacks. Whitelisting modules would ring-fence the core (software) by restricting unauthorised reworking of programmes using malwares. Strong safe boxes (Cen-1 safes) are being installed inside most new ATMs. Cen-1 strong boxes take approximately 35 minutes to cut open (a unit of measure for safe boxes) while the previously used UL291 boxes could be forced open in 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instances of card skimming and cloning are likely to come down after the move to EMV (Europay, Mastercard, Visa) cards in two years. EMV or chip cards, according to experts, offer one of the most secure conduits for banking transactions. Some 300 million magstripe cards would be replaced with chip-embedded EMV cards by end-December 2018, as directed by RBI. If security experts are to be believed, six lakh new bugs are released into the “market” (thriving on internet) daily. Malwares such as Green dispenser, Suceful, Padpin and Tyupkin have cracked open ATMs of late. Some can be downloaded on a pen drive and their ‘spit-code’ sourced from Russian or American hack mafia for a price. Banks and security agencies will have to keep plugging the holes every single day to keep black hats at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the new business plan 2017-18, unveiled by Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu on Thursday, besides the Aadhaar-based ticketing system, the Railways will move towards cashless ticketing system by installing 6,000 point-of-sale machines and 1,000 automatic ticket vending machines across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An integrated ticketing app will also be launched by May to promote cashless transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar number will be required for one-time registration at the IRCTC ticketing site. The step is aimed at eliminating touts from registering with fake identities,&amp;rdquo; a senior Railway Ministry official said, adding the Railways is preparing a software for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite taking several steps, touts corner a bulk of tickets and sell those at much higher prices and this is becoming a serious problem for the Railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new business plan also envisages launching of new tourist trains connecting hill stations and enhancing passenger comfort and providing pleasurable journey experience through improving amenities and catering service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not mandatory for train tickets of senior citizens</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets but the Railways have initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens, Lok Sabha was informed today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu made it clear that Aadhaar number has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, however, said the Railway has initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens through pre-verification of senior citizens based on Aadhaar details on voluntary basis with effect from January 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The system is intended to ensure that the senior citizen concession is not misused by unscrupulous elements by giving fictitious names and to use the data for decision making,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prabhu said to promote cashless ticketing system, various initiatives have been taken by the Indian Railways.
“Our ultimate destination is cashless ticket booking. But the immediate priority is less cash transaction,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government To Roll Out Aadhaar Pay For Cashless Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-roll-aadhaar-pay-cashless-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-roll-aadhaar-pay-cashless-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government will soon roll out Aadhaar Pay service that will enable people to make and receive payments using their Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are going to start Aadhaar Pay. With this people will not require to carry their phone for payments. They can visit any merchant, share their Aadhaar number and verify themselves using biometrics to pay and receive money,” Electronics and IT Minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, 14 banks have come on board for Aadhaar Pay and the service will be launched soon, Prasad told reporters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are in talks with other banks too. The service will be launched very soon,” he informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the Minister said, Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM), the common platform for making quick payments using the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), has also been integrated with Aadhaar Enabled Payment System on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 111 crore people in the country have Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are 49 crore bank accounts linked to Aadhaar. Every month 2 crore accounts are being seeded with Aadhaar,” Prasad said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to choose the right credit card: 6 power points to note</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-choose-the-right-credit-card-6-power-points-to-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-choose-the-right-credit-card-6-power-points-to-note/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opt for a credit card whose benefits in the form of cashbacks, discounts, reward points and lifestyle programmes outweigh the various mandatory fees associated with it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit cards today have become an integral part of our lives. They save us from the hassles of carrying cash, allow us to optimise our finances better through interest-free periods and EMI options, enable us to maintain a good credit score and avail attractive cashbacks, discounts and reward points offered by banks. However, with several types of credit cards available in the market, choosing the right one can be confusing for a customer. Here are some factors to be considered while selecting a credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spending-habits&#34;&gt;Spending habits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most credit cards aim at specific type of transactions by offering higher reward points and other benefits on those transactions. For example, while some cards offer cashback on fuel transactions or other daily spends, others offer more reward points on air travels, dining and/or hotel stays. Choose a card that will offer you maximum benefits, according to your lifestyle and spending habits. For example, if you travel a lot, take a credit card that offers travel benefits like air miles, lounge access and hotel vouchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fees&#34;&gt;Fees&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit card issuers charge various types of fees for their services, like joining fee, annual fee, rewards redemption fee, late payment fee and cash advance fee. The joining and annual fee usually ranges between Rs 199–5,000 depending on the card category. However, many card issuers do not charge joining fee and/or annual fee. Many cards also waive off their joining fee on applying through online loan aggregators while others reverse their annual and joining fee on spending a threshold amount through their credit cards. Opt for a credit card whose benefits in the form of cashbacks, discounts, reward points and lifestyle programmes outweigh the various mandatory fees associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;also-watch&#34;&gt;Also Watch:&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/FGMeZGdYUXo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;credit-limit&#34;&gt;Credit limit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit limit refers to the maximum amount that you can spend on your card without incurring any penalty. Exceeding this limit results in incurring an over limit fee on the amount exceeded. Thus, opt for a card that offers at least 3–4 times of your tentative monthly credit card spends. Also, remember that having a higher credit limit will come in handy during financial emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;joining-bonuses&#34;&gt;Joining bonuses&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many credit cards, especially in the premium and travel segments, offer attractive joining bonuses or welcome benefits in the form of free vouchers and additional bonus reward points. Many card issuers also offer exclusive joining bonuses on applying through online aggregators. Compare the joining bonuses among similar cards before zeroing on a particular option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;finance-charges&#34;&gt;Finance charges&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card issuers levy finance charges on non-payment or part-payment of outstanding balance by the due date and on cash withdrawals. This charge is levied right from the date of the transaction until the repayment of the entire outstanding. The finance charge can vary from 22–47% per annum depending on your card type. Though not paying your entire credit card bill on time or withdrawing cash using your credit card is never recommended, you should still consider these charges when applying for a credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credit-score&#34;&gt;Credit score&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approval of your credit card application primarily depends on your credit score, monthly income and occupational details. Each bank gives different weightage to these parameters. However, people with credit scores of 750 and above have higher chances of getting their credit card approved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp:10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 900 In Limited-Period Scheme. Details Here:IndiGo Offers Tickets</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indigo-offers-tickets-under-rs-900-in-limited-period-scheme-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indigo-offers-tickets-under-rs-900-in-limited-period-scheme-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IndiGo said the current offer is applicable on bookings made at least 20 days prior to the travel date.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IndiGo offers all-inclusive fares starting from Rs 899 on select flights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer valid on travel between June 26 and March 24, 2018, says IndiGo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make bookings 20 days prior to travel date, it adds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo has announced all-inclusive fares starting from Rs 899 on select one-way flights under a promotional scheme. IndiGo, which recently offered tickets from Rs 851 on select routes, said the current offer is applicable on bookings made at least 20 days prior to the travel date. Bookings under the Rs 899 scheme - applicable on travel between June 26 and March 24, 2018 - can be made till May 28, the airline said on its website. &amp;ldquo;This offer is applicable on all our booking channels,&amp;rdquo; IndiGo further said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IndiGo offer is valid only on non-stop flights from Ahmedabad, Amritsar, Bagdogra, Bengaluru, Chennai, Delhi, Goa, Guwahati, Hyderabad, Jaipur, Jammu, Kochi, Kolkata, Mumbai, Pune, Srinagar, and Visakhapatnam, among others. The IndiGo offer is also applicable on non-stop flights from Agartala, Chandigarh, Coimbatore, Dehradun, Madurai, Mangalore, Port Blair, Patna and Varanasi, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lowest all-inclusive Rs 899 tickets were being offered on flights from Srinagar to Jammu under the scheme, according to the IndiGo website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A search on the IndiGo bookings portal showed tickets for flights from Srinagar to Jammu in July were being offered at Rs 794.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other fares under the discounted fares scheme included Rs 999 for flights from Jammu to Srinagar; Rs 1,089 for Delhi-Jaipur; Rs 1,104 for Visakhapatnam-Hyderabad, Rs 1,165 for Agartala-Guwahati, Rs 1,179 for Madurai-Chennai, the IndiGo website noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other flights covered under the IndiGo scheme were Ahmedabad-Mumbai (fares starting from Rs 1,212), Bengaluru-Hyderabad (Rs 1,250) and Chennai-Coimbatore (Rs 1,169).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competition among airlines amid robust growth in number of passengers is leading to lower airfares and lucrative schemes for flyers, some analysts say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SpiceJet has announced discounted fares for non-stop flights across its network in a limited-period sale, under which it is offering tickets at a discounted base fare of Rs 12 (excluding surcharge and taxes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many airlines - including Air India, AirAsia, Jet Airways and GoAir - have offered discounted fares and lucrative schemes in the recent past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domestic air passenger traffic rose 15.15 per cent to 91.34 lakh in April, data from aviation regulator DGCA (Directorate General of Civil Aviation) showed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, economy class air travel is set to become cheaper with tax rate fixed at 5 per cent against the existing 6, under the upcoming indirect tax regime - Goods and Services Tax (GST) - from July 1. Business class tickets are expected to become more expensive as the tax will go up from 9 per cent to 12 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo plans to start flying smaller planes to second-tier towns and cities later this year under Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s UDAN or &amp;lsquo;Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik&amp;rsquo; scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Tickets Delivered To Home, Cash On Delivery</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-get-train-tickets-delivered-to-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-get-train-tickets-delivered-to-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IRCTC has now introduced pay-on-delivery as one of the payment options for its customers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has offered delivery of rail tickets allowing passengers to make payment through any payment mode, including cash. Broad-basing the customer service, the Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation has now introduced pay-on-delivery service allowing passengers to book train tickets online and pay at the time of delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC through its website and mobile app has now introduced pay-on-delivery as one of the payment options for its customers, said a senior IRCTC official. Delivering tickets at the consumer&amp;rsquo;s doorstep by offering the pay-on-delivery (PoD) option will facilitate those consumers who book through travel agents to move to online medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also encourage people who book at railway reservation counters to move to online medium as there is a cost and effort to reach the reservation counters. The customer will have to do a one-time registration for availing PoD as a payment option. He or she will have to tender either Aadhaar or Pan card to avail this payment option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PoD charges shall be Rs. 90 plus sales tax for transactions up to Rs. 5,000 and Rs. 120 plus tax for transactions over Rs. 5,000. In case of refusal or cancellation before delivery, the customer will be liable to pay the cancellation and delivery charges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UDAN Scheme: More Routes To Be Allocated By August</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/udan-scheme-more-routes-to-be-allocated-by-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/udan-scheme-more-routes-to-be-allocated-by-august/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The government will soon launch the second round of bidding under RCS-UDAN after receiving stakeholders&amp;rsquo; views on some proposed changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central government on Wednesday said that it will allocate more air routes under its regional connectivity scheme &amp;ndash; UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Nagrik) &amp;ndash; through the second round of bidding by August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Civil Aviation Minister P Ashok Gajapathi Raju, the government will soon launch the second round of bidding under RCS-UDAN after receiving stakeholders&amp;rsquo; views on some proposed changes to the scheme which are intended to make it simpler and attractive for participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry will organise a stakeholder consultation meet on June 7 and will accept stakeholders&amp;rsquo; comments on the proposed changes by June 9, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same event, Civil Aviation Secretary R.N. Choubey pointed out that the ministry is planning to host an &amp;ldquo;interactive meet&amp;rdquo; between state governments and airlines for the second round of bidding for Udan routes on July 7, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On April 27, 2017, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had flagged off the first Rs 2,500-an-hour flight between Shimla and New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scheme is a key component of the National Civil Aviation Policy (NCAP) which was released last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 30, 2017, the central government under the first round of bidding for the scheme awarded contracts to five companies to operate flight services on 128 routes that will connect 70 airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airline companies chosen during the first round of bidding were Airline Allied Services (Alliance Air), SpiceJet, Turbo Megha Airways, Air Deccan and Air Odisha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of RCS, christened as UDAN is to enhance air passenger traffic in the country by stimulating demand on regional routes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how do I protect my PC from WannaCry?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-do-i-protect-my-pc-from-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-do-i-protect-my-pc-from-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything you need to know about ransomware including the WannaCry attack, how to protect your PCs and laptops and what to do if you&amp;rsquo;re affected.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How does WannaCry work?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a lot of malware, it can arrive as an email attachment. This method relies on computer users opening the attachment, or clicking on a link in an email, which causes the program to run.
People often open these attachments or click links out of curiosity, because the sender is someone in their address book.
WannaCry then encrypts all the files and documents on the computer so the user cannot open them.
It displays a message saying “Ooops, your files have been encrypted!” and says you have three days to pay a $300 or $600 ransom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which versions of Windows are affected?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your computer runs Windows 10, it wasn’t targeted by WannaCry according to Microsoft’s blog post.
Also, up-to-date Windows 10 PCs would have been protected from the attack in any case.
The same security update in March would have protected Windows Vista, Windows 7 and Windows 8.1 systems, as long as you had automatic updates turned on (which is the default).
Only older versions of Windows which are no longer supported were vulnerable, including Windows XP and Windows 8.
It’s worth noting, though, that in general home users should not be affected by this particular piece of ransomware. It mainly targeted computers running the business version of Windows, specifically those using the SMB network file system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can I protect my files from WannaCry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has issued a security patch for Windows XP and Windows 8 – a very unusual step for unsupported operating systems – which you can download from the links on Microsoft’s blog.
If you have Windows Update enabled on other versions then you will already be protected against WannaCry and any other attacks which use the same vulnerability.
If you’re not sure, then open the Control Panel (you’ll find a link in the Start menu) and search for Windows Update. Click through to Windows Update and you’ll be able to check if it’s enabled or not.
There should be a button ‘Check for updates’ which you can click to force Windows to search and install critical updates.
Back up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, as we always recommend, you should have at least one (if not two) copies of any files you can’t afford to lose. Photos, home videos, financial documents and other files that can’t be replaced should be backed up regularly.
Ransomware is often clever enough to scan your home network and infect other computers and even network storage drives (NAS drives) so it’s really important to make a backup on an external hard drive that you disconnect and keep safely somewhere.
You can find our pick of the best backup software here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t open attachments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, as the computer user, are often the weak link in the chain. Windows and antivirus software – see below – can help to protect you from ransomware attacks, but you can help yourself by being extremely cautious about which email attachments you open and which links you click.
Typically, emails from hackers won’t contain a personal message, or it will be so generic that you can’t be sure it’s really from the person in the ‘sender’ field.
In WannaCry’s case, at least some of the emails pretended to be an important email from a bank about a money transfer.
Either just delete the email, or call the sender and ask them if they sent the email and what is in the attachment, or on the other end of the link. Unless you are absolutely sure the attachment is safe, don’t click on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Won’t antivirus software protect me from WannaCry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most but not all antivirus software now contains ‘anti-ransomware’ that should help protect your PCs and laptops from WannaCry and other ransomware.
That’s why it’s important not to rely just on Windows’ own security but to add an extra layer of protection.
Check out our list of the best antivirus to make sure you’re running one of our recommended packages. Our favourite is BitDefender, but there are plenty of other great options to choose from too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My PC is infected with WannaCry. What should I do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, don’t pay the ransom. It only encourages the criminals – getting paid is their end game.
Some security experts predict there could be a free ‘fix’ to decrypt the files in a few days and remove the malware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अधिकारियों के रेकॉर्ड पर ऑनलाइन नजर रखेगी मोदी सरकार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modi-government-will-keep-online-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modi-government-will-keep-online-records/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;नरेन्द्र मोदी सरकार ने अब अधिकारियों के कामकाज पर नजर रखने के लिए ऑनलाइन सिस्टम तैयार किया है। इसके जरिए ब्यूरोक्रैट्स के सर्विस रेकॉर्ड का आकलन होगा और खराब प्रदर्शन करने वालों या कम ईमानदार अधिकारियों को रिटायर करने का फैसला किया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डिपार्टमेंट ऑफ पर्सनल ऐंड ट्रेनिंग (DoPT) ने हाल ही में अन्य मंत्रालयों के साथ मिलकर &amp;lsquo;ऑनलाइन प्रोबिटी मैनेजमेंट सिस्टम&amp;rsquo; शुरू किया है। इसके जरिए अधिकारियों की ईमानदारी और प्रदर्शन के स्तर का आकलन किया जाएगा। सरकार 50-55 वर्ष की आयु वाले या नौकरी में 30 वर्ष पूरे कर चुके सभी अधिकारियों के प्रदर्शन का आकलन कर रही है। इसका मकसद यह फैसला करना है कि इन अधिकारियों को नौकरी जारी रखने की अनुमति दी जाए या उन्हें अनिवार्य तौर पर रिटायर कर दिया जाए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक सरकारी अधिकारी ने हमारे सहयोगी अखबार टाइम्स ऑफ इंडिया को बताया, &amp;lsquo;जिन अधिकारियों की समीक्षा की जानी है उनकी संख्या बहुत अधिक होने के कारण इसमें मंत्रालयों को काफी पेपरवर्क करने के साथ ही नियमित तौर पर रिपोर्ट्स जमा करनी पड़ती। नया &amp;lsquo;प्रोबिटी&amp;rsquo; पोर्टल इस प्रोसेस को पूरी तरह ऑनलाइन बना देगा और अब इसके जरिए मंत्रालय अपने रिपोर्ट्स ऑनलाइन जमा कर सकेंगी और सरकार को एक ही पोर्टल पर पूरी जानकारी मिल जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoPT और प्रधानमंत्री कार्यालय (PMO) के राज्यमंत्री जितेन्द्र सिंह ने मंगलवार को बताया था कि पिछले कुछ महीनों में ग्रुप A के 30 और ग्रुप B के 99 अधिकारियों को रिटायरमेंट दी गई है। उन्होंने कहा था कि सरकार ने इस तरह की अनिवार्य रिटायरमेंट देने से पहले ग्रुप A के 24,000 और ग्रुप B के 42,251 अधिकारियों के रेकॉर्ड की जांच की थी। इसके अलावा सरकार खराब प्रदर्शन करने वालों की जांच के लिए ग्रुप A के 34,451 और ग्रुप B के 42,521 अधिकारियों के सर्विस रेकॉर्ड देख रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक सीनियर अधिकारी ने ताया कि नया &amp;lsquo;प्रोबिटी&amp;rsquo; पोर्टल संवेदनशील और गैर-संवेदशील पदों पर अधिकारियों के रोटेशन पर भी नजर रख रहा है। इसके जरिए उन अधिकारियों की पहचान की जाएगी जो संवेदनशील पदों पर लंबे समय से मौजूद हैं। इसके अलावा DoPT के स्पैरो (स्मार्ट परफॉर्मेंस अप्रेजल रिपोर्ट रिकॉर्डिंग ऑनलाइन विंडो) सिस्टम के जरिए संबंधित मिनिस्ट्रीज की ओर से समीक्षा के लिए पूरे अप्रेजल सिस्टम को ऑनलाइन बनाया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoPT ने हाल ही में &amp;lsquo;स्पैरो&amp;rsquo; का दायरा केवल आईएएस कैडर से बढ़ाते हुए 13 कैडर तक किया था। DoPT का तीसरा पोर्टल &amp;lsquo;सॉल्व&amp;rsquo;- सिस्टम फॉर ऑनलाइन विजिलेंस इनक्वॉयरी फॉर बोर्ड लेवल अप्वाइंटीज- है। इस पोर्टल का दायरा बढ़ाकर अन्य एंप्लॉयीज तक करने की योजना है, जिससे सरकार को अधिकारियों के प्रदर्शन और ईमानदारी का आकलन करने के लिए &amp;lsquo;प्रोबिटी&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;स्पैरो&amp;rsquo; और &amp;lsquo;सॉल्व&amp;rsquo; पोर्टल्स के बीच कोऑर्डिनेट करने में मदद मिलेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब 1079 रुपए में करें हवाई सफर, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jet-airways-monsoon-sale-fares-starting-from-rs-1079-for-a-limited-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jet-airways-monsoon-sale-fares-starting-from-rs-1079-for-a-limited-period/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जेट एयरवेज के मानसून ऑफर को लेकर कंपनी की ओर से कहा कि यह सेल यात्रियों को मानसून के लिए एडवांस प्लानिंग करने का मौका प्रदान करता है। साथ ही आकर्षक बचत का भी मौका दे रहा है।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मानसून पर घूमने जाने की प्लानिंग कर रहे हैं और तो जेट एयरवेज आपके के लिए सस्ती हवाई सफर का तोहफा लाया है। एविएशन कंपनी जेट एयरवेज ने हवाई यात्रियों को 1000 रुपए से कुछ ज्यादा में हवाई सफर उपलब्ध करवा रही है। जेट एयरवेज के इस मानसून सेल की टिकट की कीमत 1079 रुपए (सभी करों सहित) से शुरू हो रही है। इस बात की जानकारी कंपनी द्वारा अपनी प्रेस रिलीज में दी गई है। जेट की यह स्कीन चुनिंदा रूट्स पर लागू होगी। इस ऑफर के तहत पैसेंजर 24 मई से 26 मई (तीन दिन) के बीच टिकट बुक करा कर यात्रा कर सकता है। ऑफर के तहत बुक की गई टिकट पर 15 जून से 20 सितंबर के मध्य यात्रा की जा सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जेट एयरवेज के मानसून ऑफर को लेकर कंपनी की ओर से कहा कि यह सेल यात्रियों को मानसून के लिए एडवांस प्लानिंग करने का मौका प्रदान करता है। साथ ही आकर्षक बचत का भी मौका दे रहा है। इस ऑफर के तहत टिकट पहले आओ और पहले पाओ के तहत बुक की जाएंगी। इस ऑफर के साथ किसी भी प्रोमोशन ऑफर का लाभ नहीं लिया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनी के चीफ कॉमर्शियल ऑफिसर जयराज ने कहा कि जेट एयरवेज का यह ऑफर यात्रियों को देश भर के चुनिंदा स्थानों की खोज और अनुभव का मौका प्रदान करेंगी। इसके अलावा लोग एयरलाइंस की मेहमाननवाजी का भी लुत्फ उठा सकेंगे। साथ ही पैसों की बचत करने में भी आपको मदद मिलेगी।
बता दें कि मानसून को देखते हुए देश के अधिकतर एयरलाइंस कंपनियां यात्रियों को सस्ते हवाई सफर का तोहफा दे रही है। इससे पहले विस्तारा और एयर एशिया ने सस्ते हवाई सफर का मौका दिया था। विस्तारा के ऑफर के तहत 999 रुपए में टिकट बुक की जा सकती है। वहीं, एयर एशिया के “Buy Now, Fly Now” के ऑफर के तहत मात्र 1031 रुपए में हवाई सफर का आनंद लिया जा सकता था। एयरएशिया इंडिया की इस स्कीम में 21 मई 2017 तक बुकिंग की जा सकती थी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ज्यादा EMI तो नहीं भर रहे हैं आप? यूं पता करें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/are-you-paying-more-emi-for-your-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/are-you-paying-more-emi-for-your-housing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;एक भारी-भरकम होम लोन की ईएमआई आपको &amp;lsquo;गरीब&amp;rsquo; बना सकती है। यह ऐसे हालात होते हैं जहां व्यक्ति महंगी अचल संपत्ति का मालिक तो है लेकिन ईएमआई का भुगतान करने के बाद अन्य खर्चों के लिए उसके पास कुछ नहीं बचता। यह जानने के लिए कि आप अपने घर के लिए ज्यादा भुगतान तो नहीं कर रहे, इन सवालों के जवाब देकर देखें कितने अंक मिले हैं आपको&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अपने खर्चे का अनुमान इस आधार पर लगाएं-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A- 1 पॉइंट
B- 2 पॉइंट
C- 3 पॉइंट&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- हाउस लोन चुकाने के लिए कितने साल बचे हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) &amp;gt;10 साल
b) 5-10 साल
c) &amp;lt;5 साल&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- अपनी आय का कितना हिस्सा होम लोन ईएमआई चुकाने में खर्च करते हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) आय का आधे से ज्यादा हिस्सा
b) आय का लगभग आधा हिस्सा
c) आय का आधे से कम हिस्सा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3- पर्सनल और कार लोन मिलाकर आपको कितने लोन चुकाने हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) मुझे दो से ज्यादा लोन चुकाने हैं।
b) मुझे दो लोन चुकाने हैं।
c) मुझे सिर्फ एक लोन चुकाना है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4- जरूरत पड़ने पर आप कितनी जल्दी अपनी संपत्ति को बेच सकते हैं?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) लगभग दो साल
b) 12 से 24 महाने के बीच
c) 12 महीनों में&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5- लोन की ईएमआई और घर खर्च के बाद आय का कितना हिस्सा सेविंग्स के लिए बचता है?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) &lt;10%
b) 10-30%
c) &gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आपका स्कोर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 पॉइंट्स से ज्यादा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप एक बेहतर स्थिति में हैं और बिना किसी परेशानी के अपनी सभी जरूरतों को पूरा कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8-11 पॉइंट्स&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप सभी जरूरतों के लिए योगदान करने में तब तक मुश्किल स्थिति में हैं, जब तक आप अपनी इनकम-प्रोफ़ाइल बढ़ाने या लागत में कटौती करने में सक्षम न हों।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 पॉइंट्स से कम&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आप व्यावहारिक रूप से &amp;lsquo;गरीब-घर&amp;rsquo; हालात में रह रहे हैं। जरूरतें मुश्किल से पूरी हो रही हैं, ऐसे में आपको तत्काल विकल्पों का मूल्यांकन करना होगा ताकि अन्य आवश्यकताओं पर समझौता न करना पड़े।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बेनामी 400 सौदों का खुलासा, 600 करोड़ की संपत्ति कुर्क</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/i-t-department-unearths-400-benami-deals-attaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/i-t-department-unearths-400-benami-deals-attaches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने बुधवार को बताया कि उसने 400 से ज्यादा बेनामी सौदों की पहचान कर ली है। विभाग ने कहा कि बेनामी कानून के तहत कुल 240 से अधिक मामलों में 600 करोड़ रुपये मूल्य की संपत्तियों की कुर्की की जा चुकी है। नए बेनामी कानून को अच्छी तरह लागू करने के लिए आयकर विभाग ने पिछले सप्ताह देशभर में 24 बेनामी निषेध इकाइयां (बीपीयू) स्थापित कीं, ताकि इस कानून के जमीनी परिणाम दिखना सुनिश्चित हो।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने पिछले साल नवंबर से नए बेनामी लेन-देन (निषेध) संशोधन कानून, 2016 के तहत कार्रवाइयां करनी शुरू कर दी थीं। कानून के तहत अधिकतम सात साल जेल की सजा और जुर्माने का प्रावधान किया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बेनामी संपत्ति में चल या अचल, मूर्त या अमूर्त (ब्रैंड, इक्विटी या इंटेलेक्चुअल प्रॉपर्टी) एवं वैसी संपत्तियां शामिल हैं जो उस व्यक्ति के नाम पर नहीं होती हैं जो हकीकत में इसका लाभ उठाता है। एक अधिकारिक विज्ञप्ति में कहा गया है, &amp;lsquo;इनकम टैक्स डायरेक्टरेट्स ऑफ इन्वेस्टिगेशन ने 23 मई 2017 तक 400 से ज्यादा बेनामी लेन-देन का पता लगाया है। इनमें बैंक अकाउंट्स, जमीन के प्लॉट्स, फ्लैट और जूलरी शामिल हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कानून के तहत 240 से ज्यादा संपत्तियों की अस्थाई तौर पर कुर्की कर ली गई है। बाजार में इनकी कीमत 600 करोड़ रुपये से ज्यादा है। टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;40 मामलों में कोलकाता, मुंबई, दिल्ली, गुजरात, राजस्थान और मध्य प्रदेश से 530 करोड़ रुपये से ज्यादा कीमत की अचल संपत्ति कुर्क हुई है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने बताया कि पिछले एक महीने में 10 वरिष्ठ सरकारी अधिकारों के यहां भी तलाशी अभियान चलाए गए, ताकि भ्रष्ट आचरण से की गई काली कमाई का खुलासा कर सार्वजनिक जीवन में जवाबदेही एवं विश्वनीयता सुनिश्चित की जा सके।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने तलाशी अभियानों का ब्योरा देते हुए बताया कि जयपुर में एक &amp;lsquo;बेनामीदार&amp;rsquo; ड्राइवर निकला जिसके नाम पर 7.7 करोड़ रुपये मूल्य की जमीन पाई गई जबकि हकीकत में वह संपत्ति मध्य प्रदेश की एक लिस्टेड कंपनी की है जहां वह काम करता है। इसी तरह एक अन्य मामले में राजस्थान के सांगनेर में एक जूलर ने अपने पूर्व कर्माचरी के नाम पर नौ अचल संपत्तियां रखी थीं। विभाग ने कोलकाता में शेल कंपनियों से खरीदी गईं कुछ संपत्तियां भी जब्त कर लीं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>