<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7 reasons to file your tax return early</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-return-7-reasons-to-file-your-tax-return-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-return-7-reasons-to-file-your-tax-return-early/</guid>
      <description>Are you in a never ending battle with your Income Tax Return? Do you for some reason or another get really close to the due date when filing the return? We thought so! To get you out of the practice of filing your return close to the due date, we have compiled a list of the most irresistible benefits to file your Income Tax Returns early:
 Faster refund process: You read it right!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks To Start Charging For Person To Person Payments On UPI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</guid>
      <description>SBI is charging Rs 5 per transaction of up to Rs 1 lakh, Rs 15 for transactions between Rs 1-2 lakh and Rs 25 for those between Rs 2 lakh and Rs 5 lakh, while HDFC Bank is proposing Rs 3 for transactions of up to Rs 25,000 and Rs 5 for those between Rs 25,000 and Rs 1 lakh.
Nearly two years after operationalisation of the Unified Payment Interface (UPI), banks have started moving to charge for peer-to-peer payments on the new platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Mistakes While Filing ITR (Income Tax Return) And How to Avoid Them</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/common-mistakes-while-filing-itr-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/common-mistakes-while-filing-itr-and-how-to-avoid-them/</guid>
      <description>Are you always worried about filing your income tax return (ITR) the wrong way? Here are some of the most common mistakes that people make while filing ITR. By avoiding them, you will be able to file your taxes in a hassle-free manner:
 Filing the wrong ITR form  Using the wrong type of ITR is one of the most common mistakes. If you earn income from salary only, you should file your return in Form ITR 1 (Sahaj).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.
SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonetisation: Opening another window to deposit Rs 500, Rs 1000 notes will be good; here is why</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-opening-another-window-to-deposit-rs-500-rs-1000-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-opening-another-window-to-deposit-rs-500-rs-1000-notes/</guid>
      <description>Seven months after demonetisation, the controversies around it aren’t going away. Apart from the debate over whether it was desirable, the government did all manner of flip-flops—given that this was the first such exercise anywhere in the world, and so there was no playbook to go by, though, that may have been unavoidable. What was not was the time given for people to exchange their old notes, given the rush at banks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt makes Aadhaar mandatory for students</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</guid>
      <description>The move is aimed at checking the drop-out rate and ensuring quality education
The Yogi Adityanath government in Uttar Pradesh has made Aadhaar Card mandatory for students from Class 1 to 8 in government schools. The Basic Education department has been entrusted with this task involving over 1.75 crore students.
The Basic Education Minister Anupama Jaiswal said that directions have been issued in this regard. “The main aim of the government is to link their Aadhaar Card number with different welfare schemes, including mid-day meal, run by the state for the welfare of primary students,” she said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.
After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New WannaCry-Like Ransomware Hits Computer Servers Across The Globe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-wannacry-like-ransomware-hits-computer-servers-across-the-globe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-wannacry-like-ransomware-hits-computer-servers-across-the-globe/</guid>
      <description>A ransomware attack hit computers across the world on Tuesday, taking out servers at Russia&amp;rsquo;s biggest oil company, disrupting operations at Ukrainian banks, and shutting down computers at multinational shipping and advertising firms.
Cyber security experts said those behind the attack appeared to have exploited the same type of hacking tool used in the WannaCry ransomware attack that infected hundreds of thousands of computers in May before a British researcher created a kill-switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.
Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petya ransomware attack: What you should do so that your security is not compromised</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petya-ransomware-attack-what-you-should-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petya-ransomware-attack-what-you-should-do/</guid>
      <description>A new wave of ransomware has affected critical infrastructure and business systems worldwide. The attack, carried out with an updated version of Petya, has not yet been stopped.
Europol is currently actively monitoring the spread of the ransomware and is in close contact with different law enforcement authorities from the infected countries, including India.
Europol&amp;rsquo;s executive director Rob Wainwright said, &amp;ldquo;This is another serious ransomware attack with global impact, although the number of victims is not yet known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue Rs 200 Notes In Coming Months: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-rs-200-notes-in-coming-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-rs-200-notes-in-coming-months/</guid>
      <description>The Reserve Bank is expected to introduce Rs 200 notes in the coming months to ease pressure on lower-denomination currencies that are in short supply.
The new notes of Rs 200 should be out before the end of 2017 and will greatly help in narrowing the demand and supply gap in smaller-denomination currency bills, sources said.
They also said that there is no immediate plan to re-introduce Rs 1,000 notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 5 Recharge, Vodafone Offers Unlimited Data.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone said in a press release that the 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively.
Amid a telecom industry witnessing Jio&amp;rsquo;s highly competitive tariff pricing, Vodafone India on Tuesday announced unlimited data plans with free local and STD calls priced from Rs 5 per day in the UP West telecom circle. Aimed at the Ramzan festival, Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively, according to a press release by the telecom company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 500 4G VoLTE Reliance  jio handset</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-rs-500-4g-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-rs-500-4g-phone/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is likely to launch its much-awaited 4G VoLTE feature phone within this month, with brokerage HSBC putting the price at as low as Rs 500, a move which could bring in another wave of disruption in the telecom market.
The launch — which some believe could be announced at parent Reliance Industries’ annual general meeting on July 21— would follow Jio’s likely announcement of a new tariff plan with aggressive price-points over the next couple of days with its 84-day Dhan Dhana Dhan offer — announced on April 11 — drawing to a close, people familiar with the matter said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.
 The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.
Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea stall where PM Modi sold tea to be placed on tourism map</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tea-stall-where-pm-modi-sold-tea-to-be-placed-on-tourism-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tea-stall-where-pm-modi-sold-tea-to-be-placed-on-tourism-map/</guid>
      <description>Converting the stall into a tourist spot is part of a larger project of putting PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s birthplace Vadnagar in Mehsana district of Gujarat on the global tourism map
The tea stall in Gujarat’s Vadnagar where Prime Minister Narendra Modi once sold tea during his childhood is set to become a tourist spot with the government deciding to give it a face-lift. The stall is located on one of the platforms of the Vadnagar Railway station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>your Aadhaar is safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</guid>
      <description>Amidst concerns regarding Aadhaar data leak, a look at how the unique identification system actually adheres to the principles of privacy
Privacy and data protection concerns have become serious in a digital world due to ease of search and aggregation, with or without Aadhaar. Type any name in Google and it will throw up thousands of results, giving data/information publicly available. Hence, the responsibility falls on organisations which collect data from individuals to protect it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।
विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>शुरू हुई 200 रुपये के नोटों की छपाई, जल्द आएंगे प्रचलन में!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/printing-of-rs-200-currency-notes-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/printing-of-rs-200-currency-notes-begins/</guid>
      <description>नोटबंदी के बाद 500 और 2000 रुपये के नए नोट मार्केट में लाने के बाद केंद्र सरकार अब 200 रुपये के नोट उतारने की तैयारी में है। भारतीय रिजर्व बैंक द्वारा इसकी छपाई भी शुरू कर दी गई है। केंद्रीय बैंक का कहना है कि लोगों के लिए ट्रांजैक्शंस को आसान करने के मकसद से इस नोट को जारी किया जाएगा। पूरे मामले से जुड़े दो लोगों ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया कि आरबीआई की ओर से कुछ सप्ताह पहले ही इन नोटों की छपाई का आदेश दिया गया है। इसके बाद से ही सरकारी प्रिंटिंग प्रेस में इन नोटों की छपाई का काम चल रहा है। पहले इन नोटों को जुलाई में जारी किए जाने की बात की जा रही थी, लेकिन अब इसमें कुछ देरी हो सकती है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Rooted’ Phones May Soon Have No Place In Modi’s Cashless India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rooted-phones-may-soon-no-place-modis-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rooted-phones-may-soon-no-place-modis-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>India is considering a ban on smartphones with modified firmware from all of its cashless payment platforms due to security concerns, according to the chief of National Payments Corporation of India which manages all retail payment systems in the country. “These smartphones have a certain degree of vulnerability in the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), the Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) or any kind of financial system”, AP Hota, chief executive officer and managing director of NPCI told BloombergQuint.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>