<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Lucky Grahak, Digi Dhan: Rs 1 Crore Jackpot For Person Making Rs 1,590 Digital Payment</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of the Digi Dhan scheme, three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were declared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Pranab Mukherjee picked six winners from a draw of lots under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes, aimed at promoting digital transactions in the country. &amp;ldquo;In the consumer category, three mega Prizes of Rs 1 crore, Rs 50 lakh and Rs 25 lakh went to the Consumers using Rupay Debit Cards making digital payment of less than Rs.1,000,&amp;rdquo; an official release said. Three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were also declared at the event on the final day of the 100-day scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction of Rs. 1,590 won a Central Bank of India customer a lucky draw of Rs. 1 crore under the consumer category, as part of the government&amp;rsquo;s promotional scheme to popularise digital payments. The President congratulated all the six winners - three consumers and three merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am happy today to be a part of the digital payment movement that India has embarked upon. I congratulate each one of you who has contributed in this mission to make India a less cash society,&amp;rdquo; the President said in his address on the occasion of mega draw of lots for the two schemes held at Rashtrapati Bhawan on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners will be felicitated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on April 14 at Nagpur on the occasion of Ambedkar Jayanti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his address, Mr Mukherjee asked citizens to extend their unstinted support to the mission of a less-cash India. &amp;ldquo;India has a long way to go to become a cash less society. The initiatives of the government are a good beginning and we need to sustain and nurture these with active participation from all segments of the society&amp;hellip;It is necessary to reduce cash in circulation and impart greater urgency to promoting secure digital payment methods to ensure greater transparency,&amp;rdquo; the President said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the consumer section, the second prize of Rs 50 lakh went to a Bank of Baroda customer while the third prize of Rs. 25 lakh was bagged by a customer of Punjab National Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the three customers had made the transactions using their RuPay debit cards. The names of three winners were not yet known as the draw only displayed their transaction numbers. These will be matched with card details to identify the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital transactions have gathered momentum giving a fillip to the less cash economy post demonetisation thanks to the initiatives taken by the government. NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digidhan Vyapar schemes have played a catalytic role in making it a mass movement, the statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressing that India is on the cusp of a digital revolution, Mr Mukherjee noted that more than one billion Indians have a unique identity number with a biometric identifier which is unique in its own way. &amp;ldquo;Even countries which are technologically far more advanced than India with comparatively much smaller size population do not have such a system in place. The Aadhaar card initiative is a watershed event in the development story of India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs. 1,000 notes on November 9 last year, the government took a slew of measures to promote digital payments in the country. It had launched the Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes on December 25 last year for consumers and merchants, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes are being implemented by the National Payment Corporation of India (NPCI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the scheme, daily, weekly and monthly rewards worth Rs. 256 crore have been disbursed to over 16 lakh citizens over the past 100 days for making and accepting small transactions digitally. Over the past 100 days, everyday 15,000 consumers have qualified for total prize money of Rs. 1.5 crore, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The draw has seen a positive impact from various age groups and occupations in adopting digital payments methods. We have seen a steady increase in the number of transactions made using all payment methods,&amp;rdquo; said A P Hota, MD and CEO of National Payment Corporation of India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory For Subsidy: Indian Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to curb corruption in the Public Distribution System (PDS), the Indian government had made the Aadhar Card mandatory for availing foodgrain subsidy at PDS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has already made Aadhar Card mandatory for the cooking gas LPG subsidy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has declared Rs 1.4 lakh crore subsidy under the food security law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A timeline till June 30 is given for the common people who avail subsidy to apply for Aadhar Card, the government categorically stated in the notification in this regard that no subsidised foodgrains with Aadhaar after June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since November 2016, the Government of India, under the National Food Security Law (NFSA), has been providing 5 kg of foodgrains per person per month at Rs 1-3/kg to over 80 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification has been applicable from February 8 in all States and Union Territories (UTs) except Assam, Meghalaya and Jammu and Kashmir. This move indicates Government’s serious intetion of digitisation to curb the corruption in PDS as well as a move towards a simplifies delivery process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Still Get Reliance Jio&#39;s &#39;Summer Surprise Offer&#39;? Here Are The Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-you-still-get-jios-summer-surprise-offer-here-are-the-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-you-still-get-jios-summer-surprise-offer-here-are-the-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although, the offer can still be availed over the &amp;ldquo;next few days&amp;rdquo; and those who &amp;ldquo;subscribe before the discontinuation&amp;rdquo; will remain eligible for the complimentary plan,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s website stated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) asked Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio to withdraw the complimentary &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; plan as it did not fit into the &amp;ldquo;regulatory framework&amp;rdquo;. Reliance Jio has accepted the regulator&amp;rsquo;s decision and is in the process of &amp;ldquo;fully complying&amp;rdquo; with it. Jio &amp;lsquo;complimentary&amp;rsquo; offer included free data usage and calls for three months on a recharge of Rs 303 or higher. Although, the offer can still be availed over the &amp;ldquo;next few days&amp;rdquo; and those who &amp;ldquo;subscribe before the discontinuation&amp;rdquo; will remain eligible for the complimentary plan,&amp;rdquo; the company&amp;rsquo;s website stated.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/reliance-jio_650x400_61491559381.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We examined it and found that it was not in accordance with regulatory framework, so we advised them to stop it,&amp;rdquo; TRAI Chairman RS Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the regulator&amp;rsquo;s decision, Cellular Operators Association of India (COAI) said that the TRAI&amp;rsquo;s move to stop the three-month complimentary offer would reduce the deterioration in industry&amp;rsquo;s revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When the regulator establishes a level-playing-field, the market forces establish the right price points,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said, terming the withdrawal of the offer as a &amp;ldquo;relief&amp;rdquo; for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the data released by TRAI, the revenue of telecom sector from consumer services like mobile telephony and data dipped 10.5 per cent to Rs 37,284 crore in the October-December period over the previous three months. The revenue of the sector from the same set of services stood at Rs 41,681 crore in July-September last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incumbent telecom operators have blamed free services of new entrant Reliance Jio for the decline in their quarterly numbers. While Jio provided free 4G service during the period, other telecom operators struggled to compete with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Aadhaar With PAN Made Mandatory: How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the government insists that one&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar account and Permanent Account Number (PAN) should be linked by July 31 this year to pay income taxes, millions of Indians have faced issues with syncing the two accounts due to small differences in how their names are spelt. This problem can happen even if there are minor differences in how the name is recorded &amp;ndash; like the use of one&amp;rsquo;s full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar. Issues have also cropped up due to use of special characters in the initials and punctuation that often form a person&amp;rsquo;s name as Aadhaar doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize such characters but PAN does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, while one solution is to apply for a name correction in either Aadhaar or PAN card - both time consuming procedures - the government has stepped in to provide a simple solution for frustrated potential taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If an individual&amp;rsquo;s name on the Aadhaar does not match his/her name on the PAN card, the person can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A taxpayer can also log in to the Aadhaar website and request for a change in the name which will be verified using a one-time password on the phone number registered with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One-Time Passwords (OTP) will be used in cases where there are people who have gotten married and changed their surname. In such instances the tax department will give an OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number. The tax department, on its part, would&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department is also planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for OTP, provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told news agency Press Trust of India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.08 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN, but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people. As per statistics with the tax department, only six crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Mandatory For Filing Tax Returns, PAN Card From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting of Aadhaar has been made mandatory for filing income tax returns with effect from July 1, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, an official statement said on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961 as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017 provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar /Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from July 1,&amp;rdquo; said a Finance Ministry statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or Enrolment ID will apply only to a person who is eligible to obtain Aadhaar number, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act, 2016, only a resident individual is entitled to obtain Aadhaar. Resident as per the said Act means an individual who has resided in India for a period or periods amounting in all to 182 days or more in the 12 months immediately preceding the date of application for enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the requirement to quote Aadhaar as per section 139AA of the Income-tax Act shall not apply to an individual who is not a resident as per the Aadhaar Act, 2016, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar card to be linked with flights soon?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linked-flights-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linked-flights-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Delhi: The Central government has now asked Information Technology major Wipro to come up with reports and to develop a blueprint for Aadhaar-based biometric access to flight passengers at all airports across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, based on government’s direction, Wipro is likely to submit a report in May after which the airports will start the process where a flyer’s thumb would be all the identification they need to be eligible to fly on domestic flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aviation ministry had an idea about linking Aadhaar number with flight bookings which enables the biometric access possible at all airports. Reports revealed that the solid push was taken by Aviation Minister Jayant Sinha and Aviation Secretary R N Choubey in a meeting with several airport operators and airlines officials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Airports Authority of India chief Guruprasad Mohapatra, he said that linking of Aadhaar card number and thumb identification will help an official know about the passenger boarding the flight. Mohapatra explained that at the time of booking, a passenger enters his/her Aadhaar number. On arrival at an airport, the passenger can just place the thumb on the touchpad at an entry point and at other points inside the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohapatra added that AAI wants the passengers to have effortless and seamless travel experience at airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As everyone is aware that due to security reasons, a passenger in India has to show his or her identification card along with the tickets to enter the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has been trying to make Aadhaar as the sole identity card in the future a move that could possibly replace PAN, voter and ration cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an Aadhaar card is mandatory: Getting a passport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hassle-free passport services: Now, you can get a passport in just 10 days if you have an Aadhaar card. The government has announced that an Adhaar card or e-Aadhaar card can be used as proof of date of birth while applying for passports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income tax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is trying to file income tax returns needs to link their Aadhaar number with their PAN before July. If one fails to do so it will not be considered as a valid ITR filing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to provident fund&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Provident Fund Organisation has also made it compulsory for all pensioners and members to submit their Aadhaar card numbers. It is basically done for pensioners to avail hassle-free pension at the time of retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile connections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a department of telecom notification that was issued on Friday, the telecom operators have been directed to re-verify their existing subscribers — both prepaid and postpaid — through an Aadhaar-based eKYC process by February 6, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For free LPG connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre announced that Aadhaar card is now mandatory for women in the Below Poverty Line category applying for a free LPG connection. Applicants without the unique ID number have until May 31 to apply for it to avail the benefits under the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana, the ministry of petroleum and natural gas said in a notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway ticket booking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railways have also made plans to link Aadhaar with ticket booking. They have also held a discussion with UIDAI for linking Aadhaar number with the booking of a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a driving licence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has planned to make Aadhaar mandatory for seeking a new licence or renewal of your driving licence in a bid to ensure that there are no multiple driving licences under one name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the ‘Midday meal scheme’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry of human resource development announced that the mid-day meal would no longer be free for those children without an Aadhaar card. It was stated that children must be enrolled in the Aadhar scheme by June 30, if they were to get a free meal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar to be mandatory for driving licence, effective from October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As per an order issued by the central government, Aadhaar card will become mandatory for issuance of fresh driving licences or for renewal of the same. This rule will come into effect starting October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind the move is to eradicate the issuance of multiple driving licences across different states. It will help the government to enforce traffic regulations more effectively as drivers won’t have multiple driving licences to fall back on, which isn’t an uncommon practice in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linking Aadhaar card to the driver’s licence will enable the government to maintain a centralised database (known as Sarathi). Regional Transport Offices (RTO) from all over the country can log on and instantly check whether the applicant of a driver’s licence has another one in any other part of the country. The National Informatics Centre (NIC) has already uploaded almost all the data available in RTOs across the country on to the common database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union Road Transport Ministry is currently briefing the state governments about the changes that will eventually be incorporated in the process of issuing a driver’s licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This briefing also talks about citizens who do not have an Aadhaar card issued to their name. In that case, he/she will have to submit multiple documents, although it is unclear what those additional documents will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State governments across the nation have come up with hefty penalties for breaking traffic laws and regulations. One such penalty in many states is the confiscation of driver’s licence for a few months or indefinitely, depending on the severity of the law broken.  This move will will surely force citizens to take traffic laws a lot more seriously once their licences are linked to Sarathi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Summer Surprise Packs Offer Up To 100 GB Of 4G Data</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-summer-surprise-packs-offer-up-to-100-gb-of-4g-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-summer-surprise-packs-offer-up-to-100-gb-of-4g-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime prepaid customers opting for Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 999 recharge pack will get 100GB of free data for 90 days under the Summer Surprise offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio has announced a &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer under which it is offering 100 GB of data as complimentary benefit under select recharge packs. Jio also extended its enrolment for paid Prime scheme by 15 days. &amp;ldquo;Jio Prime offers many attractive benefits - the absolute best data tariffs in the industry, free voice calling, access to all Jio apps, and many more periodic surprises going forward. Jio prime members will always get the very best of what Jio has to offer,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani said in a letter to Jio members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Summer Surprise scheme, Jio prepaid customers subscribing to Prime are being offered complimentary benefits under various recharge packs. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime members making their first paid recharge of Rs 303 plan (or any higher value plan) till April 15, 2017 will get three months of services on a complimentary basis. The paid tariff plan will be applied only in July, after the expiry of the complimentary offer. (Also read: Summer Surprise offer features, extra benefits)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime prepaid customers opting for Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 999 recharge pack will get 100GB of free data for 90 days under the Summer Surprise offer. After July, under the Rs 999 pack, Prime members will 60 GB of data for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, on recharges of Rs 1,999 (125 GB of data with validity of 90 days), Rs. 4,999 (350GB-180 days) and Rs. 9,999 (750GB-360 days), Prime plan members will get 100 GB data for 90 days, according to Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of recharge packs which offer 100GB of free high-speed data under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Summer Surprise offer:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-100gb-90-days_650x400_41491373824.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New ITR Form Filers: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-itr-form-1-sahaj-to-benefit-2-crore-filers-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-itr-form-1-sahaj-to-benefit-2-crore-filers-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sahaj makes quoting of the 12-digit Aadhaar number mandatory along with Permanent Account Number (PAN).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax return filing season has started. The Income Tax Department has launched e-filing facility for the assessment year 2017-18. In this regard, the tax department has also launched a simplified one-page ITR-1 form called Sahaj. This ITR Form-1 (Sahaj) can be filed by an individual having income up to Rs 50 lakh and who is receiving income from salary, one house property or other income (interest etc). The Income Tax Return Form-1 or Sahaj will replace the earlier seven-page form, making it much easier for filing returns for most taxpayers. The simplified ITR will &amp;ldquo;reduce the compliance burden to a significant extent on the individual tax payer&amp;rdquo;, the Income Tax Department said. Simultaneously, the number of ITR Forms has been reduced from the existing nine to seven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not much tinkering has been done with the contents of existing form and some redundant columns have been done away with which will simplify the filing to some extent for a vast majority of people. However, mandatory quoting of Aadhaar may cause some hardship as there will be a sudden rush for such people to apply for Aadhaar who don&amp;rsquo;t have one yet,&amp;rdquo; said Sandeep Sehgal, director-tax and regulatory at Ashok Maheshwary &amp;amp; Associates LLP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 key highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Sahaj makes quoting of the 12-digit Aadhaar number mandatory along with Permanent Account Number (PAN). While the earlier ITR form too had a column to quote Aadhaar, the government has through an amendment to the Income Tax Act made quoting it mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Cash deposited in excess of Rs 2 lakh during the November 9-December 30 period last year, if any, has to be mentioned in Sahaj.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) In the new form, the parts relating to tax computation and deductions have been rationalised and simplified for easy compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Besides personal details, an income tax filer needs to disclose only his or her income from salary or pension, one house property and other sources like interest. Thereafter, deduction claims are to be stated, followed by computation of taxable income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Instead of 20 columns of deductions in the old form, only five columns need to be filled - four columns specifically for claims in respect of Sections 80C, 80D, 80G and 80TTA, and one for other deductions to be specified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Section 80C is one of the most popular avenues for claiming income tax deductions. Under this section, a deduction of up to Rs 1.5 lakh is allowed. PPF, EPF, life insurance premium etc. qualify for deductions under this section. Section 80D refers to deduction for premium paid for medical insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Section 80G pertains to contributions made to certain relief funds and charitable institutions while 80TTA provides a deduction of Rs 10,000 on interest income from savings account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Bank details are to be filled in the next column. Details of advance tax, self-assessment tax payments and tax deducted at source (TDS) come next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The simplified tax form will benefit more than two crore taxpayers who will be eligible to file their returns through this simplified form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) The existing income tax return forms ITR-2, ITR-2A and ITR-3 have been rationalised and a single ITR-2 form has been notified in place of these three forms. Taxpayers having more than one house will have to file the ITR-2 form. Details of exempt income (income not to be included in total income) like long-term capital gains from transactions on which securities transaction tax is paid has been made mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ने पर अवैध हो जाएगा PAN,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) को आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ा तो संभव है कि 31 दिसंबर के बाद यह अवैध हो जाए। दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के सरकार के फैसले के बाद इसे वित्तीय लेनदेन (फाइनैंशल ट्रांजैक्शंज) के लिए जरूरी नंबर बनाने की दिशा में एक और कदम बढ़ा दिया गया है। सरकार पूरे फाइनैंशल सेक्टर में आधार आधारित नो योर कस्टमर (KYC) को इंटीग्रेट करने पर विचार कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इसकी पुष्टि करते हुए कहा कि सरकार रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) सहित सभी रेग्युलेटर्स के साथ विचार-विमर्श कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार KYC एक तुरंत, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक और मजबूत प्रमाण उपलब्ध कराता है, जिससे सेवा उद्योग की प्रक्रिया बेहतर बनाने में मदद मिलेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने फाइनैंस बिल में एक संशोधन के जरिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के लिए आवेदन पर आधार को अनिवार्य बना दिया है। अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन लोगों के पास पहले से आधार मौजूद है, उन्हें किसी भी वित्तीय मध्यस्थ (फाइनैंशल इंटरमीडियरी) को अपने अंगूठे का निशान उपलब्ध कराना होगा। इसे संबंधित सेक्टर की रिपोर्टिंग एंटिटि को दिया जाएगा, जो इसे UIDAI डेटाबेस से वैलिडेट करेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस डेटा के आधार पर सेंट्रल रजिस्ट्री ऑफ सिक्यॉरिटाइजेशन ऐंड ऐसेट रिकंस्ट्रक्शन ऐंड सिक्यॉरिटी इंट्रेस्ट ऑफ इंडिया (CERSAI) की ओर से एक यूनीक C-KYC नंबर जेनरेट किया जाएगा। इस नंबर का इस्तेमाल बैंक अकाउंट, म्यूचुअल फंड इन्वेस्टमेंट, डीमैट अकाउंट और इंश्योरेंस पॉलिसी सहित सभी फाइनैंशल प्रॉडक्ट्स में किया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा था कि देश में 98 प्रतिशत व्यस्कों या 108 करोड़ से अधिक लोगों को आधार नंबर जारी किया जा चुका है और इसी वजह से सरकार इसका इस्तेमाल बढ़ा रही है। उन्होंने इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के प्रस्ताव पर दोबारा विचार करने की संसद की मांग को खारिज कर दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC सुविधा से PAN के आवेदन के लिए जन्मतिथि या पते जैसी जानकारियों की पुष्टि का इंतजार कर रहे व्यक्ति और एंटिटि अंगूठे के निशान से बायोमेट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन कर सकेंगे। CERSAI ने पिछले वर्ष सभी वित्तीय संस्थानों में एक समान KYC प्रोसेस सुनिश्चित करने के लिए e-KYC की कोशिश शुरू की थी। 2016 में मार्केट रेग्युलेटर सेबी ने आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC को स्वेच्छा से अपनाने पर सहमति दी थी। सभी सरकारी बैंकों से भी इस तरह का अपडेटेड डेटा अथॉरिटी को उपलब्ध कराने का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>टैक्सपेयर से प्रॉपर्टी का वैध किराएदार होने का सबूत मांग सकता है आयकर विभाग</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fake-rent-receipt-wont-help-you-lower-tax-burden-anymore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fake-rent-receipt-wont-help-you-lower-tax-burden-anymore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;टैक्स का बोझ घटाने के लिए कई लोग प्रॉपर्टी रेंट की फर्जी रसीदें लगा दिया करते हैं। टैक्स रूल को धता बताने की ऐसी हरकत को ज्यादातर एंप्लॉयर्स नजरंदाज करते रहे हैं। टैक्स ऑफिस को भी संभवत: लगता रहा है कि यह छोटी गलती है। हालांकि अब हालात बदल सकते हैं। इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट को अब एक ठोस जमीन लग गई है, जिसके आधार पर वह टैक्सपेयर से इस बात का सबूत मांग सकता है कि वह संबंधित प्रॉपर्टी का वैध किराएदार है। एंप्लॉयर से &amp;lsquo;हाउस रेंट अलाउंस&amp;rsquo; पाने वाला सैलरीड एंप्लॉयी इस रकम के कम से कम 60% हिस्से पर टैक्स देने से बच सकता है, बशर्ते वह रेंट रसीद दे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ट्राइब्यूनल की एक हालिया रूलिंग के अनुसार, असेसिंग ऑफिसर अब सैलरीड एंप्लॉयी की ओर से दिखाई गई टैक्सेबल इनकम का आंकड़ा मंजूर करते वक्त सबूत की मांग कर सकता है। वह लीज ऐंड लाइसेंस अग्रीमेंट, किराएदारी के बारे में हाउसिंग को-ऑपरेटिव सोसायटी को जानकारी देने वाले लेटर, इलेक्ट्रिसिटी बिल, वॉटर बिल जैसे सबूत मांग सकता है। आईटीएटी मुंबई ने ऐसे सैलरीड एंप्लॉयी का एचआरए इग्जेम्पशन क्लेम खारिज किया था, जिसने दावा किया था कि वह अपनी मां को रेंट पेमेंट कर रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डेलॉयट हास्किंस एंड सेल्स एलएलपी के सीनियर टैक्स अडवाइजर दिलीप लखानी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इनकम टैक्स अपीलेट ट्राइब्यूनल की रूलिंग ने सैलरीड एंप्लॉयी के क्लेम पर विचार करने और जरूरी होने पर उस पर सवाल करने के लिए असेसिंग ऑफिसर के सामने एक मानक रख दिया है। इससे सैलरीड क्लास पर यह जिम्मेदारी आएगी कि वह टैक्स छूट पाने के लिए नियमों का पालन करे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;माना जाता है कि फर्जी रेंट रसीदें देने वाले सैलरीड एंप्लॉयीज के पास इनमें से कोई भी जरूरी दस्तावेज नहीं होता है। हो सकता है कि वह व्यक्ति असल में रेंट चुका ही न रहा हो और अपने परिवार के घर में ही रह रहा हो और अपने पिता की दस्तखत वाली रसीदें दिखा रहा हो। कुछ मामलों में असल में किराएदार होने पर भी किराए की रकम बढ़ाकर दिखाई जाती है और इसमें तब तक दिक्कत नहीं आती है, जब तक कि किराया पाने वाला शख्स टैक्स चुकाने की लिमिट से बाहर हो।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऐसे कई मामले देखे गए हैं, जिनमें कोई व्यक्ति भले ही अलग रह रहा हो, लेकिन वह दावा करता है कि उसी शहर में रहने वाले एक रिश्तेदार को किराया चुका रहा है, जिनकी वहीं कोई प्रॉपर्टी हो। कुछ मामलों में परिवार का एक सदस्य लोन पेमेंट डिडक्शन का क्लेम करता है तो दूसरा टैक्स से बचने के लिए फर्जी रेंट रसीद चिपका देता है। एचआरए को लेकर इस तरह की जैसी हरकतें होती हैं, उन्हें देखते हुए टैक्स अधिकारियों को बहुत ज्यादा क्लेम्स पर सवाल करने होंगे। एक टैक्स ऑफिसर ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;टेक्नॉलजी और सख्त रिपोर्टिंग सिस्टम से नजर बनाए रखने में आसानी होगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बंद नहीं होंगे 2000 रुपये के नोट, सरकार ने अटकलों पर लगाया विराम</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-plans-to-demonetise-rs-2000-notes-says-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-plans-to-demonetise-rs-2000-notes-says-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने 2000 रुपये के नए नोटों को बंद किए जाने की अटकलों पर विराम लगा दिया और कहा कि नकली नोटों की समस्या पर काबू के लिए अतिरिक्त सुरक्षा उपाय किए गए हैं। गृह राज्य मंत्री किरेन रिजिजू ने राज्यसभा में कहा कि इस संबंध में चल रही अफवाहों पर ज्यादा ध्यान नहीं दिया जाना चाहिए। कांग्रेस के मधूसुदन मिस्त्री ने प्रश्नकाल में सवाल किया था कि बाजार में ऐसी अटकलें हैं कि 2000 रुपये के नोटों को बंद किया जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस पर रिजिजू ने कहा, ‘ऐसी अफवाहों पर मत जाइए। अफवाहों पर ध्यान नहीं दिया जाना चाहिए।’ उन्होंने कहा कि नकली नोट बरामद किए जाने के ज्यादातर मामले गुजरात और पश्चिम बंगाल से आए। उन्होंने कहा कि यह कहना सही नहीं है कि नकली नोटों की पहचान नहीं की जा सकती। रिजिजू ने कहा कि नए नोटों में सुरक्षा के कई नए उपाय किए गए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा कि वह सदन को आश्वस्त कर सकते हैं कि नए नोटों की 100 प्रतिशत कॉपी करना संभव नहीं है। उन्होंने कहा कि सुरक्षा के लिए स्वदेशी डिजायन के अलावा अतिरिक्त उपाय भी किए गए हैं। उन्होंने कहा कि सरकार नकली नोटों को लेकर चौकन्नी है और ऐसे मामलों में सख्त सजा के प्रावधान किए गए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा कि ऐसे मामलों को लेकर विभिन्न खुफिया एजेंसी के बीच समन्वय पर जोर दिया गया है और लोगों के लिए प्रशिक्षण और जागरूकता कार्यक्रम शुरू किया गया है। उन्होंने बताया कि राष्ट्रीय जांच एजेंसी (एनआईए) ने गुजरात और पश्चिम बंगाल से 2000 रुपये के 22,677 नोट बरामद किए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बैंक, डाकघर से निकासी पर नकदी लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर दो लाख रुपये की नकद लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी। आयकर विभाग ने बुधवार को यह स्पष्ट किया। वित्त अधिनियम 2017 के तहत सरकार ने दो लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध लगा दिया है। इससे अधिक के लेनदेन में राशि प्राप्त करने वाले पर उतनी की राशि का जुर्माना लगाया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर कानून में नई शामिल धारा 269 एसटी के बारे में स्पष्टीकरण जारी करते हुए केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ने कहा कि यह प्रतिबंध बैंकों और डाकघरों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा। बयान में कहा गया है कि यह फैसला किया गया है कि नकद लेनदेन पर अंकुश बैंकों, सहकारी बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सीबीडीटी ने कहा कि इस बारे में आवश्यक अधिसूचना जारी की जाएगी। वित्त मंत्री अरण जेटली ने 2017-18 के बजट में 3 लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध का प्रस्ताव किया था। इस सीमा को वित्त विधेयक में संशोधन के जरिए दो लाख रुपये कर दिया गया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>