<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Govt:Over Rs 153cr awarded to 10lk people to promote e-payments</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;check if you are winner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dev.digidhanlucky&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px;padding:4px&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/logoapp.png&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on start button in Digi Dhan Lucky Yojana App.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on whether you are a Consumer or a Merchant, click on the corresponding button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box that appears next, provide the mobile phone number registered with your UPI/ USSD/ RuPay/ AEPS account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive an OTP, which you must enter in the box that appears in the middle of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Try Your Luck button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next message will show if you have won under the Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi Dhan Vyapar Yojana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been awarded over Rs 153.5 crore in the last 58 days under Niti Aayog’s schemes to promote digital payments, its CEO Amitabh Kant said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It has been 58 days since the launch of Niti Aayog’s two incentive schemes – Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana to promote digital payments and the public response has been quite encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the latest figures released by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), which has been executing the schemes, nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been disbursed over Rs 153.5 crore as reward money till February 20, 2017,” Kant said at a press conference here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s think-tank said in a statement that among the 9.8 lakh winners are more than 9.2 lakh consumers and 56,000 merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners belong to diverse socio-economic backgrounds, including farmers, merchants, small entrepreneurs, professionals, housewives, students and retired persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Uttar Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh and Delhi have emerged as the top five states/Union Territories with maximum number of winners,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While majority of the winners are in the age group of 21 to 30, Niti Aayog pointed out that a significant number are also above 60 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The diversity in age of winners is from 15 to 66 years, challenging the notion that the old find it difficult to embrace technology to adopt digital payments,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government on December 25 had launched two schemes — Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana — to boost digital transactions post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 में इन 5 कंपनियों ने भारत में की छंटनी</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/5-tech-companies-in-india-that-cut-jobs-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/5-tech-companies-in-india-that-cut-jobs-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;2017 भारत के टेक्नॉलजी सेक्टर के लिए शुभ संकेत लेकर नहीं आया। वैश्विक राजनीतिक बदलावों और कम होती फंडिंग के कारण कई स्टार्टअप्स और कंपनियां छंटनी की घोषणा कर चुके हैं। देखिए किन कंपनियों में हुई छंटनी.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;yepme&#34;&gt;YepMe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फैैशन रिटेलर येपमी ने अपनी वेयरहाउसिंग और क्विलिटी कंट्रोल टीम से छंटनी की है। कंपनी के फाउंडर विवेक गौर ने बताया कि नोटंबदी से कंपनी की सेल्स पर काफी असर पड़ा और वह भारत के बाहर कंपनी को बढ़ाने पर फोकस कर रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;snapdeal&#34;&gt;Snapdeal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पिछले महीने स्नैपडील में भारतीय ई-कॉमर्स कंपनी स्नैपडील ने साफ किया था कि वह छंटनी करने वाली है। हालांकि कंपनी ने साफ नहीं किया था कि वह कितने एंप्लॉयीज को निकालेगा। कंपनी की फाइनैंशल हालत का अंदाजा इसी से लगाया जा सकता है कि स्नैपडील के फाउंडर्स कुणाल बहल और रोहित बंसल ने अनिश्चितकाल के लिए सैलरी न लेने का फैसला किया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;leeco&#34;&gt;LeEco&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चार महीने पहले इस चीनी कंपनी ने बताया कि उसके पास कैश की कमी है। कंपनी ने भारत में अपने 85 प्रतिशत स्टाफ को बाहर का रास्ता दिखा दिया। इंडस्ट्री एक्सपर्ट्स का मानना है कि कंपनी की पेरेंट फर्म घाटे में है और वह अब केवल चीन और अमेरिका पर फोकस करना चाहती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aircel&#34;&gt;Aircel&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस साल फरवरी में टेलिकॉम कंपनी एयरसेल ने 700 एंप्लॉयीज को नौकरी से निकाल दिया। कंपनी ने अपने 10 प्रतिशत वर्कफोर्स को कम कर दिया है। कंपनी के भारत में करीब 8000 कर्मचारी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;craftsvilla&#34;&gt;Craftsvilla&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पारंपरिक परिधानों की कंपनी क्राफ्ट्सविला ने अपने सैकड़ों एंप्लॉयीज को नौकरी से निकाल दिया है। इसमें प्रॉडक्ट टीम और टेक्नॉलजी टीम में छंटनी की है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hacker can access your information via a UPI-based app</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/startup-identified-291-ways-hacker-can-access-information-via-upi-based-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/startup-identified-291-ways-hacker-can-access-information-via-upi-based-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As digitisation picks up steam with Indians expected to transact Rs 4 crore digitally every day this year, privacy of their data has become a paramount concern. The government is caught between encouraging digitisation and ensuring secure platforms. This is where startups like Appknox come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specialising in mobile apps security, Appknox recently identified 291 critical vulnerabilities (181 were accorded the status of high ctitical vulnerabilities) in Unified Payments Interface (UPI) based mobile applications developed by banks and other fintech companies. These vulnerabilities had the potential of exposing a user’s entire bank details to the eyes of any hacker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There were issues where we could bypass the entire security gamut and get access to user’s bank account details and even download those details easily. We found hackers can easily manipulate these loopholes to misuse the data,” says Appknox cofounder and CEO, Harshit Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team at Appknox, driven by Agarwal and cofounders Subho Halder and Prateek Panda was hired by NPCI in July 2016 and has been scanning UPI-based apps since November. These apps, developed and launched by banks and other fintech companies, have already seen heavy downloads and have lakhs of users transacting online.
The team found 181 high, 83 medium and 27 low critical vulnerabilities in the 35 plus apps evaluated by it. The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) then advised the banks to quickly work on the suggestions provided by Appknox in order to negate these threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other threats, the team was particularly concerned about basic security steps which the hackers at Appknox were easily able to contravene. The login password step was easily bypassed by the team in a number of UPI-based apps which could lead any hacker directly into a user’s account and access that user’s information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of apps depend on OTP (One Time Password) system to provide an extra layer of security to its users. The team shares it was able to easily brute force its way to login into a user’s account.
Given these apps were developed by banks which are considered the safest mode financial platforms, the team was surprised at the ease with which it was able to hack into the apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These banks have internal audits and we expected their apps to be pretty secure. Banks are the most important sector in fintech sector and have to be pretty ahead of the curve of security. Thus, we were surprised at how easily we could find loopholes in these apps. Whatever these banks are doing is not enough for mobile app security,” said Agarwal.
While banks are still the most secure way of transferring money digitally when it comes to platforms like NEFT however, mobile apps, shares Agarwal, are a different ball game altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mobiles can be hacked in very different ways and the internal team at these banking institutions is not that great with mobile apps. The whole security landscape is very different when it comes to mobiles,” says Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A worrying statement indeed when the financial transactions are increasingly moving from websites to mobile apps with the proliferation of e-wallets and other payments systems.
Several mobile apps have sprung in the last couple of years providing users with ease of transacting online however, to prevent this ease from metamorphosing into a security disaster, the government is working keenly on regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The government is getting very strict when it comes to security. The central government recently made empanelment mandatory for any mobile app in bank payment gateway. Regulators have been proactive in ensuring that companies follow certain standards,” shares Agarwal.
NPCI, shares Agarwal, was quick to get banks to plug the loopholes found by the team at Appknox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about their experience with Appknox NPCI, Head of Risk Management, Bharat Panchal, said in a statement, “Appknox has been a crucial partner with us to ensure utmost security of our UPI-based application. We have had good early detection of vulnerabilities with the help of very energetic and brilliant security professionals. ”
The threat however, is persistent and transformative and both the government and the fintech institutions would need all the help they can find to keep hackers from digging into sensitive user information and thereby, to drive its digitisation push further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a never-ending race where hackers look for more loopholes and banking companies innovate to keep ahead. The problem is that banks and other fintech institutions rely on a single vendor for all their security concerns. What they do not realise is that there could be many brains working to break the system and relying on a single brain for security is really dangerous,” says Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appknox specialises in providing security to mobile apps and currently services 100 plus companies in the fintech sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM gives E-Wallets a run for money</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BHIM — or the Bharat Interface For Money — is quickly becoming the favoured mobile payment solution for crores of Indians. Since its launch on December 31 till the end of February, the app had been downloaded 17 million times. Following its Android launch, BHIM is now also available on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is an extension of the Unified Payment System. It allows users to send and receive money through a mobile app that is linked to their bank savings account. This is an elegant solution compared to e-wallets that need to maintain a cash balance in order to be functional. Naturally, the question then arises: Should users switch to BHIM and simply spend from their banks, and stop using e-wallets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences between BHIM and e-wallets, and we’ll examine them here in order to help you understand the pros and cons of both ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bhim-vs-wallets-where-bhim-wins&#34;&gt;BHIM vs Wallets: Where BHIM Wins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Balance, loading &amp;amp; unloading:&lt;/em&gt; The first major difference between BHIM and UPI apps and e-wallets is how you maintain your spending balance. BHIM and UPI apps allow you to send and receive money with your bank account. You do not have to maintain a balance with the app. The app is your bank account, in a sense. But in e-wallets, you must maintain a balance in order to spend from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just that, returning your wallet balance back to your bank account will come with limitations and charges. But with BHIM and UPI, there is no need to send the money back from the app to the bank, since the money has been sitting in your account all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/em&gt; Another aspect where BHIM and UPI apps trump e-wallets. E-wallets do not have interoperability, meaning that if you are using Wallet X, you can only transfer money to another user on Wallet X, and not to a user operating Wallet Y. This isn’t a problem with BHIM, since you may move money between accounts with any bank on the BHIM platform. For example, you may be using an SBI account but you can send and receive money from users on ICICI or HDFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spending limits:&lt;/em&gt; BHIM and UPI score heavily here as well. E-wallets have a monthly spending limit of Rs 10,000 which can be raised to Rs 100,000 after the KYC process wherein users need to submit proof of ID and address in order to become authenticated. But BHIM allows a limit of Rs 10,000 per transaction and Rs 20,000 as the total worth of transactions in a 24-hour cycle. UPI apps go further, allowing you to spend up to Rs 100,000 per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-bhim-lags&#34;&gt;Where BHIM Lags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly two areas where e-wallets have an edge over UPI and BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marketing gimmicks:&lt;/em&gt; E-wallets have been around for a few years and they have had the time to build relationships with merchants and businesses. As a result, e-wallets are useful not just for money transfers but also for earning cashbacks and discounts. Not just that, some e-wallets also operate as e-commerce platforms allowing users to buy merchandise, electronics, tickets, etc. UPI and BHIM, on the other hand, are recent innovations and have some catching up to do in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit usage:* E-wallets allow you to link and spend from your credit card, allowing you to leverage the power of the credit available to you. BHIM works on simpler principles: you get to spend only if you have a bank balance, and you cannot link BHIM and UPI apps to your credit card account yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-bhim-is-catching-up&#34;&gt;How BHIM Is Catching Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest Union Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced a referral bonus and cashback scheme for BHIM users. “The government will launch two new schemes — a referral bonus for consumers and a cash-back scheme for merchants — to promote the use of BHIM,” Jaitley said during his budget speech. With these inclusions, BHIM will become a little more attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
Both e-wallets and UPI-based apps such as BHIM have a long way to go and a big role to play in India where internet penetration and smartphone usage are increasing by leaps and bounds every year. Both need to evolve in order to accommodate the changing needs of the Indian consumer in an increasingly less cash-dependent economy. However, at this point, you may want to have both BHIM and e-wallets installed on your smartphones. They both have some unique services to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BSNL Is Planning To Counter Reliance Jio, Airtel, Others</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new plan gives 2GB of 3G data per day at Rs 339&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlimited calling within its network is also applicable under the plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-run &lt;em&gt;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited&lt;/em&gt; (BSNL) announced a new plan which offers 2GB of 3G data per day with unlimited calling within its network for Rs 339. In an effort to take on the service providers like Reliance Jio, Airtel and others, BSNL will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks and after that the users will be charged 25 paise per minute. The company further said that the data of 2GB per day is one of the best in the industry. The limited offer for prepaid services comes with a validity of 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are committed to providing affordable and efficient services to all segment of our loyal mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL Director for Consumer Mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data and unlimited calling to all network till March 31. From April 1, users opting for Jio Prime service will get unlimited data and calls till March 31, 2018, for one time registration fee of Rs 99 and Rs 303 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharti Airtel has also introduced its &amp;lsquo;Surprise offer&amp;rsquo; which will give free 30GB data for three months, starting March 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers from Airtel or other operators comes in wake of the telecom war started by the new entrant Reliance Jio in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea To Sell 1GB 2G, 3G, 4G Mobile Data At Same Price From March End</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present, Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision in the wake of stiff competition in the market&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with a month validity for Rs 170&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular will start selling 1GB and above mobile data plans across its 2G, 3G and 4G network at same price by the end of this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Idea has now announced that it will allow open market data recharges of 1GB and above to work on Idea&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G or 4G network without any differential prices and this will be rolled out nationally by March 31, 2017,&amp;rdquo; Idea said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates. Due to stiff competition in the market from Reliance Jio, the 4G mobile data service of Idea is significantly cheaper than 2G service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the high speed data plans were priced higher based on their download speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customer can choose the recharge price basis usage and volume available in pack, without having to worry about the platform the customer&amp;rsquo;s device is logged in,&amp;rdquo; Idea Cellular Chief Marketing Officer Sashi Shankar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea will bring all data product categories like sachets, freedom packs to unified pricing and will be rolled out nationally in phases by May 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Idea&amp;rsquo;s pan India broadband coverage continues to expand and reduces gap with existing 2G coverage which covers 4 lakh towns and villages, customers can now seamlessly migrate services between technology &amp;amp; platform without worrying about differential costs,&amp;rdquo; Shankar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data limit in high speed internet plans gets exhausted in less time compared to that on slow speed network like 2G.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: BSNL Offers 2GB Data Per Day On Rs 339 Recharge</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-2gb-data-per-day-on-rs-339-recharge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-2gb-data-per-day-on-rs-339-recharge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analysts say incumbent telecom operators are coming up with attractive calling plans and lucrative data packs to counter additional competition triggered by Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry in the market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL is offering 2GB of 3G data per day and unlimited voice calling within its network under a special scheme priced at Rs 339. The &amp;ldquo;Combo STV&amp;rdquo; plan by state-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited or BSNL - for its prepaid customers - comes with a validity of 28 days, the telecom operator said in a statement. Analysts say incumbent telecom operators are coming up with attractive calling plans and lucrative data packs to counter additional competition triggered by Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSNL is offering 2GB of 3G data per day under a special recharge plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plan also offers unlimited voice calls on BSNL network&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telcos in India are giving attractive plans after Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special offer under its prepaid mobile services is in effect from March 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) The offer is limited for 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The &amp;ldquo;unlimited data&amp;rdquo; on offer will come with a &amp;ldquo;fair use policy&amp;rdquo; of 2 GB per day with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) BSNL is offering unlimited voice calls within its network. Calls outside the BSNL network will be for 25 minutes per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) After exhausting the 25-minute limit, the customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) &amp;ldquo;The data of 2GB per day is one of the best in the industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL added in its statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) &amp;ldquo;We are committed to providing affordable and efficient services to all segments of our loyal mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL director for consumer mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Religare analysts Rumit Dugar and Saumya Shrivastava believe the market could remain competitive for an extended period considering Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive revenue market share expectations. (Also read: 28 GB data for Rs 345: Airtel&amp;rsquo;s latest offer to counter Jio)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Reliance Industries&amp;rsquo; telecom arm - Reliance Jio Infocomm - is offering 1GB of 4G data per day and unlimited calling to all networks for free till March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) From April 1, Jio customers opting for its Prime service will continue to enjoy the unlimited calls and data benefits under its New Year Offer for a full year, till March 31, 2018. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime subscription will come at a one-time enrolment fee of Rs. 99 and &amp;ldquo;a rock-bottom introductory price” of only Rs 10 per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Proposal To Withdraw New 2,000 Rupee Notes: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday said there is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 notes that were introduced post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 denomination banknote,&amp;rdquo; the minister said in a written reply in the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley further said the Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes returned to currency chests of the RBI amounted to Rs 12.44 lakh crore (as on December 10, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data obtained in this regard would need to be reconciled with the physical cash balances to eliminate counterfeit notes, accounting errors and possible double counts after which only the final figures will be arrived at, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added that as on March 3, 2017 the currency in circulation was Rs 12 lakh crore and as on January 27, it was Rs 9.921 lakh crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley said the cash recall seeks to create a new &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; wherein the GDP will be bigger, cleaner and real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This exercise is part of the government&amp;rsquo;s resolve to eliminate corruption, blackmoney, counterfeit currency and terror funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This exercise has resulted in an increase in deposits with banks. This will facilitate reduction of interest rates and provide more headroom to banks to expand their credit base,&amp;rdquo; the minister said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation, several restrictions were imposed on withdrawal from banks as well as ATMs. The restrictions have been gradually removed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plastic Rs 10 Note Could Be A Reality Soon</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/plastic-rs10-note-could-be-a-reality-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/plastic-rs10-note-could-be-a-reality-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has been authorised to conduct field trials for printing plastic Rs 10 denomination notes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has been authorised to conduct field trials for printing plastic Rs 10 denomination notes which will have a longer life span, Parliament was informed on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Approval for procurement of plastic substrate and printing of bank notes of Rs 10 denomination on plastic banknote substrates has been conveyed to the RBI,&amp;rdquo; Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal told the Lok Sabha in a written reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Substrate denotes the underlying substance or layer on which currency is printed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister said the government had decided to conduct field trials at five locations of the country with plastic banknotes, which are expected to last longer than cotton substrate-based banknotes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जानें, क्रेडिट कार्ड के बेहद &#39;खास&#39; फायदे</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड रखना यानी उधार की जिंदगी जीना, अरे यह हम नहीं कह रहे बल्कि आमतौर पर इस तरह की बातें हमारे आसपास के लोग बोलते दिख जाते हैं। अगर आप भी ऐसा ही सोचते हैं तो अगले कुछ मिनट्स में आपके यह सोच बदलने वाली है। जी हां, आज हम आपको बता रहे हैं क्रेडिट कार्ड रखने के कुछ बेहद खास फायदे&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-ब-क&#34;&gt;कैश बैक&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कई क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां कुछ खास ब्रैंड्स के साथ 10 से 20 प्रतिशत तक का कैश बैक ऑफर देती हैं। यानी कैशलेश पेमेंट भी करिए और बचत भी पाइए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;र-व-र-ड-प-इ-ट&#34;&gt;रिवॉर्ड पॉइंट&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कैैश बैक के अलावा सभी क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां प्रत्येक ट्रांजैक्शन के वेट के अनुसार पॉइंट्स देती हैं। पॉइंट्स आपके खाते में जुड़ते जाते हैं और बाद में आप इन्हें रिडीम कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-र-ड-ट-ह-स-ट-र&#34;&gt;क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड के प्रयोग से आप अपनी क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री अपने साथ रख सकते हैं। यानि आपको पता रहता है कि आपने कब कहां कितना पैसा खर्च किया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-क-झ-झट-नह&#34;&gt;कैश का झंझट नहीं&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड का सबसे बड़ा फायदा यह है कि आपको इस बात की चिंता करने की नहीं जरूरत होती है कि बैंक में बैलेंस है या नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;emi-क-व-कल-प&#34;&gt;EMI का विकल्प&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अगर आपका मन कोई बड़ी चीज खरीदने का है, लेकिन पैसे नहीं, तो क्रेडिट कार्ड से खरीद कर आप उस पैसे को ईएमआई यानि किश्तों में बदल सकते हैं। कई बार क्रेडिट कार्ड जीरो प्रतिशत ब्याज पर ईएमआई देते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>नोटबंदी ने भ्रष्टाचार के नए रास्ते खोले: अर्थशास्त्री</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-opens-up-new-ways-for-corruption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-opens-up-new-ways-for-corruption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ऑस्ट्रेलिया के प्रख्यात अर्थशास्त्री हेन्ज डी कुर्ज ने कहा है कि भ्रष्टाचार को जड़ से समाप्त करने के लिए नोटबंदी अधिक मजबूत कदम नहीं है। उन्होंने इस कदम को ‘पत्थर को अंडे से मारने’ का प्रयास करार दिया। उन्होंने कहा कि वास्तव में भारत सरकार ने भ्रष्टाचार के नये रास्ते खोले हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कुर्ज ने विशेष बातचीत में कहा, ‘जहां तक मैं स्थिति को समझता हूं यह (नोटबंदी) कदम ‘पत्थर को अंडे से मारने’ का प्रयास साबित हुआ है।’उन्होंने कहा, ‘मुझे इस पर काफी संदेह है कि नोटबंदी भ्रष्टाचार को समाप्त कर देगी और अधिक पारदर्शिता लाएगी। यह कदम इन लक्ष्यों को हासिल करने के लिए काफी कमजोर और भरमाने वाला है।’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कुर्ज ऑस्ट्रेलिया में यूनिवर्सिटी ऑफ ग्राज में अर्थशास्त्र के प्रफेसर हैं। उन्होंने कहा, ‘सरकार ने 2,000 रुपये का नोट पेश किया है। यह प्रतिबंध नोट के मूल्य का दोगुना या चार गुना है। इसे बमुश्किल नोटबंदी कहा जा सकता है।’ उन्होंने कहा कि भ्रष्टाचार के खिलाफ लड़ाई सराहनीय है, लेकिन ‘मुझे लगता है कि कुछ नोट पर पाबंदी के जरिए यह नहीं किया जा सकता है।’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी का भारत की आर्थिक वृद्धि पर प्रभाव के बारे में पूछे जाने पर कुर्ज ने कहा, ‘अभी नोटबंदी के प्रभाव का आकलन करना जल्दबाजी होगी। दूसरा जो आंकड़े आएं हैं, वह मोटा-मोटी अनुमान है। इसमें संभवत: इसके प्रभव को शामिल नहीं किया गया है।’ प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने आठ नवंबर को 500 और 1,000 रुपये के नोट पर पाबंदी लगा दी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt tells RBI to work with stakeholders for PoS roll-out</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-tells-rbi-work-stakeholders-pos-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-tells-rbi-work-stakeholders-pos-roll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The govt has asked RBI to fix responsibilities for stakeholders, including PoS manufactures, UIDAI that administers the 12-digit Aadhaar number, and the NPCI to launch the process&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance ministry has asked the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to bring together all stakeholders, including banks and back-end service providers, and establish a process for the roll-out of Aadhaar-based point of sales (PoS) machines to promote cashless transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his budget speech last month, finance minister Arun Jaitley said two million Aadhaar-based PoS machines will be rolled out by September-end. Banks have flagged the lack of an established back-end infrastructure as an impediment in implementing this mandate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has now asked RBI to fix responsibilities for stakeholders, including PoS manufactures, back-end service providers, banks, and the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) that administers the 12-digit Aadhaar number, and the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) to launch the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For Aadhaar-based PoS machines to be a reality, many systems and processes have to be put in place. The biometric data captured on these machines has to be encrypted and transmitted after which Aadhaar authentication has to be done. The payment then has to be processed. For this, all the stakeholders have to be brought together by RBI and the process established,” said a senior finance ministry official, who did not wish to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time that an Aadhaar-based authentication process has been proposed. RBI, in a notification in September 2016, made it mandatory for all banks to ensure that all new card acceptance infrastructure deployed from 1 January, 2017 is enabled for processing payment transactions using Aadhaar-based biometric authentication. After banks raised concerns about a mismatch between demand and supply of such Aadhaar-enabled devices, the central bank gave banks time till end-June to deploy this infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deepak Bhutra, chief executive officer, India Transact Services Ltd, a merchant payment solutions firm, said it is possible to shift to new age biometric payment systems. “This is not technically a difficult task but rather a very expensive one. Companies will have to invest in securing these biometric readers and assembling them in the currently available PoS machines,” he said in an email. “We do see faster acceptance of the PoS machines now with the push from the government, but a major challenge would be to educate the customer to pay through Aadhaar payment method as opposed to paying via the card route,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are a few things which banks will incrementally have to follow. Firstly, banks will need to get certified with NPCI for AEPS (Aadhaar- enabled payment system) switching capability which will have to be managed or outsourced by the bank. Secondly, deployment of a merchant app with low cost peripheral, to enable Aadhaar biometric authentication is needed. Lastly, banks would need to upgrade their existing EDC (electronic draft capture) PoS or mPoS terminals to support biometric capture which may work out to be more costly and much less scalable,” Deepak Sharma, chief digital officer, Kotak Mahindra Bank, said in response to emailed questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“From a consumer perspective, the Aadhaar-based payment methodology will work even in the absence of feature phones and high-end smart phones—which addresses a significant part of the population at the bottom of the pyramid,” added Sharma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An IDFC Bank official said the target is easily achievable if new age banks adopt this route. “The bank has an ambitious roll-out plan for both Aadhaar Pay as well as micro ATMs,” the official added on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay is a service for merchants that will enable them to receive payments from customers without any physical payment instrument. The app has to be downloaded by merchants on their phones and linked to an Aadhaar biometric reader. Once the merchant has this infrastructure in place, consumers can start transacting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Announces Free Incoming Calls On Domestic Roaming To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move comes after different offers introduced by rival telecom firms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular today announced free incoming calls on domestic roaming and unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers come on the heels of the larger rival Bharti Airtel announcing removal of all roaming charges for outgoing and incoming calls as well as SMSes and data usage within India, to take on competition from newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Effective April 1, 2017, Idea&amp;rsquo;s 200 million customers will enjoy free incoming calls while roaming on company&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G and 4G network across 400,000 towns and villages in the country. Idea customers will be able to make outgoing calls, SMS freely at affordable rates while roaming anywhere in India,&amp;rdquo; an Idea release said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further said mobile data tariffs and data pack benefits of home circle will be available while roaming within India at no extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facility of free incoming calls on domestic roaming will be extended to both prepaid and postpaid customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For international travellers, the company is offering international roaming value packs with free bundled usage of up to 400 outgoing minutes, 100 SMSes per day, 3GB bundled data and unlimited incoming calls for Rs 2,499 for Asia, and Rs 5,999 for Europe for 30 days validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These international roaming packs also come bundled with free 1GB/2GB/3GB data and overage charges as low as Rs 3 per MB to avoid bill shock to travelling customers,&amp;rdquo; Idea said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company said it has done a study of customer&amp;rsquo;s travel destinations, usage patterns and bill shock complaints to design a new range of value packs for select destinations across Europe, Asia, America, UK and Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For value conscious customers, the packs start at Rs 1,199 for 10 days validity and go up to Rs 5,999 for 30 days validity, giving up to 85 per cent savings on international roaming charges,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;Idea is now set to enable over 200 million customers to use their mobile phones freely, without having to worry about roaming charges, while they travel anywhere in the country,&amp;rdquo; Sashi Shankar, Chief Marketing Officer of Idea Cellular said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges on calls and data, and said international call rates will be cut by up to 90 per cent to as low as Rs 3 per minute and data charges by up to 99 per cent to Rs 3 per MB across popular roaming destinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press statement, &amp;lsquo;Airtel Declares War on Roaming&amp;rsquo;, the company had then said the move will lead to &amp;ldquo;death of National Roaming&amp;rdquo; from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF (Provident Fund) Money Withdrawal: Here Are Five Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-provident-fund-money-withdrawal-here-are-five-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-provident-fund-money-withdrawal-here-are-five-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per PF rules, 12% of an employee&amp;rsquo;s salary goes into the fund along with a matching contribution from the employer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provident fund (PF) is meant for saving towards retirement years. Financial planners don&amp;rsquo;t advise withdrawal from the corpus before retirement. According to provident fund norms, 12 per cent of an employee&amp;rsquo;s salary goes into the fund along with a matching contribution from the employer. The EPFO (Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation) every year announces interest rate to be paid on the accumulated provident fund corpus. The PF money can be withdrawn after two months from the cessation of employment. The application form in this regard can be filed with PF authorities, or through the employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) To encourage long-term savings, the government has formulated tax laws accordingly. If the withdrawal from a recognised PF happens after five years of continuous employment, it attracts no tax liability. In case of employment with different employers, if the PF balance maintained with the old employer is transferred to the PF account of the new employer, it is considered a continuous employment. (Also read: I Want To Save Enough Money For Retirement. Is PF Contribution Enough?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an employee has been terminated because of certain reasons beyond his or her control (such as ill health and discontinuation of business of employer), a withdrawal does not attract any tax, irrespective of the number of years of employment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) In case of a withdrawal before five years, the amount becomes taxable in the same financial year. Thus, the amount has to be shown in your tax return for the next assessment year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The employer&amp;rsquo;s contribution to PF and interest earned on it is added to one&amp;rsquo;s income and taxed accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In addition, if you have claimed benefits under Section 80C on your own PF contribution, it will be taxed as salary. The interest earned on your own contribution will be taxed as &amp;lsquo;income from other sources&amp;rsquo; and taxed according to the respective tax slabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) TDS (tax deducted at source) - If the withdrawal is after a period of five years of continuous employment, it attracts no TDS or any tax. What happens if the period of service is less than five years? If PAN has not been submitted to the EPFO authorities, TDS is deducted at 30 per cent. If PAN has been submitted along with Form 15G/15H, no TDS is deducted. If form 15G/15H is not submitted and PAN is submitted, TDS @ 10% is deducted. Form 15H or 15G is meant to prevent TDS for those whose income falls below the taxable limit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pensioners told to apply for Aadhaar card to receive pension</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/pensioners-told-apply-aadhaar-card-receive-pension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/pensioners-told-apply-aadhaar-card-receive-pension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ministry has issued a notification making Aadhaar mandatory for pensioners to receive pension. The pensioners number approximately 25 lakh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To receive a pension, the Union Defence Ministry in its notification stated all defence pensioners and family members of a deceased personnel ‘will be required to enrol for Aadhar card latest by June 30 to receive pension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry has issued a notification making Aadhaar mandatory for pensioners to receive pension. The pensioners number approximately is 25 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any pensioner eligible to receive benefits and who hasn’t enrolled for Aadhaar, but wants to avail pension is required to apply for Aadhaar by June 30,” read the notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also stated that the ministry through agencies or other means is required to offer Aadhaar enrollment facilities for beneficiaries who have not yet applied for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The order stated the Defence Ministry through such agencies will be required to provide Aadhaar enrolment facilities in places where such facilities aren’t available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till the time Aadhaar card is not given, beneficiaries shall get on producing the ex-servicemen card. A copy of his or her request made for Aadhaar enrolment can be submitted along with a copy of Voter ID card or PAN Card or Passport among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification said Defence Ministry through related agencies should make arrangements to provide hassle-free pension benefits to the beneficiaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wide publicity through media and through other sources should be given and individual notices shall be handed over to pensioners to make them aware of the Aadhaar requirement under the scheme, it added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>