<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>1,500 रुपये का 4G फीचर फोन जल्द बन सकता है हकीकत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4G फीचर फोन या बेसिक मोबाइल फोन, जिसकी कीमत 1,500 रुपये हो, जल्द ही हकीकत बन सकता है। चाइनीज मोबाइल चिप मेकर स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस ने कहा है कि वह मौजूदा लेवल्स से शुरुआती कीमत कम से कम आधा करने पर काम कर रही है। एक डिवेलपमेंट एक्सपर्ट ने कहा कि यह कई कन्ज्यूमर को स्मार्टफोन की ओर शिफ्टिंग से रोक सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस के कंट्री हेड नीरज शर्मा ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, ‘हम एक ऐसी टेक्नॉलजी पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो कि 1,500 रुपये के 4G फीचर फोन को व्यावहारिक बनाती है। हमने अपने पार्टनर्स के लिए कॉन्सेप्ट प्रमोशन पहले ही शुरू कर दिया है।’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लावा और माइक्रोमैक्स जैसी घरेलू मोबाइल फोन कंपनियों के 4G फीचर फोन की कीमतें करीब 3,000 रुपये से शुरू होती हैं। कॉर्बन के अलावा, यह दोनों हैंडसेट मेकर कंपनियां आगे ऐसे फोन की कीमतें घटाना चाहती हैं। इस मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले इंडस्ट्री एग्जिक्यूटिव्स के मुताबिक, रिलायंस जियो इंफोकॉम भी अपनी सहयोगी रिटेल फर्म के जरिए किफायती 4G VoLTE फीचर फोन लाने की योजना बना रही है, इस फोन की कीमत 1,500 रुपये से कम हो सकती है। शंघाई बेस्ड स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस बेसबैंड चिप सेगमेंट में सधी ग्रोथ हासिल कर रही है और यह मीडियाटेक, क्वॉलकॉम जैसे मोबाइल चिप मेकर्स के साथ मुकाबला कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चिपसेट, किसी भी मोबाइल हैंडसेट का एक अहम हिस्सा है और डिवाइस की कीमत में इसकी बड़ी हिस्सेदारी होती है। स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस की रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज के साथ दो साल पुरानी पार्टनरशिप है और इसने RIL के अफोर्डेबल LYF फ्लेम 5 स्मार्टफोन को तैयार किया है। कंपनी ने लावा M1 4G फीचर फोन को भी पावर्ड किया है, जिसकी कीमत 3,599 रुपये है। कंपनी का कहना है कि उसे टेक्नॉलजी ईजाद करने और डिवाइसेज को मार्केट तक पहुंचाने में करीब छह महीने लगते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फाइनेंशल सर्विसेज फर्म जेपी मॉर्गन ने अपनी एक हालिया रिपोर्ट में कहा है कि 2017 में 4G कैपेबिलिटी वाले फीचर फोन पॉपुलर होंगे। इन्हें उम्मीद से कहीं ज्यादा तेजी से आने वाले 4G नेटवर्क से मजबूती मिलेगी। शर्मा ने कहा कि यह देखना काफी रोचक होगा कि ऐसे समय में जबकि मार्केट का झुकाव डेटा प्ले की तरफ है और वॉयस सेगमेंट स्थिर हो गया है, तब ऑपरेटर्स अपनी स्ट्रैटिजी को कैसे पुख्ता बनाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, ‘पिछले छह महीने में मार्केट पूरी तरह से 3G से 4G में शिफ्ट हो गया है और दमदार टेक्नॉलजी के बीच वेंडर्स को अपनी मार्केट स्ट्रैटेजी को दुरुस्त करना होगा।’ उन्होंने कहा कि अडिशनल वैल्यू ऑफर करने वाले LTE फीचर फोन को और आकर्षक तरीके में पैक्ड किया जाना चाहिए। साथ ही उन्हें बढ़ते डेटा मार्केट के हिसाब से टियर-III लोकेशंस और रूरल एरिया में बेचा जाना चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aims To Implement Fully Paperless Travel Soon!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/set-replace-boarding-pass-air-travel-govt-aims-implement-fully-paperless-air-travel-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/set-replace-boarding-pass-air-travel-govt-aims-implement-fully-paperless-air-travel-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In few months time, this shall be the new scenario for air travellers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Step 1: Show your mobile and Aadhaar card for getting entry into airport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Step 2: Show your Aadhaar Card, instead of Boarding Pass, and get pass through Security check&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Step 3: Experience paperless air travel: Digi Yatra&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govt. of India has now decided to extend the scope of Aadhaar Card, and introduce it in Air Travel as well. Under the new premise of ‘Digi Yatra’, translated into Digital Travel, all you would need is your mobile phone to travel anywhere in the country, using air-mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logically, Civil Aviation Minister Jayant Sinha explained: “Your payment is digital, your boarding and security interactions are digital… That is the digi yatra concept we are working on,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questioning the very need for paper anywhere in the journey, the Minister explained: “.. You would be able to book your car to the airport, get to the airport, get a digital boarding pass, board your aircraft, take a car way back and do all of that just with your mobile phone..”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficulty, as the Minister informed, lies in forming a uniform platform, wherein an Aadhaar Card would be enough to ensure air travel without any paper. For instance, Govt. is working on how to make all airlines follow the concepts of Aadhaar based boarding pass, and how to incorporate Airport into the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, it is still not clear, whether Aadhaar would be now compulsory for air travel or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govt. to Supreme Court: PAN will not be invalidated retrospectively for not linking with Aadhaar
Meanwhile, Govt. has informed the Supreme Court that PAN card would not be cancelled retrospectively, in case it is not linked with Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney general Mukul Rohatgi, while representing Govt. in Supreme Court regarding a case challenging the mandatory status of Aadhaar Card said, “It will be invalid from 1 July 2017 and not from when you had applied for a PAN number,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior advocate Arvind Datar, who is representing the petitioners, challenged Govt. by stating: “Aadhaar linkage is only for an individual assessee and not for companies, firms etc. The consequences of non-compliance are draconian,”, adding, “Aadhaar is a right that a citizen is entitled to. There is no duty cast upon him to obtain one,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Supreme Court had directly questioned Govt., when they asked why Aadhaar has been made as a mandatory requirement when the Apex Court has already passed the order to make it an optional requirement. Very soon, Supreme Court will announce its verdict on Govt. decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for filing Income Tax returns and for linking it with PAN Card.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to media, the senior Congress leader said there was a need to upgrade all post offices in the country with latest infrastructure since there was &amp;ldquo;vast availability of post offices&amp;hellip;one can find it in every nook and corner of the country, even in remote villages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said passports could be applied from post offices shortly, adding around 86 post offices have already started work in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation, including eight MPs, paid obeisance at the sanctum sanctorum of the Golden Temple here. They also visited the historic Jallianwala Bagh, where they paid tributes to the martyrs who had sacrificed their lives for the freedom of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation thereafter visited the Integrated Check Post (ICP) Attari/Wagah border where they held a meeting with the Custom and BSF officials in order to have a &amp;ldquo;first hand information with regard to the required infrastructure at ICP, import/export activities with Pakistan and problems faced by the officials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members also witnessed the evening beating retreat ceremony at Wagah border.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At 110 Crore GB Data Traffic A Month, Jio&#39;s Offers For Its Prepaid Users</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a number of recharge options to prepaid subscribers under its paid Prime service. Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website. Jio has become the largest network globally with more than 110 crore GB of data traffic per month and 220 crore voice and video minutes a day, Reliance Industries said in a statement while reporting the group&amp;rsquo;s earnings for financial year 2016-17. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mr Ambani said in the statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All recharges under Jio Prime include free voice call and roaming benefits. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at Jio&amp;rsquo;s various data offerings under its latest recharge options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Rs 19 _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 19 recharge comes with a validity of one day and includes 200 MB of 4G, or high speed, data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 49&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits on offer under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 49 pack include 600 MB of high speed data valid for three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 96&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a validity of seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge includes 7GB of 4G data per day. 4G data comes at a daily limit of 1GB under Jio&amp;rsquo;s fair usage policy, beyond which the speed is reduced to 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 149&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 309&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Jio&amp;rsquo;s three-month benefits on first recharge begin. Subscribers making their first recharge of Rs 309 after taking up Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service will get 1GB of 3G data per day for 84 days, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 509&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimed at &amp;ldquo;daily high data users&amp;rdquo;, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 509 recharge extends the daily 4G data limit offered under the Rs 309 plan to 2GB. Data benefits on subsequent recharges will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first Rs 999 recharge, valid for 120 days, Jio users will get 120 GB of 4G data, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will come with 60 GB of high speed data valid for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s next long-term pack comes at Rs 1,999. The first recharge of this kind includes 185 GB of 4G data valid for 150 days. The 4G data on offer is reduced to 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges, Jio said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 4,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those making their first Prime recharge with the Rs 4,999 pack will get 410 GB of 4G data valid for 240 days. Subsequent recharges will offer 350 GB of such data for 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is the Rs 9,999. The first recharge will offer a total of 810 GB of 4G data valid for 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with a reduced 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Plans To Eliminate Sale Of Petrol, Diesel Vehicles By 2030. Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-plans-to-eliminate-sale-of-petrol-diesel-vehicles-by-2030/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-plans-to-eliminate-sale-of-petrol-diesel-vehicles-by-2030/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ministry of Heavy Industries and the NITI Aayog are working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles, Power Minister Piyush Goyal said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India is looking at having an all-electric car fleet by 2030 with an express objective of lowering the fuel import bill and running cost of vehicles. &amp;ldquo;We are going to introduce electric vehicles in a very big way. We are going to make electric vehicles self-sufficient like UJALA. The idea is that by 2030, not a single petrol or diesel car should be sold in the country,&amp;rdquo; Power Minister Piyush Goyal said while addressing the CII Annual Session 2017 here on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyal is of the view that initially the government can handhold the electric vehicle industry for 2-3 years to help it stabilise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing the example of Maruti, which has logged over 30 per cent profit this time, he explained that the government had supported India&amp;rsquo;s largest car maker initially, which eventually led to development of the big automotive industry in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyal told reporters later that the Ministry of Heavy Industries and the NITI Aayog are working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles. The minister pointed to the cost factor, saying people would like to buy electric vehicle when they find it cost effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About offshore wind projects, Goyal said these are more like an R&amp;amp;D project. The minister suggested that big PSUs, including NTPC, can initially invest in such projects that will lead to development of this segment in coming years. Goyal said that in the last 3 years, India&amp;rsquo;s energy consumption has grown by about 6.5 per cent CAGR (compounded annual growth rate), more than the figure for the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, &amp;ldquo;Through UJALA, the LED distribution programme, we have already seen about 500 million LED bulbs sold in the last two years. My job is to improve India&amp;rsquo;s energy efficiency to reduce consumption wherever it is wasteful and ensure that demand is met fully.&amp;rdquo; He made a point that UDAY as not been just about financial re-engineering but financial discipline. The UDAY scheme is meant for revival of debt stressed discoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NITI Aayog is working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government said it can help the electric vehicle industry initially&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electric cars must be cost effective to be popular, Power Minister said&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramdev&#39;s Warning: Will Wipe Out Foreign Firms In 5 Years</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ramdevs-warning-will-wipe-out-foreign-firms-in-5-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ramdevs-warning-will-wipe-out-foreign-firms-in-5-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comparing them to the East India Company that had entered the country with a purpose to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo;, Ramdev said that he aims to make India free from the MNCs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yoga guru Ramdev said today that Patanjali Ayurveda, promoted by him, will steal the march over multinational firms manufacturing consumer products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing them to the East India Company that had entered the country with a purpose to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo;, Ramdev said that he aims to make India free from the MNCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that the MNCs here were not working for the country&amp;rsquo;s development, rather their sole objective was to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo; India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Patanjali agle panch varshon mein in videshi kampaniyon ko moksh de degi (Patanjali will finish the MNCs up from the Indian market in next five years),&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was speaking at a function organised here to mark the birth anniversary of Yogi Bharat Bhushan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the next five years, Patanjali would educate the farmers about the latest techniques in farming to boost production. We will also offer decent prices for the produce,&amp;rdquo; Ramdev, who also happens to be the founder of Patanjali, said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ramdev also hailed the Uttar Pradesh government under Yogi Adityanath, who he said, establishes a good connect with the public.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 1 Lakh Investment Turned Into Rs 1 Crore In 21 Years. Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-lakh-investment-turned-into-rs-1-crore-in-21-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-lakh-investment-turned-into-rs-1-crore-in-21-years/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund, a mid-cap oriented fund, is primarily invested in financial, information technology, industrials and healthcare companies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Capital Asset Management&amp;rsquo;s open-ended equity growth scheme, Reliance Growth Fund, has achieved a net asset value (NAV) of Rs 1,000. This is the first fund in the industry to achieve this NAV level. The fund was launched 21 years ago in October 1995.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It gives us immense satisfaction that Rs 1 lakh invested in our fund is valued at Rs 1 crore today, an endorsement of our belief that MFs are best investment option for long term value creation,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Mutual Fund CEO Sundeep Sikka said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This growth of NAV &amp;ndash; from Rs 10 to Rs 1,000 &amp;ndash; which is a growth of 100 times in 21 years, also substantiates our view that AMCs with long term track record of 15-20 years like Reliance MF after sailing through volatile market condition will continue creating wealth for investors,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NAV is the value per share of a mutual fund on a specific date or time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Growth Fund, a mid-cap oriented fund, is primarily invested in financial, information technology,
industrials and healthcare companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors that stayed with the fund since inception have been benefited by growing their wealth 100-times till date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fund has a corpus of over Rs 5,000 crore from more than six lakh investors. As of March quarter, Reliance Mutual Fund has an assets base of Rs 2,10,890 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance is the first fund in the industry to achieve NAV level of 1,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance Mutual Fund was launched 21 years ago in October 1995&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fund&amp;rsquo;s initial investors have increased their wealth by 100 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on &lt;em&gt;Rs 3,050&lt;/em&gt; crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.
He did not give further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department, on April 5, wrote to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) asking it to give a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo; on the penalty issue, and also outline the basis and provisions of law under which the said amount had been recommended by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources familiar with the matter said that DoT, in its communication, has also asked the Trai to provide information on the number of subscribers acquired by Reliance Jio during the testing phase (that is prior to its commercial launch). The incumbent operators and the Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio clashed last year over the issue of call connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio cried foul that its customers were suffering from call failures as the incumbent operators were not giving it sufficient interconnect capacity. The operators, in turn, charged the newcomer of unleashing a &amp;ldquo;tsunami&amp;rdquo; of free traffic on their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interconnection enables mobile users to make calls to customers of other telecom networks and is, therefore, crucial for smooth functioning of mobile services. In October last year, Trai recommended to the Telecom Department, the imposition of total penalty of Rs 3,050 crore on the three incumbent operators Bharti Airtel, Vodafone and Idea Cellular for allegedly denying interconnectivity to the
new entrant that led to deterioration in the quality of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Trai&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, the penalty for Airtel and Vodafone worked out to about Rs 1,050 crore each, while in case of Idea Cellular stood at about Rs 950 crore. The regulator, in fact, had stopped short of recommending cancellation of their telecom licences saying it may lead to significant consumer inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the issue was placed before the Telecom Commission earlier this year, the highest policy-making body of the telecom department, it favoured referring the matter back to Trai for a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Commission asked DoT to seek clarification from Trai on nearly a dozen points, including whether the stipulated 90-day period was given to the three telecom operators for providing point of interconnection to the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Offers Education Loan At 8.5% Interest Rate. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI is offering an interest rate of 8.5 per cent on education loans for studying in select business schools. As part of SBI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Scholar Loan&amp;rdquo; scheme, select leading institutions where Indian students can get the concessional rate of interest include Indian Institute of Management (IIM)-Ahmedabad, IIM-Calcutta and Indian School of Business-Hyderabad or ISB-Hyderabad. This was said in a tweet by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI which recently unveiled a new brand identity after merging its operations with six other banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years. Scholar loans offer an interest rate between 8.5 per cent and 10.6 per cent and cover higher education courses in select 120 premier Indian institutions, as per SBI&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-scholar-loan-rates_650x400_81492094420.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education loan at rate of interest of 8.5%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s scholar loans cover a multitude of courses from institutions under four categories: &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;. An effective rate of interest of 8.5 per cent is offered on institutes listed by SBI under the AA category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Institutes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has listed seven &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo; institutions - for which Indian students can apply for up to Rs. 30 lakh of loans - including four IIMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These Indian institutions are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Ahmedabad IIM-Calcutta IIM-Bangalore IIM-Kozhikode Indian School of Business, Hyderabad Indian School of Business, Mohali Campus Xavier Labour Relations Institute, Jamshedpur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is covered?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The loans disbursed under SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme covers college fees (including examination, hostel, library and laboratory fees), purchase of books, equipment and instrument as well as travel expenses and expenses on exchange programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approval time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers quick sanctioning of scholar loans at designated campus branches or more than 5,000 select branches, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Reduces Term Deposit Rates By Up To 0.5%</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI said the rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India has cut its term deposit rates by up to 50 basis points for various maturities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the new structure, for two to less than three years deposits, SBI will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier, the bank said. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For deposits maturing between three years and 10 years, the rates have been lowered by 25 basis points to 6.50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lender will be offering the new rates for fresh deposits and renewals and are applicable from April 29, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short term deposits, that is, for deposits maturing between seven days to less than two years, the rates have been left unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank is offering highest rates of 6.90 per cent for one year to 455 days term deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also not changed its marginal cost of funds based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want A New Jio SIM? Here&#39;s What You Pay To Get &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in getting a new Reliance Jio SIM and availing the &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer? Rs 408 is the minimum amount you need to spend. For Jio non-Prime and new users, the recharge amount is Rs 309 along with an additional Rs 99. Similarly, to get the Rs 509 plan, the amount needed will be Rs 608.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has extensively provided free data services with unlimited calls for several months and with the telecom operator starting paid services, one can expect the firm to provide the &amp;lsquo;most affordable&amp;rsquo; plans. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rs. 408 is the minimum amount needed to avail Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has provided free services with unlimited calls for last few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has been in the controversy for stretching its free trial run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-dhan.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Wifi, LCD Screens, Tejas Express To Redefine Rail Travel. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wifi-lcd-screens-tejas-express-to-redefine-rail-travel-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wifi-lcd-screens-tejas-express-to-redefine-rail-travel-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 20-coach Tejas Express will be fitted with automatic doors, LCD screens, onboard wifi, tea/coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Railways is set to launch a premium train service called Tejas Express between Mumbai and Goa this summer. Fitted with automatic doors, LCD screens, onboard wifi, tea/coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables, the 20-coach Tejas Express will also serve cuisine curated by celebrity chefs. The premium Tejas Express service was announced in Rail Budget 2016-17. Tejas will showcase the future of train travel in India, Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu has said. &amp;ldquo;Mumbai-Goa train journey will get as exciting as air travel from June&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; the Ministry of Railways said on microblogging site Twitter on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the upcoming Tejas express:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tejas Express will operate at speeds of 130 kmph and above, according to the Rail Budget 2016-17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train &amp;ldquo;will showcase the future of train travel in India&amp;rdquo;, offering onboard services such as entertainment, local cuisine, WiFi etc. through one service provider for ensuring accountability and improved customer satisfaction, it said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/tejas-express-pti_650x400_51493538210.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Mumbai-Goa Tejas Express will have 20 coaches comprising executive class and chair cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering service will be part of Tejas fares like Rajdhani and Shatabdi trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coaches will have automatic doors and secured gangways for all coaches, a first for the Indian Railways. Currently automatic doors are operational in Metro trains only, while gangways, corridors between coaches, are not closed from the sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onboard facilities will include tea and coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables, news agency Press Trust of India said citing a senior Railway Ministry official, adding that the LCD screens meant for entertainment purpose will also be used for disseminating passenger-related information and safety instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features on Tejas coaches will include integrated braille displays, digital destination boards, and electronic passenger reservation charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will also be water level indicators in bio-vacuum toilets, sensorised taps and hand driers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train&amp;rsquo;s interior colour scheme will match the exterior to give the passengers a feel of world class travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Mumbai-Goa route, the Tejas service is likely to be pressed on the Delhi-Chandigarh route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मशीन सूंघकर बताएगी आप बीमार है या नहीं!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ऐसी मशीन आपके सामने होगी जो सूंघकर बता देगी कि आप बीमार हैं या नहीं। रिसर्चर्स एक ऐसी मशीन पर काम कर रहे हैं जो आपकी सांस, ब्लड और यूरीन से आपका रोग पहचान लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हम सभी की एक यूनीक स्मेल होती है जो हजारों कार्बनिक यौगिक से मिलकर बनती है। इस महक से हमारी उम्र, जेनटिक, लाइफस्टाइल, होमटाउन और यहां तक की हमारे मेटाबॉलिक प्रोसेस के बारे में भी पता चलता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्राचीन यूनानी और चीनी चिकित्सक रोग को पहचानने के लिए मरीज की खुश्बू का इस्तेमाल किया करते थे। मॉर्डन मेडिकल रिचर्स में भी यह बात सामने आई है कि किसी की त्वचा और सांस की गंध बीमारी का सूचक हो सकते हैं। एक्सपर्ट रिपोर्ट्स की मानें तो मधुमेह रोगियों की सांस कभी-कभी सड़े हुए सेब जैसी, वहीं टाइफाइड रोगियों की त्वचा बेकिंग ब्रेड जैसी गंध देती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वैसे तो हर डॉक्टर भी कुछ बीमारियों को किसी हद तक सूंघ सकता है, लेकिन यह इस पर निर्भर करता है कि उसकी नाक कितनी संवेदनशील है और वह सूंघ कर बीमारियां पहचानने का कितना अनुभवी है। इस वजह से रिसर्चर्स कम खर्च में एक ऐसे सेंसर पर काम कर रहे हैं जो रोग को पहचान ले।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह सेंसर एक सिलिकॉन चिप है जिस पर कई मेटल लेयर्स और छोटे गोल्ड इलेक्ट्रॉड्स लगे होंगे। यह मोबाइल फोन के सिम कार्ड जैसा दिखाई देगा और केमिकल फिल्टर जैसे काम करेगा। इस मशीन को इलेक्ट्रॉनिक नाक कहें तो गलत नहीं होगा, जो आदमी की नाक की तुलना में कहीं सटीक और बेहतर ढंग से रोग की पहचान कर लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Rs 50,000 On Your Provident Fund Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-deposits-to-earn-rs-50-000-more-under-new-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-deposits-to-earn-rs-50-000-more-under-new-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund body EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation&amp;rsquo;s (EPFO) apex decision making body, the Central Board of Trustees (CBT), has recommended a minimum sum assured of Rs 2.5 lakh in the event of death of a subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The CBT has recommended amending the Employees&amp;rsquo; Deposit Linked Insurance Scheme (EDLI) to provide for minimum benefit of Rs 2.5 lakh and loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at a meeting held yesterday,&amp;rdquo; a senior official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The suggested benefits will be available to members after government approval. Initially, these will be provided for two years on a pilot basis and will be reviewed thereafter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the proposal, loyalty-cum-life benefit will be provided to all those members on retirement at 58 or 60 years who have contributed to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability. In these cases, the members who have contributed to the EDLI scheme for less than 20 years will be eligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those members whose average basic wages are up to Rs 5,000 will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of Rs 30,000. Similarly, the members with wages of Rs 5,001-10,000 Will be eligible for Rs 40,000 benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those members getting more than Rs 10,000 monthly wage will be eligible for Rs 50,000 loyalty-cum-life benefit under the proposed scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board has recommended such benefits in view of a huge EDLI corpus of Rs 18,119 crore following addition of interest that accrued on investment of this fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, the dependants of the deceased get a sum assured of up to Rs 6 lakh. There is no provision of minimum insurance and any benefit for surviving members or in cases of permanent disability under the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya launched Aadhaar Seeding Application after the meeting. The EPFO has developed this application with support of Common Service Centres (CSCs) and C-DAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CSCs are ICT-enabled front-end service delivery points at the village level for delivery of government and private services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With implementation of the seeding application, a PF member or pensioner can now walk into any of the field offices of EPFO or CSC outlets with UAN and Aadhaar and seed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO enrolled 49,39,929 workers during January-March 2017. It had launched a special enrolment scheme to cover leftout formal sector workers from January 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>