<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar must to get government co-contribution for availing Atal Pension Yojana</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The finance ministry on Monday said their subscribers of the Atal Pension Yojana (APY) will have to link their Aadhaar to their accounts for availing up to Rs 1,000 government’s co-contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any individual who is eligible to receive benefits under the APY will have to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo enrolment under Aadhaar authentication, the ministry said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pension regulator PFRDA has identified nearly 12.35 lakh subscribers who are eligible for government co-contribution for an amount up to Rs 1,000 for the financial year 2016-17, which will be released to the eligible subscribers’ savings bank accounts which are seeded with Aadhaar — the 12 digit unique identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“An APY subscriber will have to get the Aadhaar number recorded in his or her APY pension account and also in his/her savings account where the periodic pension contribution instalments are debited and government co-contribution is to be credited,” the ministry said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atal Pension Yojana, the government’s flagship social security scheme, has more than 54 lakh subscribers with an asset base of more than Rs 2,200 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an objective of bringing in “transparency, efficiency” and to enable beneficiaries to get their entitlement directly in a convenient and seamless manner, Aadhaar card has been constituted as the primary document in identification of the beneficiary under the Aadhaar Act.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s next President:10 things about Draupdi Murmu, the woman who could be India&#39;s next President</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-things-about-draupdi-murmu-the-woman-who-could-be-indias-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-things-about-draupdi-murmu-the-woman-who-could-be-indias-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the new president of India set to be elected next month, several names are doing the rounds including those of BJP veteran Najma Heptullah and Mahatma Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s writer grandson Rajmohan Gandhi. Many say Prime Minister Narendra Modi has decided Jharkhand Governor and BJP leader Draupdi Murmu to be the party candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very few people know about Murmu outside eastern states. Here are 10 things to know about the woman who can be the next president of the country:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murmu was sworn in as the first woman Governor of Jharkhand in May last year. She is also the first tribal to become the governor of a state in India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;She comes from a Santhal tribal family in Uparbeda village in Kusumi block of Mayurbhanj district. She holds a Bachelor of Arts degree. Before joining politics, she worked as a teacher and a government clerk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;She has been a two-time BJP MLA from Rairakhol in Mayurbhanj. She held several portfolios in the BJD-BJP coalition government between 2000 and 2004. She was given the Nilakantha Award for the best MLA in 2007 by the Odisha Legislative Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;She had lost her two sons and husband. She has one daughter who is married. In an interview after she was appointed the Governor of Jharkhand, she said, &amp;ldquo;I was completely devastated. But God has given me the strength to continue to serve the people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A soft-spoken Murmu has worked away from the media glare in the tribal wing of the BJP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her election is going to impact the BJP&amp;rsquo;s prospects in the next Lok Sabha polls in several states with significant tribal population. Her native district, Mayurbhanj, lies on the borders of West Bengal as well as Jharkhand. She will impact tribal votes majorly in the three states while also improving the BJP prospects in Chhattisgarh and Maharashtra.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murmu as the BJP&amp;rsquo;s choice for president can also hit the opposition unity. Many opposition parties may well have to support her candidature as they won&amp;rsquo;t like to be seen opposing a tribal. Odisha&amp;rsquo;s ruling party Biju Janata Dal (BJD) might not be able to oppose a tribal candidate from its own state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murmu&amp;rsquo;s election will improve the BJP&amp;rsquo;s chances of winning the upcoming assembly polls in Odisha too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The choice of a tribal as president will boost PM Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s new strategy to focus on Dalit and tribal votes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Murmu is elected, she will be the second president from Odisha after VV Giri.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI new Rs 500 currency. Here&#39;s what is different in new notes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Banks of India (RBI) today announced introduction of new Rs 500 currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new version will have few different aspects. The one noticeable aspect of the new currency notes is the inclusion of an inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, in the new notes the signature of the RBI Governor will be on the reverse side.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/SdLYWuNz3Nk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In continuation of issuing of Rs 500 denomination banknotes in Mahatma Gandhi (new) series from time to time which are currently legal tender, a new batch of banknotes with inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; in both the number panels bearing the signature of Dr. Urjit R. Patel Governor, Reserve Bank of India; with the year of printing &amp;lsquo;2017&amp;rsquo; on the reverse, are being issued,&amp;rdquo; RBI said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of these notes is similar in all respects to the Rs 500 banknotes in Mahatma Gandhi (New) Series, RBI added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current Rs 500 notes have inset letter E.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank had demonetised old Rs 500 and Rs 1000 notes on November 8 last year. After that RBI introduced new Rs 500 and 2000 currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, RBI had said that nearly 83 per cent of the currency has been remonetised and denied there was any shortage of cash in the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data on the amount of demonetised notes returned, however, is still not available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 12. Vodafone Announces New Ramzan Plans.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-announces-new-ramzan-plans-starting-at-rs-12-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-announces-new-ramzan-plans-starting-at-rs-12-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone also said it will offer unlimited voice calling, unlimited national roaming and 1GB data per day in plans priced at Rs 342 and Rs 442.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Vodafone India announced new Ramzan offers for its prepaid users. The new plans, called &amp;ldquo;Ramzan 342 and 442&amp;rdquo;, are valid for users in Karnataka, Vodafone India said in a release. Under the offer, users can avail of unlimited 2G data at Rs 5 per hour and unlimited 3G/4G data at Rs 19 per hour. They can download the Vodafone Play App, which allows them to watch Makkah and Madinah live, the release added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone also said it will offer unlimited voice calling, unlimited national roaming and 1GB data per day in plans priced at Rs 342 and Rs 442. While Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ramzan 342&amp;rdquo; pack comes with a validity of 28 days, the &amp;ldquo;Ramzan 442&amp;rdquo; will have a 70-day validity. The company is also offering a &amp;ldquo;Ramzan 12&amp;rdquo; pack, which facilitates calls at &lt;em&gt;Rs 30 paise per minute&lt;/em&gt; and comes with a validity of 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amit Kapur, business head, Karnataka, Vodafone India said, &amp;ldquo;The holy month of Ramzan is a month of giving and doing good deeds that benefit all. As a symbol of our endeavour to bring happy times to the lives of our customers, Vodafone has introduced a choice of plans that give them the best of talk time and data, at very attractive price. Starting from unlimited 2G data at Rs 5 per hour to Vodafone Ramzan 442 that allows unlimited Local and STD calls, plus 1GB data per day, our plans have been designed to enhance the festive spirit and promote bonding with family and friends during this holy month.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India is a wholly-owned subsidiary of British telecom company Vodafone Group Plc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Reliance-Jio-VoLTE-feature-phone.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen. It also has a dedicated button for torchlight. Maker of this feature phone is not known yet. Currently we don’t have any specifications of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to recent reports, Jio will launch these VoLTE-enabled feature phones starting at Rs. 999 that will run on Android operating system. Earlier reports said that capability to make VoLTE calls in these feature phones will be enabled by Spreadtrum chips, and Jio is in talks with Qualcomm and MediaTek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Jio plans start as low as Rs. 149 per month offering unlimited calls, this will be useful for those who make a lot of calls and need a cheap phone with a keypad. We should know more details about more upcoming VoLTE-enabled feature phones from Jio soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1. Announced in a circular on the SBI website on Thursday morning, the revisions initially created confusion among customers over news that all cash withdrawals through ATM will now be charged at Rs. 25 per transaction. The bank later clarified that the Rs 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through SBI’s mobile wallet app “State Bank Buddy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an emailed statement to NDTV Profit, an SBI spokesperson clarified that a limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applied to the Basic Savings Banks deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal Saving Bank accounts will continue to get 8 free ATM transactions (5 SBI ATMs + 3 other bank ATMs) in metros &amp;amp; 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 SBI ATM + 5 Other Bank ATMs) free, the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from ATM charges, SBI also  revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers. Here are some of the other key changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh, Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; Going forward SBI said it will charge 2 rupees for every soiled note on exchange of more than 20 notes or if the total value of exchanged notes is above Rs 5,000 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs 30 plus service tax for a 10 leaf cheque book, Rs 75 with service tax for 25 leaf cheque book and Rs 150 plus service tax for a 50 leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issue of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only Rupay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mVisa can be use for booking Railway Tickets</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/travellers-can-now-book-railway-tickets-using-mvisa-payment-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/travellers-can-now-book-railway-tickets-using-mvisa-payment-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rail travellers can now book tickets by mVisa payment method which allows them to scan a quick response (QR) code and pay through smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can securely link their visa debit, credit or prepaid account to the mVisa application on their smartphones and make their travel bookings by simply scanning their mVisa QR code on the Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC, a subsidiary of the Indian Railways, is offering a promotion offer until September 4 that will give Rs 50 cashback to consumers booking their tickets through mVisa scan and pay on the IRCTC website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The key to our success as India&amp;rsquo;s largest e-commerce organisation has been our ability to embrace new technologies that help us drive consumer engagement across our platform,&amp;rdquo; IRCTC CMD AK Manocha said on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India is currently one of the major smartphone markets in the world, with over a billion smartphones expected to be sold in the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Considering the phenomenal penetration of smartphones in India, moving to a mobile based payment solution such as mVisa was thus a natural choice for IRCTC,&amp;rdquo; Manocha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increasing popularity and adoption of mobile devices presents a huge opportunity for the growth of mobile-based digital commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mVisa payment solution on IRCTC can potentially empower millions of consumers spread across Indian cities, towns and villages, to make payments using just their smartphones from the comfort of their homes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Both Apps uses Unified Payments Interface (UPI) technology to transfer money between any two individuals and between an individual and a merchant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navneet Dubey
Moneycontrol News&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you considering using one of the mobile payment apps launched by the government recently? If so, you may be confused on whether you should use the Aadhaar Payment App or Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there are specific features of each of these apps which differentiate them which you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start with, the Aadhaar app allows to make your payments through a thumb impression while BHIM through its ‘virtual address’ facility make it possible to transfer payments from one individual to another without disclosing one’s account number on either side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in both the cases, payments can be done from any bank account to any merchant or an individual who have registered their bank account with their Aadhaar number and have also registered themselves with the apps respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We list out the features of each of these apps, how they work and what significance they carry while making the payment from one source to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is Aadhaar Pay App?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This digital payment application is made for merchants to accept payments from a customer using their Aadhaar number. Merchants need to download the app from their app stores and connect their smartphones to the biometric scanning device to accept payments from customers. The customer will then be able to make digital payments even if they don’t have a smartphone, a debit card or credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the merchants’ side, to use the app they are required to register their bank accounts and their own details on the Aadhaar payments app before receiving any money. Once the e-KYC process is validated, they can use the app to carry out the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers, on the other hand, need to have Aadhaar-linked bank account to process their payment successfully. If in case the Aadhaar number is not registered with the bank account you will not be able to make payment through this application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Features of the BHIM App&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through BHIM, you can directly make payments from one bank account to another using unified payments interface (UPI). The payments can be made from one individual to another using virtual address assigned to the respective bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also send money through IFSC and MMID Code to other individual, users who do not even have a UPI-linked bank account or do not carry a smartphone with them. To send or to request for money, you can simply login to your BHIM app through mPIN and then type in the mobile number or virtual payment address (VPA) address to make the transfer of payments easily. This way you do not have to remember or re-enter anyone’s account number while doing any number of transactions within the same account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM app is integrated with UPI mechanism via USSD code which helps in facilitating financial transactions even in offline mode through your phone, even if it not a smartphone. So, BHIM app also makes it possible to do transaction even if you do not have an internet facility. The app also allows you to make the transfer of payments using QR code for a fixed amount of money, which the merchant or an individual can scan and further make the transaction successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key Highlights&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;–Payments can be done to and from multiple bank accounts using these apps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;–BHIM App uses 4 modes to make payment facility – VPA, QR code, IFSC and MMID code&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;–Both Apps uses UPI technology to transfer money between any two individuals&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;–The apps are available on all the digital app-stores offered by various operating systems&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;–Both apps are highly secured and uses mPIN password facility&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;–Both customers and merchants must have Aadhaar-linked bank account&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-Aadhaar-is-being-challenged/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-Aadhaar-is-being-challenged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Six articles that explain why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Aadhaar is vulnerable to identity theft because of its design and the way it is used: A centralised database, dual use as identifier and authenticator, and lack of sound legal framework are its main weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Amid the debate about privacy, the more pressing issue of exclusion has been forgotten: Exclusion due to authentication errors and deactivation have an immediate impact on millions of people across India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Haryana is making babies enrol in Aadhaar before it will issue them birth certificates: Even though the state government denies that the identity number is mandatory to obtain this document, officials on the ground admit that it virtually is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Government websites are leaking Aadhaar numbers. Who will take action against the government?: Caches of Aadhaar data are leaking regularly, yet UIDAI insists the digital identity is secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Under the right to information law, Aadhaar data breaches will remain a state secret: Scroll.in’s queries for information were dismissed on grounds of national security and confidentiality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Who will own your data when your electronic health records are linked to Aadhaar?: The draft health privacy law will be made public to invite comments in the coming weeks, government officials say.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एक जुलाई से आयकर भरने के लिए आधार-पैन जोड़ना जरूरी: सीबीडीटी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pan-card-and-aadhar-card-should-be-necessary-to-file-income-tax-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pan-card-and-aadhar-card-should-be-necessary-to-file-income-tax-return/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने शनिवार को स्पष्ट किया कि एक जुलाई से आयकर रिटर्न दाखिल करने और स्थायी खाता संख्या (पैन) हासिल करने के लिए आधार और पैन को आपस में जोड़ना ‘अनिवार्य’ होगा।  सरकार की तरफ से यह स्पष्टीकरण सुप्रीम कोर्ट के इस संबंध में दिए एक फैसले के एक दिन बाद आया है। शीर्ष अदालत ने आयकर अधिनियम में किए गए उस प्रावधान को वैध माना है जिसमें पैन कार्ड आबंटन और आयकर रिटर्न दाखिल करने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य किया गया है। लेकिन निजता के अधिकार से जुड़े मामले पर संवैधानिक पीठ का फैसला आने तक इसके क्रियान्वयन पर आंशिक स्थगन लगा दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग की नीति निर्माता संस्था केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ने शनिवार को एक बयान जारी कर स्पष्ट किया कि सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने शुक्रवार के अपने फैसले में केवल उन लोगों को आंशिक राहत दी है जिनके पास आधार नंबर नहीं है या जिन्होंने आधार में पंजीकरण नहीं कराया है, ऐसे में कर अधिकारी उन लोगों के पैन को निरस्त नहीं करेंगे। सीबीडीटी ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट के फैसले के बारे में तीन बिंदुओं का स्पष्टीकरण जारी किया है। करदाताओं में सुप्रीम कोर्ट के फैसले से किसी तरह की आशंका को दूर करने के लिए यह स्पष्टीकरण दिया गया।
एक जुलाई 2017 से प्रत्येक व्यक्ति जो आधार पाने का पात्र है उसके लिए आयकर रिटर्न दाखिल करने या फिर पैन के लिए आवेदन करने में अपने आधार नंबर का उल्लेख या आधार पंजीकरण संबंधी पहचान नंबर का उल्लेख करना अनिवार्य होगा। सीबीडीटी ने कहा है, ‘एक जुलाई 2017 को जिस भी व्यक्ति को पैन नंबर आबंटित किया गया है और जिस भी व्यक्ति के पास आधार नंबर है या फिर वह आधार नंबर लेने का पात्र है, उसे पैन के साथ आधार नंबर जोड़ने के लिए अपना आधार नंबर आयकर प्रशासन को बताना होगा।’विभाग ने इस बारे में भी स्पष्टीकरण दिया है कि यदि किसी व्यक्ति के पास आधार नंबर नहीं है या आधार नंबर का उल्लेख नहीं किया जाता है तो उसका क्या होगा। विभाग ने इस बाबत कहा कि इस मामले में शीर्ष अदालत ने केवल आंशिक राहत दी है। यह राहत उन लोगों को दी गई है जिनके पास आधार नहीं है या जो फिलहाल आधार नहीं लेना चाह रहे हैं। ऐसे लोगों के मामले में पैन नंबर निरस्त नहीं किया जाएगा ताकि आयकर अधिनियम के तहत पैन नंबर का उल्लेख नहीं करने संबंधी दूसरे नियमों का खमियाजा उन्हें नहीं भुगतना पड़े।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ आयकर अधिकारी ने बताया यदि पैन को निरस्त कर दिया जाता है तो संबंधित व्यक्ति अपने सामान्य बैंकिंग और वित्तीय परिचालन नहीं कर पाएगा, इसलिए यह राहत दी गई है। लेकिन यह स्पष्ट किया गया है कि एक जुलाई से आयकर रिटर्न दाखिल करने और अगर नया पैन बनाना है तो आधार का उल्लेख करना अनिवार्य होगा। वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा कि शीर्ष अदालत के फैसले का कानून मंत्रालय, वित्त मंत्रालय, सीबीडीटी और आयकर विभाग के अधिकारियों ने अध्ययन किया है और उसके बाद ही यह स्पष्टीकरण जारी किया गया है। सरकार ने वित्त अधिनियम 2017 के तहत करदाताओं के लिए आधार नंबर या आधार पंजीकरण आवेदन संख्या का आयकर रिटर्न दाखिल करते समय उल्लेख अनिवार्य कर दिया। इसके साथ ही एक जुलाई 2017 से पैन के लिए आवेदन करने में भी आधार का उल्लेख अनिवार्य कर दिया गया है। आयकर विभाग अब तक 1.16 करोड़ आधार नंबरों को पैन के साथ जोड़ चुका है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ऑनलाइन दवाएं खरीदने से पहले जान लें ये बातें</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-pay-rent-using-your-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-pay-rent-using-your-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;इस भागदौड़ भरी जिंदगी में समय बचाने के लिए ऑनलाइन शॉपिंग का चलन तेजी से बढ़ा है। पिछले कुछ समय से इसके जरिए दवाओं की खरीददारी भी की जा रही है। ऐसे में सवाल उठता है कि क्या दवाओं की ऑनलाइन शॉपिंग एक सही कदम है?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऑनलाइन दवाएं खरीदने पर आम तौर पर आपको घर बैठे ही नए-नए डिस्काउंट मिलते हैं, जिससे आपके कुछ पैसे बच जाते हैं। सबसे बड़ा फायदा उन लोगों को होता है, जो कुछ दवाओं को दूसरों के सामने नहीं खरीदना चाहते और खरीददारी में निजता बरतना चाहते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दवाओं की ऑनलाइन खरीददारी में सबसे बड़ा जोखिम उनके नकली होने का होता है। इसके अलावा कभी-कभी प्रॉडक्ट को सही से समझने में भी चूक हो जाती है। धोखाधड़ी का सबसे ज्यादा जोखिम विदेश में स्थित कंपनियों से खरीददारी में होता है। ऐसे में खरीददारी करने से पहले आप एक बार संबंधित कंपनी के बारे में ठीक से जान लें और बिना डॉक्टर की सलाह के खरीददारी न करें।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जी हां, भारत में ऑनलाइन फार्मेसी वैध है और यह ड्रग्स ऐंड कॉस्मेटिक अधिनियम के अंतर्गत आती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस मामले में विशेषज्ञों की राय मिली-जुली है। जहां कुछ विशेषज्ञ मानते हैं कि दवाओं की ऑनलाइन खरीददारी में नकली उत्पाद मिलने की संभावनाएं होती हैं, वहीं कुछ विशेषज्ञ कहते हैं कि नकली दवाओं के मिलने का खतरा तो पारंपरिक बाजार में भी होता है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जानलेवा मच्छरों से बचा सकता है यह मेक्सिकन पौधा</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/this-mexican-plant-called-agave-americana-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/this-mexican-plant-called-agave-americana-can/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;इन दिनों नैशनल सेंटर फॉर डिजीज कंट्रोल NCDC एक मेक्सिन पौधे को प्रमोट कर रहा है जिसे मच्छरों से होने वाली बीमारियों में हथियार के तौर पर इस्तेमाल किया जा सकता है। दरअसल, अगेइवी अमेरिकाना जिसे सेंचुरी प्लांट या कमल कैक्टस भी कहते हैं, मेक्सिको का एक पौधा जो भारत में बड़ी आसानी से मिल जाता है। NCDC के वैज्ञानिकों का कहना है कि इस पौधे के पत्तों के निचोड़ में मच्छरों के लार्वा को खत्म करने के गुण मौजूद हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आसान शब्दों में कहें तो जब मच्छर, इस पौधे के पत्तों के निचोड़ के संपर्क में आते हैं तो वे मर जाते हैं। NCDC के जॉइंट डायरेक्टर डॉ. एल जे कानहेकर कहते हैं, आप इस पौधे के पत्तों के निचोड़ को कूलर और ऐसे कंटेनर में रख सकते हैं जिसमें पानी स्टोर करके रखा गया हो। महज 24 घंटे के अंदर मच्छरों के सभी लार्वा मर जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NCDC के डायरेक्टर ए सी धारीवाल कहते हैं कि म्युनिसिपल कॉर्पोरेशन्स को सलाह दी गई है कि वे अपने कैंपेन में जानकारी, शिक्षा और सूचना के माध्यम से इस पौधे को ज्यादा से ज्यादा प्रमोट करें ताकि मच्छरों से होने वाली बीमारियों से लड़ा जा सके। धारीवाल कहते हैं, &amp;lsquo;कृत्रिम कीटनाशक बेहद हानिकारक होते हैं जिसका हमारे वातावरण और मानव जाति पर बुरी प्रभाव पड़ता है लेकिन इस पौधे से निकले निचोड़ से लार्वा भी मर जाता है और इससे किसी तरह की कोई हानि भी नहीं होती।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डॉ. एल जे कानहेकर कहते हैं, &amp;lsquo;हम अगेइवी अमेरिकाना नाम के इस पौधे के पत्तों का निचोड़ निकालकर उसे पाउडर या तेल के रूप में तैयार उसका प्रॉडक्शन करने के बारे में विचार कर रहे हैं ताकि इसे इस्तेमाल करना आसान हो जाए।&amp;rsquo; पदम चंद सैनी जो दिल्ली में एक प्राइवेट नर्सरी चलाते हैं का कहना है, &amp;lsquo;अगेइवी अमेरिकाना का पौधा अपने साइज के हिसाब से 100 से 400 रूपए के बीच बिकता है। कुछ लोगों को इस पौधे के लार्वा को मारने में मदद करने वाली खूबी के बारे में पता है। पिछले साल जब चिकनगुनिया के मामलों में बढ़ोतरी हुई तो मेरे पास कई ग्राहक आए जो इस पौधे की मांग कर रहे थे।&amp;rsquo; सैनी का दावा है कि अगेइवी अमेरिकाना का अलावा लेमन ग्रास और यूकलिपटस सिट्रिओडोरा भी दो और पौधे हैं जिनमें मच्छरों को दूर भगाने की खूबियां मौजूद हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस साल तापमान पिछले सालों के मुकाबले गर्म रहने के बावजूद दिल्ली में पिछले 6 महीने में चिकनगुनिया के 100 और डेंगू के 40 केस देखने को मिले हैं। अधिकारियों को डर है कि मॉनसून के बाद मच्छरों से होने वाली बीमारियों की तादाद बढ़ सकती है। पिछले साल यानी 2016 में डेंगू के 4 हजार 431 और चिकनगुनिया के 7 हजार 760 केस देखने को मिले थे। इन बीमारियों की वजह से कई लोगों की मौत भी हो गई थी। विशेषज्ञों की मानें तो मच्छरों के पैदा से पहले ही कोई ठोस कदम उठाया जाए तभी इस बीमारी के प्रकोप को रोका जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जारी है नोटबदली का गोरखधंधा, 1 करोड़ के पुराने नोट पर मिल रहे हैं 9 लाख रुपये के नए नोट</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-lakh-rupee-in-new-notes-for-1-crore-rupee-old-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-lakh-rupee-in-new-notes-for-1-crore-rupee-old-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;500 और 1,000 रुपये के पुराने करेंसी नोट अब भी ऊंचे कमीशन पर बदले जा रहे हैं, जबकि इनको बैंक में जमा कराने की समयसीमा 30 दिसंबर 2016 को ही खत्म हो गई थी। असल में बिचौलिये पुराने नोटों के मामले में नियमों की हर खामी का फायदा उठाने की कोशिश कर रहे हैं, जिसकी वजह से यह धंधा अभी भी चल रहा है। इन नोटों की लॉन्ड्रिंग के लिए एनआरआई की मदद ली जा रही है क्योंकि उनके लिए पुराने नोट जमा कराने की आखिरी तारीख 30 जून है। उनको अपने खातों में पुराने नोट जमा कराने के लिए भारी कमीशन ऑफर किया जा रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस धंधे से जुड़े प्रवीण (बदला हुआ नाम) ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;अभी अगर आप 1 करोड़ के पुराने नोट देंगे तो उसके बदले आपको 9 लाख रुपये मिलेंगे।&amp;rsquo; कोई 1 करोड़ देकर 9 लाख रुपये क्यों लेगा, यह पूछे जाने पर प्रवीण ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;कई ऐसे लोग हैं, जो सरकार से अपनी आमदनी का जरिया छिपाना चाहते हैं। जिन लोगों ने पुराने नोट जमा नहीं कराए हैं, उन्हें डर है कि ऐसा करने पर उनकी फ्यूचर सोर्स ऑफ इनकम भी इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट की नजरों में आ जाएगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने बताया कि वे लोग 1% कमीशन पर पुराने नोट एनआरआई को दे देते हैं। प्रवीण ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;एनआरआई ने हम लोगों से संपर्क किया। हम उनसे 1 करोड़ पुराने नोटों के बदले 10 लाख के नए नोट मांगते हैं। इस तरह से यह धंधा चल रहा है।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने बताया कि 1 करोड़ पुराने नोट पर उन्हें 50,000 रुपये से एक लाख रुपये तक का कमीशन मिल रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्रवीण ने कहा कि एनआरआई के लिए 30 जून की डेडलाइन तय की गई है, लेकिन वो अपना काम 25 जून को ही बंद कर देंगे। उनके मुताबिक, 25 जून के बाद धंधे में खतरा बहुत बढ़ जाएगा। पिछले ही महीने ठाणे पुलिस ने 1 करोड़ रुपये के पुराने नोट बदलवाने की कोशिश कर रहे 3 लोगों को गिरफ्तार किया था। हैदराबाद पुलिस ने भी कुछ दिन पहले 3.48 करोड़ रुपये की पुरानी करंसी बरामद की थी। ईटी ने इस धंधे से जुड़े दूसरे लोगों से भी बात की। उन्होंने भी बताया कि 1 करोड़ के बदले 9 लाख रुपये के रेट पर पुराने नोट बदले जा रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आरबीआई के सीनियर अधिकारियों ने भी नाम नहीं जाहिर करने की शर्त पर बताया कि इस गैरकानूनी धंधे की खबर उनको भी है, लेकिन इसको रोकना उनके अधिकार क्षेत्र में नहीं आता। वे उन एनआरआई से नोटों की अदला-बदली कर रहे हैं, जो फुलप्रूफ डॉक्युमेंट्स दे रहे हैं। इस बारे में ईटी ने आरबीआई से ईमेल के जरिये सवाल पूछे थे, लेकिन उनका जवाब नहीं मिला। 2 जून को रिजर्व बैंक ने कहा था कि एनआरआई को 30 जून तक उसके मुंबई, दिल्ली, चेन्नै, कोलकाता और नागपुर ब्रांच में नोट बदलने का मौका मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रिजर्व बैंक ने जारी किए 500 रुपये के नए नोट, इनसेट में लिखा है &#39;A&#39;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-issues-500-rs-new-notes-with-inset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-issues-500-rs-new-notes-with-inset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;रिजर्व बैंक ने 500 रुपये के नए नोट जारी किए हैं। नए बैंकनोट समय-समय पर जारी किए जा रहे महात्मा गांधी (नई) सीरीज के ही हैं। 500 रुपये के नए नोट में इनसेट में अंग्रेजी का ए (A) लिखा हुआ है। यह अक्षर रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया के गवर्नर डॉ. उर्जित पटेल के हस्ताक्षर वाले दोनों नंबर पैनलों पर अंकित है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नए नोटों में इनसेट में &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; के अलावा एक बड़ा अंतर यह होगा कि इनमें प्रिंटिंग का वर्ष &amp;lsquo;2017&amp;rsquo; नोट के पिछले हिस्से में अंकित होगा। नोट के बाकी फीचर्स 8 नवंबर 2016 को नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद जारी हुए नोटों जैसे ही हैं। नोटबंदी के बाद जारी हुए 500 के नोटों में इनसेट लेटर ई (E) था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया ने एक प्रेस रिलीज के जरिए यह जानकारी दी है, साथ ही केंद्रीय बैंक ने यह जानकारी ट्वीट भी की है। इसमें कहा गया है, &amp;lsquo;इनसेट में &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; लिखे 500 रुपये के बैंकनोट्स जारी।&amp;rsquo; साफ कर दें कि नोटबंदी के बाद जारी हुए 500 के नोट वैध रहेंगे। इनसेट लेटर और छपाई का वर्ष में जो बदलाव किए गए हैं वे केवल 500 के नोट में हुए हैं, 2000 के नोट में ऐसा कोई भी बदलाव नहीं किया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>