<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory For Subsidy: Indian Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to curb corruption in the Public Distribution System (PDS), the Indian government had made the Aadhar Card mandatory for availing foodgrain subsidy at PDS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has already made Aadhar Card mandatory for the cooking gas LPG subsidy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has declared Rs 1.4 lakh crore subsidy under the food security law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A timeline till June 30 is given for the common people who avail subsidy to apply for Aadhar Card, the government categorically stated in the notification in this regard that no subsidised foodgrains with Aadhaar after June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since November 2016, the Government of India, under the National Food Security Law (NFSA), has been providing 5 kg of foodgrains per person per month at Rs 1-3/kg to over 80 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification has been applicable from February 8 in all States and Union Territories (UTs) except Assam, Meghalaya and Jammu and Kashmir. This move indicates Government’s serious intetion of digitisation to curb the corruption in PDS as well as a move towards a simplifies delivery process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards to be linked with university degrees, certificates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-to-be-linked-with-university-degrees-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-to-be-linked-with-university-degrees-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The proposal is currently under consideration by the &lt;em&gt;ministry of human resource development (MHRD)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to prevent forgery of university degrees and certificates in future, the University Grants Commission (UGC) is planning to link the Aadhaar card number and print the student’s photograph on the degree/certificate from next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposal is currently under consideration by the ministry of human resource development (MHRD). If the proposal gets approved, the commission would issue directions to the universities and educational institutions for the same by next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After receiving fraud degree-related complaints, the MHRD had sought suggestions from the UGC to tackle this issue. So, in the beginning of this month, the commission suggested a proposal of printing the Aadhaar card number and photograph of the student mandatorily on the degrees,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the proposal, having an Aadhar card number will not only prevent forgery, but will also make it easier to store the degrees in a digital format in the National Academic Depositary (NAD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The students will then just have to mention their Aadhaar card number, after which they will be able to access the degree/certificate from anywhere. If the experiment is successful for the universities, then the same will be implemented for Class 10 and 12,” the source added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar may be made mandatory for all 84 DBT schemes: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-made-mandatory-84-dbt-schemes-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-made-mandatory-84-dbt-schemes-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far, furnishing the Aadhaar card has been made mandatory by the government for nearly 34-35 central schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furnishing the Aadhaar card has now been made mandatory by the government for nearly 34-35 central schemes, whether it is investing in the employee provident fund (EPF) or availing mid-day meals in schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report in the Economic Times today, this could soon extend to all 84 schemes so far under the Direct subsidy Benefit Transfer scheme. The 12 digit unique-identity number issued to Indian residents based on their biometric and demographic data, has helped the exchequer save nearly Rs 49,000 crore over the last couple of years in DBT under various schemes including LPG subsidy and helped more than 4.47 crore people open bank accounts through e-KYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the other schemes that are now covered under the mandatory Aadhaar are Sarv Shiksha Abhiyan meant to make elementary education universal, skill training programmes National Social Assistance Programme and Deendayal Antyodaya Yojana, National Action Plan for skill training of disabled and for disabled persons seeking aids and appliances, Swadhar Greh Scheme for rehabilitation of sexually exploited women, and LPG and foodgrains under the public distribution system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be required of NGOs seeking assistance for working on welfare of SCs, backward castes, alcoholics and old people. Residents who are yet to get their Aadhaar card made can do so until June 30. Enrolment facility will be made available by the department at convenient locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone wanting to avail benefits while Aadhaar is still under process, the enrolment slip can be used along with any one of the nine prescribed identity proof documents. However, according to a source, notifications from the department on the use of Aadhaar clearly states, “no person will be denied any benefit for want of Aadhaar if he needs the benefit in a time-bound manner or as an emergency measure”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not compulsory for obtaining marriage certificate: CIC to Govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Chief Information Commission has asked the government and marriage registration authorities to raise awareness and provide publicity through various media that Aadhaar is not compulsory for the purpose of marriage registration scheme, reports LiveLaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commission ruled that the compulsory registration of marriages helps tackle various issues like child marriage, marriage without consent, bigamous marriages, etc., and as such, the government should make it easier and more convenient to facilitate the registration, by not requiring other documents like Aadhaar and making changes for online application for marriage under the Special Marriage Act etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CIC cited Supreme Court’s order from 2014, which ruled that the government should not restrict social benefits to those who are yet to receive their Aadhaar card. Last year, the SC had also said that the card scheme is purely voluntary and cannot be made mandatory for scholarships. However, contrary to its prior stance, the SC asked the Government to link all mobile numbers with Aadhaar card details within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;centre-s-push-to-increase-aadhaar-saturation&#34;&gt;Centre’s push to increase Aadhaar saturation?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usage of Aadhaar as a verification system has been on the rise where multiple services including the IIT JEE, employee provident funds, PDS food grain purchases, RTE admissions and Jharkhand’s food and public distribution systems also using it. Private companies have also started using Aadhaar for verification purposes, such as iris scans by DCB Bank for eKYC, Microsoft’s Skype Lite which supports Aadhaar based verification, etc. However, use of Aadhaar by making it compulsory to avail some services, has come under heavy criticism for not respecting user privacy or being very secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Notes Ban, 18 Lakh Cases Of Income, Bank Account Mismatches Detected: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government authorities have detected 18 lakh cases after demonetisation where the income profiles of people do not match their account profile, the Lok Sabha was informed today. Preliminary information has been sought from such people and many have responded. Those who have not given details would be issued with notices as per procedure, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said during Question Hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to supplementaries, he said there was an extended footprint of digitisation in the banking sector. With digitisation, the risk of tampering of technology also increases. But banks are also hiring experts to develop firewalls around their system to make it increasingly difficult to breach it, Jaitley said, adding that technology has to keep pace with crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that risk assessment was a continuous process for banks who do it individually and collectively. In his written response, Jaitley said as on March 31, 2016, 29 per cent of the savings accounts of public sector banks and regional rural banks sponsored by them were inoperative or lying dormant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A variety of factors have a bearing on an account being inoperative. These may include factors like opening of a new account with change of residence or office, death of the account holder or the relative convenience of operating different accounts, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM gives E-Wallets a run for money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BHIM — or the Bharat Interface For Money — is quickly becoming the favoured mobile payment solution for crores of Indians. Since its launch on December 31 till the end of February, the app had been downloaded 17 million times. Following its Android launch, BHIM is now also available on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is an extension of the Unified Payment System. It allows users to send and receive money through a mobile app that is linked to their bank savings account. This is an elegant solution compared to e-wallets that need to maintain a cash balance in order to be functional. Naturally, the question then arises: Should users switch to BHIM and simply spend from their banks, and stop using e-wallets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences between BHIM and e-wallets, and we’ll examine them here in order to help you understand the pros and cons of both ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bhim-vs-wallets-where-bhim-wins&#34;&gt;BHIM vs Wallets: Where BHIM Wins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Balance, loading &amp;amp; unloading:&lt;/em&gt; The first major difference between BHIM and UPI apps and e-wallets is how you maintain your spending balance. BHIM and UPI apps allow you to send and receive money with your bank account. You do not have to maintain a balance with the app. The app is your bank account, in a sense. But in e-wallets, you must maintain a balance in order to spend from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just that, returning your wallet balance back to your bank account will come with limitations and charges. But with BHIM and UPI, there is no need to send the money back from the app to the bank, since the money has been sitting in your account all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/em&gt; Another aspect where BHIM and UPI apps trump e-wallets. E-wallets do not have interoperability, meaning that if you are using Wallet X, you can only transfer money to another user on Wallet X, and not to a user operating Wallet Y. This isn’t a problem with BHIM, since you may move money between accounts with any bank on the BHIM platform. For example, you may be using an SBI account but you can send and receive money from users on ICICI or HDFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spending limits:&lt;/em&gt; BHIM and UPI score heavily here as well. E-wallets have a monthly spending limit of Rs 10,000 which can be raised to Rs 100,000 after the KYC process wherein users need to submit proof of ID and address in order to become authenticated. But BHIM allows a limit of Rs 10,000 per transaction and Rs 20,000 as the total worth of transactions in a 24-hour cycle. UPI apps go further, allowing you to spend up to Rs 100,000 per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-bhim-lags&#34;&gt;Where BHIM Lags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly two areas where e-wallets have an edge over UPI and BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marketing gimmicks:&lt;/em&gt; E-wallets have been around for a few years and they have had the time to build relationships with merchants and businesses. As a result, e-wallets are useful not just for money transfers but also for earning cashbacks and discounts. Not just that, some e-wallets also operate as e-commerce platforms allowing users to buy merchandise, electronics, tickets, etc. UPI and BHIM, on the other hand, are recent innovations and have some catching up to do in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit usage:* E-wallets allow you to link and spend from your credit card, allowing you to leverage the power of the credit available to you. BHIM works on simpler principles: you get to spend only if you have a bank balance, and you cannot link BHIM and UPI apps to your credit card account yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-bhim-is-catching-up&#34;&gt;How BHIM Is Catching Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest Union Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced a referral bonus and cashback scheme for BHIM users. “The government will launch two new schemes — a referral bonus for consumers and a cash-back scheme for merchants — to promote the use of BHIM,” Jaitley said during his budget speech. With these inclusions, BHIM will become a little more attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
Both e-wallets and UPI-based apps such as BHIM have a long way to go and a big role to play in India where internet penetration and smartphone usage are increasing by leaps and bounds every year. Both need to evolve in order to accommodate the changing needs of the Indian consumer in an increasingly less cash-dependent economy. However, at this point, you may want to have both BHIM and e-wallets installed on your smartphones. They both have some unique services to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Counter Jio, Airtel, Vodafone Launch New Plans. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/to-counter-jio-airtel-vodafone-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/to-counter-jio-airtel-vodafone-launch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As new comer Jio, the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, continues to offer discounted tariffs under its &amp;ldquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer in a bid to attract more customers, top two telecom players - Airtel and Vodafone - have launched data-oriented prepaid plans and offers to restrict their existing customers to switch to Reliance Jio. From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-of-the-recharge-plans-offered-by-airtel-and-vodafone-to-counter-jio-s-offers&#34;&gt;Here are some of the recharge plans offered by Airtel and Vodafone to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-399-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs 399 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs 399 recharge pack, Airtel is offering 1GB of 4G data per day along with free voice calls to any network for 70 days. However, there are some limitations on voice calls. You can do 300 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to Airtel (1200 minutes in a week) and for other networks, 3,000 minutes of free local and STD calls for 70 days. If you exhaust the free minutes, Rs 0.10 per minute will be charged.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bharti-airtel_650x400_61492413333.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-345-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel is offering 2GB of data per day at 4G speed for 28 days under its new Rs 345 recharge pack. Also, now there is no restriction with regard to the timing of data consumption. Under the earlier Rs 345 recharge pack, users were restricted to use only 500 MB of data daily from 6 am till midnight , and the remaining 500 MB between 12 am and 6 am. Along with the above data, users will also get free voice calls to Airtel and other networks as it is in the Rs 399 pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-244-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs 244 recharge, users will get 1 GB of 4G data per day for 70 days without any restriction on usage timing. But this pack offers free calls on Airtel networks only (300 minutes of daily Airtel-to-Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for a week for 70 days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above three recharge packs of Airtel have become active from April 15, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;vodafone-rs-352-recharge&#34;&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week. If you cross the call limit, a fee of 30 paise per minute will be charged for every call. This offer is not available for every Vodafone users. You can check if the offer is available for you by dialing *121# from your Vodafone number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 राज्यों के पेट्रोल पंप 14 मई से हर रविवार को रहेंगे बंद</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-in-eight-states-to-be-shut-on-sundays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-in-eight-states-to-be-shut-on-sundays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;14 मई से देश के आठ राज्यों में पेट्रोल पंप हर रविवार को बंद रहेंगे। यह फैसला प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी द्वारा &amp;lsquo;मन की बात&amp;rsquo; रेडियो कार्यक्रम में की गई उस अपील को देखते हुए लिया गया है जिसमें उन्होंने तेल बचाने के लिए देश के लोगों से एक दिन पेट्रोल-डीजल का इस्तेमाल न करने की बात कही थी। पेट्रोल पंप डीलर्स के एक संगठन ने बताया है कि तमिलनाडु, केरल, कर्नाटक, पुडुचेरी, आंध्र प्रदेश, तेलंगाना, महाराष्ट्र और हरियाणा के 20,000 पेट्रोल पंप 14 मई से हर रविवार को बंद रहेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारतीय पेट्रोलियम डीलर्स असोसिएशन की एग्जिक्युटिव कमिटी के सदस्य सुरेश कुमार ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;कुछ साल पहले हमने तय किया था कि हर रविवार को हम पेट्रोल पंप बंद रखेंगे, लेकिन तेल कंपनियों ने उस वक्त हमसे फैसले पर पुनर्विचार करने को कहा था, जिसके चलते फैसला अमल में नहीं लाया जा सका। लेकिन अब हमने पेट्रोल पंपों को रविवार को बंद करने का फैसला कर किया है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कुमार ने कहा कि असोसिएशन ने यह फैसला प्रधानमंत्री मोदी द्वारा &amp;lsquo;मन की बात&amp;rsquo; कार्यक्रम में तेल की बचत करने की अपील को देखते हुए किया है। प्रधानमंत्री ने पर्यावरण को बचाने के लिए एक दिन देशवासियों से पेट्रोल-डीजल इस्तेमाल न करने की अपील की थी। तमिलनाडु पेट्रोलियम डीलर्स असोसिएशन के उपाध्यक्ष कुमार ने बताया कि 14 मई से तमिलनाडु, केरल, कर्नाटक, पुडुचेरी, आंध्र प्रदेश, तेलंगाना, महाराष्ट्र और हरियाणा के लगभग 20,000 पेट्रोल पंप हर रविवार को 24 घंटे बंद रहेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कुमार ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;अकेले तमिलनाडु में इस फैसले के चलते हमें 150 करोड़ रुपये का घाटा होने की आशंका है, पर हमने देखा है कि रविवार के दिन वैसे भी सेल्स में 40 फीसदी की कमी आ जाती है।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि तेल कंपनियों को भी इस फैसले की जानकारी जल्द दे दी जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;असोसिएशन ने यह भी कहा है कि आपात स्थिति में तेल उपलब्ध कराने के लिए हर पेट्रोल पंप पर एक स्टाफ मेंबर मौजूद रहेगा। तेल कंपनियों द्वारा पेट्रोल पंपों का मार्जिन बढ़ाए जाने के मुद्दे पर कुमार ने कहा कि इस बारे में बातचीत चल रही है और इस बारे में जल्द ही कोई ऐलान किया जाएगा। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इसे लेकर हमारा संघर्ष जारी है। हम अपने असोसिएशन के मेंबर्स से जल्द मिलने वाले हैं। हम जल्द अपने फैसले का ऐलान करेंगे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At SBI, You Don&#39;t Need To Maintain Minimum Balance In These Accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India is offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has said it is exempting its customers holding certain account types from maintenance of average monthly balance. Such accounts include small savings bank accounts, basic savings bank accounts and Jan Dhan accounts, or the accounts opened under the government&amp;rsquo;s financial inclusion scheme Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana or PMJDY. This was said in a tweet by SBI, which recently adopted a new brand identity after merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank. SBI had earlier decided to increase the minimum balance required for maintaining savings accounts from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, State Bank of India is also offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.
Account holders of the following types of accounts are exempt from requiring to maintain an average monthly balance: pic.twitter.com/61U8QNu7xR
— State Bank of India (@TheOfficialSBI) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement was increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros. In case of non-compliance, savings bank account holders will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs. 100 (in metro cities), as per the bank&amp;rsquo;s website. (Read more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other features SBI offers under these accounts, according to its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-savings-bank-account&#34;&gt;Small savings bank account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account has a maximum balance limit of Rs 50,000 and offers a rate of interest applicable to savings bank accounts. Account holders get an ATM-cum-Debit card, issued free of cost and without any annual maintenance charge, as per the SBI website. All credits in a financial year should not aggregate to more than Rs 1 lakh and Rs 10,000 in case of withdrawals and transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-savings-account&#34;&gt;Basic savings account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s basic savings account has no minimum balance or maximum balance limits. Holders of this account type &amp;ldquo;will not be eligible to open any other Savings Bank Account&amp;rdquo; at the bank. Such an account - in case the customer already holds one - will have to be closed within 30 days of opening the basic savings bank deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;corporate-salary-package&#34;&gt;Corporate salary package&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s salary account under corporate salary package offers many benefits to the employer and the employee alike. This account type reduces employer&amp;rsquo;s paperwork and salary administration cost. Employees get free internet banking and mobile banking services, among other features, as per the SBI website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Get Time Till June 30 To Obtain PAN From Account Holders</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department has given banks three more months till June 30 to obtain permanent account number (PAN) or Form-60 from all account holders as it looks to tighten the noose around evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the notification, the Income Tax Department said that in Income-Tax Rules 114B, in the fourth proviso, &amp;ldquo;for the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;28th day of February&amp;rsquo; the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;30th day of June&amp;rsquo; shall be substituted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 114B lists various transactions for which quoting PAN is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had in January asked banks, post offices and cooperative banks to document PAN or declaration of Form 60 received from account holders and maintain all records for transactions under Rule 114B of I-T Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had said that persons who have not quoted PAN, or did not furnish Form 60 at the time of opening account, will have to provide the same by February 28. Form 60 is a declaration form filed by an individual without PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the demonetisation move effective November 9, the tax department had asked banks and post offices to report to it all deposits above Rs 2.5 lakh in savings accounts and more than Rs 12.50 lakh in current accounts made between November 10 and December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cash deposits exceeding Rs 50,000 in a single day had to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an estimated Rs 15 lakh crore in junked currency notes coming back into the banking system post demonetisation, the tax department has started analysing the bank deposit trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>