<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>67% jump in corruption complaints; railways tops: Central Vigilance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/67-jump-in-corruption-complaints-railways-tops-cvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/67-jump-in-corruption-complaints-railways-tops-cvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Corruption complaints against various government departments jumped by a whopping 67 per cent in 2016 over the previous year, with the Railways topping the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 11,000 complaints were received against the public sector behemoth, the Central Vigilance Commission (CVC) has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its annual report tabled in Parliament recently, the probity watchdog said it received a total of 49,847 complaints in 2016, as against 29,838 in 2015 &amp;ndash; an increase of 67 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Commission received a considerable number of complaints against public servants working in the state governments and other organisations who do not come under the jurisdiction of the Commission or which are of administrative nature,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of complaints received by the CVC in 2015 were 50 per cent less than a total of 62,363 received by it in 2014. The CVC had got 31,432 and 37,039 complaints of alleged corruption during 2013 and 2012 respectively, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving details, the CVC said the highest of 11,200 such complaints were against railway employees. Of these 8,852 were disposed of and 2,348 were pending. Further, a total of 1,054 complaints against railway employees were pending for more than six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of complaints against those under government of National Capital Territory of Delhi has declined with a total of 969 received last year as against 5,139 in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many as 6,513 complaints of alleged corruption were received against employees under Home Ministry, followed by 6,018 bank officials and 2,496 related to those working with the Ministry of Petroleum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 2,646 corruption complaints were received against officials of the Income Tax department, 2,514 against those in Urban Development Ministry and 2,393 related to employees working under Telecommunication Ministry, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 1,746 corruption complaints against employees under Labour Ministry, 1,668 in Food and Consumer Affairs department, 1,420 of customs and excise, 1,376 in public sector insurance companies and 1,369 against officials of Ministry of Steel, the CVC said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 759 complaints were against Coal Ministry employees, 724 of Information and Broadcasting Ministry, 689 in Defence, 571 related to employees of Health and Family Welfare department and 479 against officials of Shipping Ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar authentication a must for engineering scholarships</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The state higher and technical education department has made authentication of Aadhaar number a must for backward engineering students to avail scholarships. The move comes against the backdrop of large-scale scholarship scam across the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though decision has been welcomed by city engineering colleges, they feel the authentication process will burden them with extra work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a gazette notification dated April 13, the department states that every student desirous of availing benefits under the schemes specified in Schedule ‘A’ need to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo authentication process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process involves submission of aadhaar number along with demographic information or biometrics of the beneficiary to the Central Indentities Data Repository for verification. The repository verifies the correctness of the claims on the basis of information available with it. The repository is a centralized database having all aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schemes listed in Schedule ‘A’ are Rajashri Chhatrapati Shahu Maharaj Shikshan Shulk Shishyavrutti Yojana and Dr Panjabrao Deshmukh Vastigruh Nirvah Bhatta Yojana. The scholarships are meant for other backward class (OBC) students and take care of certain percentage of tuition and hostel fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The directorate of technical education’s website, too, has alerted students to provide aadhaar authentication details otherwise their reimbursement would be put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification issued by deputy secretary Kiran Patil clarifies that students who do not have enrolled for Aadhaar can still available the scholarships on two conditions. The Aadhaar enrolment ID slip can be attached to their applications. In case they are not able to enrol due to non-availability of enrolment centres, they may write to the UIDAI’s designated field offices or register through its web portal and attach a copy of this request with the application. The students will also have to submit a proof of identity from one of the listed documents that included voter ID card, PAN, passport driving licence, bank passbook, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department has issued the guidelines under section 3 and 4 of the Maharashtra Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act 2016, that is stringent than the mother Act. As per the new Act, proof of possession of Aadhaar number or authentication is required in availing state government subsidy, benefits or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A city college principal said the aadhaar ID is itself foolproof and there was no need to add an extra authentication process. “A person’s biometric details can be viewed through Aadhaar number. Why principals should be asked to verify a student’s domicile. The social welfare department too had asked us to verify students’ income proof. This is the tehsildar or SDO’s job. They have only increased our work,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar-Based Authentication Is ‘Fully Safe And Secure’, Assures UIDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UIDAI dismissed the recently-reported breach as an isolated case, and added that their internal security system had picked up the attempted misuse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dismissing reports of misuse of biometrics data, the government on Sunday said Aadhaar-based authentication is “fully safe and secure”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, subsidy transfers linked to Aadhaar has led the exchequer to save ₹49,000 crore during the last two-and-half years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), there has been no incident of misuse of Aadhaar biometrics leading to identity theft and financial loss when more than 400 crore Aadhaar authenticated transactions took place during the last five years, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI also said that it has carefully gone through various reports and would like to emphasise that there has been no breach to UIDAI database of Aadhaar in any manner whatsoever and personal data of individuals held by UIDAI is fully safe and secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With reference to an incident of misuse of biometrics reported in a newspaper, UIDAI said that it is an isolated case of an employee working with a bank’s Business Correspondent’s company making an attempt to misuse his own biometrics which was detected by UIDAI internal security system and subsequently actions under the Aadhaar Act were initiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to media reports about on-boarding of the ecosystem partners, UIDAI said that the regulations under the Aadhaar Act strictly regulate the on-boarding, functioning including the data sharing restrictions imposed on the companies which want to use Aadhaar information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI further said that Aadhaar is an important tool of good governance and empowerment of people and has helped more than 4.47 crore people open bank accounts through Aadhaar e-KYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has enabled the government to do Direct Benefit Transfers under various schemes including LPG subsidy and has helped the exchequer save over ₹49,000 crore during the last two and half years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar-based Public Distributions System is benefiting people by ensuring that their food grain entitlement are given only to the deserving beneficiaries and are not cornered by unscrupulous and corrupt elements, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With reference to reports that there are no extant regulations available to prevent storage and misuse of e-KYC data, while citing instances like capturing IRIS from high resolution photograph, UIDAI said that there are stringent provisions in the Aadhaar (Authentication) Regulations governing the usage of e-KYC data including storage and sharing, resident consent being paramount in both the cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any unauthorised capture of IRIS or fingerprints or storage or replay of biometrics or their misuse is a criminal offence under the Aadhaar Act, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reports of misuse of e-KYC data by various agencies and allegations that the e-KYC API is available in public domain, UIDAI said that e-KYC APIs are available only to authorised Authentication User Agencies (AUAs) and e-KYC User Agencies (KUAs) through authorised Authentication Service agencies (ASAs) which have established secured network connectivity for the purpose of authentication with the Central Identities Data Repository (CIDR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authorisation is in compliance with the Regulations, specifications, standards and technology architecture as prescribed, it said, adding, any violation would lead to penal action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statement said that news reports also speak of private agencies hired by mobile operators and banks for e-KYC leading to availability of these data in parallel database and the vulnerabilities in the scenario where there is no privacy law in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this regard, the authority pointed out that “Aadhaar authentication or e-KYC is only available to authorised agencies whose appointment, responsibilities, statutory obligations, penal provisions for contraventions are clearly provided for in the Aadhaar Act and the regulations framed thereunder.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks or mobile operators have to become UIDAI’s AUA/ASAs to obtain e-KYC data of their customers from UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-KYC data can be given by UIDAI to these agencies only after they obtain consent of their customers and can be used only for the purpose for which it was obtained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing an example, it said, a telecom operator can obtain the e-KYC data of its subscribers and will keep them in their records without biometrics and use them only for the purpose of proving telecom services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, a bank, after obtaining the e-KYC information of its account holders, will keep the information without their biometrics within the bank and will use it only for the purpose of providing banking services and cannot use it for any other purpose without obtaining consent of the customer, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI uses one of world’s most advanced encryption technologies in transmission and storage of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, it said, that during the last 7 seven years, there has been no report of breach or leak of residents’ data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authority is continuously updating its security parameters looking at the new threats in cyber space, the statement said, adding, it also undertakes security audits and ensures necessary steps to augment security features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI has decided to have registered devices for capturing biometrics data and such biometrics will be encrypted at the point of capture itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airtel, Vodafone Launch New Plans To Counter Jio. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-vodafone-launch-new-plans-to-counter-jio-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-vodafone-launch-new-plans-to-counter-jio-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As new comer Jio, the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, continues to offer discounted tariffs under its &amp;ldquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer in a bid to attract more customers, top two telecom players - Airtel and Vodafone - have launched data-oriented prepaid plans and offers to restrict their existing customers to switch to Reliance Jio. From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some of the recharge plans offered by Airtel and Vodafone to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 399 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &lt;em&gt;Rs. 399&lt;/em&gt; recharge pack, Airtel is offering 1GB of 4G data per day along with free voice calls to any network for 70 days. However, there are some limitations on voice calls. You can do 300 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to Airtel (1200 minutes in a week) and for other networks, 3,000 minutes of free local and STD calls for 70 days. If you exhaust the free minutes, Rs. 0.10 per minute will be charged.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bharti-airtel_650x400_61492413333.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel is offering 2GB of data per day at 4G speed for 28 days under its new Rs. 345 recharge pack. Also, now there is no restriction with regard to the timing of data consumption. Under the earlier Rs. 345 recharge pack, users were restricted to use only 500 MB of data daily from 6 am till midnight , and the remaining 500 MB between 12 am and 6 am. Along with the above data, users will also get free voice calls to Airtel and other networks as it is in the Rs. 399 pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs. 244 recharge, users will get 1 GB of 4G data per day for 70 days without any restriction on usage timing. But this pack offers free calls on Airtel networks only (300 minutes of daily Airtel-to-Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for a week for 70 days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above three recharge packs of Airtel have become active from April 15, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs. 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week. If you cross the call limit, a fee of 30 paise per minute will be charged for every call. This offer is not available for every Vodafone users. You can check if the offer is available for you by dialing *121# from your Vodafone number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuts in Insurance Premiums On Larger Cars, Bikes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/irdai-cuts-insurance-premiums-on-larger-cars-bikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/irdai-cuts-insurance-premiums-on-larger-cars-bikes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per the revised list, premium on mid-segment cars(1,000cc - 1,500 cc) has been reduced to Rs. 2,863 from Rs3,132 announced on March 28.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insurance sector regulator Irdai today reduced motor insurance premium rates in most of the segments like two-wheelers, cars and trucks by modifying the rates for 2017-18 issued three-weeks ago. The modified &amp;lsquo;premium rates for motor third party liability insurance cover&amp;rsquo; will apply retrospectively from April 1, the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (Irdai) said in an order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the premium rates for the current fiscal are higher than those of the previous year. As per the revised list, premium on mid-segment cars (1,000cc - 1,500 cc) has been reduced to Rs 2,863 from Rs 3,132 announced on March 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, premium for cars with engine capacity of more than 1,500 cc has been brought down to Rs 7,890 from earlier Rs 8,630.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no change in cars having engine capacity of less than 1,000 cc. The premium has been fixed at Rs 2,055. Similarly, premium has been brought down in case of two-wheelers with engine of 150 cc and more. Irdai further said premium rates have been reduced for most of the truck categories. The new rate, for instance, in case of &amp;lsquo;goods carrying vehicles public carriers (exceeding 40,000 kg)&amp;rsquo; has been reduced to Rs 33,024 from Rs 36,120 notified on March 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduction has been also affected for e-rickshaw and other passenger carrying vehicles. Modification in premium rates follows protest by a section of truckers against the Irdai&amp;rsquo;s move to substantially
hike insurance rates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016: Driving sans licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No card? Aadhaar, fingerprints will do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance minister also sought to turbo-charge the government’s objective of maximising cashless transactions with institutional support that included waiving all duties on point-of-sale (PoS) machines and biometric readers, improving rural digital infrastructure, tax breaks, cash incentives and easier loans based on digital transactions history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring about structural reforms, a Payments Regulatory Board will be created in the Reserve Bank of India. The governor and deputy governor of RBI will be on this Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sops have been lined up too. The government has announced a ‘referral bonus scheme’ for individuals and a cashback scheme for merchants who use the Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the tax front, the Budget encourages small businesses (with turnover up to Rs 2 crore) by reducing presumptive income tax to 6% on non-cash receipts against 8% at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of digital transaction is on rural and semi-urban areas through post offices, fair price shops and banking correspondents. Petrol pumps, fertilizer depots, municipalities, block offices, road transport offices, universities, colleges, hospitals and other institutions will also be encouraged, and possibly rule-bound at some point of time, to have facilities for digital payments. “A proposal to mandate all government receipts through digital means, beyond a prescribed limit, is under consideration,” Jaitley said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small Industries Development Bank of India (SIDBI) will be encouraged to refinance credit institutions that provide unsecured loans, at reasonable interest rates, to borrowers based on their electronic payment transaction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In my opinion, initiatives like cutting excise duty on manufacturing of payment devices and a Payment Regulatory Board will further boost India’s digital economy,” said Sanjay Rishi, regional president, American Express.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Himanshu Pujara, managing director, Euronet Services India said the measures would allow people in rural areas, those “beyond the 15% data-enabled smartphone users and mobile subscribers across the country” to become a part of the digital payments ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio is no longer free: Here are the tariffs and plans explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-not-free-dhan-dhana-dhan-plans-recharge-packs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-not-free-dhan-dhana-dhan-plans-recharge-packs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s services are now officially paid, and we explain all the plans and options in detail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio’s services are now officially paid. April 15 was the last day to sign up for Jio Prime by paying Rs 99 plus another Rs 309 or Rs 509 for the first recharge. Reports also say the company will start disconnecting services for those who have not gotten the Prime membership or gotten a recharge till now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are Jio’s plans like now that the service has become paid for all users? We take a detailed look at the fine print around Jio’s plans.
First up, if you go to the Jio.com, website, you can see the focus is on Jio Prime plans only. Also Jio’s website is not listing out postpaid plans. The Rs 309 and Rs 509 only apply for prepaid users. It is unclear what sort of plans will apply for Jio postpaid users, and who had got a recharge done before March 31 deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only three options are listed in recharge section now. Two are the new Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan plans, which come with a validity of 84 days each.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/reliancejio_sachets_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Rs 309&lt;/em&gt; recharge gets you 84GB day with 1GB FUP per day unlimited calls, 100 SMS per day, complimentary access to Jio app,  and a total validity of 84 days. After this period, the next recharge of Rs 309 will get you 1GB per day, and will be valid for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the &lt;em&gt;Rs 509&lt;/em&gt; recharge, which has 168 GB data for 84 days with 2GB FUP per day. Rest of it is same as the Rs 309 recharge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the cheapest plan is the &lt;em&gt;Rs 149&lt;/em&gt; one, which gives you 2GB data for 28 days, 300 SMS, and unlimited voice calls. There’s also a non-Prime version of this plan which has only 1GB data for the 28 day period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you got the Summer Surprise offer, which was priced at &lt;em&gt;Rs 303&lt;/em&gt; or higher, then you don’t need to worry. These new plans don’t apply to you, and you will still get the next three months of free service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio’s website mentions this about the Dhan Dhana Dhan offer:  &lt;em&gt;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan is limited to one recharge only. Not applicable if already recharged with Jio Prime + Rs. 303 or above plan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given Jio’s focus is on data, it also has booster packs for data recharges. These start at Rs 11 going up to &lt;em&gt;Rs 301. The Rs 11 plan has 0.1 GB data, Rs 51 pack offers 1GB data,&lt;/em&gt; Rs 91 has 2GB data, Rs 201 has 5GB and Rs 301 will give you 10 GB of data. However, these plans don’t have a validity period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teleco also has some sachet plans for users who can’t pay &lt;em&gt;Rs 309 in one go.&lt;/em&gt; You will find these when you are trying to recharge a number from the Jio website. These plans cost Rs 19, Rs 49 and Rs 96 respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Rs 19 Plan&lt;/em&gt; for Jio Prime users comes with 200 MB data, 100SMS and complimentary subscription to Jio apps along with free voice calls, but it is valid only for one day. For non-Jio Prime members, the plans has only 100 MB data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The _Rs 49 recharge offers 600 MB data _and validity of three days; for non-Jio Prime users it is 300 MB data. The Rs 96 recharge offers 1GB FUP, after which the speed is reduced to 128Kbps, 100 SMS per day and is valid for seven days. However, for non-Jio Prime members, the recharge has only 600 MB data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Skill Loan Up To Rs 1.5 Lakh: Interest Rate, Repayment And More</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-skill-loan-up-to-rs-1-5-lakh-interest-rate-repayment-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-skill-loan-up-to-rs-1-5-lakh-interest-rate-repayment-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Skill Loan comes with an effective interest rate of 9.5 per cent, based on an MCLR or marginal cost of funds-based lending rate of 8 per cent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI is offering loans for professionals so that they can add new skills to their profile. SBI&amp;rsquo;s Skill Loans scheme enables &amp;ldquo;you to get professional certification from any college or course affiliated with the various institutions&amp;rdquo;, according to a tweet by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank. The Skill Loans covers training at various training institutions besides National Skill Development Corporation and State Skill Corporation, said SBI, which recently updated its branding with a new monogram after its merger with six banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India offers loans up to Rs 1.5 lakh under the Skill Loan scheme. The Skill Loan comes with an effective interest rate of 9.5 per cent, based on an MCLR or marginal cost of funds-based lending rate of 8 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s Skill Loan scheme also offers a concession of 1 per cent for a full term, in case the interest is serviced promptly &amp;ldquo;as and when applied during the moratorium period, including course duration&amp;rdquo;, as per the bank&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-skill-loan-650_650x400_81492419021.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India is also offering 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years. Students can apply for term loans under SBI&amp;rsquo;s scholar loan scheme for pursuing higher education in select 120 premier institutions in the country - including several IIMs and IITs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, five associate banks - State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur (SBBJ), State Bank of Hyderabad (SBH), State Bank of Mysore (SBM), State Bank of Patiala (SBP) and State Bank of Travancore (SBT) - and Bharatiya Mahila Bank are now part of SBI. With the merger effective March 31, 2017, SBI said it will join the league of top 50 banks globally in terms of assets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very soon, you can do “iris” Aadhaar authentication from your smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheap in-built iris scanners will eradicate use of costly ones for mass adoption of Aadhaar verification.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID Inc., a consumer-grade iris scanning technology provider for mobile phones, proposed the introduction of iris integrated mobile phones as a cost-effective way of reducing the failure rates in Aadhaar biometric authentication, as recently reported in MGNREGA tests in Telangana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe iris integrated smartphones and tablets will address the issues reported with Aadhaar biometric authentication. The UIDAI and the worldwide biometric community have tested and found iris to have better reliability. We are confident the failure rates will be drastically lower once the cheaper iris integrated mobile devices are adopted in the market,” said Dr. Salil Prabhakar, President and CEO, Delta ID Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the government mandating the use of Aadhaar biometric authentication in more spheres of the society, the need for a biometric modality that works reliably is critical. Unlike fingerprints that are being reported to show high failure rates due to wear and tear, the iris, being a protected internal organ, is expected to be significantly more reliable. Additionally, since the iris is not affected with age, it works reliably across all age groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key impediments in the large-scale roll out of iris for Aadhaar has been the high cost of iris devices. This is being addressed with the rollout of iris integrated mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this regard, Samsung partnered with Delta ID to launch India’s first iris integrated tablet in May 2016. The technology is arriving in smartphones too, and not only in high end devices such as Samsung Galaxy S8, but also in low cost smartphones developed by Indian manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID’s ActiveIRIS technology passed the Standardisation Testing and Quality Certification’s (STQC) FRR test with better than 99 percent accuracy, and has been certified by the STQC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active IRIS and a combination of STQC-certified hardware components can be integrated by any mobile device to expeditiously introduce iris integrated mobile devices in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At SBI, You Don&#39;t Need To Maintain Minimum Balance In These Accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India is offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has said it is exempting its customers holding certain account types from maintenance of average monthly balance. Such accounts include small savings bank accounts, basic savings bank accounts and Jan Dhan accounts, or the accounts opened under the government&amp;rsquo;s financial inclusion scheme Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana or PMJDY. This was said in a tweet by SBI, which recently adopted a new brand identity after merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank. SBI had earlier decided to increase the minimum balance required for maintaining savings accounts from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, State Bank of India is also offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.
Account holders of the following types of accounts are exempt from requiring to maintain an average monthly balance: pic.twitter.com/61U8QNu7xR
— State Bank of India (@TheOfficialSBI) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement was increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros. In case of non-compliance, savings bank account holders will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs. 100 (in metro cities), as per the bank&amp;rsquo;s website. (Read more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other features SBI offers under these accounts, according to its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-savings-bank-account&#34;&gt;Small savings bank account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account has a maximum balance limit of Rs 50,000 and offers a rate of interest applicable to savings bank accounts. Account holders get an ATM-cum-Debit card, issued free of cost and without any annual maintenance charge, as per the SBI website. All credits in a financial year should not aggregate to more than Rs 1 lakh and Rs 10,000 in case of withdrawals and transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-savings-account&#34;&gt;Basic savings account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s basic savings account has no minimum balance or maximum balance limits. Holders of this account type &amp;ldquo;will not be eligible to open any other Savings Bank Account&amp;rdquo; at the bank. Such an account - in case the customer already holds one - will have to be closed within 30 days of opening the basic savings bank deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;corporate-salary-package&#34;&gt;Corporate salary package&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s salary account under corporate salary package offers many benefits to the employer and the employee alike. This account type reduces employer&amp;rsquo;s paperwork and salary administration cost. Employees get free internet banking and mobile banking services, among other features, as per the SBI website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Fixed Deposit Rates Lowest In Many Years. What Are Your Options?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fixed-deposit-rates-are-at-multi-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fixed-deposit-rates-are-at-multi-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the interest rates on bank fixed deposits are at multi-year lows. For example, State Bank of India is offering interest rate between 5.50 per cent and 6.90 per cent across different maturities on retail deposits (below Rs 1 crore), according to its website. Though the Reserve Bank of India has held its repo rate steady for some time, the 175-basis-point cut in its key lending rate since January 2015 has led to a broad decline in overall interest rate in the financial system. And the surge in deposits after demonetisation has forced banks to bring down interest rates on fixed deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;With bank fixed deposits at around 7 per cent and offering a post-tax return of 5-7 per cent depending on one&amp;rsquo;s tax slab, clearly for people in higher tax slab this will only help them match inflation and be at best a value protector,&amp;rdquo; says Manoj Nagpal, CEO, Outlook Asia Capital. But conservative investors should maintain their asset allocation based on their risk profile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some newer private banks offer higher rates, Mr Nagpal added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given that most asset classes that replace debt like gold, real estate etc have also not been giving returns in the short term, equity seems to be emerging as the only alternative. However investors should not over-allocate to equities just in the chase of higher returns. If being safe is the objective, then one should surely remember that equities are volatile by nature,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says small savings schemes like 5-year NSC (National Savings Certificates) offer a superior alternative for investors though with a slightly longer lock-in and could also be considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For senior citizens, Mr Nagpal recommends the Senior Citizen Savings Scheme and the to-be-launched Varishtha Pension Bima Yojana from LIC. The Varishtha Pension Bima Yojana 2017 is a pension scheme for senior citizens, which was earlier approved by the Union Cabinet. The Varishtha Pension Bima scheme 2017, which will be implemented through Life Insurance Corporation of India (LIC), assures pension based on a guaranteed rate of return of 8 per cent for 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among debt mutual funds, Mr Nagpal suggests accrual funds with a high quality of underlying portfolio for conservative investors. Given that the Reserve Bank of India has once again cautioned on the higher risks to inflation, conservative investors should reduce allocation to long duration debt funds, he added. Accrual funds mainly focus on earning interest income from the coupon offered by underlying bonds while debt funds based on duration try to gain from the upward or downward movement of interest rate in the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidya Bala, head of mutual fund research at Fundsindia.com, also says conservative investors should &amp;ldquo;actively considerer income accrual funds in mutual funds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If investors have a shorter time frame, Ms Bala suggests short-term and ultra short-term debt funds. &amp;ldquo;If they need regular income, they can use systematic withdrawal from short-term debt funds,&amp;rdquo; she adds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Besides generating superior returns, debt funds are more tax efficient&amp;rdquo; than bank fixed deposits, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Get Time Till June 30 To Obtain PAN From Account Holders</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department has given banks three more months till June 30 to obtain permanent account number (PAN) or Form-60 from all account holders as it looks to tighten the noose around evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the notification, the Income Tax Department said that in Income-Tax Rules 114B, in the fourth proviso, &amp;ldquo;for the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;28th day of February&amp;rsquo; the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;30th day of June&amp;rsquo; shall be substituted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 114B lists various transactions for which quoting PAN is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had in January asked banks, post offices and cooperative banks to document PAN or declaration of Form 60 received from account holders and maintain all records for transactions under Rule 114B of I-T Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had said that persons who have not quoted PAN, or did not furnish Form 60 at the time of opening account, will have to provide the same by February 28. Form 60 is a declaration form filed by an individual without PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the demonetisation move effective November 9, the tax department had asked banks and post offices to report to it all deposits above Rs 2.5 lakh in savings accounts and more than Rs 12.50 lakh in current accounts made between November 10 and December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cash deposits exceeding Rs 50,000 in a single day had to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an estimated Rs 15 lakh crore in junked currency notes coming back into the banking system post demonetisation, the tax department has started analysing the bank deposit trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-based payment modes work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government is planning to utilise the Aadhaar database to give shape to a digital future and utilise it for payments, and authentication of transactions is the key to its success. While Unified Payments Interface and BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) are processes for peer-to-peer transactions using smartphones, the government is promoting Aadhaar-enabled payment systems for the non-smartphone savvy. As per sources it is planning to launch Aadhaar Pay on April 14. ET looks into the different forms of Aadhaar payment modes being developed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems?
Payments that can be done with the help of au thentication and identi fication through the Aadhaar database is referred to as the Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems (AEPS). This is the new form of pay ment that is being pro moted by the govern ment to push for digital payments instead of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the major types of Aadhaar Enabled Payments?
The first type of payment is Aadhaar Bridge Payment System which is meant for direct bene fit transfer and subsidy payments from the gov ernment to the benefi ciaries. The second is AEPS which is used at the level of the business correspondent or `bank mitras’ where bank customers can use Aadhaar to access various services like cash withdrawal, account opening and fund transfer even without going to a bank branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is Aadhaar Pay wherein merchants can accept payments through Aadhaar identification of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we need Aadhaar Enabled payments?
These forms of payments are be ing promoted by the government specifically for the under privileged sections of the society and the rural poor who are not comfortable using cards or mobile wallets for payments.Instead of a mobile phone or a plastic card, in these forms of payments, the mode of authentication becomes the Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who runs the systems?
National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is the nodal authority for all Aadhaar-enabled payments in collaboration with banks. The payment company is trying to get as many banks to seed their customers’ accounts with their Aadhaar number so that payments can flow smoothly .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do the different forms of payments work?
Aahdaar Bridge Payment (ABPS):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant for recur ring payments done by the government to its customers for various subsidies as well as direct benefit transfer. Here the beneficiary is identified through an Aadhaar number, then NPCI manages an Aadhaar Mapper where the Aadhaar number is mapped to a specific bank account and the money flows to the connected bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-enabled-payment-aeps&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Payment (AEPS):&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the customer has to approach a business correspondent (BC), use his Aadhaar number and biometrics which the BC shares with NPCI, which checks the ID with UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India) to confirm the customer’s identity . It also checks the funds in the connected account and allows the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for merchant payments where the merchant will download the merchant payments app of his bank, authenticate the customer through his biometrics and Aadhaar number and initiate a pull transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>