<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी 2.0&#39; के लिए पोर्टल बना रहा I-T विभाग</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/it-department-building-portal-for-operation-clean-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/it-department-building-portal-for-operation-clean-money/</guid>
      <description>केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ऐसे लोगों की जांच के लिए एक खास पोर्टल बना रहा है, जिन्होंने अपनी घोषित आमदनी से कहीं ज्यादा जमा किए हैं या बड़ी खरीदारियां की हैं। सीबीडीटी यह कदम ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत उठा रहा है। उस अभियान को नोटबंदी के मद्देनजर काले धन पर लगाम कसने के लिए शुरू किया गया था।
यह प्रस्ताव प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी के सामने राजस्व विभाग की हालिया समीक्षा बैठक में रखा गया था। चर्चा की जानकारी रखने वाले एक उच्च अधिकारी ने ईटी को बताया, &amp;lsquo;हम एक पोर्टल पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो खास इसी मकसद के लिए होगा।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह उन लोगों के लिहाज से विकसित किया जाएगा, जिनकी पहचान ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत हुई थी।&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9GB Free Data: Vodafone&#39;s Latest Offer In Response To Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</guid>
      <description>Since Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September, incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Vodafone is also currently offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.
Vodafone is giving 9 GB data free to customers in a special scheme, its latest offer to counter Reliance Jio which has come up with aggressive tariff plans. &amp;ldquo;Thank you for making us a 200 million strong family!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data leak: Now govt agencies will safeguard your personal info</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</guid>
      <description>The linking of Aadhaar — the 12-digit unique identification number for Indian residents is about to become safer as new rules put the onus on government departments and agencies to safeguard personal data or information held by them.
Departments handling the data will have to ensure that end-users are made aware of the data usage and collection and their consent is taken either in writing or electronically, according to new guidelines issued by the government for security of personal data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM will now allow you to make payments via Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app will now allow users to send and receive money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number.
This comes shortly after the government announced the Aadhaar Pay which would allow any person with their Aadhaar number linked to a bank account, can make and receive payment electronically.
At the time, IT minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said that BHIM would be able to make Aadhar Payments any biometric authentication, as indicated by this Economic Times report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.
Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Reminds On Cash Transaction Limit. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-reminds-on-cash-transaction-limit-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-reminds-on-cash-transaction-limit-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Under Section 269ST of the Income Tax Act, accepting cash of Rs 2 lakh or more by any individual is restricted.
As an effort to check corruption and a further push towards digital payments, the government has capped the cash transactions at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1, 2017. Under Section 269ST of the Income Tax Act, accepting cash of Rs 2 lakh or more by any individual is restricted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Call Drop Problem: No More Tricks, Telecom Minister Warns Operators</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</guid>
      <description>Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement
Refusing to lower his guard on the issue of call drops, Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement, which leaves no room for any manipulation. &amp;ldquo;We are looking at every aspect of call drop. No trick will work in this case,&amp;rdquo; Sinha told Press Trust of India in an interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIC Announces Massive Dividend Hike, Bonuses For Shareholders </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-announces-massive-dividend-hike-bonuses-for-shareholders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-announces-massive-dividend-hike-bonuses-for-shareholders/</guid>
      <description>LIC has been able to maintain solvency ratio of 154.65 per cent against the requirement of 150 per cent.
With higher profits from its huge investment portfolio, Life Insurance Corporation (LIC) has decided to pay 40 per cent higher bonuses and dividends to the government and its customers, respectively, in 2016-17. The Corporation has allocated Rs 47,387.44 crore as reversionary bonuses with profit to policyholders and paid Rs 2,494.08 crore to the government towards its share of surplus on within the country business, against Rs 34,207.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile number will be deactivated if not linked with Aadhaar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mobile-number-will-deactivated-not-linked-aadhaar-card-heres-can-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mobile-number-will-deactivated-not-linked-aadhaar-card-heres-can-link/</guid>
      <description>The government had in March 2017, had announced that Aadhaar-based e-KYC (know your customer) will be made mandatory for mobile phone connections. The department of telecommunications (DoT) had then ordered all mobile operators to verify the details of the existing customers by using their unique Aadhaar identity number and biometric details by early 2018. Aadhaar-based e-KYC will also be made compulsory for customers who have to get new SIM cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.
The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said. The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.
HIGHLIGHTS  Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1 The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent  The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI में है आपका अकाउंट, अब इन खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-are-now-exempt-from-keeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-holders-are-now-exempt-from-keeping/</guid>
      <description>एसबीआई ने सरकारी नौकरी करने वालों को भी राहत दी है। और ऐसे अकाउंट होल्डर्स को अब न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस नहीं रखना होगा।
देश के सबसे बड़े सरकारी बैंक स्टेट बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (SBI) ने अपने यहां खाता रखने वाले ग्राहकों को बड़ी राहत दी है। SBI ने कई प्रकार के खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस ना रखने पर वसूलने वाले चार्ज को हटा दिया है। अब ग्राहक इन खातों में मिनिमम बैलेंस नहीं भी रखेंगे तो उन्हें किसी भी प्रकार का शुल्क नहीं देना पड़ेगा। एसबीआई ने ट्वीट कर इस फैसले की जानकारी दी है। एसबीआई के ट्वीट के मुताबिक अब छोटी बचत खातों, बेसिक बचत खातों में मंथली एवरेज बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं है। इसके अलावा प्रधानमंत्री जन धन अकाउंट योजना के तहत खोले गये खातों में भी न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस रखने की जरूरत नहीं है। एसबीआई ने सरकारी नौकरी करने वालों को भी राहत दी है। और ऐसे अकाउंट होल्डर्स को अब न्यूनत्तम बैलेंस नहीं रखना होगा। एसबीआई ने सभी कॉरपोरेट सैलरी रखने वालों को भी ये सुविधा दी है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI acts against 50 illegal websites</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</guid>
      <description>It came to the notice of UIDAI that websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services.
Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) has ensured that 12 websites and 12 mobile applications available on the Google Playstore are shut down and has directed to close down 26 more such fraudulent and illegal websites/applications.
It came to the notice of UIDAI that these websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services such as downloading online Aadhaar card, providing status of Aadhaar generation, PVC Aadhaar Card, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.
“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ATMs Are Going Dry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</guid>
      <description>1: The ATM expansion era is over. ATM extensions will no longer be part of future banking growth, and future ATMs may well be of the mobile kind focused only on rural cash deliveries. But even here, the growth will be limited. Standalone ATM companies may have a future, but only because banks may choose to outsource all their existing networks to them so that they can focus on growing the digital business themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>इस साल 20000 लोगों को नौकरी देंगे: इन्फोसिस</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/only-400-people-asked-to-leave-will-hire-20000-this-year-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/only-400-people-asked-to-leave-will-hire-20000-this-year-says/</guid>
      <description>इन्फोसिस के सीओओ यूबी प्रवीण राव ने कहा कि भारी पैमाने पर नौकरियां कम होने की बात अतिश्योक्ति है। उन्होंने कहा कि कंपनी की योजना इस साल 20,000 लोगों को नौकरी देने की है। राव ने कहा कि इन्फोसिस काफी नौकरियां पैदा कर रहा है और टेक्नॉलजी आधारित परिवर्तनों से इन्फोसिस जैसी कंपनियों के लिए नए अवसर पैदा हो रहे हैं।
उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;छंटनी को लेकर फैली अफवाहों पर अगर बात करें तो यह परफॉर्मेंस आधारित है और हम हर साल ऐसा करते हैं। ऐसे लोगों की संख्या 300-400 होगी जो कि बीते वर्षों की तरह ही है।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने हालांकि इन्फोसिस के सह-संस्थापक एनआर नारायणमूर्ति की उस बात पर प्रतिक्रिया देने से मना कर दिया जिसमें उन्होंने कहा था कि अगर कंपनियों के सीनियर एग्जिक्यूटिव्स अपनी कटी सैलरी लें और ट्रेनिंग एंप्लॉयी में निवेश करें तो नौकरियों को सुरक्षित रखना संभव है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>कालेधन के खिलाफ सरकार का नया अभियान, ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी वेबसाइट लॉन्च</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-website-launched-tax-defaulters-to-be-rated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/operation-clean-money-website-launched-tax-defaulters-to-be-rated/</guid>
      <description>कालेधन के खिलाफ सरकार एक नया अभियान चला रही है। वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने इसके लिए आज (16 मई) ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी वेबसाइट लॉन्च कर दी है। इस पर सरकार छापेमारी की रिपोर्ट पेश करेगी। साथ ही वेबसाइट पर डिफॉल्टर्स को ज्यादा रिस्क से लेकर बहुत कम रिस्क की अलग अलग श्रेणियों में रखा जाएगा। सेंट्रल बोर्ड ऑफ डायरेक्ट टैक्स (सीबीडीटी) के चैयरमेन सुशील चंद्र ने बताया कि हम लोगों की टैक्स नहीं देने की आदत को बदलना चाहते हैं। उन्होंने कहा कि वेबसाइट पर उस प्रक्रिया के बारे में भी जानकारी दी जाएगी, जिसके द्वारा टैक्स डिफॉल्टर की पहचान की गई होगी। हाई रिस्क, मीडियम रिस्क, कम रिस्क और बहुत कम रिस्क की श्रेणी के मुताबिक ही डिफॉल्टर पर कार्रवाई की जाएगी। सूत्रों के मुताबिक हाई रिस्क वाले लोगों और ग्रुप पर सर्च, जब्ती और सीधे जांच जैसी कार्रवाई का सामना करेंगे। वहीं मीडियम रिस्क वालों को मैसेज और ईमेल से सूचित किया जाएगा। इसके अलावा कम रिस्क और</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जीएसटी: 2,500 जरूरी वस्तुओं के दाम तय करेंगे वित्त मंत्री</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/finance-minister-to-list-possible-prices-of-2500-goods-in-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/finance-minister-to-list-possible-prices-of-2500-goods-in-gst/</guid>
      <description>गुड्स ऐंड सर्विसेज टैक्स (जीएसटी) लागू होने के बाद वस्तुओं की कीमतें नियंत्रित रखने के लिए वित्त मंत्रालय सामान्य जरूरत के 2,000-2,500 सामानों और सेवाओं की कीमतें तय करने पर काम कर रहा है। सरकार इस बात पर भी गौर कर रही है कि अभी उनकी कीमतें क्या हैं और जीएसटी लागू होने के बाद क्या हो जाएंगी। सूत्रों ने बताया कि यह डेटा इस महीने के आखिर तक रिलीज कर दिया जाएगा और इसमें सभी बड़े शहरों को समाहित किया जाएगा। एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम छोटे शहरों और ग्रामीण इलाकों के स्तर तक कीमतें कम नहीं कर सकते, हालांकि प्राइस चार्ज सांकेतिक होगा।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जून से SBI इन सेवाओं के लिए वसूलेगा एक्‍स्‍ट्रा चार्ज, ये होंगे बदलाव</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-customers-bank-will-charge-extra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-customers-bank-will-charge-extra/</guid>
      <description>देश का सबसे बड़ा बैंक एसबीआई 1 जून से अपनी कई सेवाओं के शुल्‍क में बढ़ोतरी करने जा रहा है। पहली जून से अगर आप एसबीआई जाकर कटे-फटे नोट बदलवाते हैं या एक सीमा से अधिक बार पैसे निकालते हैं तो एसबीआई आपसे चार्ज वसूलेगा। बेसिक सेविंग बैंक डिपॉजिट अकाउंट के ग्राहकों को पैसे निकालने, नए कार्ड इश्यू करवाने जैसी सुविधाएं के लिए भी 1 जून से चार्ज देना होगा।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रूपे क्रेडिट कार्ड करेगा जारी, मेट्रो-बस का पेमेंट भी कार्ड से</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupay-credit-cards-soon-says-chief-hota/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupay-credit-cards-soon-says-chief-hota/</guid>
      <description>नैशनल पेमेंट कॉर्पोरेशन ऑफ इंडिया (NPCI) जल्द ही रूपे क्रेडिट कार्ड जारी करेगा। NPCI ने इसके लिए कुछ बैंकों के साथ हाथ मिलाया है। नैशनल पेमेंट कॉर्पोरेशन ऑफ इंडिया देश में डिजिटल ट्रांजैक्शंस की नोडल एजेंसी है।
NPCI के प्रबंध निदेशक और मुख्य कार्यकारी अधिकारी एपी होता ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमारे क्रेडिट कार्ड जल्द ही जारी किए जाएंगे। ये रूपे क्रेडिट कार्ड होंगे। कुछ बैंकों के साथ प्रयोग के तौर पर यह काम चल रहा है। प्रायोगिक तौर पर करीब 7200 लेन-देन हुए हैं।&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>