<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Loan Or Credit Card Loan: Which One To Go For?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a phone call and money gets credited to your account within 2-3 days. Yes, it is this simple today to get credit card loans. Though credit card loans are easier to get, they come at a higher cost than personal loans from banks. So you need to know clearly when to take a credit card loan or a personal loan. Even if the credit card company charges you the same rate of interest as that of personal loan, the cost for servicing credit card loan is higher. Along with processing fees and pre-closure charges, credit card companies also charge service tax on the interest you pay on your loan every month, which is 15 per cent currently (service tax@14%+ Swach Bharat Cess@ 0.5%+ Krishi Klyan Cess @ 0 .5%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you take a personal loan of Rs 1 lakh from a bank at 14 per cent interest for 24 months, then your first month instalment will be Rs 4,802, in which interest component will be Rs 1,166.66 and principal repayment will be Rs 3635.33. If you take the same loan on your credit card at the same interest rate, in the first month you have to pay Rs 4,976.99 which is Rs 175 more than what you pay on a bank loan. This is because of the service tax of Rs 175 on interest of Rs 1,166.66. This service tax is also applicable when you convert your purchases on credit card to equated monthly instalment (EMI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are some instances, where credit card loans are preferred over bank personal loans. If the amount you are opting for is less (less than Rs 50,000) and the tenure you want is less than 1 year, then credit card loans become more useful (even with higher cost) because banks generally do not offer personal loans below Rs 50,000 and for less than one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit cards even offer loans even for six months and for small amounts as low as Rs 10,000. If your requirement for funds is for a short term and you think you can repay it faster, then it is worth going for a credit card loan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks To Start Charging For Person To Person Payments On UPI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI is charging Rs 5 per transaction of up to Rs 1 lakh, Rs 15 for transactions between Rs 1-2 lakh and Rs 25 for those between Rs 2 lakh and Rs 5 lakh, while HDFC Bank is proposing Rs 3 for transactions of up to Rs 25,000 and Rs 5 for those between Rs 25,000 and Rs 1 lakh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly two years after operationalisation of the Unified Payment Interface (UPI), banks have started moving to charge for peer-to-peer payments on the new platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India has came out with charges with effect from June 1, while the second largest private sector lender HDFC Bank has also gone public with its rate structure which will be effective July 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So far, no bank is charging for UPI transactions but at the same time it is at their discretion to levy a reasonable fee towards Person to Person (P2P) transactions for UPI and IMPS,&amp;rdquo; National Payments Corporation of India&amp;rsquo;s chief operating officer Dilip Asbe said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior NPCI official explained that worldover, charges are levied for such transactions and added that in case of UPI at merchant transactions it is the merchant who pays while for P2P, it is the sender who has to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the transaction fees front, the critical aspect to be examined is whether there are enough number of transactions happening on UPI which establish a maturity of the platform and also the reasonableness of charges, the official added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UPI platform is averaging around one crore transactions with a value of Rs 2,900 crore per month, the NPCI official said, adding the number of transactions needs to be at least 2-3 crore per month for the charges to set in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NPCI official said there may be a review on the subject, saying there can be a meeting with bankers which can be called in the next two months to assess the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was, however, not immediately clear if the P2P transactions on the BHIM App launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, will also be chargeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, SBI&amp;rsquo;s deputy managing director Manju Agarwal acknowledged that the bank has put out a circular on UPI charges on its website, but promised to withdraw it soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are not charging for UPI transactions. The circular will be removed,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An HDFC Bank spokesperson was not reachable for comment, but a senior official pointed out that the charges are applicable from July 10 and there may be a review based on the outcome of such a meeting with NPCI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billed as a game changing platform in the Indian banking space, UPI was launched in April 2015 and operationalised in August same year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government To Roll Out Aadhaar Pay For Cashless Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-roll-aadhaar-pay-cashless-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-roll-aadhaar-pay-cashless-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government will soon roll out Aadhaar Pay service that will enable people to make and receive payments using their Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are going to start Aadhaar Pay. With this people will not require to carry their phone for payments. They can visit any merchant, share their Aadhaar number and verify themselves using biometrics to pay and receive money,” Electronics and IT Minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, 14 banks have come on board for Aadhaar Pay and the service will be launched soon, Prasad told reporters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are in talks with other banks too. The service will be launched very soon,” he informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the Minister said, Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM), the common platform for making quick payments using the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), has also been integrated with Aadhaar Enabled Payment System on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 111 crore people in the country have Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are 49 crore bank accounts linked to Aadhaar. Every month 2 crore accounts are being seeded with Aadhaar,” Prasad said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Fine If Your SBI Account Has No Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest lender, has decided to increase manifold the minimum balance required for maintaining savings account from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Savings bank account holders of SBI and its five associates - which will merge with it on April 1 - will have to maintain the monthly balance or else they will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs 100 (in metro cities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India has 31 crore savings bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, the monthly average balance (MAB) for a savings bank account is Rs 500 without facility of cheque book and Rs 1,000 with cheque book across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank has now decided to fix separate MABs for &amp;lsquo;metro&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;urban&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;semi-urban&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;rural&amp;rsquo; areas from the beginning of next financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benchmark for MAB and penalties are likely to be followed by other public sector banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance for metro branches will be Rs 5,000 and penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance will be between Rs 50 and Rs 100. For urban and semi-urban branches, the monthly average balance has been fixed at Rs 3,000 and Rs 2,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of rural branches, the minimum balance has been fixed at Rs 1,000. Breach of MAB will attract a penalty ranging between Rs 20 and Rs 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five associates banks of SBI - State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur (SBBJ), State Bank of Mysore (SBM), State Bank of Travancore (SBT), State Bank of Patiala (SBP) and State Bank of Hyderabad (SBH) - will merge with the parent on April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1. Announced in a circular on the SBI website on Thursday morning, the revisions initially created confusion among customers over news that all cash withdrawals through ATM will now be charged at Rs. 25 per transaction. The bank later clarified that the Rs 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through SBI’s mobile wallet app “State Bank Buddy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an emailed statement to NDTV Profit, an SBI spokesperson clarified that a limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applied to the Basic Savings Banks deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal Saving Bank accounts will continue to get 8 free ATM transactions (5 SBI ATMs + 3 other bank ATMs) in metros &amp;amp; 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 SBI ATM + 5 Other Bank ATMs) free, the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from ATM charges, SBI also  revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers. Here are some of the other key changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh, Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; Going forward SBI said it will charge 2 rupees for every soiled note on exchange of more than 20 notes or if the total value of exchanged notes is above Rs 5,000 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs 30 plus service tax for a 10 leaf cheque book, Rs 75 with service tax for 25 leaf cheque book and Rs 150 plus service tax for a 50 leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issue of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only Rupay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI To Use Aadhaar For Verification In Recruitment Process</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-to-use-aadhaar-for-verification-in-recruitment-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-to-use-aadhaar-for-verification-in-recruitment-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India or SBI plans to introduce Aadhaar to verify the identity of candidates across its recruitment processes effective July 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI plans to introduce Aadhaar to verify the identity of candidates across its recruitment processes effective July 1. India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI, in a notice dated June 2, said: &amp;ldquo;Ascertaining the identities of candidates is critical for fair conduct of recruitment process and prevention of impersonation.&amp;rdquo; The Aadhaar number will be used at discretion of the bank to match the biometric information taken at the time of the examination, interview, medical fitness test or reporting for joining with that stored on the Aadhaar server to establish the identity of the candidate, the bank further said. Aadhaar is a 12-digit unique number that identifies residents based on their biometrics. Aadhaar data is managed by UIDAI or Unique Identification Authority of India in its data centres located in different parts of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the full text of SBI&amp;rsquo;s notice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India (SBI) propose to introduce the scheme of verifying the identity of candidates applying for all its recruitment processes through Aadhaar cards w.e.f. 1 st July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ascertaining the identities of candidates is critical for fair conduct of recruitment process and prevention of impersonation. The provisions of Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act, 2016 (the Aadhaar Act 2016) and the Regulations under the Act have come into effect on various dates as published in the Official Gazette. Pursuant to Section 57 of the Aadhaar Act 2016, SBI proposes to verify the identity of the candidates through Aadhaar number in all its recruitment processes w.e.f. 1st July 2017. Accordingly, while applying for appointment in SBI it will be mandatory to furnish the 12 digit Aadhaar No. (or 28 digit Aadhaar enrolment ID in case the Aadhaar has been applied for, but not received). The Aadhaar number will be used at discretion of SBI to match the biometric information taken through biometric attendance system at the time of the examination/ interview/ medical fitness test/ reporting for joining with that stored on the Aadhaar server to establish the identity of the candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above provision is applicable in all States and Union Territories of India except the States of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir, Meghalaya and Assam. Applicants from these States may use voter ID, passport, driving license or any other valid document, as may be specified by SBI in the relevant recruitment notice, as proof of identity for future recruitments in SBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI Launches Three New Mobile Apps For Voice, Data Quality Tracking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aiming to protect consumer interests, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Monday launched three new mobile applications and a web portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring. The app will help mobile phone users rate their experience about voice call quality in real time and help TRAI gather customer experience data along with network data, an official TRAI statement said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is available on Google Playstore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulator has launched new version of TRAI MySpeed App that will enable the regulator to obtain test-driven data from users in all service areas, without any action by the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These tests would be brief, very infrequent for a specific device, free to the user and anonymous. The user may also do a test and submit the results, as before,&amp;rdquo; the regulator said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also launched DND 2.0 App (Do Not Disturb) Services App that will help smartphone users to register their mobile number under DND to avoid unsolicited commercial communication/ telemarketing calls/ SMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, TRAI has also launched a new website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>your Aadhaar is safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amidst concerns regarding Aadhaar data leak, a look at how the unique identification system actually adheres to the principles of privacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy and data protection concerns have become serious in a digital world due to ease of search and aggregation, with or without Aadhaar. Type any name in Google and it will throw up thousands of results, giving data/information publicly available. Hence, the responsibility falls on organisations which collect data from individuals to protect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a state government puts bank account details of MNREGA workers or the PAN details on its portal then one doesn’t need an Aadhaar number to find any information – simply the name will do. There may be multiple people with that name. But so what! You can always find the person with their other attributes, if available publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, each data custodian must become conscious of their responsibility to protect their customer’s data. Aadhaar has been designed as a digital identity platform, which is inclusive, unique and authenticable to participate in any digital transaction. This has transformed service delivery in our country, providing huge convenience to citizens and substantial reduction of leakages. Direct benefit transfer, subscription to various services and authentication at the point of service delivery are some benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UID project has been aware of privacy and data protection issues since the very beginning and has taken every step, as per the best practices available in the world, to ensure they are not violated. The general law on privacy is beyond the ambit of the UIDAI. With the Aadhaar Act in place, let us discuss the provisions relating to privacy and data protection in the Act.
UIDAI’s strategy document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many countries, India does not have a law on privacy. The law relating to it has been evolved by the courts through various judicial pronouncements over the years. Interestingly, the former UIDAI chairman, Nandan Nilekani, had written to the PM as early as in May 2010 suggesting a need for the privacy law. The government prepared a draft bill on Right to Privacy but it was not turned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>कम दूरी के लिए शताब्दी एक्सप्रेस का किराया घटाएगा रेलवे</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/short-run-train-fares-to-compete-with-road-transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/short-run-train-fares-to-compete-with-road-transport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;इंडियन रेलवे कमाई बढ़ाने के लिए तरह-तरह की जोर आजमाइश कर रहा है। इसी क्रम में अब सुपरफास्ट ट्रेन शताब्दी एक्सप्रेस से कम दूरी के सफर का किराया घटाया जा रहा है। फाइनैंशल एक्सप्रेस की खबर के मुताबिक, रेलवे नहीं चाहता है कि कम दूरी के यात्री ट्रेन छोड़कर सड़क के रास्ते यात्रा करें और उसे नुकसान उठाना पड़े। भारतीय रेल ने यह फैसला ऐसे हो दो ट्रेनों में इस प्रयोग की सफलता के बाद लिया। दोनों ट्रेनों में कम दूरी की यात्रा के लिए किराया घटाने से रेलवे को जबर्दस्त फायदा हुआ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऐसा देखा गया है कि शताब्दी ट्रेनों के रूटों पर पड़नेवाले ऐसे स्टेशनों पर यात्रियों की आवाजाही बहुत कम होती है, जहां से ट्रेन नहीं खुलती है या उसका सफर खत्म नहीं होता। ऐसी जगहों पर लोग ट्रेनों की बजाय एसी बसों से यात्रा करना पसंद करते हैं। बीच के इन स्टेशनों के लिए बस का कम किराया यात्रियों को आकर्षित करता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रेलवे बोर्ड के सदस्य (यातायात) मोहम्मद जमशेद ने फाइनैंशल एक्सप्रेस को बताया, &amp;lsquo;हमने देखा कि एसी बसें 430 रुपये के करीब चार्ज करती हैं जबकि शताब्दी का किराया 470 रुपये के आसपास है। इस वजह से छोटी दूरी के महज 30 प्रतिशत यात्री ही ट्रेनों से सफर करते हैं। इसके मद्देनजर हमने किराया घटाकर 350 रुपये करने का फैसला किया और अब करीब-करीब सभी 100 प्रतिशत यात्री ट्रेनों से सफर करने लगे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा कि अजमेर और जयपुर के बीच एवं चेन्नै और बेंगलुरु के बीच दो स्टेशनों पर हमें पता चला कि एसी बसों का किराया 430 रुपये है जबकि शताब्दी का 470 रुपये। इसलिए, हमने शताब्दी का किराया घटाकर 350 रुपये कर दिया और यात्रियों को लुभाने की दिशा में यह बहुत कारगर साबित हुआ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रेल छोड़ सड़क मार्ग अपनाने की बढ़ती प्रवृत्ति इंडियन रेलवे के लिए चिंता की एक बड़ी वजह है। 1981 से माल ढुलाई में रेलवे की हिस्सेदारी 62 प्रतिशत से घटकर 36 प्रतिशत पर पहुंच गई है। शनिवार को रेल मंत्री सुरेश प्रभु ने कहा कि देश में रेलवे को और इनोवेटिव बनाने के लिए कुछ प्रॉजेक्ट्स का खाका खींचा गया है, लेकिन केंद्रीय मदद के बावजूद फंड की भारी कमी है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>खातों की कम जानकारी देने वाले करदाता जांच के दायरे में</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/1-6-lakh-taxpayers-under-scrutiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने सत्यापन के लिए 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान की है, जिसमें 1.58 लाख करदाता ऐसे शामिल हैं, जिन्होंने पिछले दिनों अपने खातों की आंशिक घोषणा की थी। नोटबंदी के बाद इंकम टैक्स विभाग को बैंकों द्वारा दायर वित्तीय लेनदेन के बयान (एसएफटी) सहित विभिन्न स्रोतों से कई अहम जानकारी मिली। आईटी विभाग ने कहा कि इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने 1.58 लाख करदाताओं से संबंधित 3.71 लाख नए खातों की पहचान की है, जिन्होंने पहले अपने अकाउंट के बारे में जानकारी दी थी। पहले 18 लाख मामलों के अलावा, 5.68 लाख नए मामलों की पहचान ई-वेरिफेकेशन से की गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इंकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट पहले से उप्लब्ध डेटा की मदद से विश्लेषण कर रहा है। इस डेटा की मदद से ई-वेरिफिकेशन के लिए नए मामलों की पहचान हो चुकी है। 31 जनवरी को आई-टी विभाग द्वारा शुरू किए गए &amp;lsquo;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी&amp;rsquo; के तहत 17.92 लाख लोगों को एसएमएस और ई-मेल भेजे गए हैं, जिन्होंने 10 नवंबर से 30 दिसंबर के बीच 5 लाख और उससे ज्यादा पैसे जमा किए हैं। इनमें से 9 .72 लाख लोगों ने नकदी जमा के स्रोतों पर जवाब दिया है। विभाग ने उन मामलों में वेरिफिकेशन बंद करने का निर्णय लिया है, जहां नकदी के स्रोत का पूरा ब्यौरा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;करदाताओं ने करीब 2.8 9 लाख करोड़ रुपये के नकदी जमा से जुड़े 13.33 लाख खातों के लिए जवाब दे दिए हैं। ऑनलाइन प्रतिक्रियाओं का आंकलन कर खातों की सही जानकारी देने वालों के मामलों में आगे कोई कार्रवाई नहीं की जाएगी। विभाग ने दो विशेष डेटा ऐनालिटिकल एजेंसियों और एक व्यावसायिक प्रक्रिया प्रबंधन एजेंसी को बड़ी मात्रा में नकद जमा के डेटा का विश्लेषण करने, करदाताओं की अनुपालन स्थिति और रिपोर्टिंग संस्थाओं का पता लगाने की जिम्मेदारी दी है। नकदी जमा के सोर्स के रूप में नकद बिक्री का दावा करने वाले पेट्रोल पंप व्यापारियों और संपत्ति खरीददारों जैसे व्यापारों की विस्तृत जांच की जाएगी, जिनका कैश सेल उनके नकद जमा की तुलना में ज्यादा पाया गया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>यूपी: 10वीं पास करने वाली लड़कियों को 10,000 रुपए देगी योगी सरकार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/up-govt-announces-rs-10000-each-to-one-lakh-schoolgirls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/up-govt-announces-rs-10000-each-to-one-lakh-schoolgirls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;यूपी में 10वीं और 12वीं के नतीजे घोषित होने बाकी है। परिक्षार्थियों में रिजल्ट को लेकर बहुत उत्सुकता है। इस बीच यूपी के योगी सरकार ने हाईस्कूल की लड़कियों को खुशखबरी सुनाई है। एएनआई के मुताबिक राज्य के उप-मुख्यमंत्री दिनेश शर्मा ने 10वीं कक्षा में पास होने वाली एक लाख लड़कियों को 10,000 रुपए देने&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;का ऐलान किया है। 10वीं की बोर्ड परीक्षा के रिजल्ट को लेकर कयास लगाए जा रहे हैं कि नतीजे 9 जून को आ सकते हैं। इसके साथ ही कहा जा रहा है कि 10वीं से पहले 12वीं के रिजल्ट घोषित हो सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि यूपी में 60 लाख के करीब स्टूडेंट्स बोर्ड परीक्षाओं के रिजल्ट का इंतजार कर रहे हैं। इस बार 10वीं में 34,04,471 और 12वीं में 26,24,681 लोगों ने भाग लिया है। कुल 60,29,152 परीक्षार्थी शामिल हुए। इनमें रेलगुर और प्राइवेट विद्यार्थी सम्मिलित हैं। विधानसभा चुनावों को देखते हुए इस बार परीक्षाएं&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देरी से शुरू हुईं थी। साथ ही परीक्षार्थियों की संख्या अधिक होने की वजह से भी रिजल्ट आने में देरी हो सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>वोडाफोन लाया पांच रुपए का र‍िचार्ज</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-ramzan-special-pack-at-rs-5-unlimited-data-and-voice-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-ramzan-special-pack-at-rs-5-unlimited-data-and-voice-calling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;इस स्कीम को लॉन्च करते हुए पश्चिम उत्तर प्रदेश और उत्तराखंड के कारोबार प्रमुख दिलीप कुमार गंटा ने कहा कि रमजान का महीना हमारे लिए बहुत ही अहम है।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दूरसंचार कंपनी वोडाफोन ने रमजान के मौके पर पश्चिमी उत्तर प्रदेश और उत्तराखंड के उपभोक्ताओं के लिए स्पेशल स्कीम लॉन्च की है। स्कीम के तहत उपभोक्ता अनलिमिटेड लोकल और एसटीडी कॉल के साथ मुफ्त डेटा का भी लाभ उठा पाएंगे। रमजान स्पेशल पैक में 2जी उपभोक्ता पांच रुपये का रिचार्ज कराकर एक घंटे के लिए
अनलिमिटेड डेटा का लाभ उठा सकते हैं, जबकि 3जी उपभोक्ता 19 रुपये का रिचार्ज कराकर एक घंटे के लिए अनलिमिटेड डेटा का इस्तेमाल कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रमजान पैक में 28 दिनों की वैधता वाला भी स्कीम है। इसके लिए 2जी उपभोक्ता को 253 रुपये का रिचार्ज कराना होगा। वहीं 3जी उपभोक्ता 345 रुपये का रिचार्ज कराकर इस स्कीम का लाभ उठा सकते हैं। बता दें कि 28 दिनों के अनलिमिटेड डेटा पैक में उपभोक्ताओं को अनलिमिटेड लोकल और एसटीडी मिनट भी मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस स्कीम को लॉन्च करते हुए पश्चिम उत्तर प्रदेश और उत्तराखंड के कारोबार प्रमुख दिलीप कुमार गंटा ने कहा कि रमजान का महीना हमारे लिए बहुत ही अहम है। इसलिए हम उपभोक्ताओं की जरूरतों को ध्यान में रखते हुए ये स्कीम लेकर आए हैं। रमजान के इस मौके पर उपभोक्ता नए डेटा और कॉलिंग पैक्स के साथ अपने परिवारजनों और दोस्तों के साथ जुड़े रहेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गौरतलब है कि अभी कुछ दिन पहले ही वोडाफोन ने अपने उपभोक्ताओं को 45GB फ्री 4G डेटा देने का ऑफर निकाला था। यह ऑफर प्रीपेड और पोस्टपेड के नए और पुराने दोनों तरह के उपभोक्ताओं के लिए है। इस ऑफर को वोडाफोन ने ऑनलाइन शॉपिंग वेबसाइट अमेजन के साथ मिलकर निकाला है। इस ऑफर का फायदा उठाने के लिए अमेजन से नया 4G स्मार्टफोन खरीदना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह ऑफर किन स्मार्टफोन्स के खरीदने पर मिल रहा है इसकी लिस्ट अमेजन पर दी गई है। इस ऑफर का फायदा उठाने के लिए 30 जून तक अमेजन से 4जी स्मार्टफोन खरीदना होगा। यह ऑफर 11 मई से शुरू हो गया है। कंपनी ने इसके लिए कुछ शर्तें भी रखी हैं। इस ऑफर का फायदा उठाने के लिए एक महीने के लिए कम से कम 1GB डेटा का रिचार्ज कराना होगा। उसके साथ 9GB डेटा फ्री मिलेगा। 9जीबी एक्स्ट्रा डेटा पांच बार रिचार्ज कराने पर मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>