<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Group Issues New Threat</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-as-cyberattack-eases-hacking-group-issues-new-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-as-cyberattack-eases-hacking-group-issues-new-threat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shadow Brokers, the group that has taken credit for that leak, threatened on Tuesday to release more recent code to enable hackers to break into the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used computers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governments turned their attention to possible new wave of cyber threats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber extortion campaign has infected more than 300,000 computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The attack has caused most damage in Russia, Taiwan and Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments turned their attention to a possible new wave of cyber threats on Tuesday after the group that leaked U.S. hacking tools used to launch the global WannaCry &amp;ldquo;ransomware&amp;rdquo; attack warned it would release more malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fast-spreading cyber extortion campaign, which has infected more than 300,000 computers worldwide since Friday, eased for second day on Tuesday, but the identity and motive of its creators remain unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack includes elements that belong to the U.S. National Security Agency and were leaked online last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shadow Brokers, the group that has taken credit for that leak, threatened on Tuesday to release more recent code to enable hackers to break into the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used computers, software and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog post written by the group promised from June to release tools every month to anyone willing to pay for access to some of the tech world&amp;rsquo;s biggest commercial secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also threatened to dump data from banks using the SWIFT international money transfer network and from Russian, Chinese, Iranian or North Korean nuclear and missile programs. &amp;ldquo;More details in June,&amp;rdquo; it promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spread of the WannaCry attack - which encrypts a user&amp;rsquo;s data and demands a &amp;ldquo;ransom&amp;rdquo; be paid electronically to free it up again - slowed to a trickle on Tuesday, with few, isolated examples being reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Canada, the Universite de Montreal was hit, with 120 of the French-language university&amp;rsquo;s 8,300 computers affected, according to a university spokeswoman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no new, major incidents in the United States. Fewer than 10 U.S. organizations have reported attacks to the Department of Homeland Security since Friday, a U.S. official told reporters on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack has caused most damage in Russia, Taiwan and Ukraine, according to Czech security firm Avast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States likely avoided greater harm as the attack targeted older versions of Microsoft Corp&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, and more U.S. users have licensed, up-to-date, patched versions of the software, compared to other regions of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Homeland Security began an &amp;ldquo;aggressive awareness campaign&amp;rdquo; to alert the tech industry to the importance of installing the patch that Microsoft issued in March that protected users from the vulnerability exploited by the attack, a U.S. official working on the attack told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft said on Tuesday it was aware of Shadow Brokers&amp;rsquo; most recent claim and that its security teams monitor potential threats in order to &amp;ldquo;help us prioritize and take appropriate action.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft President and Chief Legal Officer Brad Smith said earlier this week the WannaCry attack used elements stolen from the NSA. The U.S. government has not commented directly on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;north-korea-link-probed&#34;&gt;North Korea Link Probed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyber security researchers around the world have said they have found evidence that could link North Korea with the WannaCry cyber attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A researcher from South Korea&amp;rsquo;s Hauri Labs said on Tuesday their own findings matched those of Symantec and Kaspersky Lab, who said on Monday that some code in an earlier version of the WannaCry software had also appeared in programs used by the Lazarus Group, identified by some researchers as a North Korea-run hacking operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is similar to North Korea&amp;rsquo;s backdoor malicious codes,&amp;rdquo; said Simon Choi, a senior researcher with Hauri who has done extensive research into North Korea&amp;rsquo;s hacking capabilities and advises South Korean police and National Intelligence Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Symantec and Kaspersky said it was too early to tell whether North Korea was involved in the attacks, based on the evidence that was published on Twitter by Google security researcher Neel Mehta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FireEye Inc, another large cyber security firm, said it was also investigating, but it was cautious about drawing a link to North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The similarities we see between malware linked to that group and WannaCry are not unique enough to be strongly suggestive of a common operator,&amp;rdquo; FireEye researcher John Miller said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. and European security officials told Reuters on condition of anonymity that it was too early to say who might be behind the attacks, but they did not rule out North Korea as a suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lazarus hackers, acting for impoverished North Korea, have been more brazen in their pursuit of financial gain than others, and have been blamed for the theft of $81 million from the Bangladesh central bank, according to some cyber security firms. The United States accused it of being behind a cyber attack on Sony Pictures in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Korea has denied being behind the Sony and banking attacks. North Korean officials were not immediately available for comment and its state media has been quiet about the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-information-to-share&#34;&gt;No Information To Share&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In China, foreign ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said she had no information to share, when asked about the origin of the attack and whether North Korea might be connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several Asian countries have been affected by the malware, although the impact has not been as widespread as some had feared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Malaysia, cyber security firm LE Global Services said it identified 12 cases so far, including a large government-linked corporation, a government-linked investment firm and an insurance company. It did not name any of the entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We may not see the real picture yet, as companies are not mandated to disclose security breaches to authorities in Malaysia,&amp;rdquo; said LE Global CEO Fong Choong Fook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The real situation may be serious. In one of the cases, the attack was traced back to early April.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s state media said on Tuesday more than 200 computers had been affected, but one of the country&amp;rsquo;s leading anti-virus companies, Bkav, later put the figure at 1,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taiwan Power Co. said that nearly 800 of its computers were affected, although these were used for administration, not for systems involved in electricity generation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Pension Scheme (NPS) Or Public Provident Fund (PPF): Which One To Pick?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-national-pension-scheme-nps-or-public-provident-fund-ppf-which-one-to-pick/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-national-pension-scheme-nps-or-public-provident-fund-ppf-which-one-to-pick/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although EPF is an option for salaried employees only, PPF is for all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public Provident Fund (PPF) and Provident Fund (PF) take centre stage whenever savings for retirement come to mind for most of us. Although EPF or Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund is for salaried employees only, PPF is for all. People have been investing in PPF - which provides secured return over the long term - for ages. However, the National Pension Scheme or NPS has been gaining lot of attention as a retirement savings product after the government provided additional tax deduction of Rs. 50,000 in Budget 2015-16. Under NPS, there are two types of accounts: Tier I and Tier II. While the Tier I account is non-withdrawable till the age of 60 except in specific situations, the Tier II account is a voluntary savings account. Subscribers to Tier II accounts can withdraw the money whenever they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the key differences between NPS and PPF:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-invest&#34;&gt;Who can invest?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PPF account can be opened by any Indian resident. One can also open a PPF account in the name of his or her minor children and can avail tax benefit on the contribution. However, an NPS account can be opened by Indian citizens above 18 years and less than 60 years of age. Non-resident Indians (NRIs) can also open an NPS account, but they cannot open a PPF account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;maturity&#34;&gt;Maturity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PPF account matures in 15 years. One can also extend this term after 15 years by a block of five years with or without making further contribution. However, in case of NPS, the maturity tenure is not fixed. You can contribute to the NPS account till the age of 60 years with an option to extend the investment to the age of 70 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;investment-limit&#34;&gt;Investment limit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One has to contribute a minimum Rs 500 to a PPF account annually with the maximum amount capped at Rs 1,50,000. A maximum 12 contributions per year are allowed in PPF accounts. However, in case of NPS, the minimum contribution required is Rs 6,000. There is no limit on contribution as long as it does not exceed 10 per cent of your salary, or 10 per cent of your gross total income in case of self-employed. But tax benefit will be available only on Rs 1.5 lakh under Section 80CCD(1) of the Income Tax Act, and an additional Rs 50,000 will be available under Section 80CCD(2) - a total tax benefit of up to Rs 2 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premature withdrawal/partial withdrawal: In case of PPF, partial withdrawals are allowed from the seventh year onwards with some limitation. One can also avail loan against his or her PPF account during the third and sixth financial years of opening the account with certain limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of NPS, after 10 years, subscribers become eligible for early, partial withdrawal under specific circumstance like children&amp;rsquo;s higher education or marriage, construction or purchase of house and treatment of critical illness (for self, spouse, children or dependant parents). But if you want to exit before retirement, you must use at least 80 per cent of the accumulated corpus to buy an annuity from a life insurance company including LIC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;investment-option&#34;&gt;Investment option&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of PPF, you do not have any discretion in deciding where to invest your money. However, in NPS, you can choose from a mix of three funds - equity funds, government securities fund and fixed income instruments other that government securities. A subscriber is allowed to invest up to 75 per cent in the equity fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;returns&#34;&gt;Returns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For PPF subscribers, interest rate is announced every quarter by the government. In case of NPS, returns are market-linked. &amp;ldquo;In our view, the potential of returns in a market-related investment like NPS is higher than of a guaranteed return instrument like PPF/PF. This is due to two reasons, one is the choice of equity exposure in NPS and secondly the component of professional fund management,&amp;rdquo; Manog Nagpal, CEO of Outlook Asia Capital, told NDTV Profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Mr Nagpal added: &amp;ldquo;PPF continues to be an attractive investment in itself, for those looking at zero volatility and a guarantee (in return). On a risk-adjusted basis, PPF returns though will be lower, will not be subject to the vagaries of the market.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tax-treatment&#34;&gt;Tax Treatment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PPF enjoys an EEE or &amp;lsquo;exempt, exempt, exempt&amp;rsquo; status, where the amount you contribute (up to Rs 1.5 lakh), the return you get and the maturity amount, all are tax exempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, NPS comes under an EET or &amp;lsquo;exempt, exempt, tax&amp;rsquo; tax structure. This means that contributions to NPS and the growth in corpus are not taxed but the lump sum withdrawn is partially taxed. Lump sum withdrawals above 40 per cent of the maturity amount are taxable in NPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;annuity&#34;&gt;Annuity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At maturity, you have to mandatorily purchase an annuity for at least 40 per cent of the accumulated wealth in case of NPS. But in case of a maturity amount less than Rs 2 lakh, you have the option of complete withdrawal. However, in case of PPF, you are not required to buy any annuity at the time of maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason NPS is purely a retirement savings scheme. You cannot use NPS for other purposes like children&amp;rsquo;s education, daughter&amp;rsquo;s marriage etc., which you can do with PPF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are certain limitations in NPS, it scores over PPF as a retirement savings scheme on various grounds, say financial planners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Notes Ban, 91 Lakh More Came Under Tax Net, Says Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/post-notes-ban-91-lakh-more-came-under-tax-net-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/post-notes-ban-91-lakh-more-came-under-tax-net-says/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post notes ban, there has been a hike in collection of personal income tax, the finance minister said, adding that the new portal will help honest tax payer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finance Minister says number of assessees has gone up post notes ban&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal income tax collection has gone up post notes ban, he adds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr Jaitley expects further increase in tax returns going ahead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of persons under the tax net has increased by 91 lakh as unaccounted cash lost anonymity post note ban, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launching a new website on &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo;, a programme to bring illegal wealth on books, he said the fallout of the November 8 decision to demonetise higher denomination currency has increased movement towards digitisation, number of assessees going up and tax revenue jumping as also fear of dealing in cash being instilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stating that as many as 91 lakh persons have come under the tax net, Jaitley said he expects further increase in tax returns going ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post demonetisation, there has been a hike in collection of personal income tax, the finance minister said, adding that the new portal will help honest tax payer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT Chairman Sushil Chandra said there was 22 per cent growth in e-filed returns post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many as 17.92 lakh people were identified for unexplained deposits post demonetisation, he said, adding the tax department has identified one lakh suspected tax avoidance cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that an undisclosed income of Rs 16,398 crore was identified post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We identified around 17.92 lakh persons in whose case the cash transactions did not appear in line with the taxpayers&amp;rsquo; profiles. And online verifications of these transactions are underway,&amp;rdquo; Chandra said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 17.92 lakh, so far 9.72 lakh individuals responded to SMSes and e-mails sent by the income tax department.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 19 A Day 4G Data, Unlimited Calls In New Plans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-offers-4g-data-unlimited-calls-in-new-plans-starting-rs-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-offers-4g-data-unlimited-calls-in-new-plans-starting-rs-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone SuperWeek is priced at Rs 49 and will come with a validity of seven days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India on Thursday announced integrated plans offering unlimited voice and bonus data to its prepaid customers starting from Rs 19 per day. Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s two integrated &amp;ldquo;Voice plus Data&amp;rdquo; plans - Vodafone SuperDay and Vodafone SuperWeek - will enable its prepaid customers to enjoy benefits of unlimited local and STD calling with free data up to 250 MB for seven days. Under its Vodafone SuperDay plan, Vodafone is offering unlimited local and STD Vodafone-to-Vodafone calls and 100 MB data on 4G handsets at Rs 19 per day, the company said in a press release. Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s move comes amid heightened competition witnessed by existing operators in India&amp;rsquo;s telecom industry due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, say analysts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priced at Rs 19, Vodafone SuperDay will come with a validity of one day. Vodafone SuperWeek is priced at Rs 49 and will be valid for seven days. Under the Vodafone SuperWeek plan, the prepaid customers of the telecom operator will get 250 MB of data on 4G handsets, besides unlimited local and STD Vodafone-to-Vodafone calls, the company further said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India, a wholly-owned subsidiary of British telecom company Vodafone Group Plc, is also offering 100 minutes of calls to other networks as an additional benefits in a separate Vodafone SuperWeek plan priced at Rs 89. Vodafone prepaid customers recharging with the Rs 89 plan will get free local and STD calls on its own network, 100 minutes of local and STD calls on other networks and 250 MB of data on 4G devices, the press release added.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/vodafone-prepaid-650-400_650x400_51495700068.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At Vodafone, it is our constant endeavour to provide the best network, service experience and value to our customers. We are delighted to launch SuperDay andSuperWeek under our &amp;lsquo;Super&amp;rsquo; umbrella with the key objective of offering pocket friendly and affordable integrated plans that will appeal to the prepaid customers,&amp;rdquo; said Sandeep Kataria, director-commercial at Vodafone India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The SuperDay and SuperWeek packs are available across all retail outlets, website and the MyVodafone app,&amp;rdquo; the Vodafone India statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These plans will further enable our customers to remain confidently connected and enjoy a worry free Vodafone SuperNetTM4G experience on our best network ever. Moreover, these integrated plans come with unrestricted repeat purchase options ensuring more value to the customer,&amp;rdquo; Mr Kataria added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, another telecom operator Bharti Airtel announced new broadband plans, offering up to 100 per cent additional high speed data benefits. Bharti Airtel, whose broadband internet plans in the national capital start from Rs. 899 a month, said its new plans were aimed at driving India&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Jio, the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a variety of recharge options starting from Rs 19 to its prepaid subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s telecom customer base grew by about half a per cent to 119.45 crore in March, data from telecom regulator TRAI (Telecom Regulatory Authority of India) showed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 30:you could buy a litre of petrol</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/in-5-years-you-could-buy-a-litre-of-petrol-for-rs-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/in-5-years-you-could-buy-a-litre-of-petrol-for-rs-30/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-s-true&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you remember the last time you paid Rs 30 for a litre of petrol? Well, that was 14 years go, July 2003 to be precise. Seems like petrol will go easy on pockets again. In coming five years, you could be paying as less than Rs 30 per litre for the fuel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;future-tech&#34;&gt;Future tech&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A futuristic technology will be decreasing gthe world&amp;rsquo;s dependence on petrol so much that its prices will crash, predicts Tony Seba, an American futurist famous for predicting a boom in solar power when the prices used to be around ten times of what they are today, which came true eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seba, a serial Silicon Valley entrepreneur, is also an instructor in Entrepreneurship, Disruption and Clean Energy at Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Continuing Studies Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;global-oil-demand-to-go-down&#34;&gt;Global oil demand to go down&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding his prediction, Seba says that it is the rise of self-drive cars that would bring down the global demand for oil, reducing the price of oil to $25 a barrel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oil demand will peak 2021-2020 and will go down 100 million barrels, to 70 million barrels within 10 years. And what that means, the new equilibrium price is going to be $25,&amp;rdquo; says Seba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;affordable-electric-cars&#34;&gt;Affordable electric cars&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though people would not stop using fuelled cars, they would start using self-drive electric vehicles more, which would be cheaper to buy as well as run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;india-to-go-all-electric-by-2030&#34;&gt;India to go all-electric by 2030&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Union power minister Piyush Goyal had also said that India was looking to have all-electric car fleet by 2030, meaning that not a single petrol or diesel car would be sold in the country after 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Reliance-Jio-VoLTE-feature-phone.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen. It also has a dedicated button for torchlight. Maker of this feature phone is not known yet. Currently we don’t have any specifications of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to recent reports, Jio will launch these VoLTE-enabled feature phones starting at Rs. 999 that will run on Android operating system. Earlier reports said that capability to make VoLTE calls in these feature phones will be enabled by Spreadtrum chips, and Jio is in talks with Qualcomm and MediaTek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Jio plans start as low as Rs. 149 per month offering unlimited calls, this will be useful for those who make a lot of calls and need a cheap phone with a keypad. We should know more details about more upcoming VoLTE-enabled feature phones from Jio soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Imposes Fee On Cheque Payments For Credit Card Dues. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card is levying a charge on payments made by cheques. This came into effect from April 1, according to SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s website. The card company said payments made below Rs 2,000 through cheques will attract a fee of Rs 100. &amp;ldquo;A fee of Rs.100 will be charged for payments made by cheque for an amount less than or equal to Rs.2000 w.e.f. 1st April &amp;lsquo;17. No additional fee will be charged for cheque payments greater than Rs. 2000,&amp;rdquo; SBI Card said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen that the majority of payments (over 90 per cent) are made through non-cheque modes. We have observed a trend of payment related disputes arising in small cheque payments, causing inconvenience to customers as well. We offer several seamless digital modes of payment which we are seeking to encourage, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s focus towards digital payments and this step will facilitate the same,&amp;rdquo; said SBI Card CEO Vijay Jasuja.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, payments made through SBI cheques will not incur the extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost. It is also likely to provide a boost to digital payments. SBI, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, entered credit card business in 1998 by roping GE Capital India, the consumer finance arm of US-based GE Capital. SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s latest offering &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; is targeted at all State Bank of India customers, including Jan Dhan account holders throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has introduced the &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; card in an effort to bring new users into the fold of cashless transactions. The card is issued to persons with a balance of Rs 25,000 in their SBI accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No such charge on cheque payments will be levied on holders of SBI Card Unnati which is targeted at first time credit card users and aimed at inclusion of people into the organised financial stream,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jasuja added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trai Releases An App Which Lets You Rate Call Quality</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sector regulator Trai today said it will soon roll-out an app that enables subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call. The &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app would be available by the end of this month, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) chairman RS Sharma said at &amp;lsquo;Digital Broadcasting in India - Way Forward&amp;rsquo;, a seminar to commemorate the completion of 20 years of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We would like the consumers to assess the quality of calls, through &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app, which will be rolled out by this month end,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, once downloaded, the new app would give the subscribers the choice of assessing the quality of all or a portion of calls. When the call is completed, the users will be able to rate it, and the data will thereafter be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The application will pop up a window and enquire about the quality of the call. The subscriber can give it one star to five stars. There will also be assessment parameters like whether the call was indoors or outside or while travelling,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government and the regulator have refused to lower their guard on the issue of call drops, and have kept a close watch on call quality through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.
Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops. The system is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trai through its analytics portal has also rolled out initiatives that measure data speeds and maps call drops in India, which is the world&amp;rsquo;s second largest telecom market with 1.12 billion mobile subscribers.
Sharma today said that Trai also plans to &amp;ldquo;strengthen&amp;rdquo; the &amp;lsquo;Do Not Disturb&amp;rsquo; or DND service aimed at blocking pesky calls by telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already done a lot of work in this,&amp;rdquo; Sharma said, but refused to elaborate on the upcoming plans. At present, there is a framework for DND registry that allows telecom subscribers to block unwanted communication from telemarketers. Reaching out to such subscribers can result in a heavy fine for telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source familiar with the initiative said that the regulator may look at building specific intelligence features into the system such that pesky messages with certain key words could automatically generate a prompt on whether the users wishes to report the message as a spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the occasion, Communications Minister Manoj Sinha said TRAI&amp;rsquo;s regulatory framework has provided a conducive environment for the sector&amp;rsquo;s growth. It has made the sector more competitive and enhanced accessibility of services at affordable tariffs, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awareness of the some of the main challenges faced by the sector and regulatory framework of today - ranging from convergence to the persisting issue of the digital divide - is therefore necessary to be better equipped to handle these challenges in future,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WannaCry ransomware : 48,000 attempts in India, says Quick Heal</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-in-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While organisations and networks in over 150 countries were crippled by the WannaCry ransomware outbreak, India escaped from the malware spreading and causing damage, thanks to the timing of the incident, with offices being shut during the weekend.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While organisations and networks in over 150 countries were crippled by the WannaCry ransomware outbreak, India escaped from the malware spreading and causing damage, thanks to the timing of the incident, with offices being shut during the weekend. By Monday morning, everybody had become alert and it averted a lot of damage, Sanjay Katkar, MD and CTO of Quick Heal Technologies, an IT security solutions provider, said. Since Monday, Quick Heal has been receiving distress calls from customers but it was not clear whether they were affected or not, as this was not being disclosed by those calling, Katkar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick Heal detected over 48,000 attempts of WannaCry ransomware attack in India. Kolkata tops the list of cities with maximum detections, followed by Delhi, Bhubaneswar, Pune and Mumbai. The top five states with maximum detections are West Bengal, Maharashtra, Gujarat, Delhi (including NCR) and Odisha. Among the attempted attacks, 60% were targeted towards enterprises and 40% towards individual customers. In case of an attack, Katkar advises companies or users not to pay any ransom as this would go in funding the next attack.
“Hackers who are successful in collecting money will re-invest into new technologies. People who pay are funding the next attack,” warns Katkar. Protection was available if the users updated the anti-virus software and the patch was made available on March ’17 but many did not update their systems, Katkar said. Soon after the ransomware attack was spotted, Quick Heal Security Labs issued an advisory informing customer on ways to reduce the risk of infection by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry Ransomware. Quick Heal has also organized a webinar to educate businesses on how to protect their organization from the WannaCry Ransomware on Wednesday, May 17 at 4 pm. This kind of an incident helps increase awareness about security but their experience was that people go back to business as usual in quick time, says Katkar. This threat indicates people not serious about security but security has to be priority if they want to protect data, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outdated operating system and failure to use anti-virus software makes them vulnerable, he said. Some of the software in the enterprise could be running on older systems especially in the manufacturing sector and a shift would need upgrading hardware so they could be continuing with old systems, Katkar said. Banks in the country that have outsourced some of their systems/ functions to third-party service providers need to take a re-look at the security at their vendors especially their ATM networks, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The retail user are also casual so vulnerability is more on this front. A lot of data moving on the mobile phones and people are connected &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; on the net but the market is not keen on paying for security their phones so mobile security is not picking up, Katkar said. “Given their profitability, ransomware attacks are predicted to increase in the coming quarter. There can be a drastic increase in the number of Locky samples being distributed via spam emails or exploits. Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS) type attacks may increase due to its user friendliness,” a Quick Heal Security Labs Q12017 threat report had warned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your PAN card could be invalid without Aadhaar by December. Here’s what to do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar-by-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar-by-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Permanent account numbers (PAN) not linked to Aadhaar cards will likely become invalid after December 31, a government source said on Thursday, as the Centre pushes to widen the use of the 12-digit biometric identity project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permanent account numbers (PAN) not linked to Aadhaar cards will likely become invalid after December 31, a government source said on Thursday, as the Centre pushes to widen the use of the 12-digit biometric identity project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, all taxpayers need to have a PAN number to file income tax return but others, such as students outside the tax bracket, also use the card as a proof of identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government says many of these PAN cards are fraudulently obtained, a practice that can be checked by a unique identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official – who refused to be quoted as he isn’t authorised to talk to media – said the government had arrived at the tentative cutoff date of December 31 as it believed the Aadhaar enrollment process will be complete by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Considering that 98% of the adult population is Aadhaar card holders, a time frame till the end of the year is more than adequate for linking PAN with Aadhaar,” said State Bank of India group’s chief economic adviser Soumya Kanti Ghosh.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/pan-aadhaar.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अनलिमिटेड कॉलिंग और 4G इंटरनेट:19 रुपए में</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-superday-plan-to-compete-jio-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-superday-plan-to-compete-jio-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मुकेश अंबानी की कंपनी रिलायंस जियो को टक्कर देने के लिए वोडाफोन इंडिया ने गुरुवार को अपने ग्राहकों के लिए 19 रुपए की शुरुआती कीमत वाले कुछ किफायती प्लान पेश किए हैं। इस प्लान में ग्राहकों को अनलिमिटेड वॉयस कॉलिंग के साथ इंटरनेट के लिए 4जी डेटा भी दिया जा रहा है। कंपनी ने इन प्लान को एक-दिन (Vodafone SuperDay) और एक-हफ्ते (Vodafone SuperWeek) वाली दो कैटगरी में बांटा है। इसमें लोकल और एसटीडी कॉलिंग के साथ सात दिन के लिए 250 एमबी तक का डेटा पा सकेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19 रुपए वाले शुरुआती पैक की वैलिडिटी 1 दिन की है। इसमें ग्राहकों को वोडाफोन से वोडाफोन अनलिमिटेड कॉलिंग (लोकल व एसटीडी) और 100 एमबी का 4जी डेटा मिलेगा। इससे बड़े पैक की कीमत 49 रुपए और वैधता 7 दिन की होगी। इसमें ग्राहकों को 7 दिन के लिए वोडाफोन से वोडाफोन अनलिमिटेड कॉलिंग (लोकल व एसटीडी) और 250 एमबी का 4जी डेटा मिलेगा। सबसे बड़े पैक की कीमत 89 रुपए है जिसकी वैधता भी 7 दिन है। हालांकि इसमें 49 रुपए वाले पैक की सुविधाओं के अलावा वोडाफोन से अन्य नेटवर्क पर (लोकल व एसटीडी) कॉलिंग के लिए 100 मिनट दी जाएंगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ये सभी पैक्स कंपनी की वेबसाइट, माइ वोडाफोन ऐप और रिटेल स्टोर से लिए जा सकते हैं। ध्यान दें ये सभी पैक्स सिर्फ प्रीपेड यूजर्स के लिए ही है। बता दें कि इससे पहले कंपनी ने जियो की टक्कर पर प्रतिदिन एक जीबी डेटा वाला पैक पेश किया था। 352 रुपए वाले पैक के तहत ग्राहकों को प्रतिदिन एक जीबी डेटा 56 दिनों तक मिलता था। इसे वोडाफोन सुपर ऑफर के नाम से भी जाना जाता है। इस प्लान के तहत ग्राहकों को अनलिमिटेड लोकल और एसटीडी कॉलिंग की भी सुविधा दी गई थी। यह ऑफर न तो वोडाफोन की वेबसाइट पर मिलेगा और न ही ऐप पर। इस ऑफर का लाभ उठाने के लिए आपको वोडाफोन स्टोर या फिर किसी आउटलेट पर जाना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>करोड़पति शेयर: 14.3 लाख के निवेश पर तीन साल में 1 करोड़ रुपये का रिटर्न</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/crorepati-stock-rs-14-3-lakh-invested-in-this-stock-became-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/crorepati-stock-rs-14-3-lakh-invested-in-this-stock-became-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मोदी सरकार ने अपने कार्यकाल के तीन साल पूरे कर लिए। इस दौरान सरकार ने कई महत्वपूर्ण आर्थिक सुधारों को अंजाम दिया और यह प्रक्रिया जारी है। इधर, अर्थव्यवस्था के मौलिक मापदंडों में मजबूती देखी जा रही है। इनके अलावा, देश में राजनीतिक स्थिरता एवं सरकार के स्तर पर सक्रियता की वजह से शेयर बाजार नित नई ऊंचाइयां छू रहा है। इसी क्रम में पिछले तीन सालों में बॉम्बे स्टॉक एक्सचेंज (बीएसई) में लिस्टेड कंपनियों का मार्केट वैल्यू 40 लाख करोड़ रुपये बढ़ गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मार्केट वैल्यू में वृद्धि के मामले में मारुति सुजुकी, आईओसी, एचडीएफसी और रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज जैसी बड़ी कंपनियों ने नेतृत्वकारी प्रदर्शन किया। लेकिन, बेस्ट परफॉर्मर्स की टॉप 10 लिस्ट में जगह बनाने वाली एक नई कंपनी ने सबको चकित कर रखा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जिन निवेशकों ने तीन साल पहले इस कंपनी के शेयर में 14.27 लाख रुपये निवेश किए होंगे, वह आज करोड़पति बन चुके हैं। पिछले तीन साल में यह शेयर 538 प्रतिशत उछला है और अब कंपनी दिग्गजों की सूची में शुमार हो चुकी है। यह कंपनी है बजाज फाइनैंस।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस स्टॉक का मार्केट कैप शुक्रवार को 71,000 करोड़ रुपये तक पहुंच गया जो महज तीन साल पहले 10,000 करोड़ रुपये था। आंकड़े बताते हैं कि कंपनी ने पिछले तीन साल से वित्त वर्ष 2016 तक 29.31 प्रतिशत की दर से ऐनुअल प्रॉफिट ग्रोथ दर्ज की है। इस अवधि में कंपनी की बिक्री में सालाना 33.64 प्रतिशत की वृद्धि हुई। विश्लेषक अब भी इस स्टॉक में निवेश की सलाह दे रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ब्रोकरेज फर्म शेयरखान ने बजाज फाइनैंस के शेयर की रेटिंग अपग्रेड कर दी और उसे होल्ड से बाय कैटिगरी में ला दिया। फर्म में इसका रिवाज्ड प्राइस टार्गेट 1,550 रुपये रखा है। सोमवार को बीएसई में यह स्टॉक 1,282 रुपये पर ट्रेड कर रहा था। मार्केट वैल्यू के लिहाज से शानदार प्रदर्शन करने वाली टॉप 10 कंपनियों ने पिछले तीन साल में बीएसई के मार्केट कैप में 9 लाख करोड़ रुपये का इजाफा किया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जवाब नहीं देने वालों के खिलाफ कार्रवाई &#39;निश्चित&#39;:IT</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-will-take-action-against-9-29-lakh-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-will-take-action-against-9-29-lakh-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्र सरकार ने कहा है कि नोटबंदी के वक्त ज़्यादा कैश जमा कराने को लेकर आयकर विभाग द्वारा भेजे गए नोटिस का जवाब नहीं देने वाले 9.29 लाख लोगों के खिलाफ &amp;lsquo;निश्चित रूप से&amp;rsquo; कार्रवाई की जाएगी। आयकर विभाग ने इन लोगों को इसलिए नोटिस भेजा था क्योंकि इनके द्वारा जमा की गई रकम इनकी इनकम प्रोफाइल से मेल नहीं खाती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लोकसभा में फाइनैंस बिल पर हो रही चर्चा पर पूछे गए एक सवाल के जवाब में वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि नोटंबदी के 50 दिनों के दौरान 18 लाख लोगों द्वारा जमा किए गए 500 और 1000 रुपये के पुराने नोट उनकी आय के स्रोतों के अनुपात में नहीं थे। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;फिलहाल रीमोनिटाइज़ेशन का प्रोसेस चल रहा है। लेकिन प्राप्त हुए डेटा की शुरुआती जांच में सीबीडीटी (Central Board of Direct Taxes) और टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट ने पाया है कि 18 लाख लोगों द्वारा जमा किया गया कैश उनके इनकम प्रोफाइल से मेल नहीं खाता। संबंधित विभागों ने मेल और एसएमएस कर इन लोगों से स्पष्टीकरण मांगा था।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;करीब 8.71 लाख लोगों ने स्पष्टीकरण दिया है, और जिन्होंने कोई प्रतिक्रिया नहीं दी है निश्चित रूप से आयकर विभाग उनके खिलाफ आयकर अधिनियम के तहत ऐक्शन लेगा।&amp;rsquo; नोटबंदी के फायदे बताते हुए वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि इससे सरकार के संसाधनों के प्रोत्साहन में मदद मिलेगी। किसानों को मिलनेवाले फंड, रक्षा क्षेत्र और मनरेगा जैसे मुद्दों पर सभी पार्टियों द्वारा चिंता व्यक्त करने पर वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि इनके लिए ज़्यादा खर्च तभी संभव है जब सरकार के पास और संसाधन हों।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी के दौरान जमा हुई रकम की फाइनल टैली को लेकर किए गए सवालों पर जेटली ने कहा कि आरबीआई द्वारा हरेक नोट गिने जाने के बाद इसकी घोषणा की जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पांच साल और, पेट्रोल मिलेगा 30 रुपये लीटर, पढ़िये पूरी खबर</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-to-go-cheaper-due-to-low-oil-demand-and-technology-change-rs-30-per-liter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-to-go-cheaper-due-to-low-oil-demand-and-technology-change-rs-30-per-liter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;टोनी कहते हैं कि सेल्फ ड्राइव कारों की वजह से दुनिया भर में पेट्रोलियम पदार्थों की कीमतों में जबर्दस्त गिरावट दर्ज की जाएगी। और तेल की कीमतें 25 डॉलर प्रति बैरल तक आ जाएगीं।&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पेट्रोल की कीमतें हर भारतीय के बजट का मोटा हिस्सा हजम कर जाती हैं। आपके पास बाइक अथवा कार हो या ना हो लेकिन आप पेट्रोल की कीमतों से प्रभावित होते हैं। लेकिन अगर हम आपको कहेंगे कि अगले 5 साल के बाद आप पेट्रोल 30 रुपये प्रति लीटर खरीद पाएंगे तो आप इसे मजाक ही समझेंगे। लेकिन ऐसा संभव हो सकता है। और ऐसा संभव है विज्ञान और बदलती प्रोद्योगिकी की वजह से। ऐसा दावा किया है तकनीकी और इसके प्रभाव का अध्ययन करने वाले अमेरिका के मशहूर फ्यूचरिस्ट यानी की भविष्यवादी टोनी सीबा ने। बता दें कि अमेरिका के ही इस प्रोफेशनल ने दावा किया था कि दुनिया में सोलर पावर का बूम होगा। टोनी ने ये दावा तब किया था जब आज के मुकाबले सोलर पावर की कीमतें 10 गुणा थी। टोनी का आकलन सही साबित हुआ और सोलर पावर की कीमतों में गिरावट हुआ और आज दुनिया भर में सोलर पावर पेट्रोलियम पदार्थों का विकल्प बन चुका है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अंग्रेजी वेबसाइट इकोनॉमिक टाइम्स के मुताबिक टोनी सीबा सिलिकन वैली के एक बड़े बिजनेसमैन हैं साथ ही स्टैनफोर्ड यूनिवर्सिटी में भी क्लीन एनर्जी से जुड़े अध्ययन में शामिल हैं। टोनी कहते हैं कि सेल्फ ड्राइव कारों की वजह से दुनिया भर में पेट्रोलियम पदार्थों की कीमतों में जबर्दस्त गिरावट दर्ज की जाएगी। और तेल की कीमतें 25 डॉलर प्रति बैरल तक आ जाएगीं। यूं तो एक भारतीय के लिए उनकी इस भविष्यवाणी पर यकीन करना मुश्किल लगता है। लेकिन उनके आंकड़ों में दम और तर्क नजर आता है। टोनी का कहना है कि 2020-21 तक दुनिया में तेल की मांग उच्चतम स्तर पर होगी और ये 100 मिलियन बैरल तक पहुंच जाएगा। लेकिन इसके बाद तेल की कीमतें गिरने लगेंगी। 10 साल में तेल की मांग घटकर 70 मिलियन डॉलर हो जाएगीष इसका मतलब होगा कि दुनिया में तेल 25 डॉलर प्रति बैरल बिकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;टोनी सीबा का कहना है कि आने वाले सालों में इलेक्ट्रिक कार ऑयल इंडस्ट्री पर गहरा प्रभाव डालने वाली है। कुछ सालों में लोगों के लिए इलेक्ट्रिक कार खरीदना और चलाना दोनों सस्ता पड़ेगा। इसका असर तेल की कीमतों पर भी पड़ेगा। हाल ही में ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा था कि 2030 तक भारत में भी सारी कारें इलेक्ट्रिक कार से चलने वाली होंगी। इसका ये भी मतलब लगाया जा सकता है कि अगले 15 से 20 सालों में देश में पेट्रोल डीजल से चलने वाली कारें ना के बराबर रह जाएंगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>राष्ट्रीय औषधि मूल्य प्राधिकरण (एनपीपीए) ने और 30 दवाओं (फार्मूलेशन) का अधिकतम खुदरा मूल्य तय किया</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nppa-decided-maximum-retail-price-of-30-more-medicines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nppa-decided-maximum-retail-price-of-30-more-medicines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;राष्ट्रीय औषधि मूल्य प्राधिकरण (एनपीपीए) ने और 30 दवाओं (फार्मूलेशन) का अधिकतम खुदरा मूल्य तय किया है। इन दवाओं का इस्तेमाल हेपेटाइटिस, ह्दय रोग, संक्रमण, बुखार और दर्द के इलाज के लिए होता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दवा मूल्य नियामक ने कहा कि जहां 19 अनिवार्य दवाओं के लिए एमआरपी तय किया गया है, वहीं 11 के मूल्य में संशोधन किया गया है। एनपीपीए ने अधिसूचना में कहा,&amp;lsquo;सात दवाओं का खुदरा मूल्य तय किया गया है।&amp;rsquo; ताजा मूल्य संशोधन से अप्रैल, 2016 से मूल्य नियंत्रण के दायरे में आने वाली दवाओं की संख्या 760 पर पहुंच गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह कदम सरकार की देशभर में मरीजों को उचित मूल्य पर गुणवत्ता वाली सस्ती दवाएं उपलब्ध कराने की प्रक्रिया का हिस्सा है। एनपीपीए नियंत्रित थोक दवाओं और फार्मूलेशन का मूल्य तय और संशोधित करता है। वह देश में दवाओं की उपलब्धता सुनिश्चित करने के साथ ही बिना नियंत्रण वाली दवाओं के दाम उचित स्तर पर रखने के लिए मूल्य की निगरानी भी करता है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>