<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Govt:Over Rs 153cr awarded to 10lk people to promote e-payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;check if you are winner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dev.digidhanlucky&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px;padding:4px&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/logoapp.png&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on start button in Digi Dhan Lucky Yojana App.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on whether you are a Consumer or a Merchant, click on the corresponding button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box that appears next, provide the mobile phone number registered with your UPI/ USSD/ RuPay/ AEPS account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive an OTP, which you must enter in the box that appears in the middle of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Try Your Luck button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next message will show if you have won under the Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi Dhan Vyapar Yojana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been awarded over Rs 153.5 crore in the last 58 days under Niti Aayog’s schemes to promote digital payments, its CEO Amitabh Kant said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It has been 58 days since the launch of Niti Aayog’s two incentive schemes – Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana to promote digital payments and the public response has been quite encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the latest figures released by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), which has been executing the schemes, nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been disbursed over Rs 153.5 crore as reward money till February 20, 2017,” Kant said at a press conference here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s think-tank said in a statement that among the 9.8 lakh winners are more than 9.2 lakh consumers and 56,000 merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners belong to diverse socio-economic backgrounds, including farmers, merchants, small entrepreneurs, professionals, housewives, students and retired persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Uttar Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh and Delhi have emerged as the top five states/Union Territories with maximum number of winners,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While majority of the winners are in the age group of 21 to 30, Niti Aayog pointed out that a significant number are also above 60 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The diversity in age of winners is from 15 to 66 years, challenging the notion that the old find it difficult to embrace technology to adopt digital payments,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government on December 25 had launched two schemes — Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana — to boost digital transactions post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt tells RBI to work with stakeholders for PoS roll-out</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-tells-rbi-work-stakeholders-pos-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-tells-rbi-work-stakeholders-pos-roll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The govt has asked RBI to fix responsibilities for stakeholders, including PoS manufactures, UIDAI that administers the 12-digit Aadhaar number, and the NPCI to launch the process&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance ministry has asked the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to bring together all stakeholders, including banks and back-end service providers, and establish a process for the roll-out of Aadhaar-based point of sales (PoS) machines to promote cashless transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his budget speech last month, finance minister Arun Jaitley said two million Aadhaar-based PoS machines will be rolled out by September-end. Banks have flagged the lack of an established back-end infrastructure as an impediment in implementing this mandate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has now asked RBI to fix responsibilities for stakeholders, including PoS manufactures, back-end service providers, banks, and the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) that administers the 12-digit Aadhaar number, and the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) to launch the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For Aadhaar-based PoS machines to be a reality, many systems and processes have to be put in place. The biometric data captured on these machines has to be encrypted and transmitted after which Aadhaar authentication has to be done. The payment then has to be processed. For this, all the stakeholders have to be brought together by RBI and the process established,” said a senior finance ministry official, who did not wish to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time that an Aadhaar-based authentication process has been proposed. RBI, in a notification in September 2016, made it mandatory for all banks to ensure that all new card acceptance infrastructure deployed from 1 January, 2017 is enabled for processing payment transactions using Aadhaar-based biometric authentication. After banks raised concerns about a mismatch between demand and supply of such Aadhaar-enabled devices, the central bank gave banks time till end-June to deploy this infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deepak Bhutra, chief executive officer, India Transact Services Ltd, a merchant payment solutions firm, said it is possible to shift to new age biometric payment systems. “This is not technically a difficult task but rather a very expensive one. Companies will have to invest in securing these biometric readers and assembling them in the currently available PoS machines,” he said in an email. “We do see faster acceptance of the PoS machines now with the push from the government, but a major challenge would be to educate the customer to pay through Aadhaar payment method as opposed to paying via the card route,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are a few things which banks will incrementally have to follow. Firstly, banks will need to get certified with NPCI for AEPS (Aadhaar- enabled payment system) switching capability which will have to be managed or outsourced by the bank. Secondly, deployment of a merchant app with low cost peripheral, to enable Aadhaar biometric authentication is needed. Lastly, banks would need to upgrade their existing EDC (electronic draft capture) PoS or mPoS terminals to support biometric capture which may work out to be more costly and much less scalable,” Deepak Sharma, chief digital officer, Kotak Mahindra Bank, said in response to emailed questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“From a consumer perspective, the Aadhaar-based payment methodology will work even in the absence of feature phones and high-end smart phones—which addresses a significant part of the population at the bottom of the pyramid,” added Sharma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An IDFC Bank official said the target is easily achievable if new age banks adopt this route. “The bank has an ambitious roll-out plan for both Aadhaar Pay as well as micro ATMs,” the official added on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay is a service for merchants that will enable them to receive payments from customers without any physical payment instrument. The app has to be downloaded by merchants on their phones and linked to an Aadhaar biometric reader. Once the merchant has this infrastructure in place, consumers can start transacting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Announces Free Incoming Calls On Domestic Roaming To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move comes after different offers introduced by rival telecom firms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular today announced free incoming calls on domestic roaming and unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers come on the heels of the larger rival Bharti Airtel announcing removal of all roaming charges for outgoing and incoming calls as well as SMSes and data usage within India, to take on competition from newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Effective April 1, 2017, Idea&amp;rsquo;s 200 million customers will enjoy free incoming calls while roaming on company&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G and 4G network across 400,000 towns and villages in the country. Idea customers will be able to make outgoing calls, SMS freely at affordable rates while roaming anywhere in India,&amp;rdquo; an Idea release said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further said mobile data tariffs and data pack benefits of home circle will be available while roaming within India at no extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facility of free incoming calls on domestic roaming will be extended to both prepaid and postpaid customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For international travellers, the company is offering international roaming value packs with free bundled usage of up to 400 outgoing minutes, 100 SMSes per day, 3GB bundled data and unlimited incoming calls for Rs 2,499 for Asia, and Rs 5,999 for Europe for 30 days validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These international roaming packs also come bundled with free 1GB/2GB/3GB data and overage charges as low as Rs 3 per MB to avoid bill shock to travelling customers,&amp;rdquo; Idea said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company said it has done a study of customer&amp;rsquo;s travel destinations, usage patterns and bill shock complaints to design a new range of value packs for select destinations across Europe, Asia, America, UK and Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For value conscious customers, the packs start at Rs 1,199 for 10 days validity and go up to Rs 5,999 for 30 days validity, giving up to 85 per cent savings on international roaming charges,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;Idea is now set to enable over 200 million customers to use their mobile phones freely, without having to worry about roaming charges, while they travel anywhere in the country,&amp;rdquo; Sashi Shankar, Chief Marketing Officer of Idea Cellular said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges on calls and data, and said international call rates will be cut by up to 90 per cent to as low as Rs 3 per minute and data charges by up to 99 per cent to Rs 3 per MB across popular roaming destinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press statement, &amp;lsquo;Airtel Declares War on Roaming&amp;rsquo;, the company had then said the move will lead to &amp;ldquo;death of National Roaming&amp;rdquo; from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF (Provident Fund) Money Withdrawal: Here Are Five Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-provident-fund-money-withdrawal-here-are-five-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-provident-fund-money-withdrawal-here-are-five-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per PF rules, 12% of an employee&amp;rsquo;s salary goes into the fund along with a matching contribution from the employer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provident fund (PF) is meant for saving towards retirement years. Financial planners don&amp;rsquo;t advise withdrawal from the corpus before retirement. According to provident fund norms, 12 per cent of an employee&amp;rsquo;s salary goes into the fund along with a matching contribution from the employer. The EPFO (Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation) every year announces interest rate to be paid on the accumulated provident fund corpus. The PF money can be withdrawn after two months from the cessation of employment. The application form in this regard can be filed with PF authorities, or through the employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) To encourage long-term savings, the government has formulated tax laws accordingly. If the withdrawal from a recognised PF happens after five years of continuous employment, it attracts no tax liability. In case of employment with different employers, if the PF balance maintained with the old employer is transferred to the PF account of the new employer, it is considered a continuous employment. (Also read: I Want To Save Enough Money For Retirement. Is PF Contribution Enough?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an employee has been terminated because of certain reasons beyond his or her control (such as ill health and discontinuation of business of employer), a withdrawal does not attract any tax, irrespective of the number of years of employment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) In case of a withdrawal before five years, the amount becomes taxable in the same financial year. Thus, the amount has to be shown in your tax return for the next assessment year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The employer&amp;rsquo;s contribution to PF and interest earned on it is added to one&amp;rsquo;s income and taxed accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In addition, if you have claimed benefits under Section 80C on your own PF contribution, it will be taxed as salary. The interest earned on your own contribution will be taxed as &amp;lsquo;income from other sources&amp;rsquo; and taxed according to the respective tax slabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) TDS (tax deducted at source) - If the withdrawal is after a period of five years of continuous employment, it attracts no TDS or any tax. What happens if the period of service is less than five years? If PAN has not been submitted to the EPFO authorities, TDS is deducted at 30 per cent. If PAN has been submitted along with Form 15G/15H, no TDS is deducted. If form 15G/15H is not submitted and PAN is submitted, TDS @ 10% is deducted. Form 15H or 15G is meant to prevent TDS for those whose income falls below the taxable limit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pensioners told to apply for Aadhaar card to receive pension</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pensioners-told-apply-aadhaar-card-receive-pension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pensioners-told-apply-aadhaar-card-receive-pension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ministry has issued a notification making Aadhaar mandatory for pensioners to receive pension. The pensioners number approximately 25 lakh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To receive a pension, the Union Defence Ministry in its notification stated all defence pensioners and family members of a deceased personnel ‘will be required to enrol for Aadhar card latest by June 30 to receive pension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry has issued a notification making Aadhaar mandatory for pensioners to receive pension. The pensioners number approximately is 25 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any pensioner eligible to receive benefits and who hasn’t enrolled for Aadhaar, but wants to avail pension is required to apply for Aadhaar by June 30,” read the notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also stated that the ministry through agencies or other means is required to offer Aadhaar enrollment facilities for beneficiaries who have not yet applied for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The order stated the Defence Ministry through such agencies will be required to provide Aadhaar enrolment facilities in places where such facilities aren’t available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till the time Aadhaar card is not given, beneficiaries shall get on producing the ex-servicemen card. A copy of his or her request made for Aadhaar enrolment can be submitted along with a copy of Voter ID card or PAN Card or Passport among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification said Defence Ministry through related agencies should make arrangements to provide hassle-free pension benefits to the beneficiaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wide publicity through media and through other sources should be given and individual notices shall be handed over to pensioners to make them aware of the Aadhaar requirement under the scheme, it added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Communications New Offer: 1 GB 4G Data For Rs 49, 3 GB for Rs 149</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-communications-new-offer-1-gb-4g-data-for-rs-49-3-gb-for-rs-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-communications-new-offer-1-gb-4g-data-for-rs-49-3-gb-for-rs-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Communications also introduced a competitive 3G offer of unlimited data access at Rs 99, while unlimited 2G data access will be available for Rs 49.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Communications (RCOM) on Friday launched a &amp;lsquo;Joy of Holi&amp;rsquo; offer in which it will provide its 4G customers with 1GB of data access for Rs 49 and 3GB for Rs 149, along with free and unlimited on-net local and STD calls, valid for 28 days, a company statement said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also introduced a competitive 3G offer of unlimited data access at Rs 99, while unlimited 2G data access will be available for Rs 49.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Regardless of the type of smartphone or feature phone being used, customers will get best-in-class data and voice services without any additional recharge or membership-across 4G, 3G and 2G,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At RCOM, we have been overwhelmed by the response that our Unlimited Plan received last year - a validation of our efforts to constantly enhance customer experience and delight. We now take a new leap with additional benefits being offered to our 4G customers, with the &amp;lsquo;Joy of Holi&amp;rsquo; offer,&amp;rdquo; said Gurdeep Singh, Co-CEO, Reliance Communications, and Chief Executive Officer of RCOM&amp;rsquo;s Consumer Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Additionally, we still see immense potential in the 3G and 2G markets, which boast of 750 million smartphones and data-ready feature phones. We have, therefore, customized special offerings in this space as well, with segmented and value-creating propositions,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPI, Aadhaar Pay, Bharat QR force Paytm, Mobikwik to step up their game</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/upi-aadhaar-pay-bharat-qr-force-paytm-mobikwik-step-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/upi-aadhaar-pay-bharat-qr-force-paytm-mobikwik-step-game/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the arrival of state-sponsored e-payment services, electronic payment firms have ratcheted up their efforts to lure customers in the cashless driven market&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic payment firms got a big boost when India abolished most of the country’s banknotes last year, but rival state-sponsored e-payment services are forcing them to raise their game to hang on to their new customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until November’s move, which scrapped 86% of all notes to foil counterfeiting and the black market, more than 90% of transactions in India were in cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic payments providers such as market leaders Paytm and MobiKwik, and smaller players FreeCharge, Citrus, ItzCash and Oxigen, seized the opportunity, snapping up millions of customers and merchants caught out by the sudden shortage of cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the government is rolling out three tools to facilitate rival cashless transactions, including a United Payments Interface (UPI) app that simplifies inter-bank fund transfers, and Aadhaar Pay, a bank-linked payment service that relies on the national identity card and can be used with just a fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also promoted Bharat QR, another bank-linked service that uses machine-readable labels as the base for a simple payment system, helped by Visa and MasterCard. It requires only a smartphone and is aiming to sign up 2 million merchants by September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UPI app was downloaded more than 17 million times within two months of launch, and transaction values jumped 18 times between November and January, albeit from a low base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So e-wallet providers such as Alibaba-backed Paytm, the largest, with more than 200 million clients, are adding services to stay a step ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paytm is betting that its licence to set up a niche bank so it can pay interest on deposits—and connect its systems with the UPI network—will help, and it knows it will need extra services to make the business profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The point is that e-wallets as a standalone business will be massively risky and not viable,” said Vijay Shekhar Sharma, founder and chief executive of Paytm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;freebies&#34;&gt;Freebies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early stages of their build-up, the companies haven’t even paid lipservice to viability—giving a free service to customers and merchants, while burning through their start-up funding. Their only source of income has been commissions on phone and utility bill payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paytm’s parent company has raised $675 million from Alibaba and more from others, and says its current valuation is about $5 billion, but it has lost about $230 million over the last financial year. MobiKwik, part-owned by American Express and Sequoia Capital, has raised about $80 million and is eyeing a $1 billion valuation as it holds talks with investors for more funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both have waived fees to enable free money transfers from wallets to bank accounts. Paytm says transfers within its wallets and accounts will be free forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they have been using cash discounts and freebies to lure customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mumbai-based management teacher Christina Sundaresan says she started using Paytm when the government pulled the plug on notes, and now uses it so frequently she gets a free movie ticket each weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My laptop repairer, the vegetable vendor and the medical store are all accepting Paytm, so it works well,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she says she would consider other payment options, including UPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That will make it difficult for Paytm to withdraw the freebies, but they can’t keep burning cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t have a business that says ‘pay a 500 bill and take 250 cash back’,” said Aditya Puri, head of third-biggest Indian lender HDFC Bank, which has its own payment app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MobiKwik, which started as a simple digital wallet, is looking to partner with mainstream banks to market a host of financial services on its platform, from mutual funds to loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It aims to triple its wallets user base to 150 million by end-2017, and raise the value of transactions five times to $10 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It thinks its head start and extra services will keep it on top of the competition, and that banks, latecomers to e-payment, will struggle to match the scale of its operations and vendor network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“UPI is a solution for bank transfers. UPI is not a payments ecosystem today, as there are no merchants on UPI,” said MobiKwik chief executive Bipin Preet Singh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dhruv Chopra, managing director at the Indian unit of South African payments solutions provider Net1, which has invested in MobiKwik, is also betting the start-ups will be too nimble for the banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with a large number of small players, many will not survive, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avnish Bajaj of venture capital firm Matrix Partners, which has investments in payments companies ItzCash, Mswipe, and ride hailing firm Ola, which has its own e-wallet, agrees there will be a clearout under competitive pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s going to be a bit of consolidation in the e-wallets space in the next two years,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मोदी की &#39;कड़वी दवाइयों&#39; के लिए रहें तैयार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/result-get-ready-for-big-economic-reforms-by-modi-governemnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/result-get-ready-for-big-economic-reforms-by-modi-governemnt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;यूपी में बीजेपी की प्रचंड जीत से प्रभावित मोदी सरकार सुधारों की दिशा में अपने कदम और तेज कर सकती है। विदेशी निवेश के मामले में सरकार और उदारवादी रुख अपना सकती है वहीं, भारत में उत्पादन बढ़ाना, कर्ज में डूबे बैंकों का उबारना, सोशल सेक्टर में डिलिवरी सिस्टम को मजबूत करना सरकार के सुधारवादी अजेंडा में शामिल रह सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यूपी में बीजेपी अपनी &amp;lsquo;ट्रिपल सेंचुरी&amp;rsquo; को नोटबंदी पर जनता के ग्रीन सिग्नल के रूप में देख रही है। दो सालों से &amp;lsquo;सबसे बड़ा&amp;rsquo; आर्थिक सुधार माने जाने वाले जीएसटी को पास कराने की कोशिशों में लगी बीजेपी अब अन्य सुधारों की ओर तेज कदम बढ़ाएगी जिससे जीएसटी को लागू करने में भी फायदा होगा। वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने विधानसभा चुनावों में बीजेपी के प्रदर्शन पर ट्वीट किया, &amp;lsquo;विधानसभा चुनावों में बीजेपी की बेहतरीन जीत से फिर यह साबित होता है कि जनता पीएम मोदी के विकास के साथ हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;इन-स-ध-र-म-आएग-त-ज&#34;&gt;इन सुधारों में आएगी तेजी&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बीजेपी के प्रदर्शन का असर संसद में जीएसटी के पास होने को आसान बनाने में मदद करेगा। लागू होने की कई डेटलाइन मिस कर चुके जीएसटी को सरकार 1 जुलाई से लागू करना चाहती है। श्रम सुधारों पर सरकार पहले से ही काम कर रही है। इसके अलावा सरकार विदेशी निवेश के और रास्ते खोल सकती है और रिटेल में FDI की अनुमति भी दे सकती है। सरकार के सामने सबसे बड़ी समस्या बैंकिंग सेक्टर को ट्रैक पर लाने का है। एनपीए से जूझ रहे बैंकों को बचाने के लिए सरकार बड़े कदम उठा सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;आन-व-ल-स-ध-र&#34;&gt;आने वाले सुधार&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोटबंदी एक ऐसा कदम था जिसका अंदाजा भी लगाना आसान नहीं था। सरकार आने वाले समय में इन्फ्रास्ट्रकचर पर जोर देते हुए भूमि सुधार की दिशा में आगे बढ़ सकती है। भूमि अधिग्रहण बिल को पास कराने की असफल कोशिशों के बाद सरकार अब कोई और रास्ता निकाल सकती है। डायरेक्ट बेनिफिट ट्रांसफर की सफलता को और डिजिटल इंडिया के सपने के साथ सरकरा सब्सिडी के क्षेत्र में भी बड़े सुधार ला सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;न-टब-द-पर-फ-सल&#34;&gt;नोटबंदी पर फैसला?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक्सपर्ट्स का मानना है कि चुनावी नतीजे ने साफ कर दिया कि वह नोटबंदी पर क्या राय रखते हैं। नोटंबदी जिसमें 86 प्रतिशत करंसी को अमान्य घोषित कर दिया गया हो वह एक साहसी कदम था। जनता पर नोटबंदी का प्रभाव जानने के बाद सरकार, बड़े और कठोर कदम उठाने में अब हिचकेगी नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जल्द मिलेगा होम लोन कवर के साथ कम रेट का फायदा!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/profit-of-low-rate-with-home-loan-cover-home-loan-to-be-available-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/profit-of-low-rate-with-home-loan-cover-home-loan-to-be-available-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कंपनियों का रेग्युलेटर नैशनल हाउजिंग बैंक (NHB) इंश्योरेंस इंस्टीट्यूट ऑफ इंडिया के साथ मिलकर एक ऐसा व्यापक फ्रेमवर्क बनाने पर काम कर रहा है, जिसमें होम लोन का रेट आधा पर्सेंटेज पॉइंट तक घटेगा, बशर्ते लोन लेने वाले इंश्योरेंस कवर लें। मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले सूत्रों ने बताया कि इसका मकसद डिफॉल्ट रिस्क घटाना भी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NHB के नैशनल डायरेक्टर और चीफ एग्जिक्युटिव ऑफिसर श्रीराम कल्याणरमन ने ईटी से बातचीत में इस खबर को सही बताया। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम आपदा (संपत्ति) बीमा की संभावनाओं का पता लगाने के लिए इंश्योरेंस इंस्टीट्यूट ऑफ इंडिया के साथ मिलकर एक सर्वे कर रहे हैं। हम यह पता लगा रहे हैं कि क्या होम लोन लेते वक्त इंश्योरेंस कवर भी लेने पर कम लेंडिंग रेट ऑफर किया जा सकता है?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कल्याणरमन ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इंश्योरेंस कवर से रिस्क प्रीमियम घटना चाहिए। इसका फायदा लेंडर्स कंज्यूमर्स को दे सकते हैं। यह प्रक्रिया पूरी होने पर आने वाले समय में हम एक व्यापक फ्रेमवर्क जारी करेंगे।&amp;rsquo; हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कंपनियों के बीच होम लोन बॉरोअर्स को प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस ऑफर करने का चलन बना है। मिसाल के लिए देश की सबसे बड़ी होम लोन प्रोवाइडर फर्म हाउजिंग डिवेलपमेंट फाइनैंस कॉर्पोरेशन (HDFC) प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस सहित नॉन-लाइफ इंश्योरेंस के लिए HDFC एर्गो प्रॉडक्ट्स ऑफर कर रही है। इसी तरह दीवान हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कॉर्पोरेशन (DHFL) अपनी शाखाओं के जरिए चोलामंडलम एमएस जनरल इंश्योरेंस प्रॉडक्ट्स बेचती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ग्राहक ज्यादा कवरेज पर सस्ते प्रीमियम को तरजीह देते हैं। प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस आमतौर पर भूकंप, बाढ़, आतंकी घटनाओं, आगजनी से हुए नुकसान के अलावा साइक्लोन, आसमानी बिजली गिरने, तोड़फोड़ के चलते होने वाले वित्तीय घाटे से सुरक्षित करता है। फाइनैंशल इंस्टीट्यूशंस और बैंक की तरफ से कई मौकों पर कस्टमर्स को प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस लेने पर मजबूर किए जाने का आरोप लगता रहता है। बिहार, जम्मू कश्मीर, उत्तर प्रदेश, उत्तराखंड, गुजरात में हालिया प्राकृतिक आपदाओं ने स्टेकहोल्डर्स का घाटा घटाने के उपाय के तौर पर प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस की अहमियत बढ़ा दी है। मामले से जुड़े एग्जिक्युटिव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधी कवायद हो चुकी है। हालांकि यह पूरी नहीं हुई है लेकिन इससे कम-से-कम आधा पर्सेंटेज पॉइंट का फायदा हो सकता है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस मामले को एक उदाहरण से समझने की कोशिश करते हैं। अभी एक रिटेल होम लोन बॉरोअर 20 साल के लिए 8.6% के रेट से 1 लाख रुपये के होम लोन पर 874 रुपये का ईएमआई चुकाता है। अब इस लोन का रेट 50 बेसिस पॉइंट घटा दिया जाता है तो होम लोन कस्टमर का ईएमआई घटकर 842 रुपये रह जाएगा। यह एस्टीमेट क्रेडिट रेटिंग कंपनी इकरा ने दिया है। इकरा के सीनियर वीपी कार्तिक श्रीनिवासन ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;ऐसे उपाय को अगर अंतिम रूप दे दिया जाता है तो बॉरोअर्स को बहुत मदद मिलेगी। इससे उनको अपना रिस्क प्रोफाइल बेहतर बनाने में तो मदद मिलेगी ही, उनकी लोन लेने की क्षमता भी बढ़ेगी। उनको कम रेट या ज्यादा लोन मिल सकता है। इंश्योरेंस कवर की लागत बॉरोअर्स को उठानी होगी, फिर भी उनको फायदा होगा क्योंकि ऊंचे इंट्रेस्ट रेट के नजरिए से प्रीमियम मामूली होगा।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एनएचबी का कहना है कि प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस के लिए पारदर्शी और सहज ट्रांजैक्शन सिस्टम होने से कंज्यूमर्स, बैंक, हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कंपनियों जैसे लेंडिंग इंस्टीट्यूशंस और इंश्योरेंस कंपनियों का कॉन्फिडेंस बढ़ेगा और इससे कंज्यूमर्स को प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस के लिए खुद आगे आने के लिए बढ़ावा मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जाली नोट के खेल का पता लगाने के लिए बैंकों ने हायर किए फरेंसिक एक्‍सपर्ट्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-forensic-experts-help-banks-take-account-of-fake-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-forensic-experts-help-banks-take-account-of-fake-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;बैंकों ने यह पता लगाने के लिए फरेंसिक एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर किया है कि उनकी किस ब्रांच ने नोटबंदी के बाद जाली करंसी नोट डिपॉजिट किए थे। इसके साथ ही एक्सपर्ट्स यह भी पता लगाएंगे कि जाली नोट जमा करवाने में किस कर्मचारी का हाथ था। इकनॉमिक टाइम्स ने यह जानकारी विश्वसनीय सूत्रों से हासिल की है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक जांचकर्ता ने बताया कि एक मामले में ऐसे एंप्लॉयी का सीधे तौर पर हाथ होने की बात का खुलासा हुआ है, जिसने एक कस्टमर को जाली करंसी नोट जमा कराने में मदद की थी। सूत्र ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;पिछले साल दिसंबर में बैंक एंप्लॉयी ने पहले 500 रुपये के असली करंसी नोट वाला बंडल निकाला और एक कस्टमर को दिया। कस्टमर ने उसी डीनॉमिनेशन वाले नोट में उतनी ही रकम लौटा दी जो दूसरे कस्टमर्स से लिए गए कैश के बंडल में डाल दी गई। बाद में कस्टमर ने ओरिजनल, लेकिन पुरानी करंसी वाले नोट अपने और अपने परिजन के बैंक खातों में डिपॉजिट किए।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दूसरे जांचकर्ता ने बताया कि इस लेन-देन के निशान की छानबीन की जा रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;बैंकों ने डिपॉजिट रेंज और ब्रांच के हिसाब से अपने पास जमा सभी कैश डिपॉजिट को बैच नंबर दिए हैं। कुछ इंटरनल बैकवॉर्ड ट्रैकिंग हो सकती है और जाली करंसी नोट के सोर्स का पता लगाने का तरीका है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ज्यादातर जाली करंसी सिस्टम में इसलिए आ पाए कि 8 नवंबर को हुई नोटबंदी के बाद नोट जमा करने और बदलने के लिए ब्रांच में लगी लोगों की भीड़ में जाली नोटों को पकड़ना बहुत मुश्किल था। ब्लैक मनी और जाली नोट को सिस्टम से निकालने और भ्रष्टाचार को खत्म करने के मकसद से किए गए नोटबंदी के चलते सर्कुलेशन में बनी 86 पर्सेंट करंसी की वैल्यू एक झटके में जीरो हो गई।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक सरकारी बैंक के एग्जिक्युटिव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमने फरेंसिक ऑडिटर्स हायर किए हैं। हमारे ज्यादातर ग्रामीण और कुछ मेट्रो ब्रांच में फर्जी नोट पकड़ने की मशीनें नहीं हैं। लोगों की भीड़ इतनी ज्यादा थी कि हमारे टेलर के पास ब्रांच में भारी भीड़ को हैंडल करने के अलावा कोई और एक्टिविटी करने का वक्त नहीं था।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैंकों ने जाली नोट डिपॉजिट के संदेह वाले बड़े ट्रांजैक्शंस की खबर फाइनैंशल इंटेलीजेंस यूनिट (FIU) को दी थी लेकिन इसमें रकम का कोई अनुमान नहीं दिया गया है। एक बैंकर ने बताया कि आरबीआई ने जाली नोटों का पता लगा लगा लिया है। उसने बैंकों से यह पता लगाने के लिए कहा है कि वे कहां से आए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 स्मार्ट सिटीज के शहरी गरीबों के घर का किराया भी चुकाएगी मोदी सरकार!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-may-pay-your-rent-through-vouchers-soon-in-100-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-may-pay-your-rent-through-vouchers-soon-in-100-cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मोदी सरकार अब आपके फ्लैट, कमरे का किराया चुका सकती है। केंद्र सरकार 100 स्मार्ट सिटीज में जल्द ही 2700 करोड़ रुपए की नई कल्याणकारी योजना की शुरुआत करने जा रही है, जिसके तहत शहरी गरीबों को घर का किराया चुकाने के लिए वाउचर्स दिए जाएंगे। सरकार रेंट वाउचर्स के साथ नई रेंटल हाउजिंग पॉलिसी को गरीबी रेखा से नीचे वाले लोगों के लिए पेश कर सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्मार्ट सिटीज में गरीबों का किराया देने वाली पॉलिसी पर वैसे तो तीन साल से काम चल रहा है, लेकिन इसका पहला कंपोनेंट वित्त वर्ष 2017-18 में लागू किया जा सकता है। स्मार्ट सिटीज में स्कीम को शुरू करने पर हर साल 2,713 करोड़ रुपए की लागत आने की उम्मीद है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस स्कीम को अर्बन पूअर यानी शहरों में रहने वाले गरीबों के लिए लिया जा रहा है, जिससे वहां मजदूरी करने के लिए आने वाले लोगों को मदद मिलेगी। रेंट वाउचर्स को शहरी निकायों की मदद से गरीबों में बांटा जाएगा। किरायेदार इन वाउचर्स को मकान मालिक को देगा, जो उसे किसी सिटीजन सर्विस ब्यूरो से अपने अकाउंट में ट्रांसफर करा सकेंगे। अगर रेंट वाउचर की वैल्यू से अधिक होता है तो किरायेदार को उसका भुगतान अपनी जेब से करना होगा। रेंट वाउचर की वैल्यू शहर और कमरे के साइज के हिसाब से निकाय तय करेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार इस वाउचर स्कीम के लिए डायरेक्ट बेनेफिट ट्रांसफर (DBT) की संभावना भी तलाश रही है। 2011 की जनगणना के मुताबिक, शहरों में करीब 27.5 प्रतिशत आबादी किराए के घरों में रहती है। हालांकि, नैशनल सैंपल सर्वे (NSS) के आंकड़ों के मुताबिक 2009 में शहरों में 35 प्रतिशत लोग किराए के घरों में रहते हैं। इसके अलावा, NSS से यह बात भी सामने आई थी कि यह रेशियो 1991 के बाद से इतना ही बना हुआ है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आवास और शहरी गरीबी उन्मूलन मंत्रालय के एक अधिकारी ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, &amp;lsquo;प्रधानमंत्री की हाउजिंग फॉर ऑल स्कीम के पूरक के तौर पर वाउचर स्कीम को देखा जा रहा है।&amp;rsquo; केंद्र जब्त की गई बेनामी प्रॉपर्टी का इस्तेमाल किफायती घर बनाने के लिए करेगी। इससे घरों की कमी दूर करने में मदद मिलेगी। एक अधिकारी ने&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बताया, &amp;lsquo;हाल में बेनामी प्रॉपर्टीज ऐक्ट को लागू किया गया है। इससे रेंटल हाउजिंग के लिए एक और रास्ता खुल गया है। इन रूल्स में एक ऐसी शर्त डाली जा सकती है कि जो घर केंद्र सरकार जब्त करेगी, उन्हें नीलाम नहीं किया जाएगा बल्कि उन्हें राज्य सरकारों के जरिये केंद्र मिडल इनकम ग्रुप (MIG), लो इनकम ग्रुप (LIG) और गरीबों को रेंटल हाउजिंग के लिए दे सकता है।&amp;rsquo; यह फैसला प्रॉपर्टी की लोकेशन और योग्यता के आधार पर लिया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>500 और 2000 रुपये के नोटों को बचाकर खेलें होली, बैंक नहीं लेंगे रंग लगे नोट</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/keep-500-and-2000-rupees-notes-away-from-colours-in-this-holi-says-rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/keep-500-and-2000-rupees-notes-away-from-colours-in-this-holi-says-rbi/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;अगर आप होली के रंग में रंगने के लिए तैयार हैं तो कुछ एहतियात भी बरतना जरूरी होगा। ध्यान रहे कि होली खेलते वक्त जेब में नोट नहीं पड़े हों क्योंकि 500 और 2,000 रुपये के रंग लगे नोट बैंकों में बिल्कुल स्वीकार नहीं होंगे। होली के रंग में रंगे नोट सिर्फ रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया में ही जमा किए जा सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आरबीआई की क्लीन नोट पॉलिसी के तहत यह गाइड लाइन जारी की गई है। पिछले काफी दिनों से सोशल साइट और वॉट्सऐप आदि पर यह मेसेज भी वायरल हो रहा है। इस मेसेज को बैंक अधिकारियों ने सही बताया है। सेक्टर 16 स्थित पंजाब एंड सिंध बैंक के चीफ मैनेजर अनिल कुमार ने कहा कि आरबीआई की तरफ से ऐसी गाइड लाइन जारी की गई है। 500 और 2,000 रुपये के नोटों पर अगर कोई रंग या कोई पेन चलाया जाता है तो वह नोट बैंकों में जमा नहीं होंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दरअसल नोटबंदी से पहले 500 और 1,000 हजार के नोटों पर अगर किसी तरह कलर या पेन चल जाता, कोई सिग्नेचर कर देता था तो वह नोट बैंकों में चल जाते थे। कई बार त्योहार के मौके पर घरों में बने पकवान का तेल भी नोटों पर लग जाता था। उसके बावजूद ऐसे नोट बैंकों में स्वीकार कर लिए जाते थे। नोटबंदी के बाद आरबीआई ने क्लीन नोट पॉलिसी जारी करते हुए नई करंसी को साफ और स्वच्छ रखने की हिदायत दी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नीलम बाटा रोड स्थित सिंडिकेट बैंक के डीजीएम के. के. अग्रवाल का कहना है कि नोटबंदी से पहले करंसी पर कुछ लोग 500 और 1,000 रुपये के नोट पर अपने नाम लिख देते थे। नोटों पर पहले पंचिंग होती थी, स्टेपलर होते थे, जिस पर आरबीआई ने पूरी तरह रोक लगा दी है। होली के दिन अगर अगर नई करंसी पर पेन भी अगर गलती से चल जाता है या कोई रंग लग जाता है तो ऐसे नोट बैंकों में मान्य नहीं होंगे। ऐसे नोट लोगों को खुद आरबीआई में जाकर जमा करने होंगे। अग्रवाल ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;फेसबुक और वॉट्सऐप आदि पर नई करंसी को लेकर चल रहे मेसेज काफी हद तक सही है। कुछ भी लिखे या होली का रंगे नोटों को बैंक नहीं लेगा। लोगों को खुद आरबीआई में जाकर ऐसे नोट जमा करने पड़ेगे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;बड-न-ट-पर-अगर-र-ग-लग-त-ब-क-म-नह-ह-ग-म-न-य&#34;&gt;बड़े नोटों पर अगर रंग लगा तो बैंक में नहीं होंगे मान्य&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• नोटों पर पेन चलने पर भी बैंक कर देगा रिजेक्ट&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• रंगे हुए नोटों को सीधे आरबीआर्इ में ही कराना होगा जमा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• नोटबंदी से पहले 500 और 1,000 हजार के रंग लगे नोट भी बैंकों में चल जाते थे&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar payments: All you need to know about the new Aadhar Pay app</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-payments-need-know-new-aadhar-pay-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-payments-need-know-new-aadhar-pay-app/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to promote Aadhaar-based payment system, Modi government has launched a new Android app for merchants to accept payments using their biometric data or the registered data under UIDAI’s Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar-based payment system is currently being used by 1,10,000 business correspondents for disbursing cash, and is also being utilised in Common Service Centres to pay for various services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is all you need to know about the newly launched Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-the-new-app-will-work&#34;&gt;How the new app will work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After downloading the app, the user also needs to register with a valid ID. Then he/she needs to fill the required details to validate the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Merchants: After downloading the Aadhaar Pay app from Google Play Store, the user has to install a biometric scanner linked to the user’s smartphone. The user also needs to link his bank account to the phone so that the transaction can be completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Customers: Customers need their Aadhaar number which has to be linked to their bank account. They can use either a fingerprint or biometric data to complete the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages of doing a transaction through Aadhaar app is that no additional charges will be levied unlike debit and credit cards.
Also, the installing cost for a biometric scanner for Aadhaar Pay is much more less than a POS machine. A POS machine costs Rs 5,000 whereas the biometric scanner will cost around Rs 2,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;however-one-of-the-limitation-of-aadhaar-app-payments-is-that-they-can-only-take-place-if-the-internet-is-available&#34;&gt;However, one of the limitation of Aadhaar app payments is that they can only take place if the internet is available.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;meanwhile-here-are-other-related-points-about-the-newly-launched-aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Meanwhile, here are other related points about the newly launched Aadhaar Pay&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app has been jointly developed by UIDAI,NPCI and IDFC Bank. The Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is the nodal body responsible for rolling out the Aadhaar programme in the country. Transactions through the app would be made with the help of registered data under UIDAI’s          Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emphasizing upon the rural pockets of the country, UIDAI has favored “incentives” for merchants using the biometric mode for digital transactions, in line with commission given by banks to Business Correspondents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Ajay Bhushan Pandey, CEO of UIDAI told media, “If a merchant is using Aadhaar-enabled payment systems then he should be put at par with Business Correspondent and whatever facility and commission is available to the Business Correspondent, he should be paid on the same lines”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also added that incentivizing shopkeepers who adopt the biometric payment system would also “remove an extra layer” as consumers today approach banks, ATMs or business correspondents for withdrawal of money to purchase items such as ration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to an Economic Times report, the Government is mulling over an option of giving banks an incentive of up to Rs 10 for each transaction. Quoting a government official, the report stated that a suggestion to provide an incentive of 0.25% on the value of a transaction – capped at Rs 10 –     made on the biometric-based payment system Aadhaar Pay and UPI platform BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The committee of secretaries had said that if they (banks) don’t have incentives, they may not go and acquire merchants, so let them have incentives, and merchant will not bear cost and it may be borne from the financial inclusion fund,” the official told ET.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digital payment channels like mobile wallets, USSD and RuPay have seen massive uptake and rise in transactions post demonetisation on November 8. Even in case of Aadhaar-enabled payment system, the volume of transactions have jumped 2.5 times post demonetisation from 6 lakh a day before November   to 15 lakh transactions per day at present.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPF Withdrawal Rules Relaxed, Get Money In 15 Days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gpf-withdrawal-rules-relaxed-get-money-in-15-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gpf-withdrawal-rules-relaxed-get-money-in-15-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Employees can also withdraw the fund for select purposes after completing 10 years of service, as against 15 years of service earlier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In good news for about 50 lakh central government employees, the norms for withdrawal of General Provident Fund (GPF) have been relaxed which will enable them to receive payments within 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees can also withdraw the fund for select purposes after completing 10 years of service, as against 15 years of service earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GPF can be taken for education &amp;ndash; including primary, secondary and higher education, covering all streams and institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, a subscriber could withdraw GPF for beyond the high school stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some amendments have been made (in rules) from time to time to address the concerns raised by the subscribers. However, the provisions, largely remain restrictive. There is a felt need to liberalise provisions, raise limits and simplify the procedure,&amp;rdquo; the Ministry said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The provisions in the rules have been reviewed and it has now been decided to permit withdrawals from the fund by the subscriber for obligatory expenses viz. betrothal (engagement), marriage, funerals, or other ceremonies of self or family members and dependants, besides illness of self, family members or dependants, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It has been decided to permit withdrawal of up to twelve months pay or three-fourth of the amount standing at credit, whichever is less. For illness, the withdrawal may be allowed up to 90 per cent of the amount standing at credit of the subscriber. A subscriber may seek withdrawal after completion of ten years of service,&amp;rdquo; the ministry said in an order to all central government departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GPF can be withdrawn for purchase of consumer durables also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing rules do not give any time limit or sanction and payment of withdrawal amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Therefore, it has been decided to prescribe a maximum time limit of fifteen days for sanction and payment of withdrawal from the fund. In case of emergencies like illness etc., the time limit maybe restricted to seven days,&amp;rdquo; the order said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the employees also do not have to furnish any documentary proof in support of their request to withdraw from GPF except for a self-declaration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all cases of withdrawal from the fund by the subscriber, the declared head of department (HOD) is competent to sanction withdrawal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No documentary proof will be required to be furnished by the subscriber. A simple declaration form by the subscriber explaining the reasons for withdrawal would be sufficient,&amp;rdquo; the order said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, withdrawal of up to 90 per cent of balance without assigning reasons is allowed for government servants who are due for retirement on superannuation within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is proposed that this may be allowed for up to two years before superannuation, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GPF can be withdrawn for purchase of motor car, motor cycle, scooter etc. or for repayment of loan already taken for the purpose, as per new rules issued by Ministry of Personnel, Public Grievances and Pensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount will also be made available for making deposit to book a car or motor cycle, besides their extensive repair or overhauling, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The withdrawal will also be allowed for housing including building or acquiring a suitable house or ready built flat, repayment of outstanding housing loan, purchase of house site for building a house, constructing a house on a site acquired, reconstructing or making additions on a house already acquired besides renovating, additions or alterations of ancestral house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is also decided do away with the present instructions which lay down that subsequent to the sale of house for which GPF withdrawal has been availed, the amount withdrawn has to be deposited back. GPF withdrawal for housing purpose will no longer be linked with the limits prescribed under House Building Advance (HBA) rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A subscriber may be permitted to avail the facility at any time during his service,&amp;rdquo; the new rules said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Justifies Penalty For Not Keeping Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-justifies-penalty-for-not-keeping-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-justifies-penalty-for-not-keeping-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI also said it has not received any &amp;ldquo;formal communication&amp;rdquo; from the government for re-considering the penalty and it will take a call &amp;ldquo;if something comes&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facing a backlash for levying penalty on non-maintenance of minimum balance in accounts, State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, on Wednesday justified its move saying the bank needs to impose some charges to balance the &amp;ldquo;burden&amp;rdquo; of managing a large number of no-frills Jan Dhan accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank also said it has not received any &amp;ldquo;formal communication&amp;rdquo; from the government for re-considering the penalty and it will take a call &amp;ldquo;if something comes&amp;rdquo;. It also clarified the penalty would not apply to Jan Dhan accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank decided to reintroduce penalty on non-maintenance of minimum balance in accounts and also revised charges on other banking services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new charges would be applicable from April 1. The move by the state-run banking major has faced a lot of criticism, including from the opposition parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Today, we have lot of burden such as we have 11 crore financial inclusion or Jan Dhan accounts. To manage such a large number of Jan Dhan accounts, we need some charges. We have considered many factors and after analysing carefully, we have taken this step,&amp;rdquo; State Bank of India chairperson Arundhati Bhattacharya told reporters here on the sidelines of a national convention of women entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the list of revised charges of SBI, failure to maintain monthly average balance (MAB) in accounts will attract a penalty of up to Rs 100 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In metropolitan areas, there will be a charge of Rs 100 plus service tax, if the balance falls below 75 per cent of the monthly average balance of Rs 5,000. If the shortfall is 50 per cent or less of the MAB, then the bank will charge Rs 50 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The charges and monthly average balance varies according to the location of bank. It is minimum in case of rural branches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms Bhattacharya said that all the banks have minimum balance requirement for account holders and SBI as such has the lowest minimum balance requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said the penalty was there earlier also and State Bank of India was the only bank to withdraw it in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our analysis have shown that most of the account holders maintain more than Rs 5,000 on a monthly basis and so they do not have to worry about any penalty,&amp;rdquo; Ms Bhattacharya said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She clarified that the penalty on non-maintenance of minimum balance will not be applicable on Jan Dhan accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked about the government&amp;rsquo;s direction to the bank to reconsider the decision, SBI managing director (national banking) Rajnish Kumar said the bank has not received any communication on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no formal communication. We will see if something comes,&amp;rdquo; Mr Kumar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the revised charges, withdrawal of cash from ATMs will attract a charge of up to Rs 20 if the number of transactions exceeds three from other bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs in a month and Rs 10 for more than five withdrawals from State Bank of India ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, SBI will not levy any charge on withdrawals from its own ATMs if the balance exceeds Rs 25,000. In case of withdrawal by its customers from ATMs of other banks, there will be no charge if the balance exceeds Rs 1 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are charging as people go to ATMs, withdraw cash and give it to somebody who in turns deposit it into the bank. This type of transaction involves a cost which is not known to public as bankers do not levy any charge on the customers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is some cost involved in printing cash, in transportation, counting and providing security to cash. The cost is borne by the tax payers. There is a cost in installing an ATM and so we feel the charges are very reasonable,&amp;rdquo; Ms Bhattacharya said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said the customers must use alternate channels like mobile, internet to do their transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We do not see there is a requirement for an household person to withdraw cash through ATMs for more than four times. Daily cash requirement is more for people doing businesses and we want them to use mobile and internet banking to do transactions,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While addressing the convention, Ms Bhattacharya said the bank so far has given loan worth to Rs 1,60,000 crore to the MSME sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This year alone we have done more than Rs 10,000 crore. We wish to do around Rs 16,000 crore of Mudra loans by the end of this financial year,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, nearly 55 per cent of the bank&amp;rsquo;s balance sheet comprises retail segment and balance is to large segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have no problem at all if I am able to tilt that more in favour of retail. I would love to do that. Of course large segment needs support because of that you would have the airports &amp;hellip; the roads you have today, for defence you are going to set up an SME and for that you need steel, cement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So, the large sector also needs support from the bank. But that does not mean that we (banks) are not there for you (retail segment),&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>