<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Lucky Grahak, Digi Dhan: Rs 1 Crore Jackpot For Person Making Rs 1,590 Digital Payment</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of the Digi Dhan scheme, three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were declared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Pranab Mukherjee picked six winners from a draw of lots under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes, aimed at promoting digital transactions in the country. &amp;ldquo;In the consumer category, three mega Prizes of Rs 1 crore, Rs 50 lakh and Rs 25 lakh went to the Consumers using Rupay Debit Cards making digital payment of less than Rs.1,000,&amp;rdquo; an official release said. Three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were also declared at the event on the final day of the 100-day scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction of Rs. 1,590 won a Central Bank of India customer a lucky draw of Rs. 1 crore under the consumer category, as part of the government&amp;rsquo;s promotional scheme to popularise digital payments. The President congratulated all the six winners - three consumers and three merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am happy today to be a part of the digital payment movement that India has embarked upon. I congratulate each one of you who has contributed in this mission to make India a less cash society,&amp;rdquo; the President said in his address on the occasion of mega draw of lots for the two schemes held at Rashtrapati Bhawan on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners will be felicitated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on April 14 at Nagpur on the occasion of Ambedkar Jayanti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his address, Mr Mukherjee asked citizens to extend their unstinted support to the mission of a less-cash India. &amp;ldquo;India has a long way to go to become a cash less society. The initiatives of the government are a good beginning and we need to sustain and nurture these with active participation from all segments of the society&amp;hellip;It is necessary to reduce cash in circulation and impart greater urgency to promoting secure digital payment methods to ensure greater transparency,&amp;rdquo; the President said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the consumer section, the second prize of Rs 50 lakh went to a Bank of Baroda customer while the third prize of Rs. 25 lakh was bagged by a customer of Punjab National Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the three customers had made the transactions using their RuPay debit cards. The names of three winners were not yet known as the draw only displayed their transaction numbers. These will be matched with card details to identify the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital transactions have gathered momentum giving a fillip to the less cash economy post demonetisation thanks to the initiatives taken by the government. NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digidhan Vyapar schemes have played a catalytic role in making it a mass movement, the statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressing that India is on the cusp of a digital revolution, Mr Mukherjee noted that more than one billion Indians have a unique identity number with a biometric identifier which is unique in its own way. &amp;ldquo;Even countries which are technologically far more advanced than India with comparatively much smaller size population do not have such a system in place. The Aadhaar card initiative is a watershed event in the development story of India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs. 1,000 notes on November 9 last year, the government took a slew of measures to promote digital payments in the country. It had launched the Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes on December 25 last year for consumers and merchants, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes are being implemented by the National Payment Corporation of India (NPCI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the scheme, daily, weekly and monthly rewards worth Rs. 256 crore have been disbursed to over 16 lakh citizens over the past 100 days for making and accepting small transactions digitally. Over the past 100 days, everyday 15,000 consumers have qualified for total prize money of Rs. 1.5 crore, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The draw has seen a positive impact from various age groups and occupations in adopting digital payments methods. We have seen a steady increase in the number of transactions made using all payment methods,&amp;rdquo; said A P Hota, MD and CEO of National Payment Corporation of India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Accounts To Be Blocked If Not Self-Certified By April 30. What To Do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions, without which the accounts would be blocked, the income tax department said. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Account holders are informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till 30.4.2017,A/Cs would be blocked : pic.twitter.com/YICvRHqfPm
— Income Tax India (@IncomeTaxIndia) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Investors are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed, the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014-August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016, extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The financial institutions were advised to continue to work on completing the required due diligence, including obtaining self-certifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them. (With agency inputs)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar With Your PAN Card Just by Uploading a Scanned Proof</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Individuals struggling to link their Permanent Account Number with Aadhaar because of differently spelt names can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the tax department is planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for a One-Time Password (OTP), provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the linking of PAN with Aadhaar being made mandatory, individuals can log on to e-filing website of the income tax department or NSDL but the seeding cannot happen if the name is differently spelt in the two cards – like use of full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, government has allowed a simple uploading of a scanned copy of PAN on the Aadhaar website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had through amendment to tax proposals in the Finance Bill of the Budget for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-filing portal has already activated a functionality of linking PAN with Aadhaar. Over 1.08 crore assessees have already Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official said that linking of PAN with Aadhaar should not be cumbersome for people whose registered mobile number with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In case the taxpayer is unable to link PAN with Aadhaar because of discrepancy in name, we are advising them to log in to the Aadhaar website, request for a name change and upload a scanned copy of PAN card as supported proof. This is the simplest way to update name in Aadhaar and only the registered mobile number has to be functional,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This option will hold good for people who have given short forms of their name or in some cases there are some spelling errors in the name provided in Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in certain cases, there are people who have got married and changed their surname and updated the same while getting Aadhaar number, but it does not get reflected in PAN documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such and other name change cases, the tax department is planning to give the OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number and the tax department, on its part, would match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are also contemplating that when taxpayers with name discrepancy logs into the e-filing website for linkage, we will send OTP to the Aadhaar registered mobile number. The taxpayer can link PAN using the OTP. While generating the OTP, we will just check if the year of birth of the taxpayer in PAN card matches with the year given in the Aadhaar document,” the official added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, You Can Get A PAN Or TAN Within A Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax department today said it has issued Permanent Account Number (PAN) within a day to 19,704 newly incorporated companies till March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Applicant would be benefited by having a digitally signed E-PAN card which they can submit as proof of identity to other agency electronically directly or by storing in the Digital Locker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; CBDT, the apex policy making body of the Income Tax department, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said that newly incorporated companies have also been issued Tax Deduction Account Number (TAN) simultaneously with PAN as the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) has tied up with the Ministry of Corporate Affairs (MCA) under which companies can submit a common application form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicant companies submit a common application form SPICe (INC 32) on MCA portal and once the data of incorporation is sent to CBDT by the MCA, PAN and TAN are issued immediately without any further intervention of the applicant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Certificate of Incorporation (COI) of newly incorporated companies includes the PAN in addition to the Corporate Identity Number (CIN). TAN is also allotted simultaneously and communicated to the company,&amp;rdquo; the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till March 31, 2017, 19,704 newly incorporated companies were allotted PAN in this manner. During March 2017, of the 10,894 newly incorporated companies, PAN was allotted within 4 hours in 95.63 per cent cases and within one day in all cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, TAN was allotted to all such companies within 4 hrs in 94.7 per cent cases and within 1 day in 99.73 per cent cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;CBDT&amp;rsquo;s initiative in starting of a business is expected to significantly improve the ranking of India in the Ease of Doing Business Study conducted by World Bank by reducing the number of processes of registration before various authorities under law, reducing the time taken for allotment of the registration number (CIN, PAN, TAN) and making the entire registration process for new companies much simpler,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petrol Pumps Threaten Sundays Off, 9-To-6 On Other Days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-threaten-sundays-off-9-to-6-on-other-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-threaten-sundays-off-9-to-6-on-other-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Petrol pump owners across the country have threatened to shut down filling stations on Sundays unless their demands for higher margins are met. They have also said that filling stations will operate from 9 am to 6 pm to cut costs, unless the government intervenes. Ravi Shinde, general secretary of Consortium of Indian Petroleum Dealers, told NDTV Profit that pump owners have decided to observe Sunday offs from May 14 while from May 15, &lt;em&gt;dealers will operate from 9 am to 6 pm.&lt;/em&gt; Consortium of Indian Petroleum Dealers, an all-India organisation, represents over 50,000 petrol pump dealers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Shinde also said the petrol dealers association will observe May 10 as a &amp;ldquo;No Purchase Day&amp;rdquo; to press for their demands. &amp;ldquo;Not much of disruption is expected, but it will be an indication for oil companies to take note that dealers are on war path,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elaborating on pump owners&amp;rsquo; demands, Mr Shinde said oil marketing companies &amp;ldquo;have not honoured their written commitment of giving dealer margins in line with Apurva Chandra committee report&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the committee&amp;rsquo;s calculations, dealers should be getting Rs 3,333 per kilolitre on petrol and Rs 2,126 per kilolitre on diesel, he said, referring to dealers&amp;rsquo; margins. &amp;ldquo;We are currently getting Rs 2,570 and Rs 1,620 for petrol and diesel respectively,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petrol pump owners had in January threatened to stop accepting card payments over levy on digital payments, forcing the government to intervene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuel consumption in India grew at a slower rate of 5 per cent in the last fiscal year, which ended on March 31, 2017, as diesel demand cooled down. The world&amp;rsquo;s third largest oil consumer saw demand for fuel and petroleum products rise to 194.2 million tonnes in 2016-17, up from 184.6 MT in the previous fiscal year, data from Petroleum Planning and Analysis Cell (PPAC) of the Oil Ministry showed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 309 Jio&#39;s Plan, Offers &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-next-move-offers-dhan-dhana-dhan-plan-starting-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-next-move-offers-dhan-dhana-dhan-plan-starting-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier with a recharge of Rs 309, subscribers used to get 28GB data for 28 days, but under the Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, they will now get 84GB data for 84 days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After withdrawing the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, Reliance Jio came up with another plan offering unlimited data, SMS and voice calling for three months. Starting Rs 309, &amp;lsquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plan offers 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days. Earlier with a recharge of Rs 303, subscribers used to get 28GB data for 28 days, but under the ‘Dhan Dhana Dhan’ offer, they will now get 84GB data for 84 days. Also, with a recharge of Rs 509, users will get 2GB data per day for 84 days instead of 56GB data for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few days back, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) had asked Jio to withdraw the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer as the regulator observed that the plan did not fit into the &amp;ldquo;regulatory framework&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio also tweeted the details of the plan and said, &amp;ldquo;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to live the #JioDhanDhanaDhan life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/msid-58130455,width-400,resizemode-4,-10-.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Jio &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer is limited to only one recharge and is not available along with &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, the website stated. These plans are only for Jio Prime users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for Jio non-Prime members the offer is valid but at a higher price. For 1GB data per day for 84 days will cost Rs 408 (Rs 309 + Rs 99). And, for 2GB data per day for a period of 84 days, customers will have to shell out Rs 608 (Rs 509 + Rs 99).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot from the company&amp;rsquo;s website:
reliance jio
Jio recently clocked 72 million paid users and extended its one-time Rs 99 payment membership programme Prime till April 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entry of Reliance Jio has created a stir in the telecom market with every operator offering various discounts on prepaid and postpaid plans in an effort to keep up with the new entrant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Reliance-Jio-VoLTE-feature-phone.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen. It also has a dedicated button for torchlight. Maker of this feature phone is not known yet. Currently we don’t have any specifications of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to recent reports, Jio will launch these VoLTE-enabled feature phones starting at Rs. 999 that will run on Android operating system. Earlier reports said that capability to make VoLTE calls in these feature phones will be enabled by Spreadtrum chips, and Jio is in talks with Qualcomm and MediaTek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Jio plans start as low as Rs. 149 per month offering unlimited calls, this will be useful for those who make a lot of calls and need a cheap phone with a keypad. We should know more details about more upcoming VoLTE-enabled feature phones from Jio soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आपके पास हों तो फिलहाल संभालकर रखें बंद हो चुके नोट, जुलाई में सुप्रीम कोर्ट से मिल सकती है राहत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/supreme-court-ruling-on-note-exchange-window-in-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/supreme-court-ruling-on-note-exchange-window-in-july/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपके पास अब भी 1,000 और 500 रुपये के पुराने नोट बचे हैं तो इसे कम-से-कम जुलाई के आखिर तक सुरक्षित रखिए। सुप्रीम कोर्ट जुलाई में यह तय करेगा कि जो लोग उचित कारणों से या 8 नवंबर 2016 को नोटबंदी की घोषणा करते वक्त प्रधानमंत्री के वादे पर ऐतबार कर 30 दिसंबर 2016 तक पुराने नोट बंद नहीं कर सके, क्या उनके लिए सरकार को एक और मौका दिए जाने को कहा जाना चाहिए या नहीं। गौरतलब है कि प्रधानमंत्री ने 8 नवंबर के भाषण में चलन से बाहर किए गए नोट 30 दिसंबर के बाद भी जमा कराने का मौका दिए जाने की बात कही थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मंगलवार को सुप्रीम कोर्ट में संबंधित याचिका पर सुनवाई के दौरान अटॉर्नी जनरल मुकुल रोहतगी ने केंद्र सरकार का पक्ष रखा। उन्होंने कहा कि नोटबंदी पर लाए गए अध्यादेश में मियाद बढ़ाकर नागरिकों को नोट जमा कराने का एक और मौका दिए जाने की कोई बाध्यता नहीं है। अध्यादेश में चलन से बाहर हुए नोटों को रखना अपराध माना गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दर्जनभर से ज्यादा याचिकाकर्ताओं ने 30 दिसंबर से पहले नोट जमा नहीं करा पाने की विभिन्न वजहों का हवाला दिया। उनके वकीलों ने कोर्ट में शिकायत की कि केंद्र सरकार ने इन मामलों के बिल्कुल जुदा कारणों पर प्रतिक्रिया दिए बिना एक सामान्य सा शपथ पत्र दायर कर दिया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रोहतगी ने कहा कि सरकार की राय में अब बंद हो चुके नोटों को जमा कराने का कोई दूसरा मौका नहीं दिया जाएगा। केंद्र के शपथ पत्र में एक मामले का जिक्र है जिसमें याचिकाकर्ता ने 66.80 लाख रुपये मूल्य के पुराने नोट जमा कराने की मांग की है और कहा कि वह इसलिए नोट जमा नहीं करा सका क्योंकि उसका बैंक अकाउंट केवाइसी से जुड़ा नहीं था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मुख्य न्यायाधीश जे एस खेहर, जस्टिस डी वाई चंद्रचूड़ और जस्टिस संजय किशन कौल ने पुराने नोटों को रद्दी होते देखने की पीड़ा से राहत पाने के व्यक्तिगत प्रयासों में दिलचस्पी लेने से इनकार कर दिया। इन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम यह फैसला करेंगे कि क्या एक और मौका मिलेगा या नहीं। अगर हां, तो सभी को फायदा होगा।&amp;rsquo; रोहतगी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;अगर सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने पुराने नोट बदलवाने का सीमित मौका देने का फैसला करेगा तो भी यह सरकार ही तय करेगी कि 30 दिसंबर तक नोट जमा नहीं करवा पाने का किसका कारण उचित है और किसका अनुचित।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जानें, क्रेडिट कार्ड के बेहद &#39;खास&#39; फायदे</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/advantages-of-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड रखना यानी उधार की जिंदगी जीना, अरे यह हम नहीं कह रहे बल्कि आमतौर पर इस तरह की बातें हमारे आसपास के लोग बोलते दिख जाते हैं। अगर आप भी ऐसा ही सोचते हैं तो अगले कुछ मिनट्स में आपके यह सोच बदलने वाली है। जी हां, आज हम आपको बता रहे हैं क्रेडिट कार्ड रखने के कुछ बेहद खास फायदे&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-ब-क&#34;&gt;कैश बैक&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कई क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां कुछ खास ब्रैंड्स के साथ 10 से 20 प्रतिशत तक का कैश बैक ऑफर देती हैं। यानी कैशलेश पेमेंट भी करिए और बचत भी पाइए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;र-व-र-ड-प-इ-ट&#34;&gt;रिवॉर्ड पॉइंट&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कैैश बैक के अलावा सभी क्रेडिट कार्ड कंपनियां प्रत्येक ट्रांजैक्शन के वेट के अनुसार पॉइंट्स देती हैं। पॉइंट्स आपके खाते में जुड़ते जाते हैं और बाद में आप इन्हें रिडीम कर सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-र-ड-ट-ह-स-ट-र&#34;&gt;क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड के प्रयोग से आप अपनी क्रेडिट हिस्ट्री अपने साथ रख सकते हैं। यानि आपको पता रहता है कि आपने कब कहां कितना पैसा खर्च किया।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;क-श-क-झ-झट-नह&#34;&gt;कैश का झंझट नहीं&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;क्रेडिट कार्ड का सबसे बड़ा फायदा यह है कि आपको इस बात की चिंता करने की नहीं जरूरत होती है कि बैंक में बैलेंस है या नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;emi-क-व-कल-प&#34;&gt;EMI का विकल्प&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अगर आपका मन कोई बड़ी चीज खरीदने का है, लेकिन पैसे नहीं, तो क्रेडिट कार्ड से खरीद कर आप उस पैसे को ईएमआई यानि किश्तों में बदल सकते हैं। कई बार क्रेडिट कार्ड जीरो प्रतिशत ब्याज पर ईएमआई देते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जाली नोट के खेल का पता लगाने के लिए बैंकों ने हायर किए फरेंसिक एक्‍सपर्ट्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-forensic-experts-help-banks-take-account-of-fake-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-forensic-experts-help-banks-take-account-of-fake-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;बैंकों ने यह पता लगाने के लिए फरेंसिक एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर किया है कि उनकी किस ब्रांच ने नोटबंदी के बाद जाली करंसी नोट डिपॉजिट किए थे। इसके साथ ही एक्सपर्ट्स यह भी पता लगाएंगे कि जाली नोट जमा करवाने में किस कर्मचारी का हाथ था। इकनॉमिक टाइम्स ने यह जानकारी विश्वसनीय सूत्रों से हासिल की है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक जांचकर्ता ने बताया कि एक मामले में ऐसे एंप्लॉयी का सीधे तौर पर हाथ होने की बात का खुलासा हुआ है, जिसने एक कस्टमर को जाली करंसी नोट जमा कराने में मदद की थी। सूत्र ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;पिछले साल दिसंबर में बैंक एंप्लॉयी ने पहले 500 रुपये के असली करंसी नोट वाला बंडल निकाला और एक कस्टमर को दिया। कस्टमर ने उसी डीनॉमिनेशन वाले नोट में उतनी ही रकम लौटा दी जो दूसरे कस्टमर्स से लिए गए कैश के बंडल में डाल दी गई। बाद में कस्टमर ने ओरिजनल, लेकिन पुरानी करंसी वाले नोट अपने और अपने परिजन के बैंक खातों में डिपॉजिट किए।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दूसरे जांचकर्ता ने बताया कि इस लेन-देन के निशान की छानबीन की जा रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;बैंकों ने डिपॉजिट रेंज और ब्रांच के हिसाब से अपने पास जमा सभी कैश डिपॉजिट को बैच नंबर दिए हैं। कुछ इंटरनल बैकवॉर्ड ट्रैकिंग हो सकती है और जाली करंसी नोट के सोर्स का पता लगाने का तरीका है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ज्यादातर जाली करंसी सिस्टम में इसलिए आ पाए कि 8 नवंबर को हुई नोटबंदी के बाद नोट जमा करने और बदलने के लिए ब्रांच में लगी लोगों की भीड़ में जाली नोटों को पकड़ना बहुत मुश्किल था। ब्लैक मनी और जाली नोट को सिस्टम से निकालने और भ्रष्टाचार को खत्म करने के मकसद से किए गए नोटबंदी के चलते सर्कुलेशन में बनी 86 पर्सेंट करंसी की वैल्यू एक झटके में जीरो हो गई।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक सरकारी बैंक के एग्जिक्युटिव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमने फरेंसिक ऑडिटर्स हायर किए हैं। हमारे ज्यादातर ग्रामीण और कुछ मेट्रो ब्रांच में फर्जी नोट पकड़ने की मशीनें नहीं हैं। लोगों की भीड़ इतनी ज्यादा थी कि हमारे टेलर के पास ब्रांच में भारी भीड़ को हैंडल करने के अलावा कोई और एक्टिविटी करने का वक्त नहीं था।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बैंकों ने जाली नोट डिपॉजिट के संदेह वाले बड़े ट्रांजैक्शंस की खबर फाइनैंशल इंटेलीजेंस यूनिट (FIU) को दी थी लेकिन इसमें रकम का कोई अनुमान नहीं दिया गया है। एक बैंकर ने बताया कि आरबीआई ने जाली नोटों का पता लगा लगा लिया है। उसने बैंकों से यह पता लगाने के लिए कहा है कि वे कहां से आए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जियो के &#39;धन धना धन&#39; पर टेंशन में एयरटेल</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-launches-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer-at-rs-309/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-launches-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer-at-rs-309/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;रिलायंस जियो ने मंगलवार को अपने यूजर्स के लिए धन धना धन आॅफर लॉन्च किया है। इस नये आॅफर के तहत कंपनी यूजर्स को 309 रुपये में 3 महीने तक अनलिमिटेड डेटा, कॉल और एसएमएस सर्विस फ्री दे रही है। इस प्लान में हर रोज 1 जीबी डेटा मिलेगा और इसकी वलिडिटी 84 दिन रहेगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इसके अलावा एक अन्य प्लान भी है जिसमें 509 रुपये देने होंगे और इसमें यूजर्स को रोज 2 जीबी डेटा मिलेगा। इसकी वलिडिटी भी 84 दिन रहेगी।&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/msid-58130455,width-400,resizemode-4,-10-.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;ये दोनों प्लान जियो प्राइम मेंबर्स के लिए एक्सक्लूसिव होंगे। हालांकि, यह नया आॅफर उनको नहीं मिलेगा जिन्होंने &amp;lsquo;समर सरप्राइज&amp;rsquo; आॅफर ले रखा है। नॉन प्राइम यूजर्स के लिए हर रोज 1 जीबी डेटा प्लान की कीमत 408 रुपये रखी गई है। जबकि 2 जीबी रोज डेटा की डिमांड करने वाले यूजर्स को 608 रुपये देने होंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जियो ने यह आॅफर 11 अप्रैल को समर सरप्राइज आॅफर को वापस लेने के बाद लॉन्च किया। कंपनी ने इसके बारे में अपनी आॅफिशल वेबसाइट पर नोटिफिकेशन भी जारी किया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फरवरी में इसी साल रिलायंस चेयरमैन मुकेश अंबानी ने जियो प्राइम मेंबरशिप के बारे में घोषणा की थी। इसकी वन टाइम सब्सक्रिप्शन फीस 99 रुपये रखी गई थी। यह प्राइम मेंबरशिप एक साल के लिए अवलेबल थी। इसमें कस्टमर्स को 149 रुपये से शुरू होने वाले तरह-तरह के प्लान चुनने की सुविधा दी गई थी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>भविष्य में सभी कार्डों की जगह ले लेगा आधार कार्ड: अरुण जेटली</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-become-the-only-card-in-future-says-arun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लोकसभा ने बुधवार को वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली की ओर से पेश वित्त विधेयक को चर्चा के बाद पारित कर दिया। चर्चा के दौरान अरुण जेटली ने कहा कि आने वाले दिनों में आधार ही एकमात्र कार्ड होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि भविष्य में यह वोटर आईडी कार्ड और पैन कार्ड जैसे दस्तावेजों की जगह ले लेगा। इन सभी के मुकाबले एक आधार कार्ड ही किसी भी व्यक्ति की पहचान के लिए काफी होगा। लोकसभा में एक सांसद की ओर से पूछा गया था कि आधार कार्ड जारी किए जाने के बाद भी कई कार्डों की व्यवस्था क्यों लागू है। इसके जवाब में जेटली ने यह बात कही। उन्होंने कहा कि आने वाले वक्त में आधार ही व्यक्तिगत पहचान और पते के लिए पुख्ता सबूत होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाए जाने के सवाल पर जेटली ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;तमाम लोगों को कई पैन नंबर इस्तेमाल करते हुए पाया गया है। इसलिए सरकार ने इस व्यवस्था को लागू करने का फैसला लिया है।&amp;rsquo; जेटली ने एक सवाल के जवाब में कहा, &amp;lsquo;आज 98 फीसदी नागरिकों के पास आधार कार्ड है। टैक्स रिटर्न फाइल करने के दौरान व्यक्ति आधार नंबर दे सकता है या यह बता सकता है कि उसने आवेदन कर दिया है, लेकिन टैक्स चोरी की अनुमति नहीं दी जा सकती है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री ने कहा कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा लोगों को टैक्स की व्यवस्था से जोड़ने की जरूरत है। इसीलिए सरकार ने इस साल टैक्स स्लैब को नीचे लाने का प्रयास किया है। चर्चा के दौरान जेटली ने नोटबंदी को सही फैसला करार देते हुए इकॉनमिस्ट मार्टिन वॉल्फ के एक आर्टिकल का उदाहरण देते हुए कहा कि उन्होंने इसकी सराहना की है। जेटली ने लेख का हवाला देते हुए कहा, &amp;lsquo;इससे सरकार को ब्लैक मनी पर टैक्स लगाने का मौका मिला है। बड़े पैमाने पर कैश रखने वाले लोगों के लिए रिस्क पैदा हुआ है। इसके अलावा क्रिमिनल्स के पास जमा संपत्ति सरकार के पास आई है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रिश्तेदार को किराया देते हैं तो टैक्स छूट के लिए देना होगा सबूत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-relief-on-hra-you-need-proof-of-rent-paid-to-kin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-relief-on-hra-you-need-proof-of-rent-paid-to-kin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;हाल ही में मुंबई इनकम टैक्स अपेलट ट्राइब्यूनल (आईटीएटी) ने एक करदाता का आवास किराया भत्ता (एचआरए) का दावा खारिज कर दिया। उसने अपनी मां को कैश में किराया दिया था, लेकिन इसे साबित नहीं कर सकी। दूसरी ओर, अहमदाबाद आईटीएटी ने ऐसे टैक्सपेयर का एचआरए क्लेम को स्वीकार कर लिया जिन्होंने अपनी पत्नी को किराया दिया था। वेतनभोगी वर्ग के पास टैक्स छूट पाने के सीमित उपाय होने के मद्देनजर कुछ नौकरीपेशा लोग साथ रहने वाले अपने पारिवारिक सदस्य को ही किराया देने का दावा कर विभिन्न प्रावधानों के तहत आयकर छूट का भरपूर लाभ उठाना चाहते हैं। भले ही किराया वास्तव में रिश्तेदार को दिया गया हो या नहीं अथवा किराये की रसीद सही है कि नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आईटीएटी के ऊपर वाले दोनों विरोधाभासी फैसले से हम क्या सबक ले सकते हैं? मूल बात यह है कि पारिवारिक सदस्य या करीबी रिश्तेदार को किराया देना गैर-कानूनी नहीं है, लेकिन इसमें यह जोखिम यह है कि अगर अपने दावे का पूरा-पूरा सबूत नहीं दे पाते हैं तो आयकर अधिकारी गहरी छानबीन करेंगे और आपका दावा खारिज हो जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यूं बन सकते हैं टैक्स छूट के दावेदार&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इसलिए, रिश्तेदारों को रेंट देते वक्त सावधानियां जरूरी हैं। मसलन, जिसे किराया देते हैं, उसके साथ लीव ऐंड लाइसेंस अग्रीमेंट बनाएं और बैंकिंग चैनल्स से किराया दें। आयकर कानून की धारा 10 (13A) के तहत कोई सैलरीड टैक्सपेयर एचआरए पर टैक्स छूट का दावा कर सकता है। बशर्ते वह जहां रह रहा है, वह प्रॉपर्टी उस पर उसका मालिकाना हक नहीं हैं और वह रहने के लिए सच में किराया चुका है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सलाहकार संस्था ईवाइ इंडिया के पार्टनर अमरपाल एस चड्ठा कहते हैं, &amp;lsquo;जीवनसाथी या माता-पिता को किराया देने से एचआरए पर टैक्स छूट पाने की आपकी योग्यता तब तक कम नहीं होती जब तक कि उपर्युक्त शर्तें पूरी की जा रही हों और लेनदेन बिल्कुल सही हो। लेनदेन सिर्फ टैक्स से बचने का जरिया मात्र नहीं हो।&amp;rsquo; इसलिए, मुंबई और अहमदाबाद के ट्राइब्यूनल्स के फैसले एक-दूसरे के विरोधाभासी जान पड़ते हैं, लेकिन दोनों मामलों में फैसले तथ्यों पर आधारित हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यूं खारिज हुआ दावा&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बजरंग प्रसाद रामधारी केस में अहमदाबाद इनकम टैक्स अपेलट ट्राइब्यूनल बेंच ने साल 2013 में करदाता का एचआरए छूट का दावा मान लिया, हालांकि किराया पत्नी को दिया जा रहा था। वह अपनी पत्नी के साथ रह रहे थे और बैंक ट्रांसफर के जरिए पत्नी को किराया दे रहे थे। आईटीएटी ने फैसले में कहा कि टैक्सपेयर ने दोनों अनिवार्यताएं पूरी कीं। उसने यह साबित किया कि वह वहां रह रहा है जिस पर उसका मालिकाना हक नहीं है और इसके लिए वह अपनी पत्नी को किराया दे रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;तो अधिकारियों को होता है शक&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सीए फर्म मनोहर चौधरी ऐंड असोसिएट्स के टैक्स पार्टनर अमीत पटेल कहते हैं, &amp;lsquo;दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स ऐक्ट में ऐसा कुछ भी नहीं है जो नजदीकी रिश्तेदार को किराया देने पर किसी नौकरीपेशा व्यक्ति को धारा 10(13A)के तहत एचआरए इग्जेंप्शन से रोके। हालांकि, धारा 143(2) आयकर अधिकारियों को अधिकार देता है कि वो ऐसे दावों की सत्यता की जांच कर सकें।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आमतौर पर कोई अपने जीवनसाथी या माता-पिता को किराया नहीं देता है। मैं भी ऐसे लेनदेन में फंसने की सलाह नहीं देता हूं क्योंकि ऐसे दावे पर आयकर अधिकारियों के कान खड़े होना स्वाभाविक है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ब्याज के साथ जुर्माने का प्रावधान&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इधर, एस चड्ढा का कहना है, अगर नजदीकी रिश्तेदार को किराया देने के मामले में एचआरए पर टैक्स छूट का दावा खारिज हो जाता है तो बताई गई रकम को आपकी आमदनी मानी जाएगी। फिर आपको इनकम टैक्स देने में देरी की वजह से ब्याज सहित टैक्स चुकाना होगा। इतना ही नहीं, अगर आयकर अधिकारियों ने चाहा तो आमदनी छिपाने का दोषी बताकर आपसे जुर्माना भी वूसला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar card linking has mitigated 65L bogus ration card holders: Harsh Gupta</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-mitigated-65l-bogus-ration-card-holders-harsh-gupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-mitigated-65l-bogus-ration-card-holders-harsh-gupta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The linking of Aadhaar card numbers with the ration cards has helped the Department of Food and Civil Supplies to weed out 65 lakh bogus ration cards across the state, said Secretary to the department, Harsh Gupta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing media persons after chairing a progress review meeting here in the city on Sunday, he said, “Aadhaar linking process has been completed, out of the 4.10 crore ration card holders, 3.40 crore had been linked to Aadhaar numbers. Several measures initiated by the department to check pilferage in the public distribution system have helped in saving 35 metric tonnes of food grains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Though there had been an increase in the number of LPG connections, around 90 lakh families were still getting kerosene under the earlier scheme and many had not disclosed their LPG connections,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the data available with oil marketing companies, 99 % of the households in Mysuru district have LPG connection, while majority of the houses in Bengaluru Urban and Rural have gas connections. In order to prevent pilferage, subsidised kerosene (blue) was not being sold at the shops selling non-subsidised kerosene (white),” Gupta added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, “The department has listed out the names of 210 people who have no gas connection to bring them under the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana (PMUJ), launched with the objective of providing LPG connections to families below the poverty line. While the Centre gives free LPG connection, the state government will provide them gas stove with two burners.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deputy Commissioner D Randeep, Deputy Director for Food and Civil Supplies K Rameshwarappa were present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>