<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prasad also said 4.47 crore bank accounts have been opened with Aadhaar eKYC as compared to only one lakh accounts opened as of May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the government has linked the BHIM app with Aadhaar so that transactions through the app happens in a transparent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>200 Airports To Be Brought Under UDAN Scheme: Jayanta Sinha</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jayanta Sinha said government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central government has embarked upon a plan to bring 200 airports under the regional air connectivity scheme, Union Minister of State for Aviation Jayanta Sinha said here today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Under the UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) regional air connectivity scheme, 33 airports have been already included since its launch last year in addition to 75 taking the total to 108. We intend to take the number to 200,&amp;rdquo; Mr Sinha said at an interaction at Bharat Chamber of Commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this, we will have multiple rounds of bidding, he said, adding the government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Sinha said so far the subsidy burden was only Rs 200 crore and 13 lakh seats have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pointing out that regional air connectivity was both pro-poor and pro-markets, he said that this twin objective had been met by offering seats at Rs 2,500 per seat per hour of flying and reducing the cost of flying by bringing down the costs of ATF and service charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding Bagdogra airport in West Bengal, he said talks were on for getting land with the state government for building a new modern terminal. He said that all greenfield airports would be built through the PPP route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding unruly behaviour while flying it is expected that both passengers and the cabin crew would adhere with the laid-down guidelines, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks vs e-wallets: Who is winning in cashless India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-vs-e-wallets-winning-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When two of the biggest banks in the country resist wallets from fintech start-ups, you know a few things are simmering. First, SBI disallowed its net banking users to top up third party wallets and next, ICICI blocked transactions on PhonePe, a Flipkart managed wallet that was launched in partnership with YES Bank – PhonePe allows users to link bank accounts to the smartphone through the National Payments Corporation of India’s encrypted software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While SBI cited security concerns, ICICI said PhonePe was “following restrictive practices allowing users to make payments with only its UPI handle which is in contravention to the UPI guidelines of interoperability…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While security concerns could be real, there is more to it than meets the eye. There is an imminent threat from fintech start-ups to the Indian financial services industry as we see growing disintermediation in mobile payments, financial product comparison/aggregation, lending, and remittances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report by consulting firm Zinnov released mid-2016, investments in the fintech sector crossed $1.3 billion.  Mobile wallet start-ups have received the most funding – they have been using this capital to both aggressively market as well as improve the ease of using their technology. Compared to say a Paytm, SBI’s wallet ‘SBI Buddy’ and ICICI’s ‘Pockets’ have much less brand recall. These privately funded start-ups are now threatening the banks from three sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, banks are worried about relationship with their customers being upended. Banks had failed to notice India’s demographic shift; the young did not want complicated KYC norms even for small transactions such as mobile recharges. They love the app economy and the convenience it provides. Wallets stepped in to provide a better payments experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was a slipping market scenario for traditional banks.  The banking industry’s business model majorly centres around retail as well as corporate lending and not small value transactions. However, according to some estimates, the payments market is a mammoth $500 billion opportunity today when domestic and international remittances, government, utility bills as well as merchant payments are included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New payment categories have come into being as well — taxi payments were always in cash a couple of years ago. Today, tech savvy customers are paying their maid or a driver through money transfers. Many more new categories could emerge.  If these start-ups, armed with private equity money, were to garner a major share of this pie, it would be more than an opportunity lost for traditional banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third threat, and a more serious one, is about data. What happens when users start trusting payment companies? The fallout of such a scenario – where both trust and transactions move to wallet companies – would reflect in a bank’s visibility of customer data or their behaviour patterns. That, in turn, would reduce a bank’s ability to cross sell or up sell other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may, in fact, become reliant on wallet companies for such data. Payment companies, for instance, will be in a better position to judge the credit worthiness of many retail customers the banks are after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, the margins of many banks could slip due to competition. As smart phones become more affordable and pervasive, experts see fintech start-ups scale massively. And if traditional banks don’t align their cost structures with current realities — especially the public sector ones — they can find themselves in a quagmire with only “restrictive practices” as aid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Pension Fund To Go Digital On Payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-pension-fund-to-go-digital-on-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-pension-fund-to-go-digital-on-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The EPFO has over four crore subscribers and receives 1 crore claims every year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labour ministry has amended the social security schemes run by the retirement fund body EPFO to enable it to make all payments &amp;ndash; pension, provident fund and insurance &amp;ndash; to members electronically. &amp;ldquo;The labour ministry has amended the schemes run by the EPFO by a notification. This will enable the Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) to make all payments like EPF and pension through digital mode,&amp;rdquo; an official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was provided in the schemes run by the EPFO that the body can make payments to its subscribers through various modes like money order, cheques or electronically. The official said, &amp;ldquo;The scheme has been completely amended and the provision of making payments through money order or cheques has been omitted from the schemes. Thus all payments would be made through electronic mode.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining further, the official said, &amp;ldquo;Though the EPFO had been making 98 per cent of its payments through electronic mode, there were some field offices which were using other modes like cheque and money orders.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official also informed that the decision to go 100 per cent digital for payments, was taken after some complaints were received for ensuring complete transparency. The EPFO has over four crore subscribers and receives 1 crore claims every year including that of EPF withdrawal, pension fixation and insurance claims.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1,000 Each Month For 20 Years Is Now Rs. 26,00,000 In This Fund</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DSP BlackRock Equity Fund recently completed 20 years of its existence. The fund (dividend option) has delivered 20.65 per cent compound annual growth rate since its inception, outperforming the 13 per cent return of Nifty50 index by a huge margin, says its website. The objective of DSP BlackRock Equity Fund is to seek to generate long-term capital appreciation, from a portfolio that is substantially constituted of equity securities and equity related securities of issuers domiciled in India. DSP BlackRock Equity Fund benchmarks itself against NIFTY 500 index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you consider the NIFTY 500, DSP BlackRock Equity Fund has also outperformed this index by a big margin. NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you had invested Rs 1,000 in the fund each month since its inception? Now you would be sitting on a corpus of nearly Rs 26 lakh as compared to your invested amount of Rs 2.41 lakh crore. If you had invested Rs 4,000 each month, it would have been over a crore now. Returns for investments in dividend plans of schemes are calculated after assuming that the net dividend payouts post statutory taxes &amp;amp; levies, are re-invested back in the scheme. As of March 31, 2017, the fund had assets worth Rs 2,310 crore under management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the country&amp;rsquo;s mutual fund industry managed an asset base of over Rs 18 lakh crore. Mutual funds are investment vehicles made up of a pool of funds collected from a large number of investors. The funds are invested in stocks, bonds and money market instruments, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inflows into domestic equity mutual funds have helped Sensex and Nifty rise to record levels. According to estimates domestic investors are pouring in Rs 4,000 crore every month into equity mutual funds through systematic investment route. Systematic Investment Plans or SIPs are fixed amounts invested at regular intervals in a financial instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test To Check Call Drops Likely From This Month: TRAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/test-to-check-call-drops-likely-from-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/test-to-check-call-drops-likely-from-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Independent drive tests are going to begin. Actually, there was some gap (problem) which has been removed&amp;hellip;they should start probably from this month on,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom regulator Trai is likely to resume from this month its independent drive tests to check call drops and service quality of operators, after a gap of more than five months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Independent drive tests are going to begin. Actually, there was some gap (problem) which has been removed&amp;hellip;they should start probably from this month on,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the telecom operators submit performance monitoring reports to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) regularly, the regulator also undertakes audit and assessment of service quality through independent agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agencies conduct sample &amp;lsquo;drive tests&amp;rsquo; across various cities in the country, as part of audit and assessment of the operators&amp;rsquo; performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The independent drive tests are distinct from operator-assisted tests, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were doing drive tests in 11-12 cities, we will be doing it in more cities (this time). This will be different from the operator-assisted tests,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator-assisted drive test captures real-time data to monitor the level of call drops and voice quality, similar to Trai&amp;rsquo;s independent drive tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, unlike independent drive tests that are conducted by the regulator itself, the &amp;lsquo;operator-assisted&amp;rsquo; tests are conducted in co-ordination with telecom service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator-assisted tests, a new concept, involves the telecom firms&amp;rsquo; equipment and costs, with the regulator monitoring and supervising the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, all drive tests &amp;ndash; be it independent or operator-assisted tests &amp;ndash; assess the performance of networks on various quality benchmarks, including call set-up success rate, call drop, blocked calls and Radio Frequency (RF) coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last round of independent drive tests were conducted by Trai in Amritsar, Delhi, Hyderabad, Bhopal, Chandigarh, Mumbai, Lucknow, Kanpur, Ahmedabad, Ranchi, Darjeeling, Sikkim and Trivandrum in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the last few months that Trai did not undertake independent tests, the operator-assisted tests were conducted in cities including Mathura (UP-West circle), Jaisalmer, (Rajasthan), Ujjain (Madhya Pradesh) and Mangalore (Karnataka) and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the regulator and the Department of Telecom (DoT) have been keeping a vigil on service quality issues such as call drops and call failures through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort to tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of efforts to keep the call quality in check, the Trai plans to roll-out, by the month-end, an app that will enable subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call, once the call is complete. The data will, thereafter, be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पेट्रोल-डीजल प्राइस रोज बदलने से किसका लाभ?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/daily-fuel-price-revisions-to-boost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/daily-fuel-price-revisions-to-boost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;पेट्रोल-डीजल के खुदरा मूल्यों का रोजाना संशोधन करने के सरकार के फैसले से तेल कंपनियों के मार्जिन में सुधार आएगा और उन्हें अच्छा मुनाफा होने की संभावना है। इंडिया रेटिंग ने सोमवार को अपनी रिपोर्ट में कहा कि सरकार के इस कदम की सराहना किया। रिपोर्ट में कहा गया है कि 2010 में पेट्रोल के दाम को, 2014 में डीजल के दाम को नियंत्रण मुक्त करने, एलपीजी से संबंधित गिव इट अप योजना, पीडीएस केरोसिन आवंटन घटाने और उसके दामों में क्रमिक वृद्धि के बाद मार्केटिंग सेक्टर में यह एक अन्य सकारात्मक ढांचागत बदलाव है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इन सभी कदमों से ऑइल मार्केटिंग कंपनियों की बाजार उधारी में भी काफी कमी आई। वर्ष 2014 से लेकर 2016 के बीच सार्वजनिक क्षेत्र की तेल विपणन कंपनियों की बाजार उधारी 29 प्रतिशत घट गई। इसके साथ ही उनकी ब्याज अदायगी भी 37 प्रतिशत तक कम हुई है। सरकार ने पेट्रोल, डीजल के दाम रोजाना आधार पर तय करने के लिए देश के पांच नगरों में इसकी परीक्षण के तौर पर शुरुआत की गई है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पुद्दुचेरी, आंध्र प्रदेश में विजाग, राजस्थान में उदयपुर, झारखंड में जमशेदपुर और चंडीगढ़ में एक मई से दैनिक आधार पर ईंधन के दाम तय किए जाने शुरू कर दिया गया है। इसे धीरे-धीरे देश के अन्य शहरों में भी शुरू किया जाएगा। दरअसल, रोजाना बदलाव होने पर पेट्रोल, डीजल की कीमत में मामूली अंतर पड़ेगा। ऐसे में रेट रिवाइज करने को लेकर राजनीतिक दबाव खत्म हो जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गौरतलब है कि अभी सरकारी ऑयल मार्केटिंग कंपनियां महीने की पहली और 16वीं तारीख को पेट्रोल और डीजल के दाम की समीक्षा करती हैं। पिछले 15 दिनों में इंटरनैशनल प्राइस और करेंसी एक्सचेंज रेट के आधार पर यह बदलाव किया जाता है। पायलट प्रोजेक्ट के लिए इंटरनैशनल मार्केट के डेली प्राइसेज को आधार बनाया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>मोदी पूरा करेंगे 2014 का वादा? फोकस 1 करोड़ नौकरियाें पर</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-turns-focus-on-job-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/narendra-modi-turns-focus-on-job-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी सरकार में तीन साल पूरे करने वाले हैं, जिसे देखते हुए अच्छे दिन के अपने वादों को पूरा करने पर उनका जोर है। 2014 में चुनाव प्रचार के दौरान मोदी ने युवाओं को 1 करोड़ रोजगार के अवसर देने का वादा किया था। हालांकि, बीते तीन सालों में जॉब क्रिएशन में मोदी सरकार का प्रदर्शन अच्छा नहीं रहा है। पीएम मोदी ने निर्देश दिया है कि कैबिनेट को भेजे जाने वाले सभी प्रस्तावों में यह जानकारी जरूर दी जाए कि उन प्रस्तावों पर अमल करने से रोजगार के कितने मौके बनेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वाणिज्य मंत्री निर्मला सीतारमण ने ईटी को बताया कि जिस भी प्रस्ताव के साथ कुछ खर्च जुड़ा होगा, उससे देश में जॉब क्रिएशन होना ही चाहिए और ऐसे प्रस्ताव के साथ जॉब्स एस्टिमेट दिया जाना चाहिए। सीतारमण ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;जब भी कोई प्रस्ताव चर्चा के लिए आता है तो प्रधानमंत्री कैबिनेट मीटिंग में पूछते हैं कि रोजगार के कितने मौके बनेंगे?&amp;rsquo; बता दें कि क्रिसिल की एक रिपोर्ट में कहा गया है कि 15 लाख से ज्यादा लोग हर महीने देश के जॉब मार्केट में रोजगार तलाशने आते हैं। वहीं, मानव श्रम पर निर्भरता घटाने वाले ऑटोमेशन की वजह से स्थिति गंभीर होती जा रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_कई मोर्चों पर चल रहा काम _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ज्यादा रोजगार पैदा करना चाहती है ताकि आमदनी बढ़े और लाखों लोग गरीबी के जाल से बाहर निकलें। सरकार अपनी मैन्युफैक्चरिंग पॉलिसी की समीक्षा भी कर रही है ताकि उसे जॉब क्रिएशन के उद्देश्य के मुताबिक बदला जा सके। वहीं, कौशल बढ़ाने के कार्यक्रम को नए सिरे से तैयार किया जा रहा है। इससे यह सुनिश्चित होगा कि नौकरियों की तलाश में निकलने वाले लोग नई जॉब्स के लिए पहले से तैयार होंगे। बता दें कि इकनॉमिक सर्वे 2017 में कहा गया है कि आबादी में युवाओं की अधिक संख्या से ग्रोथ में होने वाली बढ़ोतरी अगले पांच वर्षों में उच्चतम स्तर पर पहुंच जाएगी क्योंकि तब तक कामकाजी उम्र वाले लोगों की संख्या में ठहराव आ चुका होगा। ऐसे में कौशल और उद्यमिता को बढ़ावा देना जरूरी हो गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_नीति आयोग ने बनाया ऐक्शन प्लान _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ग्रोथ के साथ रोजगार के मौके बनने की रफ्तार बढ़ाने के लिए नीति आयोग ने तीन साल का ऐक्शन प्लान पेश किया है, जिसमें विभिन्न सेक्टरों में जॉब क्रिएशन के कदम उठाने की बात की गई है। मोदी ने भी कहा था, &amp;lsquo;हमारा देश युवाओं का है। हमारी आबादी में 65 प्रतिशत हिस्सा 35 साल से कम के लोगों का है। भारत दुनिया में सबसे बड़ा लोकतंत्र है। किसी भी देश के पास रोजगार के मौके पैदा करने का भारत जितना अवसर नहीं है।&amp;rsquo; बता दें कि सीआईआई के अनुसार, फाइनैंशल इयर 2012 से 2016 के बीच भारत में रोजगार के 1.46 करोड़ मौके बने थे। यानी हर साल 36.5 लाख अवसर। कामकाजी उम्र वाले लोगों की संख्या में 8.41 करोड़ का इजाफा हुआ, लेकिन वास्तिक लेबर फोर्स में बढ़ोतरी केवल 2.01 करोड़ रही। कामकाजी उम्र वाली आबादी का 24% हिस्सा लेबर फोर्स में जुड़ा, जबकि 76% हिस्सा इससे बाहर रहा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी 2.0&#39; के लिए पोर्टल बना रहा I-T विभाग</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/it-department-building-portal-for-operation-clean-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/it-department-building-portal-for-operation-clean-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ऐसे लोगों की जांच के लिए एक खास पोर्टल बना रहा है, जिन्होंने अपनी घोषित आमदनी से कहीं ज्यादा जमा किए हैं या बड़ी खरीदारियां की हैं। सीबीडीटी यह कदम ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत उठा रहा है। उस अभियान को नोटबंदी के मद्देनजर काले धन पर लगाम कसने के लिए शुरू किया गया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह प्रस्ताव प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी के सामने राजस्व विभाग की हालिया समीक्षा बैठक में रखा गया था। चर्चा की जानकारी रखने वाले एक उच्च अधिकारी ने ईटी को बताया, &amp;lsquo;हम एक पोर्टल पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो खास इसी मकसद के लिए होगा।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह उन लोगों के लिहाज से विकसित किया जाएगा, जिनकी पहचान ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के तहत हुई थी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह पोर्टल ऐसे लोगों और टैक्स अथॉरिटीज के बीच संवाद का जरिया बनेगा। यह संवाद PAN के जरिए होगा। डिपार्टमेंट इस प्रोसेस में मानव हस्तक्षेप की गुंजाइश यथासंभव कम रखना चाहता है और जोर ई-असेसमेंट पर है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी का दूसरा चरण हाई-रिस्क लोगों पर केंद्रित होगा, जिन्होंने ज्यादा वैल्यू वाले ट्रांजैक्शंस किए थे। ऐसे लोगों की विस्तृत जांच की जाएगी। डेटा एनालिटिक्स के जरिए ऐसे 60,000 से ज्यादा लोगों की पहचान डिपार्टमेंट कर चुका है। जिन मामलों में गहराई से पड़ताल की तैयारी है, वे ज्यादा डिपॉजिट्स के अलावा ज्यादा कीमत की खरीद-फरोख्त से जुड़े हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने कहा कि इस डेडिकेटेड पोर्टल से टैक्स अथॉरिटीज और संदेह के घेरे में आए लोगों के बीच बिना जोर-जबरदस्ती के संवाद पर फोकस सुनिश्चित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पीएम को ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी के बारे में डिटेल्ड रिप्रेजेंटेशन दिया गया था और यह भी बताया गया था कि सीबीडीटी ने कौन से कदम उठाए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऑपरेशन क्लीन मनी को नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद शुरू किया गया था। इसका मकसद अघोषित आमदनी रखने वालों को टैक्स के दायरे में लाना था। डिपार्टमेंट ने लगभग 18 लाख लोगों की पहचान की थी, जिनसे एसएमएस और ईमेल से संपर्क किया गया था और उनसे उनके डिपॉजिट्स पर सफाई मांगी गई थी। ऐसे लोगों से कहा गया था कि या तो वे टैक्स चुकाएं या प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के जरिए पहले की अघोषित आमदनी का खुलासा करें।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनमें से लगभग 10 लाख लोग ई-वेरिफिकेशन प्रोसेस में शामिल हुए थे। डिपार्टमेंट वित्त वर्ष 2017 में करीब 95 लाख नए करदाताओं को कर के दायरे में लाने में सफल रहा। पिछले साल 8 नवंबर को नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद पैन के लिए ऐप्लिकेशंस की संख्या भी बढ़ी क्योंकि विभाग ने बैंकों को निर्देश दिया था कि सभी खातों को PAN से जोड़ा जाए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डिपार्टमेंट को PAN के लिए रोज करीब 173000 आवेदन मिले, जबकि नोटबंदी के पहले इनकी औसत संख्या 83000 हआ करती थी। कुछ दिनों में इनकी तादाद 300000 तक चली गई। डिपार्टमेंट ने 8 नवंबर 2016 सके 31 मार्च 2017 के बीच 4.65 करोड़ PAN अलॉट किए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avoid Queue At SBI Branches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is offering a virtual queue ticket or &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo; service through its newly-launched app No Queue, which enables customers to avail select banking services at its select branches without having to stand in queues. SBI customers &amp;ldquo;can book a virtual token&amp;hellip;and skip the queue,&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI said on Twitter. SBI&amp;rsquo;s No Queue app was launched by the bank&amp;rsquo;s chairperson Arundhati Bhattacharya in March this year. The mobile-based virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores. &amp;ldquo;The Application is designed to save customers&amp;rsquo; valuable time, avoid queue for Banking services and aims to provide the customers with a better customer service experience,&amp;rdquo; SBI had said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user can select a minimum of one and maximum five services in virtual ticket using No queueapp, as per the SBI website. Here are few other things to know about the No Queue app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers a variety of services under the &amp;lsquo;no queue&amp;rsquo; facility. Some of these include cheque deposit, cash deposit/withdrawal, demand draft, NEFT/RTGS and loan account opening/maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The No Queue app empowers those interested in SBI&amp;rsquo;s banking services to efficiently book a virtual token without being physically present in the branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app provides &amp;ldquo;real time status notification of your position in the queue&amp;rdquo;, as per its description on Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers can generate an e-token before being physically present in the branch. This way, he or she avoids waiting in a queue and saves time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app conveys the estimated waiting time, the number of customers ahead in the queue and the distance to the branch from the point of booking, SBI has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers will be updated about their position in the queue through alerts, according to the app&amp;rsquo;s description on Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-book-e-token&#34;&gt;Who can book &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals - SBI and non-SBI customers - registered on the No Queue app installed on their devices can avail this facility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-use&#34;&gt;How to use&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user can register on the No Queue app by entering basic information such as name and mobile number to start using the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a virtual ticket is generated through the No Queue app, the customer will receive a notification about his or her position in the queue. A button that says &amp;lsquo;Activate&amp;rsquo; will be available on the app when the customer reaches the fifth position in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reaching the branch, a customer activating the queue ticket will be &amp;ldquo;serviced immediately, thus avoiding waiting time at the Branch&amp;rdquo;, the press release added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;can-i-reschedule-my-visit&#34;&gt;Can I reschedule my visit?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After booking a virtual ticket, customers also have the facility of rescheduling or renewing the ticket in case they are running late. The rescheduling option will be available only until when the customer is within the first five positions in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-linked payment system will change the game for digital transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Unique Identification Authority of India is working with banks and the Reserve Bank of India to ensure that merchants who use its mobile-based application for digital transactions earn a commission of up to 1% of the transaction value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With UIDAI suggesting it is on path to get this in place in a couple of months, the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System could give debit cards and e-wallets a run for their money. In contrast to what UIDAI is advocating, all other forms of digital payments require merchants to pay a fee or commission for the use of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Aadhaar-based system is being used for PDS [public distribution system] in Andhra Pradesh, Rajasthan and Gujarat. We are also in discussions with Haryana,” said Ajay Bhushan Pandey, chief executive officer, UIDAI. “We are enrolling banks so that they start accepting Aadhaar-based payments. Two banks have already agreed. The process of integrating merchants with banks will be completed in the next few weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Merchants as business correspondents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once implemented, this model envisages doing away with all charges that are associated with a typical point-of-sale machine. Under the system, UIDAI would enlist merchants as business correspondents. These merchants would use their phones linked to biometric devices for the transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These require a customer to key in their Aadhaar number and verify their fingerprint on the biometric reader connected to the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable a wide acceptability, the government has pushed for linking all savings bank accounts to Aadhaar numbers against a stiff deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a customer transacts with a merchant through Aadhaar Enabled Payment System, the merchant would receive the same incentive that business correspondents employed by banks do, UIDAI has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different banks provide different incentives to business correspondents on the basis of their performance. For instance, the Vidharbha Konkan Gramin Bank, a regional rural bank provides Rs 10 for every new account opened by a business correspondent. If someone deposits money through PoS terminals, the correspondent gets 0.5% of the money. For mobilising a term deposit, the correspondent gets 0.25% of the amount. Similarly, various incentives, as a proportion of the transaction amount, are given to correspondents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Merchants will now be doing the job of a business correspondent,” said Pandey. “So what was being paid as incentives to the correspondent would be extended to merchants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, he suggested, this would reduce the need for banking correspondents as more and more merchants use the Aadhaar app on their phones for transactions. The app itself has been tested by a couple of banks and is being finalised, Pandey said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UIDAI business model would mean the banking system taking on the burden of incentivising the spread of Aadhaar-based payments through mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, at the moment, they earn from other digital transactions. But Pandey said UIDAI was convincing banks that the commission must be seen in the light of existing commission structures for correspondents and the cost of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Costs of going cashless&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A look at the fee structure of PoS machines used to carry out card transactions indicates a substantial cost for the merchant. A third-party PoS provider has multiple layers of charges. These machines are not sold but often given on rent by banks and third-party vendors. Some banks charge the merchants a monthly rental of Rs 400 for a portable PoS machine for two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some banks also recover something called a “commitment charge”. These charges can be a burden on smaller merchants with low volumes of sales. Merchants with a lower sale volume have to pay a higher commitment charge. Competition between different vendors and banks has been bringing down these costs, though, over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks such as the State Bank of India and its public-sector peers offer machines on more lenient terms than third-party vendors. SBI, for instance, says that it doesn’t take a one-time installation charge from any merchant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final layer of the cost of using a PoS machine is the merchant discount rate. This is the charge that banks collect from merchants whenever a card is swiped on the machine. Banks usually charge a lower rate if their own debit cards are used on their PoS machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before January 1, the charges were 0.75% for transactions of value up to Rs 2,000. For transactions above Rs 2,000, a rate of 1% of the transaction value was recovered from the merchant. Foreign cards attracted double the rate while credit card transactions were charged at 1.5%. This was either borne by the merchant or passed on to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After demonetisation, RBI introduced an additional layer of merchant discount rate through a notification issued on December 16, 2016. Between January 1 and March 31 this year, the merchant discount rate for transactions up to Rs 1,000 is to be 0.25%. All others would continue to be charged as before. The rate has been capped at 1%. Clearly, the multiple charges add up to a significant amount for a merchant who has little option but to either bear the cost or to pass it on to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game-changer?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RBI data show that PoS transactions through debit cards touched Rs 31,600 crore in November 2016. In November 2015, this figure stood at Rs 14,800 crore. Banks quite clearly stand to make a killing through these multiple layers of charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile wallets, too, are known to charge as high as 4% for certain types of transactions. Mobile wallet transactions were Rs 3,300 crore in November 2016 as compared to Rs 1,900 crore in November 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where the Aadhaar-linked payment system could be a major disruptor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the National Payments Corporation of India charges 1% on every financial transaction through the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System from the bank. The bank passes this on to the merchant. It’s unclear if these charges would be set off too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandey told Business Standard that a favourable decision could come soon. If it does, it would completely turn the digital transactions ecosystem on its head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change of the business model for digital transactions would require many banks to come on board. NPCI data show that of the 46 public-sector banks and private banks in India, 44 are classified as “member banks” of Aadhaar Enabled Payment System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio’s new plans offer 100% cashback on JioFi on exchange of old dongle, datacard, routers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio has launched a 100% cashback offer with JioFi 4G router, as the Mukesh Ambani-owned tries to attract users of dongles, datacard and wifi routers offered by rival telcos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has come up with two plans where as part of the first plan, users will get a 100% exchange offer where they’ll be required to exchange their existing datacard, dongle or hotspot router at any Jio Digital store or Jio Care store and will get 4G data worth Rs 2010 against the device exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customers will have to pay Rs 1999 to get the JioFi router and will have to do a mandatory first recharge of Rs 408 which is Rs309 for the plan – which ensures freebies for 84 days - and Rs99 for a Jio Prime membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the customer pays Rs 1999 minus the Rs 2010 worth 4G data which translates into zero cost for the customer and the device with internet connection becomes almost free. However, the Rs 408 mandatory recharge is the additional cost which the user will have to pay in order to avail the services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the second plan, users get JioFi at Rs 1999 after a first mandatory recharge of Rs 408 (Rs309 + Rs99) but they get 4G data worth Rs 1005 which translates to the effective cost of Rs 994 (Rs1999 - Rs1005). Users need not exchange their existing data connections for this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first plan is ideal for all existing dongle users whereas the second plan is ideal for laptop users, 2G/3G phone users and tablet users, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Queries addressed to Jio for the new plans went unanswered till the press time. Reliance Retail currently has four JioFi devices running in the market namely JioFi 1 Router, JioFi 2 Router, JioFi 3 Router, JioFi 4 Dongle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the first plan, the telco is trying to capture the market of rival telcos offering dongles, datacard and wifi routers, since the exchange scheme will encourage existing dongle users to shift to Jio’s services, say experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They added that by offering free data in the second plan to the first time users or users that are willing to keep multiple connections, the telco is looking to expand the subscriber-base for its JioFi routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIL’s retail arm namely Reliance Retail sold 2.6 million LYF and JioFi devices during the last quarter and nearly 10 million units in the financial year, and is further looking to accelerate the sales with the launch of new JioFi plans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>