<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.
The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.
Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar must to get government co-contribution for availing Atal Pension Yojana</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</guid>
      <description>The finance ministry on Monday said their subscribers of the Atal Pension Yojana (APY) will have to link their Aadhaar to their accounts for availing up to Rs 1,000 government’s co-contribution.
Any individual who is eligible to receive benefits under the APY will have to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo enrolment under Aadhaar authentication, the ministry said in a statement.
Pension regulator PFRDA has identified nearly 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar saved Rs 90, 000 crore of public money since 2014: Centre</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</guid>
      <description>An affidavit filed by the central government in the Supreme Court has stated that Aadhaar has saved Rs 90,000 crore of public money since 2014.
It further said that the total recorded savings through Direct Benefit Transfer scheme alone have been Rs 49,560 crore in just two years.
The affidavit filed by the centre provided official statistics on the impact Aadhaar on a multitude of welfare schemes and benefits across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar-Based Authentication Is ‘Fully Safe And Secure’, Assures UIDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</guid>
      <description>UIDAI dismissed the recently-reported breach as an isolated case, and added that their internal security system had picked up the attempted misuse.
Dismissing reports of misuse of biometrics data, the government on Sunday said Aadhaar-based authentication is “fully safe and secure”.
Moreover, subsidy transfers linked to Aadhaar has led the exchequer to save ₹49,000 crore during the last two-and-half years.
According to Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), there has been no incident of misuse of Aadhaar biometrics leading to identity theft and financial loss when more than 400 crore Aadhaar authenticated transactions took place during the last five years, it said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.
Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange old notes for new at a premium</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</guid>
      <description>Scrapped old notes ­ Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 ­ which were to be exchanged latest by December 20, 2016, are still there. They can be exchanged even now, but for a hefty premium.
Non-Resident Indians (NRIs), who were allowed to exchange old notes till June 30 this year, are being offered a handsome commission for exchanging these notes.
&amp;ldquo;The going rate for exchanging old notes is Rs 9 on every Rs 100, so if you want to exchange Rs 1 crore in old notes, then you would get back Rs 9 lakh in new notes,&amp;rdquo; said Pravin (name changed), who is involved in this trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government makes Aadhaar-PAN linking must from July 1: Here’re 5 things you must know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-makes-aadhaar-pan-linking-must-from-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-makes-aadhaar-pan-linking-must-from-july/</guid>
      <description>If you are holding both Aadhaar and PAN cards, then better link the two now. For, the government has made it mandatory to link the existing Aadhaar numbers with the PAN cards of taxpayers with effect from July 1 and has also notified the rules, according to a PTI report. The revenue department has said that “every person who has been allotted PAN as on July 1, 2017, and who in accordance with the provisions of sub-section (2) of section 139AA is required to intimate his Aadhaar number, shall intimate his Aadhaar number to the principal director general of income tax (systems) or DGIT (systems).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-linked payment system will change the game for digital transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</guid>
      <description>The Unique Identification Authority of India is working with banks and the Reserve Bank of India to ensure that merchants who use its mobile-based application for digital transactions earn a commission of up to 1% of the transaction value.
With UIDAI suggesting it is on path to get this in place in a couple of months, the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System could give debit cards and e-wallets a run for their money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Call Drop Problem: No More Tricks, Telecom Minister Warns Operators</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</guid>
      <description>Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement
Refusing to lower his guard on the issue of call drops, Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement, which leaves no room for any manipulation. &amp;ldquo;We are looking at every aspect of call drop. No trick will work in this case,&amp;rdquo; Sinha told Press Trust of India in an interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.
To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार नंबर को पैन कार्ड से ऐसे करें लिंक,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-aadhar-card-to-pan-card-online-link-your-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-aadhar-card-to-pan-card-online-link-your-pan/</guid>
      <description>आपके पैन कार्ड को आधार कार्ड से लिंक करने के लिए मात्र दो दिन का समय बचा है, अगर आपने ये काम अबतक नहीं किया है तो जल्द इसे कर लें। इसका तरीका हम आपको बताने जा रहै हैं। अन्यथा आप इस साल का अपना इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न नहीं फाइल कर पाएंगे। सरकार के आदेश के मुताबिक शनिवार यानी कि एक जुलाई से आयकर रिटर्न भरने के लिए दोनों नंबरों को लिंक करना जरूरी होगा।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।
विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पेट्रोल-डीजल प्राइस रोज बदलने से किसका लाभ?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/daily-fuel-price-revisions-to-boost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/daily-fuel-price-revisions-to-boost/</guid>
      <description>पेट्रोल-डीजल के खुदरा मूल्यों का रोजाना संशोधन करने के सरकार के फैसले से तेल कंपनियों के मार्जिन में सुधार आएगा और उन्हें अच्छा मुनाफा होने की संभावना है। इंडिया रेटिंग ने सोमवार को अपनी रिपोर्ट में कहा कि सरकार के इस कदम की सराहना किया। रिपोर्ट में कहा गया है कि 2010 में पेट्रोल के दाम को, 2014 में डीजल के दाम को नियंत्रण मुक्त करने, एलपीजी से संबंधित गिव इट अप योजना, पीडीएस केरोसिन आवंटन घटाने और उसके दामों में क्रमिक वृद्धि के बाद मार्केटिंग सेक्टर में यह एक अन्य सकारात्मक ढांचागत बदलाव है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>प्रतिदिन 4GB-3Gडेटा 444 रुपये में 90 दिन तक </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-new-chukaa-offer-4gb-mobile-broadband-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-new-chukaa-offer-4gb-mobile-broadband-per-day/</guid>
      <description>सार्वजनिक क्षेत्र की दूरसंचार सेवा प्रदाता कंपनी बीएसएनएल ने प्रीपेड मोबाइल ग्राहकों के लिए 444 रुपये में प्रतिदिन 4GB मोबाइल डाटा की पेशकश की है। यह पेशकश 3G ग्राहकों के लिए की गई है, जिसकी वैधता 90 दिन है।
कंपनी ने एक बयान में कहा कि उसने बीएसएनएल चौका ऑफर की पेशकश की है, जो वास्तव में 90 दिन तक असीमित डाटा इस्तेमाल की सुविधा देगा। कंपनी का दावा है कि यह देशभर में किसी कंपनी द्वारा प्रतिदिन डाटा सीमा की सबसे बड़ी पेशकश है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘what is BHIM’ to ‘what are the benefits’, here are top 5 FAQs answered</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</guid>
      <description>Whether India has really adopted digital or not would only be clear once data for the coming months is released, but what can be said with certainty is that there are enough avenues available if one wants to go digital.
While pre-demonetisation, the government had launched UPI and other services, post this it has rolled out BHIM and BharatQR, and is expected to launch AadhaarPay. In fact, PM Modi in Mann-ki-Baat lauded the initiative to go digital, urging the youth to teach BHIM transfers to 125 people commemorating the 125th anniversary of Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>