<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Govt:Over Rs 153cr awarded to 10lk people to promote e-payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;check if you are winner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dev.digidhanlucky&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px;padding:4px&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/logoapp.png&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on start button in Digi Dhan Lucky Yojana App.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on whether you are a Consumer or a Merchant, click on the corresponding button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box that appears next, provide the mobile phone number registered with your UPI/ USSD/ RuPay/ AEPS account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive an OTP, which you must enter in the box that appears in the middle of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Try Your Luck button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next message will show if you have won under the Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi Dhan Vyapar Yojana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been awarded over Rs 153.5 crore in the last 58 days under Niti Aayog’s schemes to promote digital payments, its CEO Amitabh Kant said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It has been 58 days since the launch of Niti Aayog’s two incentive schemes – Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana to promote digital payments and the public response has been quite encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the latest figures released by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), which has been executing the schemes, nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been disbursed over Rs 153.5 crore as reward money till February 20, 2017,” Kant said at a press conference here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s think-tank said in a statement that among the 9.8 lakh winners are more than 9.2 lakh consumers and 56,000 merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners belong to diverse socio-economic backgrounds, including farmers, merchants, small entrepreneurs, professionals, housewives, students and retired persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Uttar Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh and Delhi have emerged as the top five states/Union Territories with maximum number of winners,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While majority of the winners are in the age group of 21 to 30, Niti Aayog pointed out that a significant number are also above 60 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The diversity in age of winners is from 15 to 66 years, challenging the notion that the old find it difficult to embrace technology to adopt digital payments,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government on December 25 had launched two schemes — Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana — to boost digital transactions post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Mandatory For Filing Tax Returns, PAN Card From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting of Aadhaar has been made mandatory for filing income tax returns with effect from July 1, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, an official statement said on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961 as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017 provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar /Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from July 1,&amp;rdquo; said a Finance Ministry statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or Enrolment ID will apply only to a person who is eligible to obtain Aadhaar number, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act, 2016, only a resident individual is entitled to obtain Aadhaar. Resident as per the said Act means an individual who has resided in India for a period or periods amounting in all to 182 days or more in the 12 months immediately preceding the date of application for enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the requirement to quote Aadhaar as per section 139AA of the Income-tax Act shall not apply to an individual who is not a resident as per the Aadhaar Act, 2016, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar card to be linked with flights soon?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linked-flights-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linked-flights-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Delhi: The Central government has now asked Information Technology major Wipro to come up with reports and to develop a blueprint for Aadhaar-based biometric access to flight passengers at all airports across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, based on government’s direction, Wipro is likely to submit a report in May after which the airports will start the process where a flyer’s thumb would be all the identification they need to be eligible to fly on domestic flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aviation ministry had an idea about linking Aadhaar number with flight bookings which enables the biometric access possible at all airports. Reports revealed that the solid push was taken by Aviation Minister Jayant Sinha and Aviation Secretary R N Choubey in a meeting with several airport operators and airlines officials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Airports Authority of India chief Guruprasad Mohapatra, he said that linking of Aadhaar card number and thumb identification will help an official know about the passenger boarding the flight. Mohapatra explained that at the time of booking, a passenger enters his/her Aadhaar number. On arrival at an airport, the passenger can just place the thumb on the touchpad at an entry point and at other points inside the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohapatra added that AAI wants the passengers to have effortless and seamless travel experience at airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As everyone is aware that due to security reasons, a passenger in India has to show his or her identification card along with the tickets to enter the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has been trying to make Aadhaar as the sole identity card in the future a move that could possibly replace PAN, voter and ration cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an Aadhaar card is mandatory: Getting a passport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hassle-free passport services: Now, you can get a passport in just 10 days if you have an Aadhaar card. The government has announced that an Adhaar card or e-Aadhaar card can be used as proof of date of birth while applying for passports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income tax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is trying to file income tax returns needs to link their Aadhaar number with their PAN before July. If one fails to do so it will not be considered as a valid ITR filing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to provident fund&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Provident Fund Organisation has also made it compulsory for all pensioners and members to submit their Aadhaar card numbers. It is basically done for pensioners to avail hassle-free pension at the time of retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile connections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a department of telecom notification that was issued on Friday, the telecom operators have been directed to re-verify their existing subscribers — both prepaid and postpaid — through an Aadhaar-based eKYC process by February 6, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For free LPG connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre announced that Aadhaar card is now mandatory for women in the Below Poverty Line category applying for a free LPG connection. Applicants without the unique ID number have until May 31 to apply for it to avail the benefits under the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana, the ministry of petroleum and natural gas said in a notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway ticket booking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railways have also made plans to link Aadhaar with ticket booking. They have also held a discussion with UIDAI for linking Aadhaar number with the booking of a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a driving licence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has planned to make Aadhaar mandatory for seeking a new licence or renewal of your driving licence in a bid to ensure that there are no multiple driving licences under one name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the ‘Midday meal scheme’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry of human resource development announced that the mid-day meal would no longer be free for those children without an Aadhaar card. It was stated that children must be enrolled in the Aadhar scheme by June 30, if they were to get a free meal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar to be mandatory for driving licence, effective from October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As per an order issued by the central government, Aadhaar card will become mandatory for issuance of fresh driving licences or for renewal of the same. This rule will come into effect starting October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind the move is to eradicate the issuance of multiple driving licences across different states. It will help the government to enforce traffic regulations more effectively as drivers won’t have multiple driving licences to fall back on, which isn’t an uncommon practice in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linking Aadhaar card to the driver’s licence will enable the government to maintain a centralised database (known as Sarathi). Regional Transport Offices (RTO) from all over the country can log on and instantly check whether the applicant of a driver’s licence has another one in any other part of the country. The National Informatics Centre (NIC) has already uploaded almost all the data available in RTOs across the country on to the common database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union Road Transport Ministry is currently briefing the state governments about the changes that will eventually be incorporated in the process of issuing a driver’s licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This briefing also talks about citizens who do not have an Aadhaar card issued to their name. In that case, he/she will have to submit multiple documents, although it is unclear what those additional documents will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State governments across the nation have come up with hefty penalties for breaking traffic laws and regulations. One such penalty in many states is the confiscation of driver’s licence for a few months or indefinitely, depending on the severity of the law broken.  This move will will surely force citizens to take traffic laws a lot more seriously once their licences are linked to Sarathi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Summer Surprise Packs Offer Up To 100 GB Of 4G Data</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-summer-surprise-packs-offer-up-to-100-gb-of-4g-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-summer-surprise-packs-offer-up-to-100-gb-of-4g-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime prepaid customers opting for Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 999 recharge pack will get 100GB of free data for 90 days under the Summer Surprise offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio has announced a &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer under which it is offering 100 GB of data as complimentary benefit under select recharge packs. Jio also extended its enrolment for paid Prime scheme by 15 days. &amp;ldquo;Jio Prime offers many attractive benefits - the absolute best data tariffs in the industry, free voice calling, access to all Jio apps, and many more periodic surprises going forward. Jio prime members will always get the very best of what Jio has to offer,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani said in a letter to Jio members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Summer Surprise scheme, Jio prepaid customers subscribing to Prime are being offered complimentary benefits under various recharge packs. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime members making their first paid recharge of Rs 303 plan (or any higher value plan) till April 15, 2017 will get three months of services on a complimentary basis. The paid tariff plan will be applied only in July, after the expiry of the complimentary offer. (Also read: Summer Surprise offer features, extra benefits)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime prepaid customers opting for Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 999 recharge pack will get 100GB of free data for 90 days under the Summer Surprise offer. After July, under the Rs 999 pack, Prime members will 60 GB of data for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, on recharges of Rs 1,999 (125 GB of data with validity of 90 days), Rs. 4,999 (350GB-180 days) and Rs. 9,999 (750GB-360 days), Prime plan members will get 100 GB data for 90 days, according to Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of recharge packs which offer 100GB of free high-speed data under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Summer Surprise offer:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-100gb-90-days_650x400_41491373824.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New ITR Form Filers: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-itr-form-1-sahaj-to-benefit-2-crore-filers-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-itr-form-1-sahaj-to-benefit-2-crore-filers-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sahaj makes quoting of the 12-digit Aadhaar number mandatory along with Permanent Account Number (PAN).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax return filing season has started. The Income Tax Department has launched e-filing facility for the assessment year 2017-18. In this regard, the tax department has also launched a simplified one-page ITR-1 form called Sahaj. This ITR Form-1 (Sahaj) can be filed by an individual having income up to Rs 50 lakh and who is receiving income from salary, one house property or other income (interest etc). The Income Tax Return Form-1 or Sahaj will replace the earlier seven-page form, making it much easier for filing returns for most taxpayers. The simplified ITR will &amp;ldquo;reduce the compliance burden to a significant extent on the individual tax payer&amp;rdquo;, the Income Tax Department said. Simultaneously, the number of ITR Forms has been reduced from the existing nine to seven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not much tinkering has been done with the contents of existing form and some redundant columns have been done away with which will simplify the filing to some extent for a vast majority of people. However, mandatory quoting of Aadhaar may cause some hardship as there will be a sudden rush for such people to apply for Aadhaar who don&amp;rsquo;t have one yet,&amp;rdquo; said Sandeep Sehgal, director-tax and regulatory at Ashok Maheshwary &amp;amp; Associates LLP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 key highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Sahaj makes quoting of the 12-digit Aadhaar number mandatory along with Permanent Account Number (PAN). While the earlier ITR form too had a column to quote Aadhaar, the government has through an amendment to the Income Tax Act made quoting it mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Cash deposited in excess of Rs 2 lakh during the November 9-December 30 period last year, if any, has to be mentioned in Sahaj.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) In the new form, the parts relating to tax computation and deductions have been rationalised and simplified for easy compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Besides personal details, an income tax filer needs to disclose only his or her income from salary or pension, one house property and other sources like interest. Thereafter, deduction claims are to be stated, followed by computation of taxable income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Instead of 20 columns of deductions in the old form, only five columns need to be filled - four columns specifically for claims in respect of Sections 80C, 80D, 80G and 80TTA, and one for other deductions to be specified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Section 80C is one of the most popular avenues for claiming income tax deductions. Under this section, a deduction of up to Rs 1.5 lakh is allowed. PPF, EPF, life insurance premium etc. qualify for deductions under this section. Section 80D refers to deduction for premium paid for medical insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Section 80G pertains to contributions made to certain relief funds and charitable institutions while 80TTA provides a deduction of Rs 10,000 on interest income from savings account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Bank details are to be filled in the next column. Details of advance tax, self-assessment tax payments and tax deducted at source (TDS) come next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The simplified tax form will benefit more than two crore taxpayers who will be eligible to file their returns through this simplified form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) The existing income tax return forms ITR-2, ITR-2A and ITR-3 have been rationalised and a single ITR-2 form has been notified in place of these three forms. Taxpayers having more than one house will have to file the ITR-2 form. Details of exempt income (income not to be included in total income) like long-term capital gains from transactions on which securities transaction tax is paid has been made mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ने पर अवैध हो जाएगा PAN,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) को आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ा तो संभव है कि 31 दिसंबर के बाद यह अवैध हो जाए। दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के सरकार के फैसले के बाद इसे वित्तीय लेनदेन (फाइनैंशल ट्रांजैक्शंज) के लिए जरूरी नंबर बनाने की दिशा में एक और कदम बढ़ा दिया गया है। सरकार पूरे फाइनैंशल सेक्टर में आधार आधारित नो योर कस्टमर (KYC) को इंटीग्रेट करने पर विचार कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इसकी पुष्टि करते हुए कहा कि सरकार रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) सहित सभी रेग्युलेटर्स के साथ विचार-विमर्श कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार KYC एक तुरंत, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक और मजबूत प्रमाण उपलब्ध कराता है, जिससे सेवा उद्योग की प्रक्रिया बेहतर बनाने में मदद मिलेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने फाइनैंस बिल में एक संशोधन के जरिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के लिए आवेदन पर आधार को अनिवार्य बना दिया है। अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन लोगों के पास पहले से आधार मौजूद है, उन्हें किसी भी वित्तीय मध्यस्थ (फाइनैंशल इंटरमीडियरी) को अपने अंगूठे का निशान उपलब्ध कराना होगा। इसे संबंधित सेक्टर की रिपोर्टिंग एंटिटि को दिया जाएगा, जो इसे UIDAI डेटाबेस से वैलिडेट करेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस डेटा के आधार पर सेंट्रल रजिस्ट्री ऑफ सिक्यॉरिटाइजेशन ऐंड ऐसेट रिकंस्ट्रक्शन ऐंड सिक्यॉरिटी इंट्रेस्ट ऑफ इंडिया (CERSAI) की ओर से एक यूनीक C-KYC नंबर जेनरेट किया जाएगा। इस नंबर का इस्तेमाल बैंक अकाउंट, म्यूचुअल फंड इन्वेस्टमेंट, डीमैट अकाउंट और इंश्योरेंस पॉलिसी सहित सभी फाइनैंशल प्रॉडक्ट्स में किया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा था कि देश में 98 प्रतिशत व्यस्कों या 108 करोड़ से अधिक लोगों को आधार नंबर जारी किया जा चुका है और इसी वजह से सरकार इसका इस्तेमाल बढ़ा रही है। उन्होंने इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के प्रस्ताव पर दोबारा विचार करने की संसद की मांग को खारिज कर दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC सुविधा से PAN के आवेदन के लिए जन्मतिथि या पते जैसी जानकारियों की पुष्टि का इंतजार कर रहे व्यक्ति और एंटिटि अंगूठे के निशान से बायोमेट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन कर सकेंगे। CERSAI ने पिछले वर्ष सभी वित्तीय संस्थानों में एक समान KYC प्रोसेस सुनिश्चित करने के लिए e-KYC की कोशिश शुरू की थी। 2016 में मार्केट रेग्युलेटर सेबी ने आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC को स्वेच्छा से अपनाने पर सहमति दी थी। सभी सरकारी बैंकों से भी इस तरह का अपडेटेड डेटा अथॉरिटी को उपलब्ध कराने का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>टैक्सपेयर से प्रॉपर्टी का वैध किराएदार होने का सबूत मांग सकता है आयकर विभाग</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fake-rent-receipt-wont-help-you-lower-tax-burden-anymore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fake-rent-receipt-wont-help-you-lower-tax-burden-anymore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;टैक्स का बोझ घटाने के लिए कई लोग प्रॉपर्टी रेंट की फर्जी रसीदें लगा दिया करते हैं। टैक्स रूल को धता बताने की ऐसी हरकत को ज्यादातर एंप्लॉयर्स नजरंदाज करते रहे हैं। टैक्स ऑफिस को भी संभवत: लगता रहा है कि यह छोटी गलती है। हालांकि अब हालात बदल सकते हैं। इनकम टैक्स डिपार्टमेंट को अब एक ठोस जमीन लग गई है, जिसके आधार पर वह टैक्सपेयर से इस बात का सबूत मांग सकता है कि वह संबंधित प्रॉपर्टी का वैध किराएदार है। एंप्लॉयर से &amp;lsquo;हाउस रेंट अलाउंस&amp;rsquo; पाने वाला सैलरीड एंप्लॉयी इस रकम के कम से कम 60% हिस्से पर टैक्स देने से बच सकता है, बशर्ते वह रेंट रसीद दे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ट्राइब्यूनल की एक हालिया रूलिंग के अनुसार, असेसिंग ऑफिसर अब सैलरीड एंप्लॉयी की ओर से दिखाई गई टैक्सेबल इनकम का आंकड़ा मंजूर करते वक्त सबूत की मांग कर सकता है। वह लीज ऐंड लाइसेंस अग्रीमेंट, किराएदारी के बारे में हाउसिंग को-ऑपरेटिव सोसायटी को जानकारी देने वाले लेटर, इलेक्ट्रिसिटी बिल, वॉटर बिल जैसे सबूत मांग सकता है। आईटीएटी मुंबई ने ऐसे सैलरीड एंप्लॉयी का एचआरए इग्जेम्पशन क्लेम खारिज किया था, जिसने दावा किया था कि वह अपनी मां को रेंट पेमेंट कर रहा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;डेलॉयट हास्किंस एंड सेल्स एलएलपी के सीनियर टैक्स अडवाइजर दिलीप लखानी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इनकम टैक्स अपीलेट ट्राइब्यूनल की रूलिंग ने सैलरीड एंप्लॉयी के क्लेम पर विचार करने और जरूरी होने पर उस पर सवाल करने के लिए असेसिंग ऑफिसर के सामने एक मानक रख दिया है। इससे सैलरीड क्लास पर यह जिम्मेदारी आएगी कि वह टैक्स छूट पाने के लिए नियमों का पालन करे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;माना जाता है कि फर्जी रेंट रसीदें देने वाले सैलरीड एंप्लॉयीज के पास इनमें से कोई भी जरूरी दस्तावेज नहीं होता है। हो सकता है कि वह व्यक्ति असल में रेंट चुका ही न रहा हो और अपने परिवार के घर में ही रह रहा हो और अपने पिता की दस्तखत वाली रसीदें दिखा रहा हो। कुछ मामलों में असल में किराएदार होने पर भी किराए की रकम बढ़ाकर दिखाई जाती है और इसमें तब तक दिक्कत नहीं आती है, जब तक कि किराया पाने वाला शख्स टैक्स चुकाने की लिमिट से बाहर हो।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऐसे कई मामले देखे गए हैं, जिनमें कोई व्यक्ति भले ही अलग रह रहा हो, लेकिन वह दावा करता है कि उसी शहर में रहने वाले एक रिश्तेदार को किराया चुका रहा है, जिनकी वहीं कोई प्रॉपर्टी हो। कुछ मामलों में परिवार का एक सदस्य लोन पेमेंट डिडक्शन का क्लेम करता है तो दूसरा टैक्स से बचने के लिए फर्जी रेंट रसीद चिपका देता है। एचआरए को लेकर इस तरह की जैसी हरकतें होती हैं, उन्हें देखते हुए टैक्स अधिकारियों को बहुत ज्यादा क्लेम्स पर सवाल करने होंगे। एक टैक्स ऑफिसर ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;टेक्नॉलजी और सख्त रिपोर्टिंग सिस्टम से नजर बनाए रखने में आसानी होगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बंद नहीं होंगे 2000 रुपये के नोट, सरकार ने अटकलों पर लगाया विराम</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-plans-to-demonetise-rs-2000-notes-says-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-plans-to-demonetise-rs-2000-notes-says-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने 2000 रुपये के नए नोटों को बंद किए जाने की अटकलों पर विराम लगा दिया और कहा कि नकली नोटों की समस्या पर काबू के लिए अतिरिक्त सुरक्षा उपाय किए गए हैं। गृह राज्य मंत्री किरेन रिजिजू ने राज्यसभा में कहा कि इस संबंध में चल रही अफवाहों पर ज्यादा ध्यान नहीं दिया जाना चाहिए। कांग्रेस के मधूसुदन मिस्त्री ने प्रश्नकाल में सवाल किया था कि बाजार में ऐसी अटकलें हैं कि 2000 रुपये के नोटों को बंद किया जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस पर रिजिजू ने कहा, ‘ऐसी अफवाहों पर मत जाइए। अफवाहों पर ध्यान नहीं दिया जाना चाहिए।’ उन्होंने कहा कि नकली नोट बरामद किए जाने के ज्यादातर मामले गुजरात और पश्चिम बंगाल से आए। उन्होंने कहा कि यह कहना सही नहीं है कि नकली नोटों की पहचान नहीं की जा सकती। रिजिजू ने कहा कि नए नोटों में सुरक्षा के कई नए उपाय किए गए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा कि वह सदन को आश्वस्त कर सकते हैं कि नए नोटों की 100 प्रतिशत कॉपी करना संभव नहीं है। उन्होंने कहा कि सुरक्षा के लिए स्वदेशी डिजायन के अलावा अतिरिक्त उपाय भी किए गए हैं। उन्होंने कहा कि सरकार नकली नोटों को लेकर चौकन्नी है और ऐसे मामलों में सख्त सजा के प्रावधान किए गए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा कि ऐसे मामलों को लेकर विभिन्न खुफिया एजेंसी के बीच समन्वय पर जोर दिया गया है और लोगों के लिए प्रशिक्षण और जागरूकता कार्यक्रम शुरू किया गया है। उन्होंने बताया कि राष्ट्रीय जांच एजेंसी (एनआईए) ने गुजरात और पश्चिम बंगाल से 2000 रुपये के 22,677 नोट बरामद किए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बैंक, डाकघर से निकासी पर नकदी लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर दो लाख रुपये की नकद लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी। आयकर विभाग ने बुधवार को यह स्पष्ट किया। वित्त अधिनियम 2017 के तहत सरकार ने दो लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध लगा दिया है। इससे अधिक के लेनदेन में राशि प्राप्त करने वाले पर उतनी की राशि का जुर्माना लगाया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर कानून में नई शामिल धारा 269 एसटी के बारे में स्पष्टीकरण जारी करते हुए केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ने कहा कि यह प्रतिबंध बैंकों और डाकघरों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा। बयान में कहा गया है कि यह फैसला किया गया है कि नकद लेनदेन पर अंकुश बैंकों, सहकारी बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सीबीडीटी ने कहा कि इस बारे में आवश्यक अधिसूचना जारी की जाएगी। वित्त मंत्री अरण जेटली ने 2017-18 के बजट में 3 लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध का प्रस्ताव किया था। इस सीमा को वित्त विधेयक में संशोधन के जरिए दो लाख रुपये कर दिया गया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 अप्रैल से कहीं राहत, कहीं झटके</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/changes-in-financial-provisions-and-tax-laws-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/changes-in-financial-provisions-and-tax-laws-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;पहली अप्रैल से लागू होने जा रहे कई तरह के वित्तीय प्रावधानों का सीधा असर ट्रेडर्स-इंडस्ट्री पर पड़ेगा। कहीं उन्हें आयकर में रियायतें मिलेंगी तो कुछ जगहों पर कमाई निगरानी बढ़ जाएगी। 2 लाख से ज्यादा की कैश डील पर रोक का सीधा असर हाई वैल्यू ट्रेड पर पड़ेगा, वहीं दिल्ली के बजटीय प्रावधानों से भी बिजनस अछूता नहीं रहेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बुलियन-प्रॉपर्टीः काले धन पर बनी एसआईटी की सिफारिश पर 3 लाख रुपये तक कैश ट्रांजैक्शन की सीमा को बढ़ाकर अब दो लाख कर दिया गया है। पकड़े जाने पर 100 फीसदी जुर्माने के नए प्रावधान ने भी कैश डील के आदी रहे बाजारों और व्यापार को सकते में ला दिया है। जानकारों का कहना है कि इसका सबसे ज्यादा असर प्रॉपर्टी की खरीद-बिक्री और बुलियन बाजारों पर पड़ेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऑडिट-असेसमेंट: दो करोड़ तक इनकम पर सालाना ऑडिट से छूट और अनुमानित आय स्कीम के तहत आय पर 8 की जगह 6 पर्सेंट इनकम टैक्स के दायरे में कई नए कारोबारी आएंगे। कड़वी बात यह है कि सर्च ऑपरेशन के दौरान 50 लाख रुपये से अधिक की अघोषित आय या संपत्ति पाए जाने पर अधिकारी अब 6 के बजाय 10 साल पुराने मामले भी खोल सकते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्मॉल इंडस्ट्री को राहतः 50 करोड़ से कम टर्नओवर वाली फर्मों पर इनकम टैक्स की दर अब 30 के बजाय 25 पर्सेंट होगी। करीब 96 पर्सेंट (6.67 लाख) माइक्रो, स्मॉल और मीडियम एंटरप्राइजेज को फायदा मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नई वैट दरें लागूः दिल्ली बजट के वैट सहित कई प्रावधान भी 1 अप्रैल से लागू होंगे। सैनिटरी नैपकिन, टिंबर, प्लाईवुड, ब्लैकबोर्ड, पार्टिकल बोर्ड, ग्रेनाइट, स्वदेसी कोटा स्टोन सहित सभी इमारती पत्थरों पर वैट दरें 12.5 से घटाकर 5 पर्सेंट करने का प्रस्ताव है। दिल्ली से नॉर्थ-ईस्ट सहित दूर दराज की उड़ानों के ईंधन पर वैट की दर भी 25 पर्सेंट से घटकर 1 पर्सेंट हो जाएगी। जिससे इन डेस्टिनेशंस का किराया घटेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ट्रांसपॉर्ट स्ट्राइकः पहली अप्रैल से कमर्शल गाड़ियों के थर्ड पार्टी बीमा का प्रीमियम 41 पर्सेंट महंगा हो जाएगा। गुरुवार को आईआरडीए ने साफ कर दिया। इसके तुरंत बाद ऑल इंडिया कन्फेडरेशन ऑफ गुड्स वीइकल ओनर्स असोसिएशन ने करीब 15 राज्यों में 1 अप्रैल से हड़ताल पर जाने का ऐलान कर दिया। ऑल इंडिया मोटर ट्रांसपॉर्ट कांग्रेस 20 से पूरे देश में हड़ताल पर जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31 March Last Day For Depositing Old Notes In RBI: Here&#39;s A Checklist</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-31-march-last-day-for-depositing-old-notes-in-rbi-heres-a-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-31-march-last-day-for-depositing-old-notes-in-rbi-heres-a-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the March 31 deadline looming for depositing demonetised currency, the Reserve Bank offices continued to witness long queues. There is confusion among people standing in the queues as ineligible ones are making it longer. &amp;ldquo;Several people who are ineligible queueing up at RBI counters making the queue longer,&amp;rdquo; Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal said in the Rajya Sabha. As tempers ran high outside the central bank branches, he added that &amp;ldquo;each application has to be checked at the counters for his/her absence from the country from passport stamp marks, it is taking considerable time for the counter staff.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a checklist before the opportunity ends on March 31:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Possession of more than 10 notes in junked currency after March 31 is illegal for Indian residents. Violation of this is punishable with a fine which may extend to Rs 10,000 or five times the amount of the face value of the notes, whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central bank allowed Indian residents who were abroad during November-December 2016 to exchange the scrapped notes up to March 31 but for non-resident Indians (NRIs) the deadline is June 30.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NRIs coming to India are required to come through &amp;lsquo;Red Channel&amp;rsquo; disclosing to the Customs authorities at the airport the amount of the defunct notes and secure a certificate to be tendered at RBI at the time of exchange. A one-page form has been worked out for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no monetary limit for exchange for the eligible resident Indians, but the limit for NRIs will be as per the relevant FEMA Regulations (Rs 25,000 per person).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indian citizens resident in Nepal, Bhutan, Pakistan and Bangladesh cannot avail this facility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The facility to exchange old notes is available at RBI offices in Mumbai, Delhi, Kolkata, Chennai and Nagpur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On fulfillment of the terms and conditions and the genuineness of the notes tendered, the amount will be credited to the person&amp;rsquo;s Know Your Customer (KYC) compliant bank account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case of refusal by the central bank, a person may appeal to the Central Board of the Reserve Bank within 14 days of the communication of such refusal to him. Such representations may be addressed to the Central Board, Reserve Bank of India, Secretary&amp;rsquo;s Department.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto, Health Insurance To Cost More As Regulator Okays Raise For Agents</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Car, motorcycle and health insurance will cost more from April 1 with regulator Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority (IRDAI) giving go-ahead to insurers for revision in commission for agents. The change in premium after modification will be limited to around 5 per cent of the existing rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase will be in addition to the enhanced third party motor insurance rates, which too will come into affect from April. The IRDAI (Payment of Commission or Remuneration or Reward to Insurance Agents and Insurance Intermediaries) Regulations, 2016 comes into effect from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulations, the regulator said, bring about certain revisions in commission/ remuneration rates and also introduce the reward system. These may trigger insurers to revisit the pricing of their products in so far as the costing input relating to commission or remuneration is concerned, said IRDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the change in premium due to the new regulations should be &amp;ldquo;limited to +/- 5 per cent of the existing premium rates of products/add-ons&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, insurers will have to give a certificate that there is &amp;ldquo;no detrimental change&amp;rdquo; in premium rates or any other provision of policies already sold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-based payment modes work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government is planning to utilise the Aadhaar database to give shape to a digital future and utilise it for payments, and authentication of transactions is the key to its success. While Unified Payments Interface and BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) are processes for peer-to-peer transactions using smartphones, the government is promoting Aadhaar-enabled payment systems for the non-smartphone savvy. As per sources it is planning to launch Aadhaar Pay on April 14. ET looks into the different forms of Aadhaar payment modes being developed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems?
Payments that can be done with the help of au thentication and identi fication through the Aadhaar database is referred to as the Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems (AEPS). This is the new form of pay ment that is being pro moted by the govern ment to push for digital payments instead of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the major types of Aadhaar Enabled Payments?
The first type of payment is Aadhaar Bridge Payment System which is meant for direct bene fit transfer and subsidy payments from the gov ernment to the benefi ciaries. The second is AEPS which is used at the level of the business correspondent or `bank mitras’ where bank customers can use Aadhaar to access various services like cash withdrawal, account opening and fund transfer even without going to a bank branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is Aadhaar Pay wherein merchants can accept payments through Aadhaar identification of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we need Aadhaar Enabled payments?
These forms of payments are be ing promoted by the government specifically for the under privileged sections of the society and the rural poor who are not comfortable using cards or mobile wallets for payments.Instead of a mobile phone or a plastic card, in these forms of payments, the mode of authentication becomes the Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who runs the systems?
National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is the nodal authority for all Aadhaar-enabled payments in collaboration with banks. The payment company is trying to get as many banks to seed their customers’ accounts with their Aadhaar number so that payments can flow smoothly .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do the different forms of payments work?
Aahdaar Bridge Payment (ABPS):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant for recur ring payments done by the government to its customers for various subsidies as well as direct benefit transfer. Here the beneficiary is identified through an Aadhaar number, then NPCI manages an Aadhaar Mapper where the Aadhaar number is mapped to a specific bank account and the money flows to the connected bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-enabled-payment-aeps&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Payment (AEPS):&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the customer has to approach a business correspondent (BC), use his Aadhaar number and biometrics which the BC shares with NPCI, which checks the ID with UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India) to confirm the customer’s identity . It also checks the funds in the connected account and allows the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for merchant payments where the merchant will download the merchant payments app of his bank, authenticate the customer through his biometrics and Aadhaar number and initiate a pull transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>