<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 राज्यों के पेट्रोल पंप 14 मई से हर रविवार को रहेंगे बंद</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-in-eight-states-to-be-shut-on-sundays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-in-eight-states-to-be-shut-on-sundays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;14 मई से देश के आठ राज्यों में पेट्रोल पंप हर रविवार को बंद रहेंगे। यह फैसला प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी द्वारा &amp;lsquo;मन की बात&amp;rsquo; रेडियो कार्यक्रम में की गई उस अपील को देखते हुए लिया गया है जिसमें उन्होंने तेल बचाने के लिए देश के लोगों से एक दिन पेट्रोल-डीजल का इस्तेमाल न करने की बात कही थी। पेट्रोल पंप डीलर्स के एक संगठन ने बताया है कि तमिलनाडु, केरल, कर्नाटक, पुडुचेरी, आंध्र प्रदेश, तेलंगाना, महाराष्ट्र और हरियाणा के 20,000 पेट्रोल पंप 14 मई से हर रविवार को बंद रहेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;भारतीय पेट्रोलियम डीलर्स असोसिएशन की एग्जिक्युटिव कमिटी के सदस्य सुरेश कुमार ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;कुछ साल पहले हमने तय किया था कि हर रविवार को हम पेट्रोल पंप बंद रखेंगे, लेकिन तेल कंपनियों ने उस वक्त हमसे फैसले पर पुनर्विचार करने को कहा था, जिसके चलते फैसला अमल में नहीं लाया जा सका। लेकिन अब हमने पेट्रोल पंपों को रविवार को बंद करने का फैसला कर किया है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कुमार ने कहा कि असोसिएशन ने यह फैसला प्रधानमंत्री मोदी द्वारा &amp;lsquo;मन की बात&amp;rsquo; कार्यक्रम में तेल की बचत करने की अपील को देखते हुए किया है। प्रधानमंत्री ने पर्यावरण को बचाने के लिए एक दिन देशवासियों से पेट्रोल-डीजल इस्तेमाल न करने की अपील की थी। तमिलनाडु पेट्रोलियम डीलर्स असोसिएशन के उपाध्यक्ष कुमार ने बताया कि 14 मई से तमिलनाडु, केरल, कर्नाटक, पुडुचेरी, आंध्र प्रदेश, तेलंगाना, महाराष्ट्र और हरियाणा के लगभग 20,000 पेट्रोल पंप हर रविवार को 24 घंटे बंद रहेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कुमार ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;अकेले तमिलनाडु में इस फैसले के चलते हमें 150 करोड़ रुपये का घाटा होने की आशंका है, पर हमने देखा है कि रविवार के दिन वैसे भी सेल्स में 40 फीसदी की कमी आ जाती है।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि तेल कंपनियों को भी इस फैसले की जानकारी जल्द दे दी जाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;असोसिएशन ने यह भी कहा है कि आपात स्थिति में तेल उपलब्ध कराने के लिए हर पेट्रोल पंप पर एक स्टाफ मेंबर मौजूद रहेगा। तेल कंपनियों द्वारा पेट्रोल पंपों का मार्जिन बढ़ाए जाने के मुद्दे पर कुमार ने कहा कि इस बारे में बातचीत चल रही है और इस बारे में जल्द ही कोई ऐलान किया जाएगा। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इसे लेकर हमारा संघर्ष जारी है। हम अपने असोसिएशन के मेंबर्स से जल्द मिलने वाले हैं। हम जल्द अपने फैसले का ऐलान करेंगे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At SBI, You Don&#39;t Need To Maintain Minimum Balance In These Accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India is offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has said it is exempting its customers holding certain account types from maintenance of average monthly balance. Such accounts include small savings bank accounts, basic savings bank accounts and Jan Dhan accounts, or the accounts opened under the government&amp;rsquo;s financial inclusion scheme Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana or PMJDY. This was said in a tweet by SBI, which recently adopted a new brand identity after merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank. SBI had earlier decided to increase the minimum balance required for maintaining savings accounts from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, State Bank of India is also offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.
Account holders of the following types of accounts are exempt from requiring to maintain an average monthly balance: pic.twitter.com/61U8QNu7xR
— State Bank of India (@TheOfficialSBI) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement was increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros. In case of non-compliance, savings bank account holders will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs. 100 (in metro cities), as per the bank&amp;rsquo;s website. (Read more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other features SBI offers under these accounts, according to its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-savings-bank-account&#34;&gt;Small savings bank account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account has a maximum balance limit of Rs 50,000 and offers a rate of interest applicable to savings bank accounts. Account holders get an ATM-cum-Debit card, issued free of cost and without any annual maintenance charge, as per the SBI website. All credits in a financial year should not aggregate to more than Rs 1 lakh and Rs 10,000 in case of withdrawals and transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-savings-account&#34;&gt;Basic savings account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s basic savings account has no minimum balance or maximum balance limits. Holders of this account type &amp;ldquo;will not be eligible to open any other Savings Bank Account&amp;rdquo; at the bank. Such an account - in case the customer already holds one - will have to be closed within 30 days of opening the basic savings bank deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;corporate-salary-package&#34;&gt;Corporate salary package&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s salary account under corporate salary package offers many benefits to the employer and the employee alike. This account type reduces employer&amp;rsquo;s paperwork and salary administration cost. Employees get free internet banking and mobile banking services, among other features, as per the SBI website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Get Time Till June 30 To Obtain PAN From Account Holders</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department has given banks three more months till June 30 to obtain permanent account number (PAN) or Form-60 from all account holders as it looks to tighten the noose around evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the notification, the Income Tax Department said that in Income-Tax Rules 114B, in the fourth proviso, &amp;ldquo;for the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;28th day of February&amp;rsquo; the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;30th day of June&amp;rsquo; shall be substituted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 114B lists various transactions for which quoting PAN is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had in January asked banks, post offices and cooperative banks to document PAN or declaration of Form 60 received from account holders and maintain all records for transactions under Rule 114B of I-T Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had said that persons who have not quoted PAN, or did not furnish Form 60 at the time of opening account, will have to provide the same by February 28. Form 60 is a declaration form filed by an individual without PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the demonetisation move effective November 9, the tax department had asked banks and post offices to report to it all deposits above Rs 2.5 lakh in savings accounts and more than Rs 12.50 lakh in current accounts made between November 10 and December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cash deposits exceeding Rs 50,000 in a single day had to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an estimated Rs 15 lakh crore in junked currency notes coming back into the banking system post demonetisation, the tax department has started analysing the bank deposit trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, You Can Get A PAN Or TAN Within A Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax department today said it has issued Permanent Account Number (PAN) within a day to 19,704 newly incorporated companies till March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Applicant would be benefited by having a digitally signed E-PAN card which they can submit as proof of identity to other agency electronically directly or by storing in the Digital Locker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; CBDT, the apex policy making body of the Income Tax department, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said that newly incorporated companies have also been issued Tax Deduction Account Number (TAN) simultaneously with PAN as the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) has tied up with the Ministry of Corporate Affairs (MCA) under which companies can submit a common application form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicant companies submit a common application form SPICe (INC 32) on MCA portal and once the data of incorporation is sent to CBDT by the MCA, PAN and TAN are issued immediately without any further intervention of the applicant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Certificate of Incorporation (COI) of newly incorporated companies includes the PAN in addition to the Corporate Identity Number (CIN). TAN is also allotted simultaneously and communicated to the company,&amp;rdquo; the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till March 31, 2017, 19,704 newly incorporated companies were allotted PAN in this manner. During March 2017, of the 10,894 newly incorporated companies, PAN was allotted within 4 hours in 95.63 per cent cases and within one day in all cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, TAN was allotted to all such companies within 4 hrs in 94.7 per cent cases and within 1 day in 99.73 per cent cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;CBDT&amp;rsquo;s initiative in starting of a business is expected to significantly improve the ranking of India in the Ease of Doing Business Study conducted by World Bank by reducing the number of processes of registration before various authorities under law, reducing the time taken for allotment of the registration number (CIN, PAN, TAN) and making the entire registration process for new companies much simpler,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh. In the present scenario where bank interest rates are on a falling trend, financial planners say that equity mutual funds are one of the best instruments to accumulate long-term savings through systematic investment plan (SIP). Gains from equity mutual funds after a year are tax-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, fund selection is one of the most difficult things to do for a retail investor as it needs lot of research. Financial planners say diversified equity funds are the best to invest through SIP for long term. Here are some funds which have generates over 20 per cent CAGR return in past 20 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Equity Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on January 1, 1995, it is one of the oldest and best performing funds in India. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.95 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 23.56 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This fund has generated a CAGR return of 23.68 per cent since its inception. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998 would have helped you accumulate a corpus of Rs. 2.12 crore by April 1, 2017 implying 17.66 times return in 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;Franklin India Prima Fund:&lt;/em&gt; It is one of the flagship fund of Franklin Templeton India. Since its inception in December 1993, it has generated a CAGR return of 21.04 per cent till now. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 2.38 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 25.11 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Vision Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on October 8, 1995, it has generated a CAGR return of 19.92 per cent till now. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998, would have become Rs. 1.46 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Top 200 Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This flagship fund of HDFC Mutual Fund has generated a CAGR return of 20.88 per cent since its inception in September 1996. If you would have started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.43 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With falling return on bank fixed deposits, equity mutual funds are witnessing increased investment from retail investors now. Equity and equity-linked schemes have seen inflows of more than Rs. 70,000 crore in last financial year according to Association of Mutual Funds in India data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 540 Crore Black Money Detect Over In Last Fortnight by Income Tax Officials  </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/detect-over-rs-540-crore-black-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/detect-over-rs-540-crore-black-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax department has detected over Rs. 540 crore black money in the next 15 days as part of its nationwide operations to check tax evasion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the PMGKY black money window closed on March 31, the Income Tax department has detected over Rs. 540 crore black money in the next 15 days as part of its nationwide operations to check tax evasion. Officials said the tax sleuths, in the first fortnight of the new financial year that began on April 1, have conducted multiple search and survey operations on entry operators (agents using banking channels to launder funds), shell firms, government officials, real estate players and other sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per an official data compiled till April 15, the department has carried out &amp;ldquo;over 250 search and survey operations where the taxman raided at least 300 shell firms and detected more than Rs. 540 crore of black money.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action is significant as it comes after the closure of the third black money declaration window of the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), provided by the government to people holding stash funds to come clean and pay due taxes and penalty, that ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had brought the first black money declaration window in 2015 for people who held illegal assets abroad followed by the Income Declaration Scheme (IDS) last year where individuals and entities could declare their domestic black funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMGKY was brought by the government in order to check hidden money in the wake of the demonetisation that was announced by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on November 8 last
year. A senior official said three major searches were conducted in Noida near here during the said period against an entry operator who was &amp;ldquo;managing&amp;rdquo; about 200 shell firms for providing entries of bogus sale and purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;More than 20 beneficiaries who have received entries of over Rs. 1 crore have been identified and the total undisclosed income in this case is about Rs. 300 crore,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official added that a real estate broker in the national capital region, dealing in &amp;ldquo;unaccounted cash
transactions on sale of property&amp;rdquo;, was also covered by the department during the said period and tax sleuths have seized documents leading to tax evasion of more than Rs. 50 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior government official of Uttar Pradesh was also searched during the same period after which, the official said, unaccounted cash payments of Rs. 2 crore were detected while four hidden immovable properties in the name of the officer&amp;rsquo;s wife were unearthed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I-T department officials also searched an Ahmedabad-based real estate and infrastructure player where tax evasion to the tune of Rs. 120 crore has been detected, the official said, adding the investigations in this case are still on as the case involves multiple layers of bogus entities. As part of a similar search in Pune against a business group, the entity surrendered Rs. 19 crore income to the department as the black money was generated &amp;ldquo;on account of profit not recorded in the books of account.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Hyderabad-based business group engaged in digital printing was also raided by the department which led to the eizure of over Rs. 1 crore cash, the official said. The official added that these actions will continue in the coming days as after the closure of the PMGKY window all those cases where black money and tax evasion has been detected will have to be &amp;ldquo;thoroughly&amp;rdquo; investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Imposes Fee On Cheque Payments For Credit Card Dues. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card is levying a charge on payments made by cheques. This came into effect from April 1, according to SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s website. The card company said payments made below Rs 2,000 through cheques will attract a fee of Rs 100. &amp;ldquo;A fee of Rs.100 will be charged for payments made by cheque for an amount less than or equal to Rs.2000 w.e.f. 1st April &amp;lsquo;17. No additional fee will be charged for cheque payments greater than Rs. 2000,&amp;rdquo; SBI Card said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen that the majority of payments (over 90 per cent) are made through non-cheque modes. We have observed a trend of payment related disputes arising in small cheque payments, causing inconvenience to customers as well. We offer several seamless digital modes of payment which we are seeking to encourage, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s focus towards digital payments and this step will facilitate the same,&amp;rdquo; said SBI Card CEO Vijay Jasuja.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, payments made through SBI cheques will not incur the extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost. It is also likely to provide a boost to digital payments. SBI, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, entered credit card business in 1998 by roping GE Capital India, the consumer finance arm of US-based GE Capital. SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s latest offering &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; is targeted at all State Bank of India customers, including Jan Dhan account holders throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has introduced the &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; card in an effort to bring new users into the fold of cashless transactions. The card is issued to persons with a balance of Rs 25,000 in their SBI accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No such charge on cheque payments will be levied on holders of SBI Card Unnati which is targeted at first time credit card users and aimed at inclusion of people into the organised financial stream,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jasuja added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visa, Mastercard Threatened By Meteoric Rise of Aadhaar Pay &amp; UPI;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/visa-mastercard-threatened-meteoric-rise-aadhaar-pay-rs-6000-cr-market-danger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/visa-mastercard-threatened-meteoric-rise-aadhaar-pay-rs-6000-cr-market-danger/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Traditional payment processing and payment card companies, Visa and Mastercard, are feeling threatened now, and the reason is the exponential rise of Govt. backed digital payment platforms: Aadhaar Pay and UPI, which combined with BHIM App is giving these companies sleepless nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports emerging, representatives of these companies are trying to meet with senior Govt. officials, to make sure that they are not ignored in this cashless mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One senior Govt. official said, “Aadhaar Pay will be like India’s own solution to the cashless economy. Lots of players such as Visa, MasterCard are shaken up and there is a big war going on. But the government is very clear and wants to just bulldoze ahead with it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, Rs 6000 crore is at stake here, which is estimated to be Visa and Mastercard’s potential market size in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems that Govt is in no mood to assist private players in this highly competitive niche. Earlier, these companies were threatened with the rise of RuPay cards in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will Visa and Mastercard do now, to protect their territory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visa-mastercard-shaken-stirred-due-to-aadhaar-pay-upi-bhim&#34;&gt;Visa, Mastercard Shaken &amp;amp; Stirred Due To Aadhaar Pay, UPI &amp;amp; BHIM&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;payment-processing-companies-like-visa-and-mastercard-charge-1-on-every-transaction-which-is-happening-on-their-platform-and-currently-rs-6-lakh-crore-is-the-size-of-digital-transactions-as-estimated-by-the-govt&#34;&gt;Payment processing companies like Visa and Mastercard charge 1% on every transaction which is happening on their platform. And currently, Rs 6 lakh crore is the size of digital transactions, as estimated by the Govt.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the market size and potential of revenues for Visa and Mastercard is Rs 6000 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But due to the immense popularity of UPI-based transactions, and the recent launch of Aadhaar-based BHIM Appfor merchants have induced fear among these traditional payment processing companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the reason is that UPI and Aadhaar Pay doesn’t give any transactions fees to Visa or Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Govt. official said, “Card companies get 1% commission is which is around Rs 6,000 crore market for the likes of Visa, MasterCard and Rupay. Since UPI, BHIM and Aadhaar Pay don’t give this commission to them, they think it’s a big loss to them of the potential business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, these companies are feeling ignored, and out of the digital ecosystem of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports coming in, officials from these companies are making rounds of Niti Ayog office, and Finance Department for seeking more collaboration and partnerships. But Govt. is in no mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One official from Niti Aayog said, “We are not in the process of protecting the revenue of private players. The government will continue to provide alternate and cheaper options to end users to enable them to board our digital payment drive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note here, that earlier this month, Amitabh Kant, CEO of Niti Aayog had declared that in future, ATMs and Credit/Debit cards will disappear; and only mobile wallets and Aadhaar based payment mechanism will survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that Aadhaar Pay is supported by 27 banks and 715,000 merchants within weeks of its launch, 19 million people are already using BHIM App is not good news for Visa and Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visa-mastercard-puts-up-a-brave-face&#34;&gt;Visa, Mastercard Puts Up A Brave Face&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;meanwhile-both-mastercard-and-visa-officials-in-india-have-put-up-a-brave-face-and-have-assured-that-there-is-nothing-to-worry-despite-the-fact-that-aadhaar-already-covers-99-of-indian-population-40-banks-are-already-linked-with-aadhaar&#34;&gt;Meanwhile, both Mastercard and Visa officials in India have put up a brave face and have assured that there is nothing to worry, despite the fact that Aadhaar already covers 99% of Indian population, 40 banks are already linked with Aadhaar.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porush Singh, divisional president for MasterCard in South Asia said, “We don’t see it as a loss of business. There is enough opportunity for multiple players. Otherwise, you wouldn’t have had more banks in the ecosystem or wallet operators or payment solutions. We haven’t seen it yet (possible impact), but yes if the consumer finds it more relevant, then we will have to start evaluating.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Visa is devising plans to work with the Govt., in order to take the digital story forward. TR Ramachandran, group country manager, India and South Asia said, “We will continue working with the government, our clients and merchants to expand access to electronic payments in support of India’s drive to a less-cash society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to stay relevant in the market, both of these companies have launched innovative schemes, such as QR Code based payments, and contactless payment interface. Last year, talks were on regarding a massive collaboration to combine forces of Visa, Mastercard and BharatQR code into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Govt. estimates, cashless payment ecosystem will increase from Rs 6 lakh to Rs 90 lakh crore in few years. But, will Visa and Mastercard be relevant then?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can Win Up To 168 GB Of 4G Data In Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-win-up-to-168-gb-of-4g/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-win-up-to-168-gb-of-4g/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio subscribers with Vivo smartphones can participate in the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania scheme &amp;ldquo;only once&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within days of announcing its &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans, Jio is offering up to 168GB of 4G data to Vivo smartphone users. &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania - exciting new contest for all cricket fans out there! Win extra 4G data by supporting your favourite IPL team,&amp;rdquo; Jio said on its website. Under its &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania&amp;rdquo; scheme, IPL or Indian Premier League 2017 fans can pick their favourite team and bag &amp;ldquo;extra 4G data&amp;rdquo; every time the selected team wins, loses or draws a league match &amp;ldquo;because winning and losing is part of the game&amp;rdquo;, said Jio - the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries. (Also read: Jio helps Reliance Industries to become India&amp;rsquo;s most valued company)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-avail-vivo-jio-cricket-mania-offer&#34;&gt;Who can avail Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be a Jio subscriber with a Vivo smartphone to be able to participate in the scheme. You can avail the offer only once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users are required to register by May 10, 2017 to enjoy the full benefit of the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, those registering to Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer after April 30 will get 50 per cent of complimentary 4G data accumulated. The amount of 4G data on offer will be based on the outcome of the league matches played by the selected team till the end of the first round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-much-data-if-my-team-wins-loses-draws-an-ipl-2017-match&#34;&gt;How much data if my team wins/loses/draws an IPL 2017 match?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering 3GB of 4G data for a win, 2GB for a draw and 1GB for a loss. If your favourite IPL 2017 team wins more than one time, &amp;ldquo;your 4G Data multiply&amp;rdquo;, according to Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-subscribe&#34;&gt;How to subscribe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those using a Vivo smartphone with a Jio connection need to select their favourite IPL 2017 team on or before May 10, 2017. Customers need to send their entries by an SMS from their Jio number to 59009 in a format specified by Jio on its website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/vivo-jio-cricket-mania-sms-format-650_650x400_61492496761.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now, support your favourite team and every time it wins, VIVO and JIO WILL WALK THE EXTRA MILE FOR YOU to support your passion,&amp;rdquo; Jio added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-will-i-get-my-data&#34;&gt;When will I get my data?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users will accumulate all the 4G data under the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer at the end of the series. The 4G data on offer under this scheme can be as much as 168GB. Users will have to recharge with Rs. 303 or more every month to be eligible for this extra data benefit. Jio will credit the GBs earned under the &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania&amp;rdquo; offer over the next 10 recharges as data boosters, starting from June 1, 2017 to March 31, 2018, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>काले धन वालों को आयकर विभाग की चेतावनी, 31 मार्च के बाद 137.25% तक लगेगा टैक्स</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/137-tax-if-you-dont-come-clean-on-hidden-cash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आयकर विभाग ने आज काले धन वालों को आगाह करते हुए कहा है कि उसके पास उनके द्वारा बैंकों में जमा कराई गई बेहिसाब नकदी के बारे में जानकारी है। विभाग ने सलाह दी कि काले धन वालों को पाक साफ होकर निकलने के लिए प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना (पीएमजीकेवाई) का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए। ऐसा नहीं करने वालों से जमा राशि का 137 प्रतिशत तक वसूला जा सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विभाग ने इस बारे में राष्ट्रीय समाचार पत्रों में विज्ञापन प्रकाशित किया है। इसमें कहा गया है कि उलटी गिनती शुरू हो गई है और बेहिसाबी धन जमा कराने वाले इसकी घोषणा करें, वरना बाद में पछताना पड़ सकता है। प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत घोषणा की अंतिम तारीख 31 मार्च है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;विज्ञापन में कहा गया है कि आयकर विभाग के पास आपकी जमाओं की जानकारी है। विभाग ने कहा है कि इस योजना के तहत कालेधन की घोषणा करने वालों की गोपनीयता सुनिश्चित की जाएगी। विज्ञापन में स्पष्ट चेतावनी दी गई है कि योजना के तहत काले धन की जानकारी नहीं देने वालों को बेनाम कानून के तहत कठोर कार्रवाई का सामना करना होगा। यहां तक कि उनके नाम ईडी और सीबीआई जैसी केंद्रीय जांच एजेंसियों के साथ साझा कर दिए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने कहा कि जो लोग प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना का लाभ लेते हुए अपनी काली कमाई उजागर नहीं करेंगे, उन्हें जमा राशि पर 137% तक जुर्माना लगाया जा सकता है। उनके मुताबिक, विभाग ऐसे डिफॉल्टरों पर नए बेनामी लेनदेन कानून के तहत कार्रवाई करने से भी नहीं हिचकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अधिकारी ने बताया कि प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना के तहत काला धन की जानकारी देने वालों को 49.9 प्रतिशत टैक्स देना होगा, जबकि ऐसा नहीं कर इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न में इस धन का जिक्र करने वालों को टैक्स के साथ-साथ 77.25 प्रतिशत जुर्माना देना होगा। साथ ही, जो लोग योजना के तहत काले धन का खुलासा नहीं करते हैं और जांच आकलन में इसका पता चलता है तो उन्हें 83.25 प्रतिशत की दर से टैक्स वसूला जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो लोग योजना का फायदा लेते हुए काले धन की जानकारी सरकार को नहीं देते हैं और छापेमारी के दौरान छिपा हुआ धन सरेंडर करते हैं तो उन्हें 107.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना होगा। लेकिन, जो लोग छापेमारी में भी काला धन खुद निकाल कर नहीं देते हैं, उन्हें 137.25 प्रतिशत टैक्स और जुर्माना देना पड़ सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बेनामी कानून में दोषियों को 7 साल तक की कैद से दंडित करने का प्रावधान है। इसके अलावा, उस पर आयकर कानून के तहत भी मुकदमा चल सकता है। साथ ही, उस पर बेनामी संपत्ति के उचित बाजार मूल्य का 25 प्रतिशत और दूसरे जुर्माने भी भरने होंगे। गौरतलब है कि सरकार ने नोटबंदी के ऐलान के बाद प्रधानमंत्री गरीब कल्याण योजना की घोषणा की थी। इस योजना के तहत कुल घोषित काले धन का एक चौथाई हिस्सा चार साल के लिए बिना ब्याज के सरकार के पास जमा रखने की बाध्यता है। यह योजना पिछले साल 17 दिसंबर को शुरू हुई।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>67% jump in corruption complaints; railways tops: Central Vigilance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/67-jump-in-corruption-complaints-railways-tops-cvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/67-jump-in-corruption-complaints-railways-tops-cvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Corruption complaints against various government departments jumped by a whopping 67 per cent in 2016 over the previous year, with the Railways topping the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 11,000 complaints were received against the public sector behemoth, the Central Vigilance Commission (CVC) has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its annual report tabled in Parliament recently, the probity watchdog said it received a total of 49,847 complaints in 2016, as against 29,838 in 2015 &amp;ndash; an increase of 67 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Commission received a considerable number of complaints against public servants working in the state governments and other organisations who do not come under the jurisdiction of the Commission or which are of administrative nature,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of complaints received by the CVC in 2015 were 50 per cent less than a total of 62,363 received by it in 2014. The CVC had got 31,432 and 37,039 complaints of alleged corruption during 2013 and 2012 respectively, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving details, the CVC said the highest of 11,200 such complaints were against railway employees. Of these 8,852 were disposed of and 2,348 were pending. Further, a total of 1,054 complaints against railway employees were pending for more than six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of complaints against those under government of National Capital Territory of Delhi has declined with a total of 969 received last year as against 5,139 in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many as 6,513 complaints of alleged corruption were received against employees under Home Ministry, followed by 6,018 bank officials and 2,496 related to those working with the Ministry of Petroleum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 2,646 corruption complaints were received against officials of the Income Tax department, 2,514 against those in Urban Development Ministry and 2,393 related to employees working under Telecommunication Ministry, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 1,746 corruption complaints against employees under Labour Ministry, 1,668 in Food and Consumer Affairs department, 1,420 of customs and excise, 1,376 in public sector insurance companies and 1,369 against officials of Ministry of Steel, the CVC said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 759 complaints were against Coal Ministry employees, 724 of Information and Broadcasting Ministry, 689 in Defence, 571 related to employees of Health and Family Welfare department and 479 against officials of Shipping Ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar authentication a must for engineering scholarships</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The state higher and technical education department has made authentication of Aadhaar number a must for backward engineering students to avail scholarships. The move comes against the backdrop of large-scale scholarship scam across the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though decision has been welcomed by city engineering colleges, they feel the authentication process will burden them with extra work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a gazette notification dated April 13, the department states that every student desirous of availing benefits under the schemes specified in Schedule ‘A’ need to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo authentication process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process involves submission of aadhaar number along with demographic information or biometrics of the beneficiary to the Central Indentities Data Repository for verification. The repository verifies the correctness of the claims on the basis of information available with it. The repository is a centralized database having all aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schemes listed in Schedule ‘A’ are Rajashri Chhatrapati Shahu Maharaj Shikshan Shulk Shishyavrutti Yojana and Dr Panjabrao Deshmukh Vastigruh Nirvah Bhatta Yojana. The scholarships are meant for other backward class (OBC) students and take care of certain percentage of tuition and hostel fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The directorate of technical education’s website, too, has alerted students to provide aadhaar authentication details otherwise their reimbursement would be put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification issued by deputy secretary Kiran Patil clarifies that students who do not have enrolled for Aadhaar can still available the scholarships on two conditions. The Aadhaar enrolment ID slip can be attached to their applications. In case they are not able to enrol due to non-availability of enrolment centres, they may write to the UIDAI’s designated field offices or register through its web portal and attach a copy of this request with the application. The students will also have to submit a proof of identity from one of the listed documents that included voter ID card, PAN, passport driving licence, bank passbook, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department has issued the guidelines under section 3 and 4 of the Maharashtra Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act 2016, that is stringent than the mother Act. As per the new Act, proof of possession of Aadhaar number or authentication is required in availing state government subsidy, benefits or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A city college principal said the aadhaar ID is itself foolproof and there was no need to add an extra authentication process. “A person’s biometric details can be viewed through Aadhaar number. Why principals should be asked to verify a student’s domicile. The social welfare department too had asked us to verify students’ income proof. This is the tehsildar or SDO’s job. They have only increased our work,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>