<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>1,500 रुपये का 4G फीचर फोन जल्द बन सकता है हकीकत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4G फीचर फोन या बेसिक मोबाइल फोन, जिसकी कीमत 1,500 रुपये हो, जल्द ही हकीकत बन सकता है। चाइनीज मोबाइल चिप मेकर स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस ने कहा है कि वह मौजूदा लेवल्स से शुरुआती कीमत कम से कम आधा करने पर काम कर रही है। एक डिवेलपमेंट एक्सपर्ट ने कहा कि यह कई कन्ज्यूमर को स्मार्टफोन की ओर शिफ्टिंग से रोक सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस के कंट्री हेड नीरज शर्मा ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, ‘हम एक ऐसी टेक्नॉलजी पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो कि 1,500 रुपये के 4G फीचर फोन को व्यावहारिक बनाती है। हमने अपने पार्टनर्स के लिए कॉन्सेप्ट प्रमोशन पहले ही शुरू कर दिया है।’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लावा और माइक्रोमैक्स जैसी घरेलू मोबाइल फोन कंपनियों के 4G फीचर फोन की कीमतें करीब 3,000 रुपये से शुरू होती हैं। कॉर्बन के अलावा, यह दोनों हैंडसेट मेकर कंपनियां आगे ऐसे फोन की कीमतें घटाना चाहती हैं। इस मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले इंडस्ट्री एग्जिक्यूटिव्स के मुताबिक, रिलायंस जियो इंफोकॉम भी अपनी सहयोगी रिटेल फर्म के जरिए किफायती 4G VoLTE फीचर फोन लाने की योजना बना रही है, इस फोन की कीमत 1,500 रुपये से कम हो सकती है। शंघाई बेस्ड स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस बेसबैंड चिप सेगमेंट में सधी ग्रोथ हासिल कर रही है और यह मीडियाटेक, क्वॉलकॉम जैसे मोबाइल चिप मेकर्स के साथ मुकाबला कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चिपसेट, किसी भी मोबाइल हैंडसेट का एक अहम हिस्सा है और डिवाइस की कीमत में इसकी बड़ी हिस्सेदारी होती है। स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस की रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज के साथ दो साल पुरानी पार्टनरशिप है और इसने RIL के अफोर्डेबल LYF फ्लेम 5 स्मार्टफोन को तैयार किया है। कंपनी ने लावा M1 4G फीचर फोन को भी पावर्ड किया है, जिसकी कीमत 3,599 रुपये है। कंपनी का कहना है कि उसे टेक्नॉलजी ईजाद करने और डिवाइसेज को मार्केट तक पहुंचाने में करीब छह महीने लगते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फाइनेंशल सर्विसेज फर्म जेपी मॉर्गन ने अपनी एक हालिया रिपोर्ट में कहा है कि 2017 में 4G कैपेबिलिटी वाले फीचर फोन पॉपुलर होंगे। इन्हें उम्मीद से कहीं ज्यादा तेजी से आने वाले 4G नेटवर्क से मजबूती मिलेगी। शर्मा ने कहा कि यह देखना काफी रोचक होगा कि ऐसे समय में जबकि मार्केट का झुकाव डेटा प्ले की तरफ है और वॉयस सेगमेंट स्थिर हो गया है, तब ऑपरेटर्स अपनी स्ट्रैटिजी को कैसे पुख्ता बनाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, ‘पिछले छह महीने में मार्केट पूरी तरह से 3G से 4G में शिफ्ट हो गया है और दमदार टेक्नॉलजी के बीच वेंडर्स को अपनी मार्केट स्ट्रैटेजी को दुरुस्त करना होगा।’ उन्होंने कहा कि अडिशनल वैल्यू ऑफर करने वाले LTE फीचर फोन को और आकर्षक तरीके में पैक्ड किया जाना चाहिए। साथ ही उन्हें बढ़ते डेटा मार्केट के हिसाब से टियर-III लोकेशंस और रूरल एरिया में बेचा जाना चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been reported that a new ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; is spreading widely, the RBI advisory to the banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wannacry encrypts the files on infected Windows system and spreads by exploiting vulnerabilities, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI also asked all banks to put in place a software update at ATMs to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate malware attack last year, 3.2 lakh debit cards were compromised in the country. Data of the users who transacted from ATM machines of Hitachi were compromised during May, June and July last year. The Hitachi ATMs deployed by many White Label ATM players and Yes Bank were impacted by the malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, ATMs or automated teller machines are highly vulnerable to such malware attacks as they currently run on old version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, making a software security patch update a necessary exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a total of 2.2 lakh ATMs in India, of which many old ones run on Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, the ransomware has hit systems in more than 150 countries, including Russia and the UK, in one of the most widespread cyber attacks in history. It infected computers running on older versions of Microsoft operating systems like XP, locking access to files on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cyber criminals have demanded a fee of about $300 in crypto-currencies like Bitcoin for unlocking the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has introduced a security patch to tackle the situation, and consumers across the globe have been advised to download the solution at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CERT-In on Monday said it has not received any formal report of cyber attack on India&amp;rsquo;s vital networks by the crippling global ransomware, &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) had said on Sunday that a few systems of the Police Department in Andhra Pradesh were impacted and that the state government has been informed to follow the advisory by the CERT-In.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the Maharashtra Police department said it was partially hit by the ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the alert, the Gujarat government began equipping its state computer systems with anti-virus software and upgrading its Microsoft operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the advisory issued by CERT-In, the ransomware infects other computers on the same network and is also spreading through malicious attachments to e-mails. Security firms have suggested that users immediately disconnect the infected device from the local network to contain the spread of infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, major companies including telecommunications firm Telefonica have been infected. The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks limit functions to a minimum to avoid hack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/amid-wannacry-chaos-banks-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/amid-wannacry-chaos-banks-limit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Indian banks ordered a ban on staff using internet in office except for essential banking services, while the leader, State Bank of India, has installed new software and ordered branches to follow instructions to prevent Wannacry malware from crippling operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bankers were barred from accessing various websites, including Gmail and Yahoo. Those in non-sensitive departments were also told not to visit social media sites like Facebook and Twitter. The use of internet was permitted only for clearing operations and necessary businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is to be taken most seriously. Please ensure these are percolated to the last mile up to every employee having access to the network, including staff working in offices/departments/TCs/call centres, etc,&amp;rdquo; Union Bank of India chairman Arun Tiwary said in a message to departmental heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian Banks&amp;rsquo; Association warned its members to take precaution in a way that would protect the individual banks as well as the system from the attack, which is threatening to stall businesses. &amp;ldquo;We have advised banks to take utmost precaution in light of the reports of a global cyber attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This advisory is just precautionary in nature and we are confident that banks are well equipped to deal with any challenges that come,&amp;rdquo; said an IBA official. He cannot be named because he is not allowed to speak to media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks, in general, use dedicated computers to access internet so that their core banking solutions remain immune to outside threats, but these dedicated machines are now being used with restrictions, senior officials of three state-run banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are being extremely vigilant because of this new threat. Though we have found nothing extraordinary in our systems so far, our IT teams are on high alert because of this heightened threat,&amp;rdquo; said the chief operating officer at a private sector bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The malware spreads by exploiting vulnerable systems running on Windows operating system. The Indian Computer Emergency Response Team has issued advisory for prevention of this threat. &amp;ldquo;So far, there is nothing damaging coming out of India, but there is considerable risk for the large databases of KYC and Aadhaar, which banks will have to be careful about,&amp;rdquo; said Ashvin Parekh, an independent banking consultant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October last year, a malwarerelated security breach had forced SBI to block six-lakh debit cards as a precaution after it was alerted by card network companies such as Mastercard and Visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Digital transactions in financial services have grown at a rapid pace in India, but investment in security is not commensurate with the risk the transactions pose,&amp;rdquo; said Piyush Singh, managing director, financial services - Asia Pacific, Accenture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks in India will not only have to look at investment in technology infrastructure, but also operations management and contagion of risks posed by technology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Banks Cut Home Loans Rates, Special Discounts for Women</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ICICI and HDFC&amp;rsquo;s decision comes close on the heels of the State Bank of India and LIC Housing Finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICICI Bank cut home loan rates by 0.3% for loans up to Rs 30 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDFC lowers rate to 8.35% for new home loan up to 30 lakh for women&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest private sector lender ICICI Bank cut its home loan rates by 0.3 per cent for loans up to Rs 30 lakh, a move that was matched by HDFC Bank on Monday bringing them in line with the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India. SBI is the biggest player in the home loan segment with around 26 per cent market share, followed by HDFC. With the cut in interest rates, salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40 per cent while salaried women borrowers will get home loans at 8.35 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the move, ICICI Bank managing director Chanda Kochhar said the bank is committed to supporting the government&amp;rsquo;s vision to provide housing for all by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In line with this commitment, we have reduced the home loan interest rates for the affordable housing segment. With this announcement, customers of Economically Weaker Section (EWS) and Low Income Group (LIG) can avail the dual benefit of low interest rates from us and the Credit Linked Subsidy under the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICICI Bank also said that its customers taking home loans in the affordable segment will also have the option to select the type of interest rate. In both these cases, the reduction in interest rates is 30 basis points from the previous rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can enjoy the benefit of floating interest rate or a fixed interest rate for the initial two/three years followed by floating rate, ICICI Bank said, claiming to be the first to offer such flexibility to customers. &amp;ldquo;The reduced rate will be effective from May 15, 2017 for new borrowers,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI and LIC Housing Finance had dialed back interest rates on housing loans last week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Correct Aadhaar, PAN Details Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-aadhaar-pan-details-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-aadhaar-pan-details-online/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tax department has launched facilities to correct errors in PAN, Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has urged taxpayers to link Aadhaar with PAN immediately. This will be useful for e-verification of income tax returns using OTP (one-time password) sent to their mobile registered with Aadhaar, the tax department said. In this regard, the income tax department has launched an online facility to link Aadhaar with PAN, In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided by taxpayer when compared to the actual data in Aadhaar, One Time Password (Aadhaar OTP) will be sent to the mobile registered with Aadhaar. In rare cases where Aadhaar name is completely different from name in PAN, then the linking will fail and taxpayer will be prompted to change the name in either Aadhaar or in PAN database, the tax department said. For the benefit of taxpayers, the income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IT department has launched an online facility to link Aadhaar with PAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor mismatches in Aadhaar name and PAN name can be fixed with an OTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In rare cases a user will be prompted to change name in Aadhaar or PAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website - &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; - one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/graph_650x400_51494824521.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/pan_650x400_41494824562.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;2) The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for correcting data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The income tax department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has a new link on its homepage for connecting Aadhaar with PAN of a taxpayer.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/graph_650x400_51494824644.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;4) There is no need to log in or be registered on e-filing website of the income tax department. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The link requires a person to key in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact&amp;rdquo; name as mentioned on the Aadhaar card. After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR). Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN or permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware Virus WannaCry Hits Gujarat Government&#39;s IT Network</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-virus-affects-gujarat-government-it-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-virus-affects-gujarat-government-it-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The virus has affected around 120 computers linked to the Gujarat State Wide Area Network.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 120 computers connected to the Gujarat government&amp;rsquo;s information technology network were hit by ransomware virus &amp;lsquo;Wannacry&amp;rsquo; though no &amp;ldquo;valuable&amp;rdquo; data was compromised, a senior government official said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As per our information, so far the virus has affected around 120 computers in different government departments linked to the Gujarat State Wide Area Network (GSWAN),&amp;rdquo; said Science and Technology Department Secretary Dhananjay Dwivedi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But none of the affected computer has any valuable data or important information that could adversely impact the government&amp;rsquo;s functioning,&amp;rdquo; said Dwivedi. Many computers linked to the district collectorate across the state were affected by the virus even though no major data loss was reported.
Following the attack, computers that were functioning were shut down as precautionary measure, crippling the work, the officials said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six computers at Mehsana district collectorate were affected by the ransomware virus with the message reflecting on the screen saying that the data of the computer has been &amp;ldquo;encrypted&amp;rdquo; and one will have to pay a certain amount in bitcoins to get the data back, an official of the National Informatics Centre said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mehsana Collector Alok Pandey said following the attack, all computers connected to the district collectorate were shut down as precautionary measure. &amp;ldquo;All computers have been shut down after the attack was reported in some computers. These were the computers operating independently and there is no data loss as such due to the attack,&amp;rdquo; said Pandey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several collectorates across the state reported instances of computers getting affected by the virus. At least three computers of Jamnagar Regional Transport Office were also affected by the virus, leading to shutting down of the RTO&amp;rsquo;s entire operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The computers which were linked to the works related to the registration certificate (RC) books were affected by the virus, which sent out the message that the data have been encrypted, said Assistant RTO F U Jakhra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affected computers, however, were not linked to GSWAN network, and were being handled by a private agency, added Jakhra. State&amp;rsquo;s Crime Records Bureau (CRB) issued advisory for the police stations and public to take precautionary measures to prevent the attack and said reports have been sought from individual police stations where computers were affected by the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have sought reports from police stations on what kind of problem they have faced with their computer with regards to data. We will analyse the report and take corrective actions accordingly,&amp;rdquo; said SCRB SP Ashok Kumar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, anti-virus software was being installed and operating system upgraded in computers connected to GSWAN to prevent such hacking attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Reliance-Jio-VoLTE-feature-phone.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen. It also has a dedicated button for torchlight. Maker of this feature phone is not known yet. Currently we don’t have any specifications of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to recent reports, Jio will launch these VoLTE-enabled feature phones starting at Rs. 999 that will run on Android operating system. Earlier reports said that capability to make VoLTE calls in these feature phones will be enabled by Spreadtrum chips, and Jio is in talks with Qualcomm and MediaTek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Jio plans start as low as Rs. 149 per month offering unlimited calls, this will be useful for those who make a lot of calls and need a cheap phone with a keypad. We should know more details about more upcoming VoLTE-enabled feature phones from Jio soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Indian companies pay WannaCry ransom</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/despite-legal-implication-some-companies-pay-the-ransom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/despite-legal-implication-some-companies-pay-the-ransom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A top executive working with an Indian conglomerate couldn&amp;rsquo;t fathom how a bill of $300 (Rs 19,000) landed up at his company for using a free Wi-Fi at a five-star hotel coffee shop. The CEO of another New Delhibased manufacturing company clicked on an unknown link — a mistake that would come back to haunt him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laptops of the executive and the CEO were compromised by ransomware WannaCry, the malicious fast-spreading virus that has confounded cyber security experts around the world. The malware demands $300 in bitcoins to release the infected system and its data, causing hundreds of millions of dollars in business damage to corporations and government utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though lawyers and experts have been advising companies to not pay bitcoins, some Indian companies are believed to have gone ahead and paid the ransom to get their systems unlocked. &amp;ldquo;There would be some companies that may have paid the ransom in haste to retrieve their encrypted data. As of Monday morning, the hackers seem to have globally collected 23 bitcoins, which is around $41,400,&amp;rdquo; said Amit Jaju, executive director, Fraud Investigation &amp;amp; Dispute Services (FIDS), EY India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most legal experts and cybercrime experts are cautioning companies not to pay as this could also have legal implications. &amp;ldquo;PwC never recommends paying ransomware ransom — unless there is a threat to life. Doing so fuels the ransomware economy, funding development of additional ransomware techniques and campaigns. In many cases, we have seen that when money is paid, larger attack happens a few days or weeks later,&amp;rdquo; said Sivarama Krishnan, leader -cyber security at PwC India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Twitter handle, @actual_ransom, that describes itself as &amp;ldquo;a bot that is watching the bitcoin wallets tied to WannaCry ransomware attack&amp;rdquo; is also providing live updates of bitcoins paid by companies globally. &amp;ldquo;While we are monitoring this Twitter handle, you can&amp;rsquo;t trust the authenticity of this,&amp;rdquo; said a cybercrime expert with a consultancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports of corporations crippled by the attack are pouring in three days after the hackers stunned the world and showed the impotence of cyber security networks. The ransomware locked about 200 computers of a Mumbai-headquartered company, which did not have any backup for its crucial income tax data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The company worried that the income tax department would come after it if it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the data readily available,&amp;rdquo; said a person in the know. Legal experts are cautioning companies against paying the ransom as this could land them in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While some companies may consider making payment to obtain the decryption key to unlock their computers that have been locked by the WCry virus, one must consider the legal implications of this action,&amp;rdquo; said Tushar Ajinkya, partner, DSK Legal, a law firm. &amp;ldquo;In the event it is concluded that the actions of the ransomware WCry in demanding payment for release of the encrypted data tantamount to extortion, then in addition to a FEMA violation, facilitators and recipients of such payment may also attract provisions of the PMLA,&amp;rdquo; Ajinkya said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies are believed to have paid the bitcoins with the help of third-party service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Typically, the process involves creating a bitcoin wallet and then making the payment. However, this should ideally be done in consultation with legal, forensic and cyber expert advisors as there tends to be little or no guarantee of regaining access to the data once the ransom is paid,&amp;rdquo; said Jaju of EY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time a ransomware has attacked India Inc. ET on January 11 reported that hackers seized control of computers at three banks and a pharmaceutical company and then demanded a ransom in bitcoins for the decryption keys to unfreeze them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases, Indian companies do not wish to report the cases or file a complaint with the investigative authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even Indian banks, which are required to make a mandatory disclosure to the regulator of any cyberattack, seldom do this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trai Releases An App Which Lets You Rate Call Quality</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sector regulator Trai today said it will soon roll-out an app that enables subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call. The &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app would be available by the end of this month, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) chairman RS Sharma said at &amp;lsquo;Digital Broadcasting in India - Way Forward&amp;rsquo;, a seminar to commemorate the completion of 20 years of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We would like the consumers to assess the quality of calls, through &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app, which will be rolled out by this month end,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, once downloaded, the new app would give the subscribers the choice of assessing the quality of all or a portion of calls. When the call is completed, the users will be able to rate it, and the data will thereafter be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The application will pop up a window and enquire about the quality of the call. The subscriber can give it one star to five stars. There will also be assessment parameters like whether the call was indoors or outside or while travelling,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government and the regulator have refused to lower their guard on the issue of call drops, and have kept a close watch on call quality through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.
Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops. The system is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trai through its analytics portal has also rolled out initiatives that measure data speeds and maps call drops in India, which is the world&amp;rsquo;s second largest telecom market with 1.12 billion mobile subscribers.
Sharma today said that Trai also plans to &amp;ldquo;strengthen&amp;rdquo; the &amp;lsquo;Do Not Disturb&amp;rsquo; or DND service aimed at blocking pesky calls by telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already done a lot of work in this,&amp;rdquo; Sharma said, but refused to elaborate on the upcoming plans. At present, there is a framework for DND registry that allows telecom subscribers to block unwanted communication from telemarketers. Reaching out to such subscribers can result in a heavy fine for telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source familiar with the initiative said that the regulator may look at building specific intelligence features into the system such that pesky messages with certain key words could automatically generate a prompt on whether the users wishes to report the message as a spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the occasion, Communications Minister Manoj Sinha said TRAI&amp;rsquo;s regulatory framework has provided a conducive environment for the sector&amp;rsquo;s growth. It has made the sector more competitive and enhanced accessibility of services at affordable tariffs, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awareness of the some of the main challenges faced by the sector and regulatory framework of today - ranging from convergence to the persisting issue of the digital divide - is therefore necessary to be better equipped to handle these challenges in future,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is WannaCry ransomware? How can it affect India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-is-wannacry-ransomware-how-can-it-affect-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-is-wannacry-ransomware-how-can-it-affect-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware, also known as WannaCrypt, has affected over 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on May 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware, also known as WannaCrypt, has affected over 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on May 12. Termed as one of the biggest ransomware attacks the world has ever seen, this bug has slept open dark signs of vulnerabilities in the digital era. Governments and experts are expecting a possible worsening of the ransomware cyber-attack. The indiscriminate attack began Friday and struck banks, hospitals and government agencies, exploiting known vulnerabilities in older Microsoft computer operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the attack about?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware that is also called WannaCrypt, affected at least 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on Friday. The WanaCrypt0r 2.0 bug basically encrypts data on a computer within seconds and displays a message asking the user to pay a ransom of $ 300 in Bitcoins to restore access to the device and the data inside. Even FedEx, European car factories, Spanish telecoms giant Telefonica, Britain’s health service and Germany’s Deutsche Bahn rail network have been hit. Payment is demanded within three days or the price is doubled, and if none is received within seven days the locked files will be deleted, according to the screen message, agencies reported.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/cZ543_0bjbw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is India safe? Is you Aadhaar card save?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack was specifically targeted at Microsoft Windows devices. Microsoft claims it “released a security update which addresses the vulnerability that these attacks are exploiting” in March itself, and advised users to update their systems in order to deploy the latest patches. However, Indians usually have the Windows running on office desktops, which makes the data vulnerable. A lot of personal data online are now connected to the Aadhaar data of over a billion Indians. “Since the user’s bank account is linked with his Aadhaar number, the ransomware can potentially lock down the account and make it unusable unless a ransom is paid,” Pradipto Chakrabarty, Regional Director, CompTIA India.
F-Secure highlighted the need for a four-phase approach to cybersecurity: Predict, Prevent, Detect, and Respond; and detect by monitoring infrastructure for signs of intrusion or suspicious behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how do I protect my PC from WannaCry?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-do-i-protect-my-pc-from-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-do-i-protect-my-pc-from-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything you need to know about ransomware including the WannaCry attack, how to protect your PCs and laptops and what to do if you&amp;rsquo;re affected.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How does WannaCry work?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a lot of malware, it can arrive as an email attachment. This method relies on computer users opening the attachment, or clicking on a link in an email, which causes the program to run.
People often open these attachments or click links out of curiosity, because the sender is someone in their address book.
WannaCry then encrypts all the files and documents on the computer so the user cannot open them.
It displays a message saying “Ooops, your files have been encrypted!” and says you have three days to pay a $300 or $600 ransom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which versions of Windows are affected?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your computer runs Windows 10, it wasn’t targeted by WannaCry according to Microsoft’s blog post.
Also, up-to-date Windows 10 PCs would have been protected from the attack in any case.
The same security update in March would have protected Windows Vista, Windows 7 and Windows 8.1 systems, as long as you had automatic updates turned on (which is the default).
Only older versions of Windows which are no longer supported were vulnerable, including Windows XP and Windows 8.
It’s worth noting, though, that in general home users should not be affected by this particular piece of ransomware. It mainly targeted computers running the business version of Windows, specifically those using the SMB network file system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can I protect my files from WannaCry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has issued a security patch for Windows XP and Windows 8 – a very unusual step for unsupported operating systems – which you can download from the links on Microsoft’s blog.
If you have Windows Update enabled on other versions then you will already be protected against WannaCry and any other attacks which use the same vulnerability.
If you’re not sure, then open the Control Panel (you’ll find a link in the Start menu) and search for Windows Update. Click through to Windows Update and you’ll be able to check if it’s enabled or not.
There should be a button ‘Check for updates’ which you can click to force Windows to search and install critical updates.
Back up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, as we always recommend, you should have at least one (if not two) copies of any files you can’t afford to lose. Photos, home videos, financial documents and other files that can’t be replaced should be backed up regularly.
Ransomware is often clever enough to scan your home network and infect other computers and even network storage drives (NAS drives) so it’s really important to make a backup on an external hard drive that you disconnect and keep safely somewhere.
You can find our pick of the best backup software here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t open attachments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, as the computer user, are often the weak link in the chain. Windows and antivirus software – see below – can help to protect you from ransomware attacks, but you can help yourself by being extremely cautious about which email attachments you open and which links you click.
Typically, emails from hackers won’t contain a personal message, or it will be so generic that you can’t be sure it’s really from the person in the ‘sender’ field.
In WannaCry’s case, at least some of the emails pretended to be an important email from a bank about a money transfer.
Either just delete the email, or call the sender and ask them if they sent the email and what is in the attachment, or on the other end of the link. Unless you are absolutely sure the attachment is safe, don’t click on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Won’t antivirus software protect me from WannaCry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most but not all antivirus software now contains ‘anti-ransomware’ that should help protect your PCs and laptops from WannaCry and other ransomware.
That’s why it’s important not to rely just on Windows’ own security but to add an extra layer of protection.
Check out our list of the best antivirus to make sure you’re running one of our recommended packages. Our favourite is BitDefender, but there are plenty of other great options to choose from too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My PC is infected with WannaCry. What should I do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, don’t pay the ransom. It only encourages the criminals – getting paid is their end game.
Some security experts predict there could be a free ‘fix’ to decrypt the files in a few days and remove the malware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ने पर अवैध हो जाएगा PAN,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) को आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ा तो संभव है कि 31 दिसंबर के बाद यह अवैध हो जाए। दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के सरकार के फैसले के बाद इसे वित्तीय लेनदेन (फाइनैंशल ट्रांजैक्शंज) के लिए जरूरी नंबर बनाने की दिशा में एक और कदम बढ़ा दिया गया है। सरकार पूरे फाइनैंशल सेक्टर में आधार आधारित नो योर कस्टमर (KYC) को इंटीग्रेट करने पर विचार कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इसकी पुष्टि करते हुए कहा कि सरकार रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) सहित सभी रेग्युलेटर्स के साथ विचार-विमर्श कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार KYC एक तुरंत, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक और मजबूत प्रमाण उपलब्ध कराता है, जिससे सेवा उद्योग की प्रक्रिया बेहतर बनाने में मदद मिलेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने फाइनैंस बिल में एक संशोधन के जरिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के लिए आवेदन पर आधार को अनिवार्य बना दिया है। अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन लोगों के पास पहले से आधार मौजूद है, उन्हें किसी भी वित्तीय मध्यस्थ (फाइनैंशल इंटरमीडियरी) को अपने अंगूठे का निशान उपलब्ध कराना होगा। इसे संबंधित सेक्टर की रिपोर्टिंग एंटिटि को दिया जाएगा, जो इसे UIDAI डेटाबेस से वैलिडेट करेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस डेटा के आधार पर सेंट्रल रजिस्ट्री ऑफ सिक्यॉरिटाइजेशन ऐंड ऐसेट रिकंस्ट्रक्शन ऐंड सिक्यॉरिटी इंट्रेस्ट ऑफ इंडिया (CERSAI) की ओर से एक यूनीक C-KYC नंबर जेनरेट किया जाएगा। इस नंबर का इस्तेमाल बैंक अकाउंट, म्यूचुअल फंड इन्वेस्टमेंट, डीमैट अकाउंट और इंश्योरेंस पॉलिसी सहित सभी फाइनैंशल प्रॉडक्ट्स में किया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा था कि देश में 98 प्रतिशत व्यस्कों या 108 करोड़ से अधिक लोगों को आधार नंबर जारी किया जा चुका है और इसी वजह से सरकार इसका इस्तेमाल बढ़ा रही है। उन्होंने इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के प्रस्ताव पर दोबारा विचार करने की संसद की मांग को खारिज कर दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC सुविधा से PAN के आवेदन के लिए जन्मतिथि या पते जैसी जानकारियों की पुष्टि का इंतजार कर रहे व्यक्ति और एंटिटि अंगूठे के निशान से बायोमेट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन कर सकेंगे। CERSAI ने पिछले वर्ष सभी वित्तीय संस्थानों में एक समान KYC प्रोसेस सुनिश्चित करने के लिए e-KYC की कोशिश शुरू की थी। 2016 में मार्केट रेग्युलेटर सेबी ने आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC को स्वेच्छा से अपनाने पर सहमति दी थी। सभी सरकारी बैंकों से भी इस तरह का अपडेटेड डेटा अथॉरिटी को उपलब्ध कराने का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>खौफ से सोमवार को एहतियातन बंद रहे कुछ एटीएम</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/some-atms-closed-due-to-wannacry-ransomware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/some-atms-closed-due-to-wannacry-ransomware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;रैनसमवेयर वानाक्राइ के खतरे के मद्देनजर बैंकों ने सोमवार को पुराने सॉफ्टवेयर पर चलने वाले कुछ एटीएम को बंद रखा। रिजर्व बैंक ने बैंकों को निर्देश दिया था कि वे रैनसमवेयर पर सरकारी संगठन सीईआरटी-इन के निर्देशों का पालन करें।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;साइबर अटैक का भारत पर बड़ा असर नहीं: IT मिनिस्टर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रैनसमवेयर ने 150 से अधिक देशों में विभिन्न आईटी नेटवर्कों को प्रभावित किया है। (इंडियन कंप्यूटर इमरजेंसी रेस्पॉन्स टीम) सीईआरटी-इन ने इस स्थिति में क्या करें और क्या न करें की सूची जारी की है। साथ ही यह भी सलाह दी है कि वैश्विक रैनसमवेयर हमले से नेटवर्क को किस तरीके से बचाया जाए।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सूत्रों ने कहा कि ज्यादातर एटीएम बढि़या तरीके से काम कर रहे हैं। कुछ में माइक्रोसाफ्ट विंडोज ऑपरेटिंग सिस्टम अपडेट संभवत नहीं है। सूत्रों ने कहा कि इस तरह के एटीएम पर हमले की संभावना बन सकती है। इसलिए एहतियाती उपाय के तौर पर उन एटीएम को बंद रखा गया है। हालांकि इस बारे में रिजर्व बैंक ने आज शाम तक आधिकारिक तौर पर कुछ नहीं कहा था। देश में कुल 2.2 लाख एटीएम हैं। इसमें से कुछ पुराने विंडोज एक्सपी ऑपरेटिंग सिस्टम पर चल रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>माइक्रो ATM की ट्रांजैक्शन पर लगेगी 0.5% इंटरचेंज फीस</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/micro-atm-will-charge-0-5-as-interchange-fees-on-every-transaction-above-100-rupees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/micro-atm-will-charge-0-5-as-interchange-fees-on-every-transaction-above-100-rupees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;नैशनल पेमेंट्स कॉरपोरेशन ऑफ इंडिया (NPCI) ने माइक्रो ATM पर प्रत्येक ट्रांजैक्शन की रकम का 0.5 पर्सेंट इंटरचेंज फीस के तौर पर तय किया है। इससे बड़े बैंकों और छोटे बैंकों के बीच इंटरचेंज फीस को लेकर विवाद समाप्त हो जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;देश में डिजिटल पेमेंट्स के लिए नोडल बॉडी, NPCI के मैनेजिंग डायरेक्टर, एपी होता ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;चार्ज को ट्रांजैक्शन की रकम के 0.5 पर्सेंट पर तय किया गया है और अधिकतम चार्ज 15 रुपये होगा। 100 रुपये से कम की सभी ट्रांजैक्शन फ्री कर दी गई हैं।&amp;rsquo; माइक्रो ATM से कैश निकाला जा सकता है और इनका इस्तेमाल क्रेडिट/डेबिट कार्ड और आधार के इस्तेमाल से डिजिटल पेमेंट्स करने के लिए भी हो सकता है। डीमॉनेटाइजेशन के बाद ग्रामीण इलाकों में नकदी की कमी की समस्या को दूर करने के लिए माइक्रो ATM से काफी मदद मिली थी। ग्रामीण इलाकों में बैंकिंग इंफ्रास्ट्रक्चर लगाना महंगा होता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;माइक्रो ATM को लेकर समस्या उस समय शुरू हुई थी, जब मर्चेंट्स ने इनका इस्तेमाल डिजिटल पेमेंट्स की जगह कैश निकालने के लिए करना शुरू कर दिया था। इससे उन्हें इंटरचेंज फीस मिल रही थी और वे ट्रांजैक्शंस के लिए मर्चेंट डिस्काउंट रेट (MDR) के भुगतान को बचा रहे थे। डेबिट कार्ड जारी करने वाले बैंकों को मर्चेंट्स से MDR हासिल करने के बजाय एक्वायरिंग बैंकों को इंटरचेंज फीस चुकानी पड़ रही थी।
देश के एक बड़े बैंक के वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने बताया, &amp;lsquo;5 रुपये न्यूनतम और 15 रुपये अधिकतम के साथ ट्रांजैक्शन की रकम के 1 पर्सेंट इंटरचेंज चार्ज से हमें नुकसान हो रहा था। कम वैल्यू की ट्रांजैक्शंस के लिए इसका गलत इस्तेमाल किया जा रहा था।&amp;rsquo; इस समस्या के मद्देनजर बड़े बैंकों ने अपने संगठन इंडियन बैंक्स एसोसिएशन के जरिए इंटरचेंज फीस को 90 पर्सेंट घटाने का सुझाव दिया था। इसका माइक्रो ATM इंडस्ट्री की ओर से विरोध हुआ था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिजनेस कॉरेस्पॉन्डेंट्स फेडरेशन ऑफ इंडिया ने फाइनेंस मिनिस्ट्री और रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) को लिखे एक पत्र में कहा था, &amp;lsquo;बैंक कभी भी अन्य बैंकों की ओर से माइक्रो ATM के इस्तेमाल को प्रोत्साहन नहीं देंगे क्योंकि उन्हें आधार से होने वाली पेमेंट (AEPS) से केवल 0.1 पर्सेंट चार्ज मिलेगा, जबकि उन्हें बिजनेस कॉरेसपॉन्डेंट एजेंट्स को 0.5-1 पर्सेंट का भुगतान करना होगा।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस मामले में इंफॉर्मेशन टेक्नोलॉजी मिनिस्ट्री ने भी हस्तक्षेप किया था और बैंकों से कहा था कि वे खुद आपसी सहमति से रेट तय करें जिससे सरकार के फाइनेंशियल इनक्लूजन प्रोग्राम को नुकसान न हो। NPCI ने सभी संबंधित पक्षों के साथ बातचीत के बाद फाइनल चार्ज तय किए हैं। एक डिजिटल पेमेंट्स फर्म के सीनियर एग्जिक्यूटिव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम नए रेट्स से संतुष्ट हैं। 0.5 पर्सेंट के चार्ज को 1 पर्सेंट किया जा सकता था, लेकिन 100 रुपये से कम की ट्रांजैक्शंस पर फीस जीरो करने से मर्चेंट्स अतिरिक्त आमदनी के लिए कम वैल्यू में कैश निकालने को बढ़ावा नहीं देंगे।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>