<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar to be mandatory for driving licence, effective from October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As per an order issued by the central government, Aadhaar card will become mandatory for issuance of fresh driving licences or for renewal of the same. This rule will come into effect starting October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind the move is to eradicate the issuance of multiple driving licences across different states. It will help the government to enforce traffic regulations more effectively as drivers won’t have multiple driving licences to fall back on, which isn’t an uncommon practice in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linking Aadhaar card to the driver’s licence will enable the government to maintain a centralised database (known as Sarathi). Regional Transport Offices (RTO) from all over the country can log on and instantly check whether the applicant of a driver’s licence has another one in any other part of the country. The National Informatics Centre (NIC) has already uploaded almost all the data available in RTOs across the country on to the common database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union Road Transport Ministry is currently briefing the state governments about the changes that will eventually be incorporated in the process of issuing a driver’s licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This briefing also talks about citizens who do not have an Aadhaar card issued to their name. In that case, he/she will have to submit multiple documents, although it is unclear what those additional documents will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State governments across the nation have come up with hefty penalties for breaking traffic laws and regulations. One such penalty in many states is the confiscation of driver’s licence for a few months or indefinitely, depending on the severity of the law broken.  This move will will surely force citizens to take traffic laws a lot more seriously once their licences are linked to Sarathi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 30 Link bank accounts to Aadhaar : I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-bank-accounts-aadhaar-april-30-t-department/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-bank-accounts-aadhaar-april-30-t-department/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accounts opened from July 2014 to August, 2015 will have to submit know your customer (KYC) details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tax officials said that the accounts would include banks, insurance, stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account holders will also have to mention their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounts opened from July 2014 to August, 2015 will have to submit know your customer (KYC) details and their Aadhaar number to banks and financial institutions+ by April 30 and self-certify them to comply with FATCA regulations(Foreign Tax Compliance Act), the tax department said on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the account holders are unable to furnish details and provide self-certification by the new deadline, banks and financial institutions have the option ofblocking the accounts+ .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the details are furnished they can operate the accounts. The provision applies to accounts which come under the ambit of FATCA regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks and financial institutions were asked to obtain self-certification and carry out due diligence for all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015 to comply with the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act(FATCA) pact signed by India and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July 2015, India and the US signed a tax information sharing agreement under a new US law, FATCA, aimed at bolstering efforts for automatic exchange of financial information between the two nations about tax evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,” the tax department said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax officials said that the accounts would include banks, insurance, stocks. Account holders will also have to mention their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto, Health Insurance To Cost More As Regulator Okays Raise For Agents</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Car, motorcycle and health insurance will cost more from April 1 with regulator Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority (IRDAI) giving go-ahead to insurers for revision in commission for agents. The change in premium after modification will be limited to around 5 per cent of the existing rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase will be in addition to the enhanced third party motor insurance rates, which too will come into affect from April. The IRDAI (Payment of Commission or Remuneration or Reward to Insurance Agents and Insurance Intermediaries) Regulations, 2016 comes into effect from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulations, the regulator said, bring about certain revisions in commission/ remuneration rates and also introduce the reward system. These may trigger insurers to revisit the pricing of their products in so far as the costing input relating to commission or remuneration is concerned, said IRDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the change in premium due to the new regulations should be &amp;ldquo;limited to +/- 5 per cent of the existing premium rates of products/add-ons&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, insurers will have to give a certificate that there is &amp;ldquo;no detrimental change&amp;rdquo; in premium rates or any other provision of policies already sold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuts in Insurance Premiums On Larger Cars, Bikes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/irdai-cuts-insurance-premiums-on-larger-cars-bikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/irdai-cuts-insurance-premiums-on-larger-cars-bikes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per the revised list, premium on mid-segment cars(1,000cc - 1,500 cc) has been reduced to Rs. 2,863 from Rs3,132 announced on March 28.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insurance sector regulator Irdai today reduced motor insurance premium rates in most of the segments like two-wheelers, cars and trucks by modifying the rates for 2017-18 issued three-weeks ago. The modified &amp;lsquo;premium rates for motor third party liability insurance cover&amp;rsquo; will apply retrospectively from April 1, the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (Irdai) said in an order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the premium rates for the current fiscal are higher than those of the previous year. As per the revised list, premium on mid-segment cars (1,000cc - 1,500 cc) has been reduced to Rs 2,863 from Rs 3,132 announced on March 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, premium for cars with engine capacity of more than 1,500 cc has been brought down to Rs 7,890 from earlier Rs 8,630.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no change in cars having engine capacity of less than 1,000 cc. The premium has been fixed at Rs 2,055. Similarly, premium has been brought down in case of two-wheelers with engine of 150 cc and more. Irdai further said premium rates have been reduced for most of the truck categories. The new rate, for instance, in case of &amp;lsquo;goods carrying vehicles public carriers (exceeding 40,000 kg)&amp;rsquo; has been reduced to Rs 33,024 from Rs 36,120 notified on March 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduction has been also affected for e-rickshaw and other passenger carrying vehicles. Modification in premium rates follows protest by a section of truckers against the Irdai&amp;rsquo;s move to substantially
hike insurance rates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving sans licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-based payment modes work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government is planning to utilise the Aadhaar database to give shape to a digital future and utilise it for payments, and authentication of transactions is the key to its success. While Unified Payments Interface and BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) are processes for peer-to-peer transactions using smartphones, the government is promoting Aadhaar-enabled payment systems for the non-smartphone savvy. As per sources it is planning to launch Aadhaar Pay on April 14. ET looks into the different forms of Aadhaar payment modes being developed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems?
Payments that can be done with the help of au thentication and identi fication through the Aadhaar database is referred to as the Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems (AEPS). This is the new form of pay ment that is being pro moted by the govern ment to push for digital payments instead of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the major types of Aadhaar Enabled Payments?
The first type of payment is Aadhaar Bridge Payment System which is meant for direct bene fit transfer and subsidy payments from the gov ernment to the benefi ciaries. The second is AEPS which is used at the level of the business correspondent or `bank mitras’ where bank customers can use Aadhaar to access various services like cash withdrawal, account opening and fund transfer even without going to a bank branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is Aadhaar Pay wherein merchants can accept payments through Aadhaar identification of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we need Aadhaar Enabled payments?
These forms of payments are be ing promoted by the government specifically for the under privileged sections of the society and the rural poor who are not comfortable using cards or mobile wallets for payments.Instead of a mobile phone or a plastic card, in these forms of payments, the mode of authentication becomes the Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who runs the systems?
National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is the nodal authority for all Aadhaar-enabled payments in collaboration with banks. The payment company is trying to get as many banks to seed their customers’ accounts with their Aadhaar number so that payments can flow smoothly .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do the different forms of payments work?
Aahdaar Bridge Payment (ABPS):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant for recur ring payments done by the government to its customers for various subsidies as well as direct benefit transfer. Here the beneficiary is identified through an Aadhaar number, then NPCI manages an Aadhaar Mapper where the Aadhaar number is mapped to a specific bank account and the money flows to the connected bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-enabled-payment-aeps&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Payment (AEPS):&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the customer has to approach a business correspondent (BC), use his Aadhaar number and biometrics which the BC shares with NPCI, which checks the ID with UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India) to confirm the customer’s identity . It also checks the funds in the connected account and allows the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for merchant payments where the merchant will download the merchant payments app of his bank, authenticate the customer through his biometrics and Aadhaar number and initiate a pull transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very soon, you can do “iris” Aadhaar authentication from your smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheap in-built iris scanners will eradicate use of costly ones for mass adoption of Aadhaar verification.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID Inc., a consumer-grade iris scanning technology provider for mobile phones, proposed the introduction of iris integrated mobile phones as a cost-effective way of reducing the failure rates in Aadhaar biometric authentication, as recently reported in MGNREGA tests in Telangana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe iris integrated smartphones and tablets will address the issues reported with Aadhaar biometric authentication. The UIDAI and the worldwide biometric community have tested and found iris to have better reliability. We are confident the failure rates will be drastically lower once the cheaper iris integrated mobile devices are adopted in the market,” said Dr. Salil Prabhakar, President and CEO, Delta ID Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the government mandating the use of Aadhaar biometric authentication in more spheres of the society, the need for a biometric modality that works reliably is critical. Unlike fingerprints that are being reported to show high failure rates due to wear and tear, the iris, being a protected internal organ, is expected to be significantly more reliable. Additionally, since the iris is not affected with age, it works reliably across all age groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key impediments in the large-scale roll out of iris for Aadhaar has been the high cost of iris devices. This is being addressed with the rollout of iris integrated mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this regard, Samsung partnered with Delta ID to launch India’s first iris integrated tablet in May 2016. The technology is arriving in smartphones too, and not only in high end devices such as Samsung Galaxy S8, but also in low cost smartphones developed by Indian manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID’s ActiveIRIS technology passed the Standardisation Testing and Quality Certification’s (STQC) FRR test with better than 99 percent accuracy, and has been certified by the STQC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active IRIS and a combination of STQC-certified hardware components can be integrated by any mobile device to expeditiously introduce iris integrated mobile devices in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ने पर अवैध हो जाएगा PAN,</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-pan-card-could-be-invalid-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगर आपने परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) को आधार कार्ड से नहीं जोड़ा तो संभव है कि 31 दिसंबर के बाद यह अवैध हो जाए। दरअसल, इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के सरकार के फैसले के बाद इसे वित्तीय लेनदेन (फाइनैंशल ट्रांजैक्शंज) के लिए जरूरी नंबर बनाने की दिशा में एक और कदम बढ़ा दिया गया है। सरकार पूरे फाइनैंशल सेक्टर में आधार आधारित नो योर कस्टमर (KYC) को इंटीग्रेट करने पर विचार कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्रालय के एक वरिष्ठ अधिकारी ने इसकी पुष्टि करते हुए कहा कि सरकार रिजर्व बैंक ऑफ इंडिया (RBI) सहित सभी रेग्युलेटर्स के साथ विचार-विमर्श कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार KYC एक तुरंत, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक और मजबूत प्रमाण उपलब्ध कराता है, जिससे सेवा उद्योग की प्रक्रिया बेहतर बनाने में मदद मिलेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार ने फाइनैंस बिल में एक संशोधन के जरिए इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और परमानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के लिए आवेदन पर आधार को अनिवार्य बना दिया है। अधिकारी ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;जिन लोगों के पास पहले से आधार मौजूद है, उन्हें किसी भी वित्तीय मध्यस्थ (फाइनैंशल इंटरमीडियरी) को अपने अंगूठे का निशान उपलब्ध कराना होगा। इसे संबंधित सेक्टर की रिपोर्टिंग एंटिटि को दिया जाएगा, जो इसे UIDAI डेटाबेस से वैलिडेट करेगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस डेटा के आधार पर सेंट्रल रजिस्ट्री ऑफ सिक्यॉरिटाइजेशन ऐंड ऐसेट रिकंस्ट्रक्शन ऐंड सिक्यॉरिटी इंट्रेस्ट ऑफ इंडिया (CERSAI) की ओर से एक यूनीक C-KYC नंबर जेनरेट किया जाएगा। इस नंबर का इस्तेमाल बैंक अकाउंट, म्यूचुअल फंड इन्वेस्टमेंट, डीमैट अकाउंट और इंश्योरेंस पॉलिसी सहित सभी फाइनैंशल प्रॉडक्ट्स में किया जा सकेगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वित्त मंत्री अरुण जेटली ने कहा था कि देश में 98 प्रतिशत व्यस्कों या 108 करोड़ से अधिक लोगों को आधार नंबर जारी किया जा चुका है और इसी वजह से सरकार इसका इस्तेमाल बढ़ा रही है। उन्होंने इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न दाखिल करने और PAN के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य बनाने के प्रस्ताव पर दोबारा विचार करने की संसद की मांग को खारिज कर दिया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC सुविधा से PAN के आवेदन के लिए जन्मतिथि या पते जैसी जानकारियों की पुष्टि का इंतजार कर रहे व्यक्ति और एंटिटि अंगूठे के निशान से बायोमेट्रिक आइडेंटिफिकेशन कर सकेंगे। CERSAI ने पिछले वर्ष सभी वित्तीय संस्थानों में एक समान KYC प्रोसेस सुनिश्चित करने के लिए e-KYC की कोशिश शुरू की थी। 2016 में मार्केट रेग्युलेटर सेबी ने आधार-बेस्ड e-KYC को स्वेच्छा से अपनाने पर सहमति दी थी। सभी सरकारी बैंकों से भी इस तरह का अपडेटेड डेटा अथॉरिटी को उपलब्ध कराने का निर्देश दिया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बैंक, डाकघर से निकासी पर नकदी लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rupees-2-lakh-limit-not-applicable-on-bank-post-office-withdrawals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर दो लाख रुपये की नकद लेनदेन की सीमा लागू नहीं होगी। आयकर विभाग ने बुधवार को यह स्पष्ट किया। वित्त अधिनियम 2017 के तहत सरकार ने दो लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध लगा दिया है। इससे अधिक के लेनदेन में राशि प्राप्त करने वाले पर उतनी की राशि का जुर्माना लगाया जाएगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आयकर कानून में नई शामिल धारा 269 एसटी के बारे में स्पष्टीकरण जारी करते हुए केंद्रीय प्रत्यक्ष कर बोर्ड (सीबीडीटी) ने कहा कि यह प्रतिबंध बैंकों और डाकघरों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा। बयान में कहा गया है कि यह फैसला किया गया है कि नकद लेनदेन पर अंकुश बैंकों, सहकारी बैंकों और डाकघर बचत खातों से निकासी पर लागू नहीं होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सीबीडीटी ने कहा कि इस बारे में आवश्यक अधिसूचना जारी की जाएगी। वित्त मंत्री अरण जेटली ने 2017-18 के बजट में 3 लाख रुपये से अधिक के नकद लेनदेन पर प्रतिबंध का प्रस्ताव किया था। इस सीमा को वित्त विधेयक में संशोधन के जरिए दो लाख रुपये कर दिया गया।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>साल-डेढ़ साल अग्रेसिव प्राइसिंग अपनाए रह सकता है जियो</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/half-year-agressive-pricing-can-be-adopted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/half-year-agressive-pricing-can-be-adopted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;रिलायंस जियो इन्फोकॉम अगले 12 से 18 महीने तक भारी छूट वाली कॉमप्लिमेंट सर्विस ऑफर करने की अग्रेसिव प्राइसिंग स्ट्रैटिजी पर कायम रह सकता है। विश्लेषकों का कहना है कि देश के 15% वायरलेस सब्सक्राइबर बेस हासिल करने की कंपनी की ये कवायद प्रतिस्पर्धियों को नुकसान पहुंचाती रह सकती है। ब्रोकरेज फर्म मॉर्गन स्टेनली ने कहा कि इस रणनीति से मौजूदा कंपनियों- भारती एयरटेल, आइडिया सेल्युलर और वोडाफोन इंडिया की प्रति ग्राहक औसत आमदनी (ARPU) पर दबाव बनेगा। जियो के मौजूदा ऑफर्स के चलते प्रतिस्पर्धी कंपनियों का ARPU लगभग 300 रुपये तक सीमित हो सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मॉर्गन स्टेनली की रिपोर्ट के मुताबिक, कंपनी को टोटल वायरलेस सब-सेगमेंट में 6% सब्सक्राइबर मार्केट शेयर हासिल हुआ है। कंपनी इसको बढ़ाकर कम से कम 15% तक ले जाना चाहती है। जियो ने मार्च में 2020-2021 तक इंडस्ट्री का लगभग आधा रेवेन्यू मार्केट शेयर हासिल करने का टारगेट तय किया था। दिसंबर तिमाही के अंत में भारती एयरटेल के पास अभी 33.1 % जबकि वोडाफोन के पास 23.5 % और आइडिया के पास 18.7 % रेवेन्यू मार्केट शेयर था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ऐनालिस्टों का कहना है कि जियो के ग्राहक बढ़ने की रफ्तार में कमी आई है। इसको देखते हुए कंपनी को अपनी अग्रेसिव प्राइसिंग बरकरार रखना होगा। कंपनी रोज 6 लाख सब्सक्राइबर्स बनाकर अपने पहले 170 दिन में 21 फरवरी को 10 करोड़ के आंकड़े पर पहुंच गई थी। 31 मार्च 2017 को कंपनी के ग्राहकों की संख्या 10.9 करोड़ पर पहुंच गई। यानी अगले 40 दिनों में रोजाना 2.25 लाख के इजाफे के साथ कुल 90 लाख ग्राहक जुड़े।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नोमुरा ने कहा कि जियो के नए ग्राहकों के जुड़ने में आ रही सुस्ती की वजह यह है कि कंपनी 31 मार्च को भारत में इस्तेमाल हो रहे लगभग 13.4 करोड़ 4G स्मार्टफोनों में से ज्यादातर पर पहले ही पहुंच चुकी है। विश्लेषकों ने यह भी कहा, &amp;lsquo;ग्राहकों को जोड़ने की रफ्तार नए 4G फोनों के जुड़ने (हर महीने 70-80 लाख) के हिसाब से सीमित हो सकती है। बहुत से वेंडर्स के 4G हैंडसेट्स लॉन्चिंग पर फोकस करने से 4G सेवाओं की पहुंच बढ़ेगी। नॉन 4G हैंडसेट यूजर्स को अपने प्लेटफॉर्म पर लाने के लिए रिलायंस जियो निकट भविष्य में अपने जियोफाई को जोरदार तरीके से बढ़ावा देगी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ब्रोकरेज फर्म एमके का कहना है कि अच्छी-खासी कमाई कराने वाले कस्टमर्स बेस हासिल करने का जियो का लक्ष्य मीडियम टर्म में इंडस्ट्री में बेहद प्रतिस्पर्दी माहौल बनाए रख सकता है। उसने कहा कि जियो के नफे-नुकसान का आंकड़ा 1 जुलाई से शुरू होने वाली तिमाही से रिलायंस के शेयरों की कीमत पर असर डालना शुरू कर देगा। ब्रोकरेज फर्म जेपी मॉर्गन के मुताबिक जियो का यूजर बेस दमदार है और इनमें से ज्यादातर ने लगभग 300 रुपये का ऊंचा रिचार्ज ऑप्शन चुना है। लेकिन यह देखने वाली बात होगी कि इनमें से कितने लोग अगस्त के बाद इसी रेट पर पेमेंट करते रह पाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 हजार किलोमीटर हाइवे जल्द होंगे हाइस्पीड</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-u-turns-no-side-entry-20000-km-of-highways-will-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-u-turns-no-side-entry-20000-km-of-highways-will-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;अगले 4 से 5 सालों में नैशनल हाइवे के 20 हजार किलोमीटर से ज्यादा का हिस्सा यू-टर्न और कट्स फ्री होगा। इसके साथ ही हाइवे के दोनों ओर बैरिकेडिंग भी होगी जिससे जानवर हाइवे पर नहीं घुस पाएंगे। मुख्य हाइवेज को इस तरह से तैयार किया जाएगा कि भारी वीइकल्स भी रफ्तार के साथ बिना परेशानी मंजिल तक जल्द पहुंच जाएं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सरकार का यह प्रॉजेक्ट &amp;lsquo;भारतमाला&amp;rsquo; स्कीम का हिस्सा है इसके फेज-1 के तहत कुछ मुख्य मार्गों को कम से कम चार लेन का किया जाएगा। इस फेज पर 3.85 लाख करोड़ रुपए खर्च होंगे। अभी हाइवेज पर कई तरह की स्पीड वाली गाड़ियां चलती है जिससे न केवल हाइवे की स्पीड कम होती बल्कि दुर्घटना की संभावनाएं भी बढ़ जाती हैं। हाइवे मिनिस्ट्री द्वारा की गई एक स्टडी के मुताबिक, जापान के फोर-लेन हाइवे पर एक दिन में करीब 40,000 गाड़ियां चल सकती हैं वहीं, भारत में ऐसे ही हाइवे पर 20,000 गाड़ियां ही चल पाती हैं जिस कारण हाइवे की लेन बढ़ानी पड़ती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नए हाइवेज को बनाने की बजाए पुराने हाइवेज में कुछ बदलाव कर उन्हें अपग्रेड करने का प्रपोजल रोड और ट्रांसपोर्ट मिनिस्ट्री ने आगे बढ़ाया है। मिनिस्ट्री 20 हजार किलोमीटर को &amp;lsquo;ऐक्सेस कंट्रोल्ड&amp;rsquo; करेगी। इस तरह का कॉन्सेप्ट विकसित देशों में अपनाया जाता है। ऐक्सेस कंट्रोल्ड हाइवे में घुसने और निकलने के पॉइंट्स कम होते हैं। अभी हाइवे पर हर छोटी-मोटी जगह पर हाइवे में कट और यू-टर्न होते हैं जिससे गाड़ियों की स्पीड प्रभावित होती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;ऐक्सेस कंट्रोल्ड&amp;rsquo; कॉन्सेप्ट के तहत कुछ हाइवेज की पहचान कर ली गई है। इसमें मुंबई-कोलकाता, मैंगलोर-बेंगलुरु, लुधियाना-कांधला और पोरबंदर से सिलचर को शामिल किया गया है। सूत्रों के मुताबिक, पीएम ऑफिस ने नैशनल हाइवे अथॉरिटी ऑफ इंडिया (NHAI) बोर्ड को इस प्रपोजल पर आगे बढ़ने का सिग्नल दे दिया है। इससे पहले इसी मॉडल के तहत बीजेपी शासन में पूर्व प्रधानमंत्री अटल बिहारी वाजपेयी ने स्वर्णिम चतुर्भुज की शुरुआत की थी जिसके तहत देश के चार मेट्रो शहरों को जोड़ा गया था।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs 333: BSNL Takes On Jio With New Prepaid Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnl-takes-on-jio-with-new-prepaid-offers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnl-takes-on-jio-with-new-prepaid-offers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special tariff voucher &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo;, priced at Rs. 349, comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive tariffs, BSNL has launched prepaid plans priced from Rs 333, under which it is offering 3GB of 3G data per day for up to three months. As part of its revised Rs 339 plan, BSNL is also offering 3GB of high speed data per day. &amp;ldquo;#BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new 333 &amp;amp; 339 STV&amp;rsquo;s offer there is nothing better than this!&amp;rdquo; state-run telecom company BSNL said on site Twitter. New entrant Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing has given rise to a highly competitive Indian telecom market, pushing incumbent players to revise their existing offerings to protect market share, some analysts say. &amp;ldquo;The price war in the Rs 1.5-trillion wireless telecom market will continue this fiscal year as well leaving bruised bottom lines,&amp;rdquo; Crisil&amp;rsquo;s said in a note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333 special tariff voucher, called &amp;ldquo;Triple ACE&amp;rdquo;, comes with a validity of three months and offers 3GB of 3G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-of-the-other-offerings-by-bsnl&#34;&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 339&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL users subscribing to the Rs 339 voucher will now get 3 GB of 3G data, which is high-speed data, per day, instead of 2 GB earlier. The Rs 339 plan - which comes with a validity of 28 days - includes unlimited local and STD BSNL-to-BSNL calls and 25 minutes of local and inter-circle calls made to other networks, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special tariff voucher &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo;, priced at Rs. 349, comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs. 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all four plans - &lt;em&gt;Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 395 and Rs 375&lt;/em&gt;, the internet or data speed is reduced to 80 Kbps after a subscriber exhausts the daily 3G limit, BSNL has said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>