<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/programming/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose Which Programming Language to Learn First</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/which-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/which-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I think everybody in this country should learn how to program a computer because it teaches you how to think.” ~ Steve Jobs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have guessed by now that I’m a huge advocate for coding — and not just for geeks or programmers, either!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning a programming language is becoming an invaluable life skill.
Just twenty years ago, could you have imagined coding being taught in some public schools? I mean, it was only in 1982 that the Commodore 64 came out! It seems like it must have been eons ago, but that’s well within our lifetime and even our career, for many of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because that’s the thing — coding is a completely and uniquely democratized skill. While you can certainly learn it in the most prestigious universities around the world, you can also learn how to code from your couch, or even on the bus or train with your smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wherever and whenever you want, you can learn to code. Once you have a programming language or two under your belt, an entire world of career possibilities opens to you. IT jobs are expected to grow 22% by 2020, but that’s just one area in which programming skills are useful.
Software is automating all kinds of jobs in every industry, but the opportunity looming largest on the horizon is in the Internet of Things. One report predicts that by 2020, we’ll need 4.5 million developers to power the IoT — currently, there are only 350,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of learning a programming language as future-proofing your career. You don’t have to worry about the machines putting you out of a job if you’re the person powering the machines.
With all of this opportunity before you, how can you decide which programming language offers the greatest upside for Future-You?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out their 4 ways to pick your first (or next) programming language:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/images/0-F6sRFQLVL0slCUOr.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>