<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Aadhaar With PAN Made Mandatory: How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the government insists that one&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar account and Permanent Account Number (PAN) should be linked by July 31 this year to pay income taxes, millions of Indians have faced issues with syncing the two accounts due to small differences in how their names are spelt. This problem can happen even if there are minor differences in how the name is recorded &amp;ndash; like the use of one&amp;rsquo;s full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar. Issues have also cropped up due to use of special characters in the initials and punctuation that often form a person&amp;rsquo;s name as Aadhaar doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize such characters but PAN does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, while one solution is to apply for a name correction in either Aadhaar or PAN card - both time consuming procedures - the government has stepped in to provide a simple solution for frustrated potential taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If an individual&amp;rsquo;s name on the Aadhaar does not match his/her name on the PAN card, the person can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A taxpayer can also log in to the Aadhaar website and request for a change in the name which will be verified using a one-time password on the phone number registered with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One-Time Passwords (OTP) will be used in cases where there are people who have gotten married and changed their surname. In such instances the tax department will give an OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number. The tax department, on its part, would&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department is also planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for OTP, provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told news agency Press Trust of India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.08 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN, but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people. As per statistics with the tax department, only six crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Mandatory For Filing Tax Returns, PAN Card From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting of Aadhaar has been made mandatory for filing income tax returns with effect from July 1, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, an official statement said on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961 as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017 provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar /Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from July 1,&amp;rdquo; said a Finance Ministry statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or Enrolment ID will apply only to a person who is eligible to obtain Aadhaar number, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act, 2016, only a resident individual is entitled to obtain Aadhaar. Resident as per the said Act means an individual who has resided in India for a period or periods amounting in all to 182 days or more in the 12 months immediately preceding the date of application for enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the requirement to quote Aadhaar as per section 139AA of the Income-tax Act shall not apply to an individual who is not a resident as per the Aadhaar Act, 2016, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar card to be linked with flights soon?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linked-flights-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linked-flights-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Delhi: The Central government has now asked Information Technology major Wipro to come up with reports and to develop a blueprint for Aadhaar-based biometric access to flight passengers at all airports across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, based on government’s direction, Wipro is likely to submit a report in May after which the airports will start the process where a flyer’s thumb would be all the identification they need to be eligible to fly on domestic flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aviation ministry had an idea about linking Aadhaar number with flight bookings which enables the biometric access possible at all airports. Reports revealed that the solid push was taken by Aviation Minister Jayant Sinha and Aviation Secretary R N Choubey in a meeting with several airport operators and airlines officials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Airports Authority of India chief Guruprasad Mohapatra, he said that linking of Aadhaar card number and thumb identification will help an official know about the passenger boarding the flight. Mohapatra explained that at the time of booking, a passenger enters his/her Aadhaar number. On arrival at an airport, the passenger can just place the thumb on the touchpad at an entry point and at other points inside the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohapatra added that AAI wants the passengers to have effortless and seamless travel experience at airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As everyone is aware that due to security reasons, a passenger in India has to show his or her identification card along with the tickets to enter the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has been trying to make Aadhaar as the sole identity card in the future a move that could possibly replace PAN, voter and ration cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an Aadhaar card is mandatory: Getting a passport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hassle-free passport services: Now, you can get a passport in just 10 days if you have an Aadhaar card. The government has announced that an Adhaar card or e-Aadhaar card can be used as proof of date of birth while applying for passports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income tax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is trying to file income tax returns needs to link their Aadhaar number with their PAN before July. If one fails to do so it will not be considered as a valid ITR filing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to provident fund&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Provident Fund Organisation has also made it compulsory for all pensioners and members to submit their Aadhaar card numbers. It is basically done for pensioners to avail hassle-free pension at the time of retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile connections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a department of telecom notification that was issued on Friday, the telecom operators have been directed to re-verify their existing subscribers — both prepaid and postpaid — through an Aadhaar-based eKYC process by February 6, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For free LPG connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre announced that Aadhaar card is now mandatory for women in the Below Poverty Line category applying for a free LPG connection. Applicants without the unique ID number have until May 31 to apply for it to avail the benefits under the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana, the ministry of petroleum and natural gas said in a notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway ticket booking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railways have also made plans to link Aadhaar with ticket booking. They have also held a discussion with UIDAI for linking Aadhaar number with the booking of a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a driving licence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has planned to make Aadhaar mandatory for seeking a new licence or renewal of your driving licence in a bid to ensure that there are no multiple driving licences under one name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the ‘Midday meal scheme’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry of human resource development announced that the mid-day meal would no longer be free for those children without an Aadhaar card. It was stated that children must be enrolled in the Aadhar scheme by June 30, if they were to get a free meal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar to be mandatory for driving licence, effective from October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As per an order issued by the central government, Aadhaar card will become mandatory for issuance of fresh driving licences or for renewal of the same. This rule will come into effect starting October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind the move is to eradicate the issuance of multiple driving licences across different states. It will help the government to enforce traffic regulations more effectively as drivers won’t have multiple driving licences to fall back on, which isn’t an uncommon practice in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linking Aadhaar card to the driver’s licence will enable the government to maintain a centralised database (known as Sarathi). Regional Transport Offices (RTO) from all over the country can log on and instantly check whether the applicant of a driver’s licence has another one in any other part of the country. The National Informatics Centre (NIC) has already uploaded almost all the data available in RTOs across the country on to the common database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union Road Transport Ministry is currently briefing the state governments about the changes that will eventually be incorporated in the process of issuing a driver’s licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This briefing also talks about citizens who do not have an Aadhaar card issued to their name. In that case, he/she will have to submit multiple documents, although it is unclear what those additional documents will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State governments across the nation have come up with hefty penalties for breaking traffic laws and regulations. One such penalty in many states is the confiscation of driver’s licence for a few months or indefinitely, depending on the severity of the law broken.  This move will will surely force citizens to take traffic laws a lot more seriously once their licences are linked to Sarathi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar to made compulsory for getting driver’s licence: report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-made-compulsory-getting-drivers-licence-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-made-compulsory-getting-drivers-licence-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar’s scope is further expanding. The Times of India reports that Aadhaar will now be made mandatory for obtaining a driver’s licence and renewal of existing licences. The publication added that this was being done prevent issuance of multiple licences under one name. It added that multiple licences were being issued to a single person as fake identifications to beat traffic and criminal offences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union transport ministry is looking at a bringing all the regional transport offices (RTOs) under a central database called Sarathi which will prevent people from getting multiple licences from different RTOs.  The rules are expected to kick off from October this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar is being made compulsory for Income Tax returns and it will also be made mandatory to link mobile numbers to Aadhaar. Last week, the Department of Telecom issued a note saying that all telecom operators will have to ensure that their subscribers link mobile numbers within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driver’s licences are also used as proof of address and identity and are used for opening bank accounts and getting mobile phone connections. However, the Aadhaar to be used as both an identity proof as well as an address proof. Banks and telecom companies use biometric eKYC to open accounts and mobile connections. But the reality is that UIDAI does not validate the address of every applicant. Though applicants are asked to provide an address proof for Aadhaar enrolment, it is optional — the enrolment process (and form) is designed to allow anyone to get an identity without any documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that driver’s licence has security features like holograms in an original document. However, as St_Hill noted in a post, that there is no concept of an “original” Aadhaar card. A printout of Aadhaar information is being treated by various entities as a valid document, so it is easy for a fraudster (even an amateur) to print out details card if he knows your basic information, and start submitting in different places where the government asks us to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Rules On Home Loan To Change From Saturday. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-rules-on-home-loan-benefits-to-change-from-april-see-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-rules-on-home-loan-benefits-to-change-from-april-see-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tax experts say that some high net worth individuals, who used to buy properties on loan and were able to set off the full interest liability against the lettable value of property and thus bring down their tax liability substantially, would be particularly hit from this new tax rule.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the anomaly of interest deduction in respect of let-out property vs self-occupied property, the government has changed income tax rules, which will come into effect from next financial year April 1, 2017 (assessment year 2018-19). In this regard, the government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. According to current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get Rs 2 lakh deduction on interest repayment on home loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on rented properties, effective from April 1, interest paid above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, your interest outgo on a second property is Rs. 5 lakh in a particular year. Assume that you are earning a rent of Rs. 1.5 lakh annually from the property. Such buyers, according to the current rule, are allowed to adjust the difference of Rs. 3.5 lakh (Rs. 5 lakh interest minus Rs. 1.5 lakh). But from the next financial year, they will be allowed deduction of just Rs. 2 lakh. The remaining amount of Rs. 1.5 lakh (Rs. 3.5 lakh minus Rs. 2 lakh) can be carried forward up to eight financial years and be adjusted later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax experts say that some high net worth individuals, who used to buy properties on loan and were able to set off the full interest liability against the lettable value of property and thus bring down their tax liability substantially, would be particularly hit from this new tax rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From April another tax rule related to the properties will also change. The new tax rule will help bring down tax liability from property sale. The holding period of a property for qualifying under long-term gains will get reduced to two years, from three years currently. As per current tax norms, if a property is sold within three years of buying, the profit from the transaction is treated as short-term capital gain and is taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her. So reducing this time period to two years will bring down tax liability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, after two years, the transaction will be able to qualify for long-term capital gains, thus lower taxes. Under long-term capital gains on immovable properties, the profit is taxed at 20 per after indexation. Under indexation, inflation during the holding period is taken into account and thus the purchase price is adjusted, reducing the tax burden on the property seller. There are also other benefits for the seller under the long-term capital gains tax. If the gains are invested in some select government investment schemes, the tax liability goes down significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI:No Plans To Introduce New Denomination Notes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-plans-to-introduce-new-denomination-notes-rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-plans-to-introduce-new-denomination-notes-rbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal had told Parliament on Friday that the government is not planning to print Rs 5,000 and Rs 10,000 currency notes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India currently has no plans of introducing new denomination currencies, a senior RBI official said on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Presently RBI has no idea to introduce currencies of new denominations. The central banking institution wants to encourage cashless transactions, which are helpful to the people&amp;rdquo;, RBI Deputy Governor N.S. Vishwanathan said while speaking at a lecture here on &amp;ldquo;Credit culture and the financial system&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this connection, Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal had told Parliament on Friday that the government is not planning to print &lt;em&gt;Rs 5,000 and Rs 10,000&lt;/em&gt; currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referring to banks&amp;rsquo; non-performing assets (NPAs), or bad loans, Vishwanathan said here that these are affecting the income and profit of banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks cannot escape from the responsibility of controlling NPAs in their balance sheets,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks are expected to base their lending decisions on a careful and prudent assessment of the financial position and repaying capacity of the borrower, while credit should be given to only the right people, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magnitude of the problem can be guaged from the NPA figures of state-run banks, which at the end of the current fiscal&amp;rsquo;s second quarter that ended in September, rose to Rs 6.3 lakh crore, as compared to Rs 5.5 lakh crore at the end of the first quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even if you have Aadhaar, linking it to PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-aadhaar-linking-pan-easier-said-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-aadhaar-linking-pan-easier-said-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The income tax department then verifies your name, date of birth, gender as per PAN and Aadhaar number with UIDAI. Only if the data matches, it will be linked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merely having an Aadhaar number issued to you by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) does not mean you will be able to link it to your Permanent Account Number (PAN) during filing of income tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department website gives you the option to link the Aadhaar number to the PAN once you login into your personal profile. You are required to provide the Aadhaar number there. The income tax department then verifies your name, date of birth, gender as per PAN and Aadhaar number with UIDAI. Only if the data matches, it will be linked. Similarly, if there is a name change post marriage on one document and not on others, Aadhaar linking will be disallowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officers at the help line of the income tax department said that one can use other agencies like NSDL to file their returns. However, they remained mum when asked about how to rectify issues related to different names once Aadhaar became mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has recently started accepting initials that can be put on the PAN card. However, you will be required to put your full name while applying for a verification of data. For instance, if your official name is M Ramamurthy where the full name is Madurai Ramamurthy where Ramamurthy is the first name, I-T will allow initials only for the first name. Hence, you can either print your name on the PAN card as either Ramamurthy or R Madurai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you try to link PAN to your Aadhaar card which accepts initials, there is bound to be a name mismatch. This will lead to a rejection of request for linking Aadhaar card. In several parts of the country, especially the south of India, the names of villages are often suffixed or prefixed to the name of an individual. Here, any name except the first name of the person is considered as surname and will have to be mentioned in full on the PAN card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax consultants are of the view that where there are different names on different identity proofs, the government will need to either provide them more time or have a separate mechanism to resolve such discrepancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the tax department has a mechanism to rectify names on the PAN card, considering the number of people who will have different names on different documents, meeting the July 1 deadline will be an arduous task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Finance Bill 2017, which was passed by the Lok Sabha, has proposed that Aadhaar will now be compulsory from July 1 to file one’s income tax returns. For retaining your PAN number, too, you need to link this number to your IT account.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can now lock your Aadhaar data to keep it safe from hackers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now, you can lock your Aadhaar biometric details to keep it safe and unlock it whenever you want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With digital payments using Aadhaar data on the rise and cases of misuse being reported, officials of the &lt;em&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India&lt;/em&gt; (UIDAI) have come out with the new security feature to lock the biometric details (fingerprint and retinal scan data).The UIDAI introduced the lock and unlock facility following an uproar that Aadhaar deprived people of their right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric data of citizens is being collected on various platforms for government schemes, often without much safeguards. Aadhaar identification has become almost compulsory in some cases. Banks, mobile phone operators and others have access to it. “People can hack into this data and access individuals’ details, including bank accounts,” a UIDAI official warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Each time you shop and pay using your fingerprint, the data processed by POS machines can be hacked. Fingerprint details can be captured as well,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lock and unlock facility is purely voluntary. “If a person wants to lock his data, he or she can do it. No other person can unlock it. One can keep it locked as long as one wishes,” the official said Once the Aadhaar data is locked, even banks cannot access the biometric information stored in the main server.This will lead to failed transactions due to non-verification or non-authentication of the Aadhaar. The UIDAI is also planning to introduce a mobile application to lockunlock biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hacker can access your information via a UPI-based app</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/startup-identified-291-ways-hacker-can-access-information-via-upi-based-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/startup-identified-291-ways-hacker-can-access-information-via-upi-based-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As digitisation picks up steam with Indians expected to transact Rs 4 crore digitally every day this year, privacy of their data has become a paramount concern. The government is caught between encouraging digitisation and ensuring secure platforms. This is where startups like Appknox come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specialising in mobile apps security, Appknox recently identified 291 critical vulnerabilities (181 were accorded the status of high ctitical vulnerabilities) in Unified Payments Interface (UPI) based mobile applications developed by banks and other fintech companies. These vulnerabilities had the potential of exposing a user’s entire bank details to the eyes of any hacker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There were issues where we could bypass the entire security gamut and get access to user’s bank account details and even download those details easily. We found hackers can easily manipulate these loopholes to misuse the data,” says Appknox cofounder and CEO, Harshit Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team at Appknox, driven by Agarwal and cofounders Subho Halder and Prateek Panda was hired by NPCI in July 2016 and has been scanning UPI-based apps since November. These apps, developed and launched by banks and other fintech companies, have already seen heavy downloads and have lakhs of users transacting online.
The team found 181 high, 83 medium and 27 low critical vulnerabilities in the 35 plus apps evaluated by it. The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) then advised the banks to quickly work on the suggestions provided by Appknox in order to negate these threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other threats, the team was particularly concerned about basic security steps which the hackers at Appknox were easily able to contravene. The login password step was easily bypassed by the team in a number of UPI-based apps which could lead any hacker directly into a user’s account and access that user’s information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of apps depend on OTP (One Time Password) system to provide an extra layer of security to its users. The team shares it was able to easily brute force its way to login into a user’s account.
Given these apps were developed by banks which are considered the safest mode financial platforms, the team was surprised at the ease with which it was able to hack into the apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These banks have internal audits and we expected their apps to be pretty secure. Banks are the most important sector in fintech sector and have to be pretty ahead of the curve of security. Thus, we were surprised at how easily we could find loopholes in these apps. Whatever these banks are doing is not enough for mobile app security,” said Agarwal.
While banks are still the most secure way of transferring money digitally when it comes to platforms like NEFT however, mobile apps, shares Agarwal, are a different ball game altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mobiles can be hacked in very different ways and the internal team at these banking institutions is not that great with mobile apps. The whole security landscape is very different when it comes to mobiles,” says Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A worrying statement indeed when the financial transactions are increasingly moving from websites to mobile apps with the proliferation of e-wallets and other payments systems.
Several mobile apps have sprung in the last couple of years providing users with ease of transacting online however, to prevent this ease from metamorphosing into a security disaster, the government is working keenly on regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The government is getting very strict when it comes to security. The central government recently made empanelment mandatory for any mobile app in bank payment gateway. Regulators have been proactive in ensuring that companies follow certain standards,” shares Agarwal.
NPCI, shares Agarwal, was quick to get banks to plug the loopholes found by the team at Appknox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about their experience with Appknox NPCI, Head of Risk Management, Bharat Panchal, said in a statement, “Appknox has been a crucial partner with us to ensure utmost security of our UPI-based application. We have had good early detection of vulnerabilities with the help of very energetic and brilliant security professionals. ”
The threat however, is persistent and transformative and both the government and the fintech institutions would need all the help they can find to keep hackers from digging into sensitive user information and thereby, to drive its digitisation push further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a never-ending race where hackers look for more loopholes and banking companies innovate to keep ahead. The problem is that banks and other fintech institutions rely on a single vendor for all their security concerns. What they do not realise is that there could be many brains working to break the system and relying on a single brain for security is really dangerous,” says Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appknox specialises in providing security to mobile apps and currently services 100 plus companies in the fintech sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM gives E-Wallets a run for money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BHIM — or the Bharat Interface For Money — is quickly becoming the favoured mobile payment solution for crores of Indians. Since its launch on December 31 till the end of February, the app had been downloaded 17 million times. Following its Android launch, BHIM is now also available on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is an extension of the Unified Payment System. It allows users to send and receive money through a mobile app that is linked to their bank savings account. This is an elegant solution compared to e-wallets that need to maintain a cash balance in order to be functional. Naturally, the question then arises: Should users switch to BHIM and simply spend from their banks, and stop using e-wallets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences between BHIM and e-wallets, and we’ll examine them here in order to help you understand the pros and cons of both ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bhim-vs-wallets-where-bhim-wins&#34;&gt;BHIM vs Wallets: Where BHIM Wins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Balance, loading &amp;amp; unloading:&lt;/em&gt; The first major difference between BHIM and UPI apps and e-wallets is how you maintain your spending balance. BHIM and UPI apps allow you to send and receive money with your bank account. You do not have to maintain a balance with the app. The app is your bank account, in a sense. But in e-wallets, you must maintain a balance in order to spend from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just that, returning your wallet balance back to your bank account will come with limitations and charges. But with BHIM and UPI, there is no need to send the money back from the app to the bank, since the money has been sitting in your account all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/em&gt; Another aspect where BHIM and UPI apps trump e-wallets. E-wallets do not have interoperability, meaning that if you are using Wallet X, you can only transfer money to another user on Wallet X, and not to a user operating Wallet Y. This isn’t a problem with BHIM, since you may move money between accounts with any bank on the BHIM platform. For example, you may be using an SBI account but you can send and receive money from users on ICICI or HDFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spending limits:&lt;/em&gt; BHIM and UPI score heavily here as well. E-wallets have a monthly spending limit of Rs 10,000 which can be raised to Rs 100,000 after the KYC process wherein users need to submit proof of ID and address in order to become authenticated. But BHIM allows a limit of Rs 10,000 per transaction and Rs 20,000 as the total worth of transactions in a 24-hour cycle. UPI apps go further, allowing you to spend up to Rs 100,000 per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-bhim-lags&#34;&gt;Where BHIM Lags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly two areas where e-wallets have an edge over UPI and BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marketing gimmicks:&lt;/em&gt; E-wallets have been around for a few years and they have had the time to build relationships with merchants and businesses. As a result, e-wallets are useful not just for money transfers but also for earning cashbacks and discounts. Not just that, some e-wallets also operate as e-commerce platforms allowing users to buy merchandise, electronics, tickets, etc. UPI and BHIM, on the other hand, are recent innovations and have some catching up to do in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit usage:* E-wallets allow you to link and spend from your credit card, allowing you to leverage the power of the credit available to you. BHIM works on simpler principles: you get to spend only if you have a bank balance, and you cannot link BHIM and UPI apps to your credit card account yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-bhim-is-catching-up&#34;&gt;How BHIM Is Catching Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest Union Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced a referral bonus and cashback scheme for BHIM users. “The government will launch two new schemes — a referral bonus for consumers and a cash-back scheme for merchants — to promote the use of BHIM,” Jaitley said during his budget speech. With these inclusions, BHIM will become a little more attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
Both e-wallets and UPI-based apps such as BHIM have a long way to go and a big role to play in India where internet penetration and smartphone usage are increasing by leaps and bounds every year. Both need to evolve in order to accommodate the changing needs of the Indian consumer in an increasingly less cash-dependent economy. However, at this point, you may want to have both BHIM and e-wallets installed on your smartphones. They both have some unique services to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: BSNL Offers 2GB Data Per Day On Rs 339 Recharge</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-2gb-data-per-day-on-rs-339-recharge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-2gb-data-per-day-on-rs-339-recharge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analysts say incumbent telecom operators are coming up with attractive calling plans and lucrative data packs to counter additional competition triggered by Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry in the market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL is offering 2GB of 3G data per day and unlimited voice calling within its network under a special scheme priced at Rs 339. The &amp;ldquo;Combo STV&amp;rdquo; plan by state-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited or BSNL - for its prepaid customers - comes with a validity of 28 days, the telecom operator said in a statement. Analysts say incumbent telecom operators are coming up with attractive calling plans and lucrative data packs to counter additional competition triggered by Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSNL is offering 2GB of 3G data per day under a special recharge plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plan also offers unlimited voice calls on BSNL network&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telcos in India are giving attractive plans after Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special offer under its prepaid mobile services is in effect from March 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) The offer is limited for 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The &amp;ldquo;unlimited data&amp;rdquo; on offer will come with a &amp;ldquo;fair use policy&amp;rdquo; of 2 GB per day with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) BSNL is offering unlimited voice calls within its network. Calls outside the BSNL network will be for 25 minutes per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) After exhausting the 25-minute limit, the customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) &amp;ldquo;The data of 2GB per day is one of the best in the industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL added in its statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) &amp;ldquo;We are committed to providing affordable and efficient services to all segments of our loyal mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL director for consumer mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Religare analysts Rumit Dugar and Saumya Shrivastava believe the market could remain competitive for an extended period considering Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive revenue market share expectations. (Also read: 28 GB data for Rs 345: Airtel&amp;rsquo;s latest offer to counter Jio)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Reliance Industries&amp;rsquo; telecom arm - Reliance Jio Infocomm - is offering 1GB of 4G data per day and unlimited calling to all networks for free till March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) From April 1, Jio customers opting for its Prime service will continue to enjoy the unlimited calls and data benefits under its New Year Offer for a full year, till March 31, 2018. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime subscription will come at a one-time enrolment fee of Rs. 99 and &amp;ldquo;a rock-bottom introductory price” of only Rs 10 per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>