<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unique Identification Authority of India Uidai on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unique Identification Authority of India Uidai on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: Airtel Offers 30 GB Extra, Free Sim Delivery; Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-airtel-offers-30-gb-extra-free-sim-delivery-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-airtel-offers-30-gb-extra-free-sim-delivery-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Bharti Airtel, India’s largest telecom operator has come out with a new offer for potential post-paid customers. The offer gives 30 GB of free data to new post-paid customers over three months, which amounts to 10 GB of free data every month. The offer is valid on all Airtel post-paid plans apart from the Rs. 299 plan, according to the Airtel website. The bonus data can all be rolled over, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to verify if aadhaar card and pan card is linked</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-verify-if-both-cards-are-linked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-verify-if-both-cards-are-linked/</guid>
      <description>Steps to Check if Aadhar Card and PAN Card are Linked
 Go to the official website of the Income Tax Department. Enter your credentials – user ID, password, date of birth and captcha. Under ‘_Profile Setting_’ select ‘_Link Aadhaar_’. If your Aadhaar is linked with your PAN, then the display on the page will mention the same.  The benefit of linking Aadhaar and PAN in the income tax e-filing portal is to eliminate the necessity of furnishing your Income Tax acknowledgment while filing for returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customers’ consent must for use of Aadhaar-based e-KYC: IRDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-consent-must-use-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-irdai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/customers-consent-must-use-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-irdai/</guid>
      <description>The use of Aadhaar and accessing of personal information of Unique Identity Authority of India (UIDAI) for e-Know Your Customer (e-KYC) purposes can only be done only on the voluntary consent of customer, the insurance regulator has said.
In a clarification on the existing circulars issued on the matter, the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (IRDAI) said that insurers can use the e-authentication facility being provided by UIDAI either through the fingerprint or iris scanning) or through one time password (OTP) received on client’s mobile number or on e-mail address registered with UIDAI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadline for Linking Aadhaar with Govt Schemes is Now Dec 31</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/deadline-linking-aadhaar-govt-schemes-now-dec-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/deadline-linking-aadhaar-govt-schemes-now-dec-31/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court was informed on Wednesday the deadline for linking Aadhaar to various government schemes for benefits will be extended till December 31.
A bench of Chief Justice Dipak Misra, Justice Amitava Roy and Justice A.M. Khanwilkar said the challenge to the constitutional validity of the Aadhaar scheme would be heard in the first week of November.
Attorney General K.K. Venugopal told the court that the existing deadline of September 30 would be extended by three months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with bank a/c at the earliest else you won’t get scholarship</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-bank-ac-earliest-else-wont-get-scholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-bank-ac-earliest-else-wont-get-scholarship/</guid>
      <description>If you are entitled for “Central Sector Scheme of Scholarship for College and University Students” and have not linked your bank account with Aadhaar, then do it as early as possible else you won’t be able to claim scholarship. This year, the central government has made it clear that scholarships will be disbursed only through Direct Benefit Transfer (DBT) and told state governments to ensure 100 per cent seeding of beneficiaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May Take 3 Months For Rs. 200 Note To Reach ATMs: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/may-take-3-months-for-rs-200-note-to-reach-atms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/may-take-3-months-for-rs-200-note-to-reach-atms/</guid>
      <description>While the RBI launched the 200-rupee note a week ago, it may take up to three months for ATMs to start dispensing the new denomination currency as it will involve a huge exercise of recalibration.
Some banks have even asked the ATM companies to begin testing the new note for recalibration of the machines, though they have not got supplies of the new currency. Only last year, the banks were involved in recalibration of ATM machines after the demonetisation of high-value currency notes in November.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now you can check if your bank account is linked to Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-check-if-your-bank-account-is-linked-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-check-if-your-bank-account-is-linked-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory for financial institutions, including banks, to verify and link Aadhaar of their customers with their accounts. According to a notification dated June 1, 2017, the deadline for doing this is December 31, 2017 (as of now), and accounts where this is not done are to be made inoperable after this date till the details are updated.
To comply with this directive, banks are now asking customers to submit their Aadhaar to link the same with their accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can now lock your Aadhaar data to keep it safe from hackers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</guid>
      <description>Now, you can lock your Aadhaar biometric details to keep it safe and unlock it whenever you want to use it.
With digital payments using Aadhaar data on the rise and cases of misuse being reported, officials of the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) have come out with the new security feature to lock the biometric details (fingerprint and retinal scan data).The UIDAI introduced the lock and unlock facility following an uproar that Aadhaar deprived people of their right to privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.
A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Aadhaar With PAN Made Mandatory: How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>As the government insists that one&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar account and Permanent Account Number (PAN) should be linked by July 31 this year to pay income taxes, millions of Indians have faced issues with syncing the two accounts due to small differences in how their names are spelt. This problem can happen even if there are minor differences in how the name is recorded &amp;ndash; like the use of one&amp;rsquo;s full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar authentication a must for engineering scholarships</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>The state higher and technical education department has made authentication of Aadhaar number a must for backward engineering students to avail scholarships. The move comes against the backdrop of large-scale scholarship scam across the state.
Though decision has been welcomed by city engineering colleges, they feel the authentication process will burden them with extra work.
In a gazette notification dated April 13, the department states that every student desirous of availing benefits under the schemes specified in Schedule ‘A’ need to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo authentication process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avoid Queue At SBI Branches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</guid>
      <description>SBI&amp;rsquo;s virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores.
SBI or State Bank of India is offering a virtual queue ticket or &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo; service through its newly-launched app No Queue, which enables customers to avail select banking services at its select branches without having to stand in queues. SBI customers &amp;ldquo;can book a virtual token&amp;hellip;and skip the queue,&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI said on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar-Based Authentication Is ‘Fully Safe And Secure’, Assures UIDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</guid>
      <description>UIDAI dismissed the recently-reported breach as an isolated case, and added that their internal security system had picked up the attempted misuse.
Dismissing reports of misuse of biometrics data, the government on Sunday said Aadhaar-based authentication is “fully safe and secure”.
Moreover, subsidy transfers linked to Aadhaar has led the exchequer to save ₹49,000 crore during the last two-and-half years.
According to Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), there has been no incident of misuse of Aadhaar biometrics leading to identity theft and financial loss when more than 400 crore Aadhaar authenticated transactions took place during the last five years, it said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-linked payment system will change the game for digital transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</guid>
      <description>The Unique Identification Authority of India is working with banks and the Reserve Bank of India to ensure that merchants who use its mobile-based application for digital transactions earn a commission of up to 1% of the transaction value.
With UIDAI suggesting it is on path to get this in place in a couple of months, the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System could give debit cards and e-wallets a run for their money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI acts against 50 illegal websites</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</guid>
      <description>It came to the notice of UIDAI that websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services.
Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) has ensured that 12 websites and 12 mobile applications available on the Google Playstore are shut down and has directed to close down 26 more such fraudulent and illegal websites/applications.
It came to the notice of UIDAI that these websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services such as downloading online Aadhaar card, providing status of Aadhaar generation, PVC Aadhaar Card, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>