<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>400 Benami Transactions Crackdown by Income Tax Department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/i-t-department-crackdown-yeilds-400-benami-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/i-t-department-crackdown-yeilds-400-benami-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Benami property includes movable or immovable assets and property which is in name of someone other than the beneficial owner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department today said it has identified over 400 benami transactions and attached properties worth Rs 600 crore in about 240 cases. Keen to implement the new Benami Act to ensure &amp;ldquo;visible outcomes on the ground&amp;rdquo;, the tax department last week set up 24 dedicated Benami Prohibition Units (BPUs) all over India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department started initiating actions under the new Benami Transactions (Prohibition) Amendment Act, 2016 from November 1 last year. The law provides for a maximum punishment of seven years in jail and a fine. Benami property includes movable or immovable, tangible or intangible, corporeal or incorporeal property which is in name of someone other than the beneficial owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Income-tax Directorates of Investigation have identified more than 400 benami transactions up to May 23, 2017. These include deposits in bank accounts, plots of land, flat and jewellery,&amp;rdquo; said an official release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provisional attachment of properties under the law has been done in more than 240 cases. The market value of properties under attachment is more than Rs 600 crore, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Immovable properties have been attached in 40 cases with total value of more than Rs 530 crore in Kolkata, Mumbai, Delhi, Gujarat, Rajasthan and Madhya Pradesh,&amp;rdquo; the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also undertaken searches on 10 &amp;ldquo;senior government officials&amp;rdquo; during the past one month, in line with its policy to &amp;ldquo;unearth black money earned through corrupt practices and introduce accountability and probity in public life&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving details, the department said in one case in Jabalpur, the &amp;ldquo;benamidar&amp;rdquo;, a driver, was found to be owner of land worth Rs 7.7 crore. The beneficial owner was a Madhya Pradesh based listed company, his employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mumbai, a professional was found to be holding several immovable properties in the name of shell companies which exist only on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another case in Sanganer, Rajasthan, a jeweller was found to be the beneficial owner of nine immovable properties in the name of his former employee, a man of no means. Certain properties purchased through shell companies have also been attached by the department in Kolkata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crackdown on all forms of illicit wealth is being spearheaded by the department to ensure that any economic misdeed is immediately identified and actions as per law follow, the release added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 24 dedicated units are under the overall supervision of the Principal Directors of Investigation in the Income-tax Department to enable swift action and follow up, especially in cases where criminality has been detected.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATM hacks are less about losing a few lakhs &amp; more about erosion of reputation.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bankers-atm-hacks-are-less-about-losing-a-few-lakhs-more-about-erosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bankers-atm-hacks-are-less-about-losing-a-few-lakhs-more-about-erosion/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last year, Vijay Kumar, an Indian Army sepoy, got the shock of his life when he discovered a shortfall of Rs 2 lakh in his SBI salary account. Subsequently drawing out of transaction details and CCTV footage revealed Kumar’s card was “cloned” by fraudsters several kilometers from his base in Delhi Cantonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kumar had never even travelled to Connaught Place where his card was used (or misused). Miscreants managed to get his bank details using a Malaysian-make card reader and a hidden camera (affixed to the ceiling of the rigged ATM, focused on the keypad) to capture the PIN. Card skimming – an old trick – is common in India, but on a waning curve as swindlers have moved on to more sophisticated technologies. Daring raids on ATM switches and payment gateways, in rising numbers, have turned fraudsters of yore into new-age hackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to India Forensic, an educational &amp;amp; research organisation specialising in banking frauds, roughly 37,000 ATM fraud cases have been reported in the country since 2014. Industry experts estimate over 8,000 ATMs got infected by bugs last year – a good number on account of mishandling by third party handlers. Most banks outsource ‘ATM management’ (software updates, hardware service and others) to external agencies. ATMs get infected when third party service engineers use (virus) infected pen drives. Eight dacoity cases were reported in 2014, according to the National Crime Records Bureau, a couple of which included uprooting ATM machines and trucking them into the woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ransomware-rears-up&#34;&gt;RANSOMWARE REARS UP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a response to the recent ‘WannaCry Ransomware’ malware attack, the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) asked banks to update software systems. There are unconfirmed reports of two south India based banks being infected, The Times of India stated recently. “Ample security measures have to be employed across all banks as customers use non-home ATMs as well. So only one bank with strong system or network may not really help. ATMs are easy targets,” explains Mahesh Patel, group CTO, AGS Transact Technologies, an ATM manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bankers, it appears, are not overly worried about individual ATMs as these hold only “a few lakhs of rupees” at any given time. But they are concerned about reputational risk associated with their ATMs getting hacked and plundered. Beyond that, banks are focused on securing pricier installations such as the ‘ATM or core banking switch,’ which link core accounts and clusters of ATMs. “Hackers are not interested in individual customers or ATMs anymore… they’re looking for larger gains and bigger play,” admits Johnson K Jose, head of IT at Federal Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Most ATM attacks happen at the (ATM) switch level these days… precisely for this reason, we don’t outsource switch-level operations to outsiders. But then securing individual ATMs is also important for banks… customers should feel safe when they transact on a particular bank’s ATM,” Johnson adds. ATM/debit card fraud complaints shot up 23% to 13,081 in 2015-16, as per the latest Banking Ombudsman Report. Of the 22,000 card-related complaints received, 8,300 pertain to failed ATM withdrawal transactions, short/non-dispensation and fraudulent removal of cash from customer accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;physical-attacks&#34;&gt;PHYSICAL ATTACKS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 2016, four youths uprooted an SBI ‘pass book updating machine’ thinking it was an ATM kiosk. Such instances of ‘ATM ramming’ are fairly common in Australia, where miscreants use tractors to pull out cash dispensers bolted to the ground. Physical attacks on ATMs are also on a rising curve in India. AnG India, an electronic security solutions company, receives over 100 alerts of “force” being exerted on ATMs every day. Of this, around 10 pertain to breakage or forced entry. “Not many ATMs have guards anymore… Banks mostly use e-surveillance systems,” says Pulkit Punj, director of AnG India. “Some kind of access restriction has to be there to keep away undesirable elements (near ATMs),” feels Mukul Shrivastava, partner – fraud investigation &amp;amp; dispute services, EY. “Also, there’s a lot of hardware (wires, connecting cables) lying around openly in ATMs. These have to be concealed properly… Such inlet points come handy for expert hackers to get through,” he warns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;defence-countermeasures&#34;&gt;DEFENCE, COUNTERMEASURES&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, when banks requisitioned for new ATMs, they did not ask for security packages that came at extra cost. This has changed now. Banks have started demanding whitelisting modules, antiskimming devices and hard disk encryption software along with new ATMs. “Multiple banking touchpoints — from net banking to mobile banking and ewallets — are vulnerable to cyber attacks. So banks should not look at security in a piecemeal fashion,” says Navroze Dastur, MD of NCR Corporation, an ATM manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operating system updation would go a long way to secure ATMs from minor hacks. Whitelisting modules would ring-fence the core (software) by restricting unauthorised reworking of programmes using malwares. Strong safe boxes (Cen-1 safes) are being installed inside most new ATMs. Cen-1 strong boxes take approximately 35 minutes to cut open (a unit of measure for safe boxes) while the previously used UL291 boxes could be forced open in 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instances of card skimming and cloning are likely to come down after the move to EMV (Europay, Mastercard, Visa) cards in two years. EMV or chip cards, according to experts, offer one of the most secure conduits for banking transactions. Some 300 million magstripe cards would be replaced with chip-embedded EMV cards by end-December 2018, as directed by RBI. If security experts are to be believed, six lakh new bugs are released into the “market” (thriving on internet) daily. Malwares such as Green dispenser, Suceful, Padpin and Tyupkin have cracked open ATMs of late. Some can be downloaded on a pen drive and their ‘spit-code’ sourced from Russian or American hack mafia for a price. Banks and security agencies will have to keep plugging the holes every single day to keep black hats at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government To Roll Out Aadhaar Pay For Cashless Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-roll-aadhaar-pay-cashless-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-roll-aadhaar-pay-cashless-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government will soon roll out Aadhaar Pay service that will enable people to make and receive payments using their Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are going to start Aadhaar Pay. With this people will not require to carry their phone for payments. They can visit any merchant, share their Aadhaar number and verify themselves using biometrics to pay and receive money,” Electronics and IT Minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, 14 banks have come on board for Aadhaar Pay and the service will be launched soon, Prasad told reporters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are in talks with other banks too. The service will be launched very soon,” he informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the Minister said, Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM), the common platform for making quick payments using the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), has also been integrated with Aadhaar Enabled Payment System on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 111 crore people in the country have Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are 49 crore bank accounts linked to Aadhaar. Every month 2 crore accounts are being seeded with Aadhaar,” Prasad said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to choose the right credit card: 6 power points to note</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-choose-the-right-credit-card-6-power-points-to-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-choose-the-right-credit-card-6-power-points-to-note/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opt for a credit card whose benefits in the form of cashbacks, discounts, reward points and lifestyle programmes outweigh the various mandatory fees associated with it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit cards today have become an integral part of our lives. They save us from the hassles of carrying cash, allow us to optimise our finances better through interest-free periods and EMI options, enable us to maintain a good credit score and avail attractive cashbacks, discounts and reward points offered by banks. However, with several types of credit cards available in the market, choosing the right one can be confusing for a customer. Here are some factors to be considered while selecting a credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spending-habits&#34;&gt;Spending habits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most credit cards aim at specific type of transactions by offering higher reward points and other benefits on those transactions. For example, while some cards offer cashback on fuel transactions or other daily spends, others offer more reward points on air travels, dining and/or hotel stays. Choose a card that will offer you maximum benefits, according to your lifestyle and spending habits. For example, if you travel a lot, take a credit card that offers travel benefits like air miles, lounge access and hotel vouchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fees&#34;&gt;Fees&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit card issuers charge various types of fees for their services, like joining fee, annual fee, rewards redemption fee, late payment fee and cash advance fee. The joining and annual fee usually ranges between Rs 199–5,000 depending on the card category. However, many card issuers do not charge joining fee and/or annual fee. Many cards also waive off their joining fee on applying through online loan aggregators while others reverse their annual and joining fee on spending a threshold amount through their credit cards. Opt for a credit card whose benefits in the form of cashbacks, discounts, reward points and lifestyle programmes outweigh the various mandatory fees associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;also-watch&#34;&gt;Also Watch:&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/FGMeZGdYUXo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;credit-limit&#34;&gt;Credit limit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit limit refers to the maximum amount that you can spend on your card without incurring any penalty. Exceeding this limit results in incurring an over limit fee on the amount exceeded. Thus, opt for a card that offers at least 3–4 times of your tentative monthly credit card spends. Also, remember that having a higher credit limit will come in handy during financial emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;joining-bonuses&#34;&gt;Joining bonuses&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many credit cards, especially in the premium and travel segments, offer attractive joining bonuses or welcome benefits in the form of free vouchers and additional bonus reward points. Many card issuers also offer exclusive joining bonuses on applying through online aggregators. Compare the joining bonuses among similar cards before zeroing on a particular option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;finance-charges&#34;&gt;Finance charges&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card issuers levy finance charges on non-payment or part-payment of outstanding balance by the due date and on cash withdrawals. This charge is levied right from the date of the transaction until the repayment of the entire outstanding. The finance charge can vary from 22–47% per annum depending on your card type. Though not paying your entire credit card bill on time or withdrawing cash using your credit card is never recommended, you should still consider these charges when applying for a credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credit-score&#34;&gt;Credit score&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approval of your credit card application primarily depends on your credit score, monthly income and occupational details. Each bank gives different weightage to these parameters. However, people with credit scores of 750 and above have higher chances of getting their credit card approved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 900 In Limited-Period Scheme. Details Here:IndiGo Offers Tickets</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indigo-offers-tickets-under-rs-900-in-limited-period-scheme-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indigo-offers-tickets-under-rs-900-in-limited-period-scheme-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IndiGo said the current offer is applicable on bookings made at least 20 days prior to the travel date.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IndiGo offers all-inclusive fares starting from Rs 899 on select flights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer valid on travel between June 26 and March 24, 2018, says IndiGo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make bookings 20 days prior to travel date, it adds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo has announced all-inclusive fares starting from Rs 899 on select one-way flights under a promotional scheme. IndiGo, which recently offered tickets from Rs 851 on select routes, said the current offer is applicable on bookings made at least 20 days prior to the travel date. Bookings under the Rs 899 scheme - applicable on travel between June 26 and March 24, 2018 - can be made till May 28, the airline said on its website. &amp;ldquo;This offer is applicable on all our booking channels,&amp;rdquo; IndiGo further said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IndiGo offer is valid only on non-stop flights from Ahmedabad, Amritsar, Bagdogra, Bengaluru, Chennai, Delhi, Goa, Guwahati, Hyderabad, Jaipur, Jammu, Kochi, Kolkata, Mumbai, Pune, Srinagar, and Visakhapatnam, among others. The IndiGo offer is also applicable on non-stop flights from Agartala, Chandigarh, Coimbatore, Dehradun, Madurai, Mangalore, Port Blair, Patna and Varanasi, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lowest all-inclusive Rs 899 tickets were being offered on flights from Srinagar to Jammu under the scheme, according to the IndiGo website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A search on the IndiGo bookings portal showed tickets for flights from Srinagar to Jammu in July were being offered at Rs 794.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other fares under the discounted fares scheme included Rs 999 for flights from Jammu to Srinagar; Rs 1,089 for Delhi-Jaipur; Rs 1,104 for Visakhapatnam-Hyderabad, Rs 1,165 for Agartala-Guwahati, Rs 1,179 for Madurai-Chennai, the IndiGo website noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other flights covered under the IndiGo scheme were Ahmedabad-Mumbai (fares starting from Rs 1,212), Bengaluru-Hyderabad (Rs 1,250) and Chennai-Coimbatore (Rs 1,169).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competition among airlines amid robust growth in number of passengers is leading to lower airfares and lucrative schemes for flyers, some analysts say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SpiceJet has announced discounted fares for non-stop flights across its network in a limited-period sale, under which it is offering tickets at a discounted base fare of Rs 12 (excluding surcharge and taxes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many airlines - including Air India, AirAsia, Jet Airways and GoAir - have offered discounted fares and lucrative schemes in the recent past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domestic air passenger traffic rose 15.15 per cent to 91.34 lakh in April, data from aviation regulator DGCA (Directorate General of Civil Aviation) showed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, economy class air travel is set to become cheaper with tax rate fixed at 5 per cent against the existing 6, under the upcoming indirect tax regime - Goods and Services Tax (GST) - from July 1. Business class tickets are expected to become more expensive as the tax will go up from 9 per cent to 12 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo plans to start flying smaller planes to second-tier towns and cities later this year under Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s UDAN or &amp;lsquo;Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik&amp;rsquo; scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UDAN Scheme: More Routes To Be Allocated By August</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/udan-scheme-more-routes-to-be-allocated-by-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/udan-scheme-more-routes-to-be-allocated-by-august/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The government will soon launch the second round of bidding under RCS-UDAN after receiving stakeholders&amp;rsquo; views on some proposed changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central government on Wednesday said that it will allocate more air routes under its regional connectivity scheme &amp;ndash; UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Nagrik) &amp;ndash; through the second round of bidding by August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Civil Aviation Minister P Ashok Gajapathi Raju, the government will soon launch the second round of bidding under RCS-UDAN after receiving stakeholders&amp;rsquo; views on some proposed changes to the scheme which are intended to make it simpler and attractive for participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry will organise a stakeholder consultation meet on June 7 and will accept stakeholders&amp;rsquo; comments on the proposed changes by June 9, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same event, Civil Aviation Secretary R.N. Choubey pointed out that the ministry is planning to host an &amp;ldquo;interactive meet&amp;rdquo; between state governments and airlines for the second round of bidding for Udan routes on July 7, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On April 27, 2017, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had flagged off the first Rs 2,500-an-hour flight between Shimla and New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scheme is a key component of the National Civil Aviation Policy (NCAP) which was released last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 30, 2017, the central government under the first round of bidding for the scheme awarded contracts to five companies to operate flight services on 128 routes that will connect 70 airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airline companies chosen during the first round of bidding were Airline Allied Services (Alliance Air), SpiceJet, Turbo Megha Airways, Air Deccan and Air Odisha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of RCS, christened as UDAN is to enhance air passenger traffic in the country by stimulating demand on regional routes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Mandatory For Filing Tax Returns, PAN Card From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-for-filing-tax-returns-pan-card-from-july-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting of Aadhaar has been made mandatory for filing income tax returns with effect from July 1, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, an official statement said on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be compulsory for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN), with effect from July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961 as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017 provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar /Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from July 1,&amp;rdquo; said a Finance Ministry statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or Enrolment ID will apply only to a person who is eligible to obtain Aadhaar number, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act, 2016, only a resident individual is entitled to obtain Aadhaar. Resident as per the said Act means an individual who has resided in India for a period or periods amounting in all to 182 days or more in the 12 months immediately preceding the date of application for enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the requirement to quote Aadhaar as per section 139AA of the Income-tax Act shall not apply to an individual who is not a resident as per the Aadhaar Act, 2016, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar mandatory to avoid fake PAN cards: Government tells Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government today defended in the Supreme Court its decisionto make Aadhaar mandatory for issuing of PAN cards, saying it was done to curb the use of fake PAN cards across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi told a bench comprising Justices A K Sikri and Ashok Bhushan that the programme of PAN had become suspect as it could be faked while Aadhaar is a &amp;ldquo;secure and robust&amp;rdquo; system by which the identity of an individual cannot be faked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AG said that due to Aadhaar, government has saved over Rs 50,000 crore on the schemes to benefit the poor as well as the pension schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that around 10 lakh PAN cards have been cancelled, while out of the 113.7 crore Aadhaar cards issued, no case of duplication has been found by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that Aadhaar was an effective tool to check the menace of terror funding and circulation of black money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The idea behind Aadhaar is to make a secure and robust system by which the identity of a person cannot be faked,&amp;rdquo; the Attorney General told the court, which would continue hearing the arguments tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court is hearing three petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Section 139 AA of the Income Tax Act which was introduced through the latest budget and the Finance Act 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Section 139AA provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns and making an application for allotment of PAN number with effect from July 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior counsel Shyam Divan, representing the petitioners, had earlier argued that section 139AA was unconstitutional and was in &amp;ldquo;direct collision&amp;rdquo; with the Aadhaar Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had also contended that there was no question of forcing a person to give his consent for Aadhaar and this was an issue which &amp;ldquo;alters the relationship of Republic of India with its citizens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The petitioner had also argued that a law-abiding tax payer cannot be forced to give his Aadhaar number while filing income tax returns and this was like an &amp;ldquo;electronic leash&amp;rdquo; as government would be able to keep a tab on its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nowhere in the world there is such a biometric system which can track a person 24X7. They (government) are doing it even before the age of consent,&amp;rdquo; he had said during the arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had earlier put a poser as to why there was no objection from the lawmakers on the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for making PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rohatgi had also clarified that nowhere in section 139AA of IT Act, was it mentioned that it would be effective with retrospective effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had earlier told the apex court that fake PAN cards were being used to &amp;ldquo;divert funds&amp;rdquo; to shell companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>keep your computer safe from WannaCry 10 Do’s and Don’ts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-ransomware-scare-10-dos-and-donts-to-keep-your-computer-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-ransomware-scare-10-dos-and-donts-to-keep-your-computer-safe/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-is-a-list-of-do-s-and-don-ts-which-you-should-follow-to-keep-your-computer-safe&#34;&gt;Here is a list of Do’s and Don’ts which you should follow to keep your computer safe:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to immediately install the May Windows Update bundles. Shutting down your system for a few minutes will be worth it, if it enables you to avoid this. If you’re still using Windows XP, you’re out of luck, but the March and April update bundles are available for Windows Vista. Also, Microsoft has released a patch for Windows XP and its server counterpart Windows 2003.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to prevent the infection, users and organisations should apply relevant patches to Windows systems as mentioned in the Microsoft Security Bulletin MS17-010. The malware has been targeting commonly used office file extensions such as .ppt (PowerPoint), .doc and .docx (Word), .xlsx (Excel), and image file extensions such as .tiff, .raw, among various other common file types for archiving, emails, databases, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This attack type may evolve over time, so any additional defense-in-depth strategies will provide additional protections. (For example, to further protect against SMBv1 attacks, customers should consider blocking legacy protocols on their networks).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As part of the best practices to prevent ransomware attacks, users should maintain an updated antivirus software, regularly check for integrity of the information stored on databases, to not open attachments in unsolicited e-mails, restrict users’ ability to install and run unwanted software applications, among various others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals or organisations are not encouraged to pay the ransom, as this does not guarantee files will be released. Report such instances of fraud to CERT-In and law enforcement agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform regular backups of all critical information to limit the impact of data or system loss and to help expedite the recovery process. Ideally, this data should be kept on a separate device, and backups should be stored offline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CERT-In advisory: Block SMB ports on Enterprise Edge/perimeter network devices [UDP 137, 138 and TCP 139, 445] or Disable SMBv1. &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/2696547&#34;&gt;http://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/2696547&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t open attachments in unsolicited e-mails, even if they come from people in your contact list, and never click on a URL contained in an unsolicited e-mail, even if the link seems benign. In cases of genuine URLs close out the e-mail and go to the organisation’s website directly through browser&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deploy web and email filters on the network. Configure these devices to scan for known bad domains, sources, and addresses; block these before receiving and downloading messages. Scan all emails, attachments, and downloads both on the host and at the mail gateway with a reputable antivirus solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;USE THESE TOOLS:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tool (NoMoreCry) to prevent Wannacry Ransomware by CCN-CERT:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sophos: Hitman.Pro&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Malwarebytes Anti-Ransomware(formally Crypto Monitor)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trendmicro Ransomware Screen Unlocker tool&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Enhanced mitigation and experience toolkit(EMET)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EPFO Reduces Wait For Pension, Provident Fund Withdrawal To 10 days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-reduces-wait-for-pension-provident-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-reduces-wait-for-pension-provident-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The retirement fund manager had launched an online claim settlement facility on May 1, 2017.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund manager EPFO has reduced the stipulated period for settlement of various claims such PF withdrawal, pension and insurance to 10 days from 20 at present. In July 2015, the Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had reduced the timeline for settling various claims to 20 day to improve the service delivery for its over four crore subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body has launched the online claim settlement facility on May 1, 2017. It has planned to eventually settle claims of all Aadhaar and bank account seeded EPF accounts within three hours of receipt of an application. &amp;ldquo;The timeline in case of claim settlements is 10 days and 15 days in case of grievance redressal management,&amp;rdquo; an EPFO statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are new provisions in the EPFO&amp;rsquo;s Citizens&amp;rsquo; Charter 2017 launched in Bangalore today by Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said the Charter is an attempt to bring transparency and accountability on the part of EPFO and make service delivery system and grievance redressal mechanism more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO e-court Management System has also been launched which is in tune with the vision of Prime Minister Narendra Modi of digital India. The objective of the project is a transparent and electronic case management system which will cater to aspirations of all stakeholders - the employers, the employees, litigants and CBT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a step towards paperless court system wherein court procedure of EPF &amp;amp; MP Act, 1952 and EPFAT (tribunal) will take place in a digital environment. Further, in order to facilitate easy access to the tribunal, automated messages will be sent to the litigants on their registered mobile numbers on the status of their cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stakeholders can also track the individual cases online, it said. Now the parties can file all their paper/evidence/ documents online and all the details alongwith status can be accessed online. Updation is an important part of e-court management system in which digital case record will create a digital database which can be utilised to generate meaningful and accurate reports, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST impact: here’s how much it may cost you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-impact-services-set-to-get-costlier-heres-how-much-it-may-cost-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-impact-services-set-to-get-costlier-heres-how-much-it-may-cost-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the 120 services that are currently being taxed, a vast majority is likely to come under the goods and services tax (GST) slab of 18%, while a clutch of them including air travel services, renting of hotels, restaurants and other “bundled” food supply services could get taxed at 12%. A handful of services including transport of goods by road (trucks) and rail and financial leasing including hire purchase could fall under the lowest GST rate of 5%. While the principle that underlies the GST rates fitment, recommended by a committee of officials, is to minimise rate shocks, services would still be the category to witness rate hikes the most as the country adopts the new indirect tax structure, official sources said. Since the current service tax rate is 15% (including the 0.5% Swachh Bharat Cess and an equal Krishi Kalyan cess), levy of GST at 18% would mean a significant increase in the tax liability of consumers of most services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even for the relatively smaller number of services to be taxed at 12% in the GST regime, the tax incidence could actually increase in some cases. This is because taxes paid after the abatements permitted by the government work out to be lower than 12% in many such cases at present. For example, restaurant services are currently taxed with 30% abatement, which means actual tax incidence of 10.5%. This could increase to 12% in the GST regime, rather than decrease to 5%. The sources added that all the 60-odd exempt services, which are on the negative list now, would be outside the GST net too. These include services provided by educational institutions, healthcare services, EPFO- Irdai-Sebi services, non-A/c restaurants etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since the service providers will get greater opportunity to avail of input tax credit in the GST regime, their tax liability could soften if a rate hike is big enough to offset it. Transport of goods by rail is now taxed after 70% abatement on the condition that CENVAT credit has not been taken by the businesses concerned. Since the credit flows will be more efficient in the GST regime, the tax rate is likely to be fixed taking into account the abatements being given now for the new regime to be rate-neutral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at least in some cases, this principle might not be followed and the tax liability of businesses and consumers could rise, analysts said. However, the instances of GST leading to higher tax liabilities and price increases will be very few in the case of goods. Items constituting half of the consumer price index (CPI) basket including food grain will be exempt from GST; many other goods of mass consumption, together another tenth of the basket, will be taxed at a benign 5%; a quarter of the basket will come under either 12% or 18%, the two “standard rates.
The government has maintained that rate fitment will be a “mechanical (rather than discretionary) exercise” as the process has taken into account the real tax incidence at present rather than the nominal rate. For instance, if the nominal tax rate on an item with maximum retail price of Rs 150 and ex-factory price of Rs 100 is 26.5% (12.5% excise and 14% VAT), the real tax incidence on the price to the consumer is just 22%, as the excise duty is virtually levied on the ex-factory price, with abatement for post-manufacturing value addition. Chances are that the item will come under 18% GST, rather than the highest rate of 28%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The committee of officials has prepared a detailed document on the fitment of GST rates for the consideration of the GST Council. The 800-page document is likely to be vetted by the council as it meets in Srinagar on May 18-19. Source told FE that even after the GST Council approval, the rates will be notified and made public only closer to the July 1 roll-out to avoid market distortion and hoarding. Experts said that the reason for delaying announcement of rates could be to negate the possibility that a manufacturer may ramp up or slow down production till July 1 if it’s known that a commodity will be taxed at a lower/ higher rate under GST.
Apart from final approval to the rates, the GST Council is expected to okay the five draft rules related to accounts and records, advance ruling, appeals and revision, assessment and audit and e-way bill. So far, the Council has approved nine GST rules in its earlier meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian-Origin Techie Links Ransomware Attack To North Korea</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-origin-techie-links-ransomware-attack-to-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-origin-techie-links-ransomware-attack-to-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About 200,000 machines have been infected worldwide by the ransomware &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Indian-origin security researcher with Google has found evidence suggesting that North Korean hackers may have carried out the &amp;ldquo;unprecedented&amp;rdquo; ransomware cyberattack that hit over 150 countries, including India. Neel Mehta has published a code which a Russian security firm has termed as the &amp;ldquo;most significant clue to date&amp;rdquo;, BBC reported today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code, published on Twitter, is exclusive to North Korean hackers, researchers said. Researchers have said that some of the code used in Friday&amp;rsquo;s ransomware, known as WannaCry software, was nearly identical to the code used by the Lazarus Group, a group of North Korean hackers who used a similar version for the devastating hack of Sony Pictures Entertainment in 2014 and the last year&amp;rsquo;s hack of Bangladesh Central Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security experts are now cautiously linking the Lazarus Group to this latest attack after the discovery by Mehta. Mehta has found similarities between code found within WannaCry and other tools believed to have been created by the Lazarus Group in the past, BBC reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security expert Prof Alan Woodward said that time stamps within the original WannaCry code are set to UTC +9 - China&amp;rsquo;s time zone - and the text demanding the ransom uses what reads like machine-translated English, but a Chinese segment apparently written by a native speaker, the report said.
&amp;ldquo;As you can see it is pretty thin and all circumstantial. However, it is worth further investigation,&amp;rdquo; Woodward said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neel Mehta&amp;rsquo;s discovery is the most significant clue to date regarding the origins of WannaCry,&amp;rdquo; said Russian security firm Kaspersky, but noted a lot more information is needed about earlier versions of WannaCry before any firm conclusion can be reached, it reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We believe it is important that other researchers around the world investigate these similarities and attempt to discover more facts about the origin of WannaCry,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attributing cyberattacks can be notoriously difficult-often relying on consensus rather than confirmation, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Korea has never admitted any involvement in the Sony Pictures hack - and while security researchers, and the US government, have confidence in the theory, neither can rule out the possibility of a false flag, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skilled hackers may have simply made it look like it had origins in North Korea by using similar techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of WannaCry, it is possible that hackers simply copied code from earlier attacks by the Lazarus Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ifs in there. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stand up in court as it is. But it&amp;rsquo;s worth looking deeper, being conscious of confirmation bias now that North Korea has been identified as a possibility,&amp;rdquo; Woodward said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the strongest theory yet as to the origin of WannaCry, but there are also details that arguably point  way from it being the work of North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, China was among the countries worst hit, and not accidentally - the hackers made sure there was a version of the ransom note written in Chinese. It seems unlikely North Korea would want to antagonise its strongest ally. Russia too was badly affected, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, North Korean cyber-attacks have typically been far more targeted, often with a political goal in mind. In the case of Sony Pictures, hackers sought to prevent the release of The Interview, a film that mocked North Korean leader Kim Jong-Un. WannaCry, in contrast, was wildly indiscriminate - it would infect anything and everything it could, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if the plan was simply to make money, it&amp;rsquo;s been pretty unsuccessful on that front too - only around $60,000 has been paid in ransoms, according to analysis of Bitcoin accounts being used by the criminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more than 200,000 machines infected, it&amp;rsquo;s a terrible return, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Europol Director Rob Wainwright said, &amp;ldquo;The global reach is unprecedented. The latest count is over 200,000 victims in at least 150 countries and those victims many of those will be businesses including large corporations&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not happy with bank fixed deposits? Check out 4 alternatives</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/not-happy-with-bank-fixed-deposits-check-out-4-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/not-happy-with-bank-fixed-deposits-check-out-4-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compared to bank deposits or small savings, non-convertible debentures, liquid funds, tax-free bonds and company fixed deposits offer higher returns, albeit with some risks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a time when interest rates on bank deposit and small savings are falling, investors can look at other debt financial instruments to earn some higher returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;non-convertible-debentures&#34;&gt;Non-convertible debentures&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies issue non-convertible debentures (NCDs) to raise long-term funds. These debentures cannot be converted into shares or equities and lenders offer a higher rate of return compared to convertible debentures. Non-convertible debentures are of two types —secured and non-secured. The secured ones are backed by assets, wherein if the company is unable to fulfil its obligations, the assets are liquidated to repay the investors.
So, secured non-convertible debentures pay lower coupons than non-secured ones. Companies issuing non-convertible debentures offer higher rates because they carry default risk compared to bank or postal deposits. Investing in NCDs makes sense for those in the 10% to 20% tax brackets, as those in the lowest tax bracket can get post tax returns around 7% for a 120-month tenure. One should invest in non-convertible debentures only if he can hold them till maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Liquid funds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors can also look at liquid funds offered by asset management companies for short-term investment for up to a year. The fund will yield marginally higher returns than bank deposits. Moreover, they are as liquid as time and demand deposits as the market regulator has allowed fund houses to offer instant redemption facility of up to Rs 50,000. In fact, one aspect where bank deposits scored over liquid funds or any other money market funds was same day redemption.
Now that has been taken care and investors can manage cash flows better. At the time of investing in debt funds, investors must analyse the credit rating of the bonds in which the fund house invests. While debt funds are not rated, their safety can be analysed from the portfolio they invest in. Fund managers may sometimes take higher position in bonds with lower rating for higher returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Tax-free bonds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, tax-free bonds were issued by state-owned companies such as NHAI, IRFC, HUDCO till March 2016. However, investors can now buy these bonds from the secondary market and can earn up to 2% more than bank fixed deposits after tax. Tax-free bonds are an attractive long-term investment as there is no deduction of tax at source from the interest that accrues to bondholders, irrespective of the interest amount or status of the investor.
These bonds score over fixed deposits or other debt investment as investors do not have to pay tax on the returns. Before investing in tax-free bonds, one must look at the issue size as it may impact liquidity. For instance, NHAI’s Rs 10,000-crore bond issue has the highest traded volume on bourses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;company-fixed-deposits&#34;&gt;Company fixed deposits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even by investing in company fixed deposits of top-rated firms, investors can earn up to 150 basis points more than bank fixed deposits. However, investors must exercise utmost caution because while bank deposits provide security for investment up to Rs 1 lakh, this is not the case with corporate fixed deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tenure of company deposits ranges from one to seven years and one can earn compounding interest by reinvesting the principal amount along with the interest earned. Investors can get direct ECS credit facility for interest payments or advance interest warrants for the year. However, unless one needs income regularly, they should prefer cumulative schemes to regular income options since the interest earned gets reinvested at the same coupon rate, resulting in better yields.
Diversify investment in four to five companies and avoid investing in those companies that mention very high interest rates and whose balance sheets show losses. If one invests in a company that is low on ratings, go for a short tenure, which will enable you to opt out if the company is not performing well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>