<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not compulsory for obtaining marriage certificate: CIC to Govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Chief Information Commission has asked the government and marriage registration authorities to raise awareness and provide publicity through various media that Aadhaar is not compulsory for the purpose of marriage registration scheme, reports LiveLaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commission ruled that the compulsory registration of marriages helps tackle various issues like child marriage, marriage without consent, bigamous marriages, etc., and as such, the government should make it easier and more convenient to facilitate the registration, by not requiring other documents like Aadhaar and making changes for online application for marriage under the Special Marriage Act etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CIC cited Supreme Court’s order from 2014, which ruled that the government should not restrict social benefits to those who are yet to receive their Aadhaar card. Last year, the SC had also said that the card scheme is purely voluntary and cannot be made mandatory for scholarships. However, contrary to its prior stance, the SC asked the Government to link all mobile numbers with Aadhaar card details within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;centre-s-push-to-increase-aadhaar-saturation&#34;&gt;Centre’s push to increase Aadhaar saturation?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usage of Aadhaar as a verification system has been on the rise where multiple services including the IIT JEE, employee provident funds, PDS food grain purchases, RTE admissions and Jharkhand’s food and public distribution systems also using it. Private companies have also started using Aadhaar for verification purposes, such as iris scans by DCB Bank for eKYC, Microsoft’s Skype Lite which supports Aadhaar based verification, etc. However, use of Aadhaar by making it compulsory to avail some services, has come under heavy criticism for not respecting user privacy or being very secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM gives E-Wallets a run for money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BHIM — or the Bharat Interface For Money — is quickly becoming the favoured mobile payment solution for crores of Indians. Since its launch on December 31 till the end of February, the app had been downloaded 17 million times. Following its Android launch, BHIM is now also available on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is an extension of the Unified Payment System. It allows users to send and receive money through a mobile app that is linked to their bank savings account. This is an elegant solution compared to e-wallets that need to maintain a cash balance in order to be functional. Naturally, the question then arises: Should users switch to BHIM and simply spend from their banks, and stop using e-wallets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences between BHIM and e-wallets, and we’ll examine them here in order to help you understand the pros and cons of both ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bhim-vs-wallets-where-bhim-wins&#34;&gt;BHIM vs Wallets: Where BHIM Wins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Balance, loading &amp;amp; unloading:&lt;/em&gt; The first major difference between BHIM and UPI apps and e-wallets is how you maintain your spending balance. BHIM and UPI apps allow you to send and receive money with your bank account. You do not have to maintain a balance with the app. The app is your bank account, in a sense. But in e-wallets, you must maintain a balance in order to spend from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just that, returning your wallet balance back to your bank account will come with limitations and charges. But with BHIM and UPI, there is no need to send the money back from the app to the bank, since the money has been sitting in your account all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/em&gt; Another aspect where BHIM and UPI apps trump e-wallets. E-wallets do not have interoperability, meaning that if you are using Wallet X, you can only transfer money to another user on Wallet X, and not to a user operating Wallet Y. This isn’t a problem with BHIM, since you may move money between accounts with any bank on the BHIM platform. For example, you may be using an SBI account but you can send and receive money from users on ICICI or HDFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spending limits:&lt;/em&gt; BHIM and UPI score heavily here as well. E-wallets have a monthly spending limit of Rs 10,000 which can be raised to Rs 100,000 after the KYC process wherein users need to submit proof of ID and address in order to become authenticated. But BHIM allows a limit of Rs 10,000 per transaction and Rs 20,000 as the total worth of transactions in a 24-hour cycle. UPI apps go further, allowing you to spend up to Rs 100,000 per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-bhim-lags&#34;&gt;Where BHIM Lags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly two areas where e-wallets have an edge over UPI and BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marketing gimmicks:&lt;/em&gt; E-wallets have been around for a few years and they have had the time to build relationships with merchants and businesses. As a result, e-wallets are useful not just for money transfers but also for earning cashbacks and discounts. Not just that, some e-wallets also operate as e-commerce platforms allowing users to buy merchandise, electronics, tickets, etc. UPI and BHIM, on the other hand, are recent innovations and have some catching up to do in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit usage:* E-wallets allow you to link and spend from your credit card, allowing you to leverage the power of the credit available to you. BHIM works on simpler principles: you get to spend only if you have a bank balance, and you cannot link BHIM and UPI apps to your credit card account yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-bhim-is-catching-up&#34;&gt;How BHIM Is Catching Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest Union Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced a referral bonus and cashback scheme for BHIM users. “The government will launch two new schemes — a referral bonus for consumers and a cash-back scheme for merchants — to promote the use of BHIM,” Jaitley said during his budget speech. With these inclusions, BHIM will become a little more attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
Both e-wallets and UPI-based apps such as BHIM have a long way to go and a big role to play in India where internet penetration and smartphone usage are increasing by leaps and bounds every year. Both need to evolve in order to accommodate the changing needs of the Indian consumer in an increasingly less cash-dependent economy. However, at this point, you may want to have both BHIM and e-wallets installed on your smartphones. They both have some unique services to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar card to be linked with flights soon?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linked-flights-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linked-flights-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Delhi: The Central government has now asked Information Technology major Wipro to come up with reports and to develop a blueprint for Aadhaar-based biometric access to flight passengers at all airports across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, based on government’s direction, Wipro is likely to submit a report in May after which the airports will start the process where a flyer’s thumb would be all the identification they need to be eligible to fly on domestic flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aviation ministry had an idea about linking Aadhaar number with flight bookings which enables the biometric access possible at all airports. Reports revealed that the solid push was taken by Aviation Minister Jayant Sinha and Aviation Secretary R N Choubey in a meeting with several airport operators and airlines officials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Airports Authority of India chief Guruprasad Mohapatra, he said that linking of Aadhaar card number and thumb identification will help an official know about the passenger boarding the flight. Mohapatra explained that at the time of booking, a passenger enters his/her Aadhaar number. On arrival at an airport, the passenger can just place the thumb on the touchpad at an entry point and at other points inside the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohapatra added that AAI wants the passengers to have effortless and seamless travel experience at airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As everyone is aware that due to security reasons, a passenger in India has to show his or her identification card along with the tickets to enter the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has been trying to make Aadhaar as the sole identity card in the future a move that could possibly replace PAN, voter and ration cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an Aadhaar card is mandatory: Getting a passport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hassle-free passport services: Now, you can get a passport in just 10 days if you have an Aadhaar card. The government has announced that an Adhaar card or e-Aadhaar card can be used as proof of date of birth while applying for passports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income tax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is trying to file income tax returns needs to link their Aadhaar number with their PAN before July. If one fails to do so it will not be considered as a valid ITR filing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to provident fund&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Provident Fund Organisation has also made it compulsory for all pensioners and members to submit their Aadhaar card numbers. It is basically done for pensioners to avail hassle-free pension at the time of retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile connections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a department of telecom notification that was issued on Friday, the telecom operators have been directed to re-verify their existing subscribers — both prepaid and postpaid — through an Aadhaar-based eKYC process by February 6, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For free LPG connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre announced that Aadhaar card is now mandatory for women in the Below Poverty Line category applying for a free LPG connection. Applicants without the unique ID number have until May 31 to apply for it to avail the benefits under the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana, the ministry of petroleum and natural gas said in a notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway ticket booking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railways have also made plans to link Aadhaar with ticket booking. They have also held a discussion with UIDAI for linking Aadhaar number with the booking of a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a driving licence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has planned to make Aadhaar mandatory for seeking a new licence or renewal of your driving licence in a bid to ensure that there are no multiple driving licences under one name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the ‘Midday meal scheme’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry of human resource development announced that the mid-day meal would no longer be free for those children without an Aadhaar card. It was stated that children must be enrolled in the Aadhar scheme by June 30, if they were to get a free meal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Aadhaar With PAN Made Mandatory: How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the government insists that one&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar account and Permanent Account Number (PAN) should be linked by July 31 this year to pay income taxes, millions of Indians have faced issues with syncing the two accounts due to small differences in how their names are spelt. This problem can happen even if there are minor differences in how the name is recorded &amp;ndash; like the use of one&amp;rsquo;s full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar. Issues have also cropped up due to use of special characters in the initials and punctuation that often form a person&amp;rsquo;s name as Aadhaar doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize such characters but PAN does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, while one solution is to apply for a name correction in either Aadhaar or PAN card - both time consuming procedures - the government has stepped in to provide a simple solution for frustrated potential taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If an individual&amp;rsquo;s name on the Aadhaar does not match his/her name on the PAN card, the person can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A taxpayer can also log in to the Aadhaar website and request for a change in the name which will be verified using a one-time password on the phone number registered with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One-Time Passwords (OTP) will be used in cases where there are people who have gotten married and changed their surname. In such instances the tax department will give an OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number. The tax department, on its part, would&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department is also planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for OTP, provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told news agency Press Trust of India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.08 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN, but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people. As per statistics with the tax department, only six crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards to be linked with university degrees, certificates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-to-be-linked-with-university-degrees-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-to-be-linked-with-university-degrees-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The proposal is currently under consideration by the &lt;em&gt;ministry of human resource development (MHRD)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to prevent forgery of university degrees and certificates in future, the University Grants Commission (UGC) is planning to link the Aadhaar card number and print the student’s photograph on the degree/certificate from next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposal is currently under consideration by the ministry of human resource development (MHRD). If the proposal gets approved, the commission would issue directions to the universities and educational institutions for the same by next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After receiving fraud degree-related complaints, the MHRD had sought suggestions from the UGC to tackle this issue. So, in the beginning of this month, the commission suggested a proposal of printing the Aadhaar card number and photograph of the student mandatorily on the degrees,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the proposal, having an Aadhar card number will not only prevent forgery, but will also make it easier to store the degrees in a digital format in the National Academic Depositary (NAD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The students will then just have to mention their Aadhaar card number, after which they will be able to access the degree/certificate from anywhere. If the experiment is successful for the universities, then the same will be implemented for Class 10 and 12,” the source added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar may be made mandatory for all 84 DBT schemes: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-made-mandatory-84-dbt-schemes-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-made-mandatory-84-dbt-schemes-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far, furnishing the Aadhaar card has been made mandatory by the government for nearly 34-35 central schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furnishing the Aadhaar card has now been made mandatory by the government for nearly 34-35 central schemes, whether it is investing in the employee provident fund (EPF) or availing mid-day meals in schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report in the Economic Times today, this could soon extend to all 84 schemes so far under the Direct subsidy Benefit Transfer scheme. The 12 digit unique-identity number issued to Indian residents based on their biometric and demographic data, has helped the exchequer save nearly Rs 49,000 crore over the last couple of years in DBT under various schemes including LPG subsidy and helped more than 4.47 crore people open bank accounts through e-KYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the other schemes that are now covered under the mandatory Aadhaar are Sarv Shiksha Abhiyan meant to make elementary education universal, skill training programmes National Social Assistance Programme and Deendayal Antyodaya Yojana, National Action Plan for skill training of disabled and for disabled persons seeking aids and appliances, Swadhar Greh Scheme for rehabilitation of sexually exploited women, and LPG and foodgrains under the public distribution system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be required of NGOs seeking assistance for working on welfare of SCs, backward castes, alcoholics and old people. Residents who are yet to get their Aadhaar card made can do so until June 30. Enrolment facility will be made available by the department at convenient locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone wanting to avail benefits while Aadhaar is still under process, the enrolment slip can be used along with any one of the nine prescribed identity proof documents. However, according to a source, notifications from the department on the use of Aadhaar clearly states, “no person will be denied any benefit for want of Aadhaar if he needs the benefit in a time-bound manner or as an emergency measure”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>67% jump in corruption complaints; railways tops: Central Vigilance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/67-jump-in-corruption-complaints-railways-tops-cvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/67-jump-in-corruption-complaints-railways-tops-cvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Corruption complaints against various government departments jumped by a whopping 67 per cent in 2016 over the previous year, with the Railways topping the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 11,000 complaints were received against the public sector behemoth, the Central Vigilance Commission (CVC) has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its annual report tabled in Parliament recently, the probity watchdog said it received a total of 49,847 complaints in 2016, as against 29,838 in 2015 &amp;ndash; an increase of 67 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Commission received a considerable number of complaints against public servants working in the state governments and other organisations who do not come under the jurisdiction of the Commission or which are of administrative nature,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of complaints received by the CVC in 2015 were 50 per cent less than a total of 62,363 received by it in 2014. The CVC had got 31,432 and 37,039 complaints of alleged corruption during 2013 and 2012 respectively, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving details, the CVC said the highest of 11,200 such complaints were against railway employees. Of these 8,852 were disposed of and 2,348 were pending. Further, a total of 1,054 complaints against railway employees were pending for more than six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of complaints against those under government of National Capital Territory of Delhi has declined with a total of 969 received last year as against 5,139 in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many as 6,513 complaints of alleged corruption were received against employees under Home Ministry, followed by 6,018 bank officials and 2,496 related to those working with the Ministry of Petroleum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 2,646 corruption complaints were received against officials of the Income Tax department, 2,514 against those in Urban Development Ministry and 2,393 related to employees working under Telecommunication Ministry, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 1,746 corruption complaints against employees under Labour Ministry, 1,668 in Food and Consumer Affairs department, 1,420 of customs and excise, 1,376 in public sector insurance companies and 1,369 against officials of Ministry of Steel, the CVC said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 759 complaints were against Coal Ministry employees, 724 of Information and Broadcasting Ministry, 689 in Defence, 571 related to employees of Health and Family Welfare department and 479 against officials of Shipping Ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar authentication a must for engineering scholarships</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The state higher and technical education department has made authentication of Aadhaar number a must for backward engineering students to avail scholarships. The move comes against the backdrop of large-scale scholarship scam across the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though decision has been welcomed by city engineering colleges, they feel the authentication process will burden them with extra work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a gazette notification dated April 13, the department states that every student desirous of availing benefits under the schemes specified in Schedule ‘A’ need to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo authentication process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process involves submission of aadhaar number along with demographic information or biometrics of the beneficiary to the Central Indentities Data Repository for verification. The repository verifies the correctness of the claims on the basis of information available with it. The repository is a centralized database having all aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schemes listed in Schedule ‘A’ are Rajashri Chhatrapati Shahu Maharaj Shikshan Shulk Shishyavrutti Yojana and Dr Panjabrao Deshmukh Vastigruh Nirvah Bhatta Yojana. The scholarships are meant for other backward class (OBC) students and take care of certain percentage of tuition and hostel fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The directorate of technical education’s website, too, has alerted students to provide aadhaar authentication details otherwise their reimbursement would be put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification issued by deputy secretary Kiran Patil clarifies that students who do not have enrolled for Aadhaar can still available the scholarships on two conditions. The Aadhaar enrolment ID slip can be attached to their applications. In case they are not able to enrol due to non-availability of enrolment centres, they may write to the UIDAI’s designated field offices or register through its web portal and attach a copy of this request with the application. The students will also have to submit a proof of identity from one of the listed documents that included voter ID card, PAN, passport driving licence, bank passbook, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department has issued the guidelines under section 3 and 4 of the Maharashtra Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act 2016, that is stringent than the mother Act. As per the new Act, proof of possession of Aadhaar number or authentication is required in availing state government subsidy, benefits or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A city college principal said the aadhaar ID is itself foolproof and there was no need to add an extra authentication process. “A person’s biometric details can be viewed through Aadhaar number. Why principals should be asked to verify a student’s domicile. The social welfare department too had asked us to verify students’ income proof. This is the tehsildar or SDO’s job. They have only increased our work,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar-Based Authentication Is ‘Fully Safe And Secure’, Assures UIDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UIDAI dismissed the recently-reported breach as an isolated case, and added that their internal security system had picked up the attempted misuse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dismissing reports of misuse of biometrics data, the government on Sunday said Aadhaar-based authentication is “fully safe and secure”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, subsidy transfers linked to Aadhaar has led the exchequer to save ₹49,000 crore during the last two-and-half years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), there has been no incident of misuse of Aadhaar biometrics leading to identity theft and financial loss when more than 400 crore Aadhaar authenticated transactions took place during the last five years, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI also said that it has carefully gone through various reports and would like to emphasise that there has been no breach to UIDAI database of Aadhaar in any manner whatsoever and personal data of individuals held by UIDAI is fully safe and secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With reference to an incident of misuse of biometrics reported in a newspaper, UIDAI said that it is an isolated case of an employee working with a bank’s Business Correspondent’s company making an attempt to misuse his own biometrics which was detected by UIDAI internal security system and subsequently actions under the Aadhaar Act were initiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to media reports about on-boarding of the ecosystem partners, UIDAI said that the regulations under the Aadhaar Act strictly regulate the on-boarding, functioning including the data sharing restrictions imposed on the companies which want to use Aadhaar information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI further said that Aadhaar is an important tool of good governance and empowerment of people and has helped more than 4.47 crore people open bank accounts through Aadhaar e-KYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has enabled the government to do Direct Benefit Transfers under various schemes including LPG subsidy and has helped the exchequer save over ₹49,000 crore during the last two and half years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar-based Public Distributions System is benefiting people by ensuring that their food grain entitlement are given only to the deserving beneficiaries and are not cornered by unscrupulous and corrupt elements, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With reference to reports that there are no extant regulations available to prevent storage and misuse of e-KYC data, while citing instances like capturing IRIS from high resolution photograph, UIDAI said that there are stringent provisions in the Aadhaar (Authentication) Regulations governing the usage of e-KYC data including storage and sharing, resident consent being paramount in both the cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any unauthorised capture of IRIS or fingerprints or storage or replay of biometrics or their misuse is a criminal offence under the Aadhaar Act, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reports of misuse of e-KYC data by various agencies and allegations that the e-KYC API is available in public domain, UIDAI said that e-KYC APIs are available only to authorised Authentication User Agencies (AUAs) and e-KYC User Agencies (KUAs) through authorised Authentication Service agencies (ASAs) which have established secured network connectivity for the purpose of authentication with the Central Identities Data Repository (CIDR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authorisation is in compliance with the Regulations, specifications, standards and technology architecture as prescribed, it said, adding, any violation would lead to penal action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statement said that news reports also speak of private agencies hired by mobile operators and banks for e-KYC leading to availability of these data in parallel database and the vulnerabilities in the scenario where there is no privacy law in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this regard, the authority pointed out that “Aadhaar authentication or e-KYC is only available to authorised agencies whose appointment, responsibilities, statutory obligations, penal provisions for contraventions are clearly provided for in the Aadhaar Act and the regulations framed thereunder.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks or mobile operators have to become UIDAI’s AUA/ASAs to obtain e-KYC data of their customers from UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-KYC data can be given by UIDAI to these agencies only after they obtain consent of their customers and can be used only for the purpose for which it was obtained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing an example, it said, a telecom operator can obtain the e-KYC data of its subscribers and will keep them in their records without biometrics and use them only for the purpose of proving telecom services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, a bank, after obtaining the e-KYC information of its account holders, will keep the information without their biometrics within the bank and will use it only for the purpose of providing banking services and cannot use it for any other purpose without obtaining consent of the customer, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI uses one of world’s most advanced encryption technologies in transmission and storage of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, it said, that during the last 7 seven years, there has been no report of breach or leak of residents’ data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authority is continuously updating its security parameters looking at the new threats in cyber space, the statement said, adding, it also undertakes security audits and ensures necessary steps to augment security features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI has decided to have registered devices for capturing biometrics data and such biometrics will be encrypted at the point of capture itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016: Driving sans licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very soon, you can do “iris” Aadhaar authentication from your smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheap in-built iris scanners will eradicate use of costly ones for mass adoption of Aadhaar verification.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID Inc., a consumer-grade iris scanning technology provider for mobile phones, proposed the introduction of iris integrated mobile phones as a cost-effective way of reducing the failure rates in Aadhaar biometric authentication, as recently reported in MGNREGA tests in Telangana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe iris integrated smartphones and tablets will address the issues reported with Aadhaar biometric authentication. The UIDAI and the worldwide biometric community have tested and found iris to have better reliability. We are confident the failure rates will be drastically lower once the cheaper iris integrated mobile devices are adopted in the market,” said Dr. Salil Prabhakar, President and CEO, Delta ID Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the government mandating the use of Aadhaar biometric authentication in more spheres of the society, the need for a biometric modality that works reliably is critical. Unlike fingerprints that are being reported to show high failure rates due to wear and tear, the iris, being a protected internal organ, is expected to be significantly more reliable. Additionally, since the iris is not affected with age, it works reliably across all age groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key impediments in the large-scale roll out of iris for Aadhaar has been the high cost of iris devices. This is being addressed with the rollout of iris integrated mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this regard, Samsung partnered with Delta ID to launch India’s first iris integrated tablet in May 2016. The technology is arriving in smartphones too, and not only in high end devices such as Samsung Galaxy S8, but also in low cost smartphones developed by Indian manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID’s ActiveIRIS technology passed the Standardisation Testing and Quality Certification’s (STQC) FRR test with better than 99 percent accuracy, and has been certified by the STQC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active IRIS and a combination of STQC-certified hardware components can be integrated by any mobile device to expeditiously introduce iris integrated mobile devices in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>