<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hacker can access your information via a UPI-based app</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/startup-identified-291-ways-hacker-can-access-information-via-upi-based-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/startup-identified-291-ways-hacker-can-access-information-via-upi-based-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As digitisation picks up steam with Indians expected to transact Rs 4 crore digitally every day this year, privacy of their data has become a paramount concern. The government is caught between encouraging digitisation and ensuring secure platforms. This is where startups like Appknox come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specialising in mobile apps security, Appknox recently identified 291 critical vulnerabilities (181 were accorded the status of high ctitical vulnerabilities) in Unified Payments Interface (UPI) based mobile applications developed by banks and other fintech companies. These vulnerabilities had the potential of exposing a user’s entire bank details to the eyes of any hacker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There were issues where we could bypass the entire security gamut and get access to user’s bank account details and even download those details easily. We found hackers can easily manipulate these loopholes to misuse the data,” says Appknox cofounder and CEO, Harshit Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team at Appknox, driven by Agarwal and cofounders Subho Halder and Prateek Panda was hired by NPCI in July 2016 and has been scanning UPI-based apps since November. These apps, developed and launched by banks and other fintech companies, have already seen heavy downloads and have lakhs of users transacting online.
The team found 181 high, 83 medium and 27 low critical vulnerabilities in the 35 plus apps evaluated by it. The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) then advised the banks to quickly work on the suggestions provided by Appknox in order to negate these threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other threats, the team was particularly concerned about basic security steps which the hackers at Appknox were easily able to contravene. The login password step was easily bypassed by the team in a number of UPI-based apps which could lead any hacker directly into a user’s account and access that user’s information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of apps depend on OTP (One Time Password) system to provide an extra layer of security to its users. The team shares it was able to easily brute force its way to login into a user’s account.
Given these apps were developed by banks which are considered the safest mode financial platforms, the team was surprised at the ease with which it was able to hack into the apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These banks have internal audits and we expected their apps to be pretty secure. Banks are the most important sector in fintech sector and have to be pretty ahead of the curve of security. Thus, we were surprised at how easily we could find loopholes in these apps. Whatever these banks are doing is not enough for mobile app security,” said Agarwal.
While banks are still the most secure way of transferring money digitally when it comes to platforms like NEFT however, mobile apps, shares Agarwal, are a different ball game altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mobiles can be hacked in very different ways and the internal team at these banking institutions is not that great with mobile apps. The whole security landscape is very different when it comes to mobiles,” says Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A worrying statement indeed when the financial transactions are increasingly moving from websites to mobile apps with the proliferation of e-wallets and other payments systems.
Several mobile apps have sprung in the last couple of years providing users with ease of transacting online however, to prevent this ease from metamorphosing into a security disaster, the government is working keenly on regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The government is getting very strict when it comes to security. The central government recently made empanelment mandatory for any mobile app in bank payment gateway. Regulators have been proactive in ensuring that companies follow certain standards,” shares Agarwal.
NPCI, shares Agarwal, was quick to get banks to plug the loopholes found by the team at Appknox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about their experience with Appknox NPCI, Head of Risk Management, Bharat Panchal, said in a statement, “Appknox has been a crucial partner with us to ensure utmost security of our UPI-based application. We have had good early detection of vulnerabilities with the help of very energetic and brilliant security professionals. ”
The threat however, is persistent and transformative and both the government and the fintech institutions would need all the help they can find to keep hackers from digging into sensitive user information and thereby, to drive its digitisation push further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a never-ending race where hackers look for more loopholes and banking companies innovate to keep ahead. The problem is that banks and other fintech institutions rely on a single vendor for all their security concerns. What they do not realise is that there could be many brains working to break the system and relying on a single brain for security is really dangerous,” says Agarwal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appknox specialises in providing security to mobile apps and currently services 100 plus companies in the fintech sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM gives E-Wallets a run for money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-gives-e-wallets-run-money/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BHIM — or the Bharat Interface For Money — is quickly becoming the favoured mobile payment solution for crores of Indians. Since its launch on December 31 till the end of February, the app had been downloaded 17 million times. Following its Android launch, BHIM is now also available on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is an extension of the Unified Payment System. It allows users to send and receive money through a mobile app that is linked to their bank savings account. This is an elegant solution compared to e-wallets that need to maintain a cash balance in order to be functional. Naturally, the question then arises: Should users switch to BHIM and simply spend from their banks, and stop using e-wallets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences between BHIM and e-wallets, and we’ll examine them here in order to help you understand the pros and cons of both ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bhim-vs-wallets-where-bhim-wins&#34;&gt;BHIM vs Wallets: Where BHIM Wins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Balance, loading &amp;amp; unloading:&lt;/em&gt; The first major difference between BHIM and UPI apps and e-wallets is how you maintain your spending balance. BHIM and UPI apps allow you to send and receive money with your bank account. You do not have to maintain a balance with the app. The app is your bank account, in a sense. But in e-wallets, you must maintain a balance in order to spend from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just that, returning your wallet balance back to your bank account will come with limitations and charges. But with BHIM and UPI, there is no need to send the money back from the app to the bank, since the money has been sitting in your account all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/em&gt; Another aspect where BHIM and UPI apps trump e-wallets. E-wallets do not have interoperability, meaning that if you are using Wallet X, you can only transfer money to another user on Wallet X, and not to a user operating Wallet Y. This isn’t a problem with BHIM, since you may move money between accounts with any bank on the BHIM platform. For example, you may be using an SBI account but you can send and receive money from users on ICICI or HDFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spending limits:&lt;/em&gt; BHIM and UPI score heavily here as well. E-wallets have a monthly spending limit of Rs 10,000 which can be raised to Rs 100,000 after the KYC process wherein users need to submit proof of ID and address in order to become authenticated. But BHIM allows a limit of Rs 10,000 per transaction and Rs 20,000 as the total worth of transactions in a 24-hour cycle. UPI apps go further, allowing you to spend up to Rs 100,000 per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-bhim-lags&#34;&gt;Where BHIM Lags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly two areas where e-wallets have an edge over UPI and BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marketing gimmicks:&lt;/em&gt; E-wallets have been around for a few years and they have had the time to build relationships with merchants and businesses. As a result, e-wallets are useful not just for money transfers but also for earning cashbacks and discounts. Not just that, some e-wallets also operate as e-commerce platforms allowing users to buy merchandise, electronics, tickets, etc. UPI and BHIM, on the other hand, are recent innovations and have some catching up to do in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit usage:* E-wallets allow you to link and spend from your credit card, allowing you to leverage the power of the credit available to you. BHIM works on simpler principles: you get to spend only if you have a bank balance, and you cannot link BHIM and UPI apps to your credit card account yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-bhim-is-catching-up&#34;&gt;How BHIM Is Catching Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest Union Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced a referral bonus and cashback scheme for BHIM users. “The government will launch two new schemes — a referral bonus for consumers and a cash-back scheme for merchants — to promote the use of BHIM,” Jaitley said during his budget speech. With these inclusions, BHIM will become a little more attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
Both e-wallets and UPI-based apps such as BHIM have a long way to go and a big role to play in India where internet penetration and smartphone usage are increasing by leaps and bounds every year. Both need to evolve in order to accommodate the changing needs of the Indian consumer in an increasingly less cash-dependent economy. However, at this point, you may want to have both BHIM and e-wallets installed on your smartphones. They both have some unique services to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: BSNL Offers 2GB Data Per Day On Rs 339 Recharge</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-2gb-data-per-day-on-rs-339-recharge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-2gb-data-per-day-on-rs-339-recharge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analysts say incumbent telecom operators are coming up with attractive calling plans and lucrative data packs to counter additional competition triggered by Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry in the market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL is offering 2GB of 3G data per day and unlimited voice calling within its network under a special scheme priced at Rs 339. The &amp;ldquo;Combo STV&amp;rdquo; plan by state-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited or BSNL - for its prepaid customers - comes with a validity of 28 days, the telecom operator said in a statement. Analysts say incumbent telecom operators are coming up with attractive calling plans and lucrative data packs to counter additional competition triggered by Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSNL is offering 2GB of 3G data per day under a special recharge plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plan also offers unlimited voice calls on BSNL network&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telcos in India are giving attractive plans after Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special offer under its prepaid mobile services is in effect from March 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) The offer is limited for 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The &amp;ldquo;unlimited data&amp;rdquo; on offer will come with a &amp;ldquo;fair use policy&amp;rdquo; of 2 GB per day with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) BSNL is offering unlimited voice calls within its network. Calls outside the BSNL network will be for 25 minutes per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) After exhausting the 25-minute limit, the customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) &amp;ldquo;The data of 2GB per day is one of the best in the industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL added in its statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) &amp;ldquo;We are committed to providing affordable and efficient services to all segments of our loyal mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL director for consumer mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Religare analysts Rumit Dugar and Saumya Shrivastava believe the market could remain competitive for an extended period considering Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive revenue market share expectations. (Also read: 28 GB data for Rs 345: Airtel&amp;rsquo;s latest offer to counter Jio)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Reliance Industries&amp;rsquo; telecom arm - Reliance Jio Infocomm - is offering 1GB of 4G data per day and unlimited calling to all networks for free till March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) From April 1, Jio customers opting for its Prime service will continue to enjoy the unlimited calls and data benefits under its New Year Offer for a full year, till March 31, 2018. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime subscription will come at a one-time enrolment fee of Rs. 99 and &amp;ldquo;a rock-bottom introductory price” of only Rs 10 per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF (Provident Fund) Money Withdrawal: Here Are Five Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-provident-fund-money-withdrawal-here-are-five-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-provident-fund-money-withdrawal-here-are-five-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per PF rules, 12% of an employee&amp;rsquo;s salary goes into the fund along with a matching contribution from the employer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provident fund (PF) is meant for saving towards retirement years. Financial planners don&amp;rsquo;t advise withdrawal from the corpus before retirement. According to provident fund norms, 12 per cent of an employee&amp;rsquo;s salary goes into the fund along with a matching contribution from the employer. The EPFO (Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation) every year announces interest rate to be paid on the accumulated provident fund corpus. The PF money can be withdrawn after two months from the cessation of employment. The application form in this regard can be filed with PF authorities, or through the employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) To encourage long-term savings, the government has formulated tax laws accordingly. If the withdrawal from a recognised PF happens after five years of continuous employment, it attracts no tax liability. In case of employment with different employers, if the PF balance maintained with the old employer is transferred to the PF account of the new employer, it is considered a continuous employment. (Also read: I Want To Save Enough Money For Retirement. Is PF Contribution Enough?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an employee has been terminated because of certain reasons beyond his or her control (such as ill health and discontinuation of business of employer), a withdrawal does not attract any tax, irrespective of the number of years of employment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) In case of a withdrawal before five years, the amount becomes taxable in the same financial year. Thus, the amount has to be shown in your tax return for the next assessment year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The employer&amp;rsquo;s contribution to PF and interest earned on it is added to one&amp;rsquo;s income and taxed accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In addition, if you have claimed benefits under Section 80C on your own PF contribution, it will be taxed as salary. The interest earned on your own contribution will be taxed as &amp;lsquo;income from other sources&amp;rsquo; and taxed according to the respective tax slabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) TDS (tax deducted at source) - If the withdrawal is after a period of five years of continuous employment, it attracts no TDS or any tax. What happens if the period of service is less than five years? If PAN has not been submitted to the EPFO authorities, TDS is deducted at 30 per cent. If PAN has been submitted along with Form 15G/15H, no TDS is deducted. If form 15G/15H is not submitted and PAN is submitted, TDS @ 10% is deducted. Form 15H or 15G is meant to prevent TDS for those whose income falls below the taxable limit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pensioners told to apply for Aadhaar card to receive pension</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pensioners-told-apply-aadhaar-card-receive-pension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pensioners-told-apply-aadhaar-card-receive-pension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ministry has issued a notification making Aadhaar mandatory for pensioners to receive pension. The pensioners number approximately 25 lakh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To receive a pension, the Union Defence Ministry in its notification stated all defence pensioners and family members of a deceased personnel ‘will be required to enrol for Aadhar card latest by June 30 to receive pension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry has issued a notification making Aadhaar mandatory for pensioners to receive pension. The pensioners number approximately is 25 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any pensioner eligible to receive benefits and who hasn’t enrolled for Aadhaar, but wants to avail pension is required to apply for Aadhaar by June 30,” read the notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also stated that the ministry through agencies or other means is required to offer Aadhaar enrollment facilities for beneficiaries who have not yet applied for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The order stated the Defence Ministry through such agencies will be required to provide Aadhaar enrolment facilities in places where such facilities aren’t available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till the time Aadhaar card is not given, beneficiaries shall get on producing the ex-servicemen card. A copy of his or her request made for Aadhaar enrolment can be submitted along with a copy of Voter ID card or PAN Card or Passport among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification said Defence Ministry through related agencies should make arrangements to provide hassle-free pension benefits to the beneficiaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wide publicity through media and through other sources should be given and individual notices shall be handed over to pensioners to make them aware of the Aadhaar requirement under the scheme, it added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Pay launch by month-end</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-launch-month-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-launch-month-end/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Centre has asked all banks to launch Aadhaar Pay, which will facilitate financial transactions by using fingerprints, by the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All banks will also have to enable ‘Pay to Aadhaar’ facility on the BHIM app by March 31 with SBI and Punjab National Bank asked to provide the facility by the end of the week. This feature on BHIM will help in making payments by simply entering the 12-digit Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The twin moves, which will make digital transactions easier, will encourage the use of online payments among the poor and illiterate in rural areas. The government has nudged banks to expedite seeding of Aadhaar numbers and also mobile numbers which are key to accelerate the big initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts believe that Aadhaar Pay, which is the merchant version of the already in use Aadhaar-enabled payment system (AEPS), will become an alternative for all online and card transactions which require password and PIN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app allows merchants to take cashless payments from a customer who is only required to give his Aadhaar number, name of the bank (from where the money is to be deducted) and fingerprint for authentication. To use this service, the customer has to first link his/her bank account to the Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay works on any android-based phone, even a low cost one, with an attached finger biometric device. A top government official said banks have been directed to take merchants on board for using BHIM, fitted with ‘Pay to Aadhaar’ feature and Aadhaar Pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another official said that banks have been asked to speed up deployment of normal PoS (point of sale)machines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No One Will Be Deprived Of Benefits For Lack Of Aadhaar: Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-one-will-be-deprived-of-benefits-for-lack-of-aadhaar-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-one-will-be-deprived-of-benefits-for-lack-of-aadhaar-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar has so far been given to more than 112 crore people in the country.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citizens can avail all the benefits of government schemes on alternate means of identification till the time they get their Aadhaar number, the government said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No one will be deprived of the benefits for lack of Aadhaar&amp;hellip; Till Aadhaar number is assigned to any individual, the benefit will continue to be given based on alternate means of identification,&amp;rdquo; according to a statement issued by the Cabinet Secretariat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar has so far been given to more than 112 crore people in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In case of Mid-Day Meal scheme and under the Integrated Child Development Scheme, the schools and Anganwadis have been asked to collect the Aadhaar number of the children beneficiaries and in case a child does not have Aadhaar, the school or ICDS functionary will be required to provide enrolment facilities to a child and till Aadhaar number is assigned, the benefits will continue,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the usefulness of Aadhaar in curbing leakages and bringing transparency in delivery system, the government has recently issued orders to use Aadhaar in several other welfare schemes funded from the Consolidated Fund of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While these orders require beneficiaries of these programmes to give their Aadhaar number, it has also been ensured that no one is deprived of the benefits for want of Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total savings by plugging leakages on account of Aadhaar introduction during the last two-and-a-half years in just a few schemes amount to over Rs 49,000 crore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Enabled Payment System (AEPS) saw 2.65M transactions in January</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-aeps-saw-2-65m-transactions-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-aeps-saw-2-65m-transactions-january/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of financial transactions of the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System (AEPS) for the month of January 2017 stood at 2.65 million and the value of these transactions stood at Rs 316 crore, National Payments Corporation of India data showed. In December 2016, the number of financial transactions on the AEPS stood at 1.97 million with a value of Rs 207 crore. Financial transactions include cash withdrawal and cash deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of transactions on the payment system grew sharply following the demonetization of Rs 500 and Rs 1000 notes.  To give context, the volume of transactions on the AEPS for the financial year 2015-16 was 0.36 million with the value of transactions at Rs 86 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that in January government had claimed that “more than 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through AEPS, which was only 46 lakhs in May 2014.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AEPS is a financial inclusion product developed by the NPCI which allows cash withdrawal, deposit and funds transfer at POS (Micro ATM) through a business correspondent of any bank using the Aadhaar authentication. So far, there are 119 banks on the AEPS. Most recently, Spice Money, the domestic remittance service from Spice Digital, got permission from the NPCI to process payments over the AEPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AEPS also allows a number of non-financial transactions such as balance enquiry and mini statements. For January 2017, the number stood at 1.6 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reminder: So far there are three other payment infrastructures which are linked or will be liked to the Aadhaar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– First is the Unified Payments Interface (UPI). Although the UPI currently only maps a bank account to the registered mobile number. The second version of the UPI is supposed to have Aadhaar integration by March 2017. Note that the draft paper for the UPI had detailed out that it would be using     the Aadhaar to map out financial addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Second is the Aadhaar Pay. The government launched the Aadhaar Pay in January. Customers can pay using their bank account linked with Aadhaar. To process payments, the customers will need to provide their Aadhaar number to the merchant and authorize payment through their fingerprint. The solution requires a biometric device to be linked to merchant’s mobile phone for payment authentication but customers do not need the phone at all. Currently, 14 banks have signed up for Aadhaar Pay as indicated by this Economic Times report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– The third is the Aadhaar Payments Bridge System (APBS) which is responsible for direct benefit transfer of subsidies by the government. Subsidies will be transferred to bank accounts linked to Aadhaar. The total number of transactions on the APBS were logged in 167.36 crore worth Rs 44,967 crore which has risen by ten folds in value since 31st May 2014 ( 7 crore transactions, worth Rs 4000 crores ).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar may be made mandatory for all 84 DBT schemes: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-made-mandatory-84-dbt-schemes-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-may-made-mandatory-84-dbt-schemes-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far, furnishing the Aadhaar card has been made mandatory by the government for nearly 34-35 central schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furnishing the Aadhaar card has now been made mandatory by the government for nearly 34-35 central schemes, whether it is investing in the employee provident fund (EPF) or availing mid-day meals in schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report in the Economic Times today, this could soon extend to all 84 schemes so far under the Direct subsidy Benefit Transfer scheme. The 12 digit unique-identity number issued to Indian residents based on their biometric and demographic data, has helped the exchequer save nearly Rs 49,000 crore over the last couple of years in DBT under various schemes including LPG subsidy and helped more than 4.47 crore people open bank accounts through e-KYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the other schemes that are now covered under the mandatory Aadhaar are Sarv Shiksha Abhiyan meant to make elementary education universal, skill training programmes National Social Assistance Programme and Deendayal Antyodaya Yojana, National Action Plan for skill training of disabled and for disabled persons seeking aids and appliances, Swadhar Greh Scheme for rehabilitation of sexually exploited women, and LPG and foodgrains under the public distribution system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar will also be required of NGOs seeking assistance for working on welfare of SCs, backward castes, alcoholics and old people. Residents who are yet to get their Aadhaar card made can do so until June 30. Enrolment facility will be made available by the department at convenient locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone wanting to avail benefits while Aadhaar is still under process, the enrolment slip can be used along with any one of the nine prescribed identity proof documents. However, according to a source, notifications from the department on the use of Aadhaar clearly states, “no person will be denied any benefit for want of Aadhaar if he needs the benefit in a time-bound manner or as an emergency measure”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar-Based Authentication Is ‘Fully Safe And Secure’, Assures UIDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-authentication-fully-safe-secure-assures-uidai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UIDAI dismissed the recently-reported breach as an isolated case, and added that their internal security system had picked up the attempted misuse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dismissing reports of misuse of biometrics data, the government on Sunday said Aadhaar-based authentication is “fully safe and secure”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, subsidy transfers linked to Aadhaar has led the exchequer to save ₹49,000 crore during the last two-and-half years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), there has been no incident of misuse of Aadhaar biometrics leading to identity theft and financial loss when more than 400 crore Aadhaar authenticated transactions took place during the last five years, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI also said that it has carefully gone through various reports and would like to emphasise that there has been no breach to UIDAI database of Aadhaar in any manner whatsoever and personal data of individuals held by UIDAI is fully safe and secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With reference to an incident of misuse of biometrics reported in a newspaper, UIDAI said that it is an isolated case of an employee working with a bank’s Business Correspondent’s company making an attempt to misuse his own biometrics which was detected by UIDAI internal security system and subsequently actions under the Aadhaar Act were initiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to media reports about on-boarding of the ecosystem partners, UIDAI said that the regulations under the Aadhaar Act strictly regulate the on-boarding, functioning including the data sharing restrictions imposed on the companies which want to use Aadhaar information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI further said that Aadhaar is an important tool of good governance and empowerment of people and has helped more than 4.47 crore people open bank accounts through Aadhaar e-KYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has enabled the government to do Direct Benefit Transfers under various schemes including LPG subsidy and has helped the exchequer save over ₹49,000 crore during the last two and half years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar-based Public Distributions System is benefiting people by ensuring that their food grain entitlement are given only to the deserving beneficiaries and are not cornered by unscrupulous and corrupt elements, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With reference to reports that there are no extant regulations available to prevent storage and misuse of e-KYC data, while citing instances like capturing IRIS from high resolution photograph, UIDAI said that there are stringent provisions in the Aadhaar (Authentication) Regulations governing the usage of e-KYC data including storage and sharing, resident consent being paramount in both the cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any unauthorised capture of IRIS or fingerprints or storage or replay of biometrics or their misuse is a criminal offence under the Aadhaar Act, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reports of misuse of e-KYC data by various agencies and allegations that the e-KYC API is available in public domain, UIDAI said that e-KYC APIs are available only to authorised Authentication User Agencies (AUAs) and e-KYC User Agencies (KUAs) through authorised Authentication Service agencies (ASAs) which have established secured network connectivity for the purpose of authentication with the Central Identities Data Repository (CIDR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authorisation is in compliance with the Regulations, specifications, standards and technology architecture as prescribed, it said, adding, any violation would lead to penal action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statement said that news reports also speak of private agencies hired by mobile operators and banks for e-KYC leading to availability of these data in parallel database and the vulnerabilities in the scenario where there is no privacy law in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this regard, the authority pointed out that “Aadhaar authentication or e-KYC is only available to authorised agencies whose appointment, responsibilities, statutory obligations, penal provisions for contraventions are clearly provided for in the Aadhaar Act and the regulations framed thereunder.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks or mobile operators have to become UIDAI’s AUA/ASAs to obtain e-KYC data of their customers from UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-KYC data can be given by UIDAI to these agencies only after they obtain consent of their customers and can be used only for the purpose for which it was obtained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing an example, it said, a telecom operator can obtain the e-KYC data of its subscribers and will keep them in their records without biometrics and use them only for the purpose of proving telecom services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, a bank, after obtaining the e-KYC information of its account holders, will keep the information without their biometrics within the bank and will use it only for the purpose of providing banking services and cannot use it for any other purpose without obtaining consent of the customer, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI uses one of world’s most advanced encryption technologies in transmission and storage of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, it said, that during the last 7 seven years, there has been no report of breach or leak of residents’ data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authority is continuously updating its security parameters looking at the new threats in cyber space, the statement said, adding, it also undertakes security audits and ensures necessary steps to augment security features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI has decided to have registered devices for capturing biometrics data and such biometrics will be encrypted at the point of capture itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Database Safe, Verification Process Was Misused, Say Authorities</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-database-safe-verification-process-misused-say-authorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-database-safe-verification-process-misused-say-authorities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the Centre expands the list of government services that would require beneficiaries to have an Aadhaar number, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) on Tuesday insisted that its biometrics database of a billion people was safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reassurance comes against the backdrop of the authority suspending Aadhaar authentication services of Axis Bank after a business correspondent sent a large number of authentication requests to the UIDAI; in each case the fingerprint was exactly the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While UIDAI says the authority is yet to get the probe report, an official said this indicated at the possibility that someone was sending a stored version of the fingerprint. The unusual activity was flagged by the UIDAI’s security system and a complaint registered with Delhi Police’s cyber cell for breach of its regulations, a UIDAI official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from Axis bank, the complaint had also named its business correspondent Suvidhaa Infoserve and e-sign provider eMudhra, which has denied that it saved any biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aadhaar law does not allow anyone to store biometrics taken by anyone for authentication by UIDAI, or send a stored version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A top UIDAI official said this was an instance of misuse of Aadhaar authentication by a private party, not a breach. “There hasn’t been a breach of any biometric data… which is not shared anybody under any circumstances,” the official said, pointing that was barred from sharing the data under the law enacted parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2016 law also empowered the government to list government services that can be provided to people if they have an Aadhaar number, or have enrolled for one. Over the last few weeks, the government has mandated that people who produce the number for getting subsidised rations, scholarship for students or benefits at Anganwadi, the government-funded child-care and mother-care programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since September 2010 when the first Aadhaar number was issued to a woman in Maharashtra’s Nandurbag district, UIDAI has issued the 12-digit identity number – that is key to the government’s thrust on cashless transactions and direct benefit transfer programmes – to 112 crore people. The authority has so far authenticated 490 crore transactions, an average of four transactions for every number issued.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not mandatory for withdrawals under EPS, says EPFO</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-withdrawals-eps-says-epfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-withdrawals-eps-says-epfo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rolling back its earlier decision, retirement fund body EPFO on Tuesday said Aadhaar was no longer mandatory for withdrawal claims under EPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…It has been decided that obtaining of Aadhaar should be mandatory for the time being only for pension (10D claims) and not in withdrawal cases (Form 10C),” said a circular issued to all zonal offices on February 27, by the Employees’ Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Form 10C is used for withdrawal benefits, employer share refunds and scheme certificates before completion of 10 years in service, while form 10D is for withdrawal of pension after superannuation, widow/orphan/disability pension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, the retirement fund body had extended the deadline for submitting Aadhaar till March 31, extending its earlier deadline of February 28. In its January 4 notification, the Labour Ministry had made it mandatory for 4 crore PF subscribers and 50 lakh pensioners of the Employees Pension Scheme (EPS) to furnish proof of possession of the Aadhaar number or undergo Aadhaar authentication, as per procedures laid down by EPFO, to avail of benefits under EPFO schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its February 27 circular, EPFO said: “It has been brought to notice that with the present instructions on mandatory obtaining Aadhaar No. for settlement of pension cases, it is not possible to sanction withdrawal benefit claims in Form10C also if Aadhaar No. is not furnished. This has led to issues in settlement in withdrawals,” adding that after examining the matter, it had decided that Aadhaar was no longer required for withdrawal of claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO, however, urged all zonal offices to expedite linking of Aadhaar for pensioners under EPS 1995 “at the earliest.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, EPFO introduced a single-page form to submit claims with self-attestation and without employer attestation. Earlier, subscribers who had seeded Aadhaar and bank account details to their Universal Account Number (UAN) without employer attestation had to fill claims in Forms No. 19 (UAN), 10C (UAN) &amp;amp; 31(UAN). For subscribers yet to seed Aadhaar and bank details with their UAN, another single form has been introduced to replace forms No. 19, 10C &amp;amp; 31.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Post Payments Bank will keep operations simple: CEO Ashok Singh</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-post-payments-bank-will-keep-operations-simple-ceo-ashok-singh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-post-payments-bank-will-keep-operations-simple-ceo-ashok-singh/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India Post Payments Bank CEO Ashok Pal Singh says the bank will focus on mutual funds, pure life insurance products and small loans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India Post Payments Bank Ltd’s managing director and chief executive officer Ashok Pal Singh wants to keep it simple. The bank will offer payment solutions for recurring transactions, index funds, term plans and small loans. The bank will provide only index funds in the mutual fund space to avoid misselling. In insurance, the bank will sell term plans but not endowment plans. Edited excerpts from an interview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-is-your-target-customer-how-do-you-plan-to-roll-out-business-across-the-country&#34;&gt;Who is your target customer? How do you plan to roll out business across the country?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are targeting three segments with a bottom-up approach. The first is the 250 million people who don’t have mobile phones and are typically the DBT (direct benefits transfer) beneficiaries. The second is the middle layer, the 500 million people who have feature phones. In terms of products, the focus will be on recurring expenditure such as school fees, electricity bills, phone bills, healthcare expenditure and conveyance. If you look at state transport corporations, the transactions are all cash-based. We want to introduce electronic payment in remittances. We are also targeting “unreserved” railway ticketing. The third segment is the 250 million smartphone users. We will simplify a lot of payments which are common for both smartphone as well as feature phone users. Additionally, we plan to offer very simple third-party products such as life insurance, equity products and credit largely based on smart analytics. That is how we plan to cover the entire spectrum. The focus will be on payment solutions and not on banking solutions. Every household has a bank account. The way the regulator has structured the business of a payments bank is that there is no skin in float. So we are going to make a living out of transactions. Within this space, our private sector competitors will be looking at all kinds of applications in the private sector. We will typically focus on the government and public sector undertakings space where we have natural affinity in terms of being an acceptable payment service provider. We have a commitment that by September-end access points in post offices across the country should go live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-kind-of-third-party-products-do-you-plan-to-offer-how-will-you-ensure-there-is-no-misselling-will-you-have-exclusive-partners-for-third-party-products&#34;&gt;What kind of third-party products do you plan to offer? How will you ensure there is no misselling? Will you have exclusive partners for third-party products?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would largely look at mutual funds. Within mutual funds, probably just index funds because I don’t have a sophisticated sales force. Also, I don’t think I have a sophisticated customer and we don’t want to missell. We will go to the market and make initial forays with standard and simple products. In insurance, we are interested only in pure life term insurance and nothing else. Life insurance companies’ core competence is insuring and not necessarily investments. In terms of making a correct sell, it is very simple for me to deal with my customers and tell “look, what we are proposing is a life cover: nothing less, nothing more”. For everything that we do, there are two non-negotiables: one is competition and other is choice. If we are going to take on any service, including a third-party product, it has to be on competitive basis. And my customers will always get a choice. We will deal with organizations on a non-exclusive basis. I will do some simple standardizations For instance, in case of life insurance, it will be group insurance because that is where I can negotiate the best rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-kind-of-loan-products-will-you-offer&#34;&gt;What kind of loan products will you offer?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit will take some time because an analytics engine has to be put in place based on transaction history of our customers. We will have to work with a third party for a format to offer instant unsecured loans. We will be looking at small-ticket loans. For instance, if an account holder comes to the post office and needs a Rs20,000 loan, we should be able to given him this at a click of a button. I should be able to tell him these are the five providers who are willing to offer it with terms and conditions. We will simplify and standardize it. The guy can take a pick, we disburse it and take a mandate for EMI (equated monthly instalment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;you-have-partnered-with-punjab-national-bank-how-will-this-help-you&#34;&gt;You have partnered with Punjab National Bank. How will this help you?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Punjab National Bank is helping us on interim technology solutions. We will be happy to dispense their products within the framework that we intend to operate. Everything is on a non-exclusive basis. Nobody has a head-start and nobody is a laggard. When I say interim technology, a standard CBS (core banking solution) is not really designed for high volume payment transactions. We are just using Punjab National Bank’s platform to test the technology with our kind of customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;compared-to-airtel-payments-bank-you-offer-a-lower-interest-rate-on-savings-deposit&#34;&gt;Compared to Airtel Payments Bank, you offer a lower interest rate on savings deposit.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only largely invest in government securities. Currently they give you about 6.1% before tax. I am not in a position to give anything higher than that for sure. Any economics beyond that does beat us but we don’t levy transaction charges on our customers for deposits. Charges are for door-to-door transactions. Other payments banks are taking a transaction fee. Ultimately, no corporate pays from its pocket. There are no free lunches. Either you levy an upfront charge or you do it on whatever other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-do-plan-to-train-your-employees-to-provide-digital-services&#34;&gt;How do plan to train your employees to provide digital services?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am afraid that they can’t do anything complicated. And that is why I intend to use Aadhaar (the unique ID dispensed by the Unique Identification Authority of India). Biometrics enabled transaction is the only thing that will work. I just have to keep it simple which is also an operational necessity. Simplicity hurts no one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-you-plan-to-tie-up-with-fintech-companies-for-payment-solutions&#34;&gt;Do you plan to tie up with fintech companies for payment solutions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we will have to reach out to fin-tech companies while having sufficiently enabled in-house ability to deal with technology. The plan is to use open systems, APIs (application protocol interfaces; essentially bits of software that can fit right into larger programs), developing apps with the help of trusted partners and developers and opening the payments space for whoever needs it. We don’t need a lot of partners but (need) the right one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt says Aadhaar a must for labourers to avail benefits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-says-aadhaar-must-labourers-avail-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-says-aadhaar-must-labourers-avail-benefits/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;labour department has made Aadhaar card and self declaration form compulsory for the labourers at the time of registration to avail benefits under Building and Other Construction Workers (BOCW) Board schemes.The move is aimed to check duplicity and prevent dual distribution of benefits among beneficiaries. The decision was taken in a recent meeting held this month at Chandigarh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting was chaired by labour commissioner Tajinder Singh Dhaliwal and a direction regarding the same was issued to all the assistant labour commissioners (ALC) across the state on Friday. As per the directions, the labour commissioners have been asked to mention Aadhaar card details of the beneficiary and family members along with a self-declaration form mentioning that other family members of the beneficiary will not take benefits of labour schemes after him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is aimed to check duplicity and prevent dual distribution of benefits among beneficiaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision was taken in a recent meeting held this month at Chandigarh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting was chaired by labour commissioner Tajinder Singh Dhaliwal and a direction regarding the same was issued to all the assistant labour commissioners (ALC) across the state on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the directions, the labour commissioners have been asked to mention Aadhaar card details of the beneficiary and family members along with a self-declaration form mentioning that other family members of the beneficiary will not take benefits of labour schemes after him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move came after some complaints of dual benefits under various schemes were availed by many persons of a single family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under BOCW Act provisions for registration of four family members of the beneficiary can be submitted to the board but only one member can claim the benefits on behalf of the family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources said that in some cases beneficiary and his wife as a member have claimed benefits under Shagun Scheme separately as earlier, there was no check on the number of claimants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, each beneficiary has to submit details in an amendment forum about the Aadhaar card and family members’ detail declaring that no other member of his family will take same benefits from the labour department,” assistant labour commissioner Sukhjinder Singh said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;boosting-workers-registration&#34;&gt;BOOSTING WORKERS’ REGISTRATION&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concerning low registration of workers with board, labour department has also asked its officials to paste a list of all the registering labour officers with their name, contact number at the notice board of labour department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While, contact details with complete information of PWD and other department officers, who registered construction workers with board, have been asked to display in their district labour departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dhaliwal said that many workers are still not aware from where they can get registered so all the officers, workers, trade union workers and NGOs can be directly approached for registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the information, state labour department has managed to register about 5.61 lakh workers till December 31, even the estimated figures are said to be over 20 lakhs in the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labour department is not able to utilise funds collected in lieu of cess in the state as labour department has collected about Rs 921.75 crore cess amount and spent about Rs 335.99 crore towards the distribution of benefits to beneficiaries and other administrative expenses till the end of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board earns its revenue from the ‘welfare cess’, 1% of the total cost of construction projects which are worth Rs 10 lakh or more, which is submitted to the labour department to utilise the labour schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labour department has also faced wrath of the Punjab and Haryana high court in past due to its slow utilisation of welfare funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>