<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar authentication a must for engineering scholarships</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-authentication-must-engineering-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The state higher and technical education department has made authentication of Aadhaar number a must for backward engineering students to avail scholarships. The move comes against the backdrop of large-scale scholarship scam across the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though decision has been welcomed by city engineering colleges, they feel the authentication process will burden them with extra work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a gazette notification dated April 13, the department states that every student desirous of availing benefits under the schemes specified in Schedule ‘A’ need to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo authentication process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process involves submission of aadhaar number along with demographic information or biometrics of the beneficiary to the Central Indentities Data Repository for verification. The repository verifies the correctness of the claims on the basis of information available with it. The repository is a centralized database having all aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schemes listed in Schedule ‘A’ are Rajashri Chhatrapati Shahu Maharaj Shikshan Shulk Shishyavrutti Yojana and Dr Panjabrao Deshmukh Vastigruh Nirvah Bhatta Yojana. The scholarships are meant for other backward class (OBC) students and take care of certain percentage of tuition and hostel fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The directorate of technical education’s website, too, has alerted students to provide aadhaar authentication details otherwise their reimbursement would be put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification issued by deputy secretary Kiran Patil clarifies that students who do not have enrolled for Aadhaar can still available the scholarships on two conditions. The Aadhaar enrolment ID slip can be attached to their applications. In case they are not able to enrol due to non-availability of enrolment centres, they may write to the UIDAI’s designated field offices or register through its web portal and attach a copy of this request with the application. The students will also have to submit a proof of identity from one of the listed documents that included voter ID card, PAN, passport driving licence, bank passbook, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department has issued the guidelines under section 3 and 4 of the Maharashtra Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act 2016, that is stringent than the mother Act. As per the new Act, proof of possession of Aadhaar number or authentication is required in availing state government subsidy, benefits or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A city college principal said the aadhaar ID is itself foolproof and there was no need to add an extra authentication process. “A person’s biometric details can be viewed through Aadhaar number. Why principals should be asked to verify a student’s domicile. The social welfare department too had asked us to verify students’ income proof. This is the tehsildar or SDO’s job. They have only increased our work,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can now lock your Aadhaar data to keep it safe from hackers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now, you can lock your Aadhaar biometric details to keep it safe and unlock it whenever you want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With digital payments using Aadhaar data on the rise and cases of misuse being reported, officials of the &lt;em&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India&lt;/em&gt; (UIDAI) have come out with the new security feature to lock the biometric details (fingerprint and retinal scan data).The UIDAI introduced the lock and unlock facility following an uproar that Aadhaar deprived people of their right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric data of citizens is being collected on various platforms for government schemes, often without much safeguards. Aadhaar identification has become almost compulsory in some cases. Banks, mobile phone operators and others have access to it. “People can hack into this data and access individuals’ details, including bank accounts,” a UIDAI official warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Each time you shop and pay using your fingerprint, the data processed by POS machines can be hacked. Fingerprint details can be captured as well,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lock and unlock facility is purely voluntary. “If a person wants to lock his data, he or she can do it. No other person can unlock it. One can keep it locked as long as one wishes,” the official said Once the Aadhaar data is locked, even banks cannot access the biometric information stored in the main server.This will lead to failed transactions due to non-verification or non-authentication of the Aadhaar. The UIDAI is also planning to introduce a mobile application to lockunlock biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper published under Creative Commons is titled ‘Information Security Practices of Aadhaar (or lack thereof): A documentation of public availability of Aadhaar Numbers with sensitive personal financial information’ and was released on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha and Kodali looked at databases on four government portals — National Social Assistance Programme, National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme, Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh and Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We chose major government programmes that use Aadhaar for payments and banking transactions. We found sensitive and personal data and information accessible on these portals,” the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaked through portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Based on the numbers available on the websites, estimated number of Aadhaar numbers leaked through these 4 portals could be around 130-135 million and the number of bank account numbers leaked at around 100 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these numbers are only from two major government programmes of pensions and rural employment schemes, other major schemes, that have also used Aadhaar for DBT, could have leaked PII similarly due to lack of information security practices,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They fear that data of over 23 crore beneficiaries under DBT of LPG subsidies could be leaked also. Identity theft and financial fraud “risks increase multifold in India…,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar payments unsafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case a financial fraud takes place through Aadhaar enabled Payment System (AePS), the consumer may not be able to assert his claims for compensation due to the terms and conditions around liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These terms force the consumer to take liabilities onto oneself than the payment provider….. Regulations and standards around Aadhaar are at a very early and nascent stage causing (an) increase in financial risk for both consumers and banks to venture into AePS,” they added. The authors also pulled up UIDAI for their inability in providing strong legislation against such leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaky govt portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Social Assistance Programme&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII available – Access to Aadhaar no., name, bank account number, account frozen status  94,32,605&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bank accounts linked with Aadhaar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14,98,919  post office accounts linked with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though total Aadhaar number is 1,56,42,083, not all are linked to bank accounts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NREGA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII Details available: Job card no., Aadhaar number, bank/postal account number, no. of days worked, registration no., account frozen status&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;78,74,315  post office accounts of individual workers seeded with Aadhaar numbers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8,24,22,161 bank accounts of individual workers with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10,96,41,502 total number of Aadhaar numbers stored by portal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other websites&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Luxurious Maharajas&#39; Express Offers Free Seats On New Routes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Railways and IRCTC have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian Railways’ super-luxury trains, which cater to various tourist circuits throughout India have long been in demand with travellers with deep pockets looking to explore the cities, towns, villages and regional areas, while travelling in style along the world’s fourth largest rail network. Expanding the network of its super-luxury trains, the Indian Railways and Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation Ltd (IRCTC) have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of their promotional campaign, the Railways are offering one free ticket on the booking of first adult on twin sharing at full cost, for the newly-introduced Maharajas’ Express circuits during monsoon period of June-July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, for a ‘Deluxe Cabin’, you can get a chance to upgrade it to a ‘Junior Suite’ by paying 50 per cent of the difference in tariff, the Railways said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the new Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express routes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two new routes have been named as ‘Southern Sojourn’ and ‘Southern Jewels’ which will cover prominent destinations in West and South India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ‘Southern Sojourn’ will cover Goa, Hampi, Mysore, Ernakulam, Kumarakom and Trivandrum. And, the ‘Southern Jewels’ will cover Chettinad, Mahabalipuram, Mysore, Hampi and Goa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both the journeys will take about 8 Days and 7 Nights and IRCTC will organize visits to monuments and sight-seeing at each destination under these trips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regular trip of ‘Southern Sojourn’ will start from Mumbai on September 9 and ‘Southern Jewels’ will start from Trivandrum on September 16.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guests on the Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express shall also have an opportunity to enjoy traditional cultural performances at Cochin, visit a Coir Factory and enjoy a cruise with lunch at Alleppey, savour traditional Chettinad Cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trains will be equipped with two restaurants, two bars, lounge, LCD TVs, direct dial phone, internet, individual temperature controls and in suite bathroom as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 23 coach long Maharajas’ Express carries only 88 guests in one trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maharajas’ Express commenced its operations in 2010, and is the recipient of the coveted Leading Luxury Train of the World Award for the last five years in a row since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indian Railways also operates a number of other luxury trains such as Fairy Queen, Heritage on Wheels, The Indian Maharaja and Splendor of South&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The booking and other details for the super-luxury trains can either be done online on the official website of Maharajas’ Express or on the official website of IRCTC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why SBI Cut Its Fixed Deposit Rates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-sbi-cut-its-fixed-deposit-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-sbi-cut-its-fixed-deposit-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;According to SBI&amp;rsquo;s new rates, for two to less than three-year deposits, the bank will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank, cut its term deposit rates in select maturities from April 29, 2017. The government&amp;rsquo;s move in November last year to withdraw Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 bank notes from the financial system led to a &amp;ldquo;huge inflow of current account and savings bank deposits&amp;rdquo;, State Bank of India (SBI) chief financial officer Anshula Kant told NDTV Profit, while explaining the rationale behind her bank&amp;rsquo;s decision to lower its deposit rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Post-demonetisation gradually some of the deposits have started to go out of the system and roughly for us about 40 per cent of the deposits have gone out from the bank. We still have 60 per cent. That is one thing,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were not very keen to increase the MCLR (marginal cost of funds-based lending rates) at this point. As cost of deposit goes up, it has an upward pressure on the MCLR as well. To maintain MCLR for our borrower customers where it is, we have tweaked the rates in certain longer deposit buckets.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marginal cost of funds-based rate is a new benchmark which banks are using for pricing their home and car loans. They add a margin above their MCLR to price retail loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to SBI&amp;rsquo;s new rates, for two to less than three-year deposits, the bank will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has not changed its marginal cost of funds-based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She further said that &amp;ldquo;there has been a slight uptick in the cost of deposits&amp;rdquo; since its mega merger last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the merger, SBI entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EPFO Reduces Wait For Pension, Provident Fund Withdrawal To 10 days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-reduces-wait-for-pension-provident-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-reduces-wait-for-pension-provident-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The retirement fund manager had launched an online claim settlement facility on May 1, 2017.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund manager EPFO has reduced the stipulated period for settlement of various claims such PF withdrawal, pension and insurance to 10 days from 20 at present. In July 2015, the Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had reduced the timeline for settling various claims to 20 day to improve the service delivery for its over four crore subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body has launched the online claim settlement facility on May 1, 2017. It has planned to eventually settle claims of all Aadhaar and bank account seeded EPF accounts within three hours of receipt of an application. &amp;ldquo;The timeline in case of claim settlements is 10 days and 15 days in case of grievance redressal management,&amp;rdquo; an EPFO statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are new provisions in the EPFO&amp;rsquo;s Citizens&amp;rsquo; Charter 2017 launched in Bangalore today by Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said the Charter is an attempt to bring transparency and accountability on the part of EPFO and make service delivery system and grievance redressal mechanism more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO e-court Management System has also been launched which is in tune with the vision of Prime Minister Narendra Modi of digital India. The objective of the project is a transparent and electronic case management system which will cater to aspirations of all stakeholders - the employers, the employees, litigants and CBT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a step towards paperless court system wherein court procedure of EPF &amp;amp; MP Act, 1952 and EPFAT (tribunal) will take place in a digital environment. Further, in order to facilitate easy access to the tribunal, automated messages will be sent to the litigants on their registered mobile numbers on the status of their cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stakeholders can also track the individual cases online, it said. Now the parties can file all their paper/evidence/ documents online and all the details alongwith status can be accessed online. Updation is an important part of e-court management system in which digital case record will create a digital database which can be utilised to generate meaningful and accurate reports, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST impact: here’s how much it may cost you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-impact-services-set-to-get-costlier-heres-how-much-it-may-cost-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-impact-services-set-to-get-costlier-heres-how-much-it-may-cost-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the 120 services that are currently being taxed, a vast majority is likely to come under the goods and services tax (GST) slab of 18%, while a clutch of them including air travel services, renting of hotels, restaurants and other “bundled” food supply services could get taxed at 12%. A handful of services including transport of goods by road (trucks) and rail and financial leasing including hire purchase could fall under the lowest GST rate of 5%. While the principle that underlies the GST rates fitment, recommended by a committee of officials, is to minimise rate shocks, services would still be the category to witness rate hikes the most as the country adopts the new indirect tax structure, official sources said. Since the current service tax rate is 15% (including the 0.5% Swachh Bharat Cess and an equal Krishi Kalyan cess), levy of GST at 18% would mean a significant increase in the tax liability of consumers of most services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even for the relatively smaller number of services to be taxed at 12% in the GST regime, the tax incidence could actually increase in some cases. This is because taxes paid after the abatements permitted by the government work out to be lower than 12% in many such cases at present. For example, restaurant services are currently taxed with 30% abatement, which means actual tax incidence of 10.5%. This could increase to 12% in the GST regime, rather than decrease to 5%. The sources added that all the 60-odd exempt services, which are on the negative list now, would be outside the GST net too. These include services provided by educational institutions, healthcare services, EPFO- Irdai-Sebi services, non-A/c restaurants etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since the service providers will get greater opportunity to avail of input tax credit in the GST regime, their tax liability could soften if a rate hike is big enough to offset it. Transport of goods by rail is now taxed after 70% abatement on the condition that CENVAT credit has not been taken by the businesses concerned. Since the credit flows will be more efficient in the GST regime, the tax rate is likely to be fixed taking into account the abatements being given now for the new regime to be rate-neutral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at least in some cases, this principle might not be followed and the tax liability of businesses and consumers could rise, analysts said. However, the instances of GST leading to higher tax liabilities and price increases will be very few in the case of goods. Items constituting half of the consumer price index (CPI) basket including food grain will be exempt from GST; many other goods of mass consumption, together another tenth of the basket, will be taxed at a benign 5%; a quarter of the basket will come under either 12% or 18%, the two “standard rates.
The government has maintained that rate fitment will be a “mechanical (rather than discretionary) exercise” as the process has taken into account the real tax incidence at present rather than the nominal rate. For instance, if the nominal tax rate on an item with maximum retail price of Rs 150 and ex-factory price of Rs 100 is 26.5% (12.5% excise and 14% VAT), the real tax incidence on the price to the consumer is just 22%, as the excise duty is virtually levied on the ex-factory price, with abatement for post-manufacturing value addition. Chances are that the item will come under 18% GST, rather than the highest rate of 28%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The committee of officials has prepared a detailed document on the fitment of GST rates for the consideration of the GST Council. The 800-page document is likely to be vetted by the council as it meets in Srinagar on May 18-19. Source told FE that even after the GST Council approval, the rates will be notified and made public only closer to the July 1 roll-out to avoid market distortion and hoarding. Experts said that the reason for delaying announcement of rates could be to negate the possibility that a manufacturer may ramp up or slow down production till July 1 if it’s known that a commodity will be taxed at a lower/ higher rate under GST.
Apart from final approval to the rates, the GST Council is expected to okay the five draft rules related to accounts and records, advance ruling, appeals and revision, assessment and audit and e-way bill. So far, the Council has approved nine GST rules in its earlier meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian-Origin Techie Links Ransomware Attack To North Korea</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-origin-techie-links-ransomware-attack-to-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-origin-techie-links-ransomware-attack-to-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About 200,000 machines have been infected worldwide by the ransomware &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Indian-origin security researcher with Google has found evidence suggesting that North Korean hackers may have carried out the &amp;ldquo;unprecedented&amp;rdquo; ransomware cyberattack that hit over 150 countries, including India. Neel Mehta has published a code which a Russian security firm has termed as the &amp;ldquo;most significant clue to date&amp;rdquo;, BBC reported today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code, published on Twitter, is exclusive to North Korean hackers, researchers said. Researchers have said that some of the code used in Friday&amp;rsquo;s ransomware, known as WannaCry software, was nearly identical to the code used by the Lazarus Group, a group of North Korean hackers who used a similar version for the devastating hack of Sony Pictures Entertainment in 2014 and the last year&amp;rsquo;s hack of Bangladesh Central Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security experts are now cautiously linking the Lazarus Group to this latest attack after the discovery by Mehta. Mehta has found similarities between code found within WannaCry and other tools believed to have been created by the Lazarus Group in the past, BBC reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security expert Prof Alan Woodward said that time stamps within the original WannaCry code are set to UTC +9 - China&amp;rsquo;s time zone - and the text demanding the ransom uses what reads like machine-translated English, but a Chinese segment apparently written by a native speaker, the report said.
&amp;ldquo;As you can see it is pretty thin and all circumstantial. However, it is worth further investigation,&amp;rdquo; Woodward said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neel Mehta&amp;rsquo;s discovery is the most significant clue to date regarding the origins of WannaCry,&amp;rdquo; said Russian security firm Kaspersky, but noted a lot more information is needed about earlier versions of WannaCry before any firm conclusion can be reached, it reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We believe it is important that other researchers around the world investigate these similarities and attempt to discover more facts about the origin of WannaCry,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attributing cyberattacks can be notoriously difficult-often relying on consensus rather than confirmation, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Korea has never admitted any involvement in the Sony Pictures hack - and while security researchers, and the US government, have confidence in the theory, neither can rule out the possibility of a false flag, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skilled hackers may have simply made it look like it had origins in North Korea by using similar techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of WannaCry, it is possible that hackers simply copied code from earlier attacks by the Lazarus Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ifs in there. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stand up in court as it is. But it&amp;rsquo;s worth looking deeper, being conscious of confirmation bias now that North Korea has been identified as a possibility,&amp;rdquo; Woodward said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the strongest theory yet as to the origin of WannaCry, but there are also details that arguably point  way from it being the work of North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, China was among the countries worst hit, and not accidentally - the hackers made sure there was a version of the ransom note written in Chinese. It seems unlikely North Korea would want to antagonise its strongest ally. Russia too was badly affected, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, North Korean cyber-attacks have typically been far more targeted, often with a political goal in mind. In the case of Sony Pictures, hackers sought to prevent the release of The Interview, a film that mocked North Korean leader Kim Jong-Un. WannaCry, in contrast, was wildly indiscriminate - it would infect anything and everything it could, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if the plan was simply to make money, it&amp;rsquo;s been pretty unsuccessful on that front too - only around $60,000 has been paid in ransoms, according to analysis of Bitcoin accounts being used by the criminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more than 200,000 machines infected, it&amp;rsquo;s a terrible return, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Europol Director Rob Wainwright said, &amp;ldquo;The global reach is unprecedented. The latest count is over 200,000 victims in at least 150 countries and those victims many of those will be businesses including large corporations&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not happy with bank fixed deposits? Check out 4 alternatives</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/not-happy-with-bank-fixed-deposits-check-out-4-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/not-happy-with-bank-fixed-deposits-check-out-4-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compared to bank deposits or small savings, non-convertible debentures, liquid funds, tax-free bonds and company fixed deposits offer higher returns, albeit with some risks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a time when interest rates on bank deposit and small savings are falling, investors can look at other debt financial instruments to earn some higher returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;non-convertible-debentures&#34;&gt;Non-convertible debentures&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies issue non-convertible debentures (NCDs) to raise long-term funds. These debentures cannot be converted into shares or equities and lenders offer a higher rate of return compared to convertible debentures. Non-convertible debentures are of two types —secured and non-secured. The secured ones are backed by assets, wherein if the company is unable to fulfil its obligations, the assets are liquidated to repay the investors.
So, secured non-convertible debentures pay lower coupons than non-secured ones. Companies issuing non-convertible debentures offer higher rates because they carry default risk compared to bank or postal deposits. Investing in NCDs makes sense for those in the 10% to 20% tax brackets, as those in the lowest tax bracket can get post tax returns around 7% for a 120-month tenure. One should invest in non-convertible debentures only if he can hold them till maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Liquid funds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors can also look at liquid funds offered by asset management companies for short-term investment for up to a year. The fund will yield marginally higher returns than bank deposits. Moreover, they are as liquid as time and demand deposits as the market regulator has allowed fund houses to offer instant redemption facility of up to Rs 50,000. In fact, one aspect where bank deposits scored over liquid funds or any other money market funds was same day redemption.
Now that has been taken care and investors can manage cash flows better. At the time of investing in debt funds, investors must analyse the credit rating of the bonds in which the fund house invests. While debt funds are not rated, their safety can be analysed from the portfolio they invest in. Fund managers may sometimes take higher position in bonds with lower rating for higher returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Tax-free bonds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, tax-free bonds were issued by state-owned companies such as NHAI, IRFC, HUDCO till March 2016. However, investors can now buy these bonds from the secondary market and can earn up to 2% more than bank fixed deposits after tax. Tax-free bonds are an attractive long-term investment as there is no deduction of tax at source from the interest that accrues to bondholders, irrespective of the interest amount or status of the investor.
These bonds score over fixed deposits or other debt investment as investors do not have to pay tax on the returns. Before investing in tax-free bonds, one must look at the issue size as it may impact liquidity. For instance, NHAI’s Rs 10,000-crore bond issue has the highest traded volume on bourses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;company-fixed-deposits&#34;&gt;Company fixed deposits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even by investing in company fixed deposits of top-rated firms, investors can earn up to 150 basis points more than bank fixed deposits. However, investors must exercise utmost caution because while bank deposits provide security for investment up to Rs 1 lakh, this is not the case with corporate fixed deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tenure of company deposits ranges from one to seven years and one can earn compounding interest by reinvesting the principal amount along with the interest earned. Investors can get direct ECS credit facility for interest payments or advance interest warrants for the year. However, unless one needs income regularly, they should prefer cumulative schemes to regular income options since the interest earned gets reinvested at the same coupon rate, resulting in better yields.
Diversify investment in four to five companies and avoid investing in those companies that mention very high interest rates and whose balance sheets show losses. If one invests in a company that is low on ratings, go for a short tenure, which will enable you to opt out if the company is not performing well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Notes Ban, 91 Lakh More Came Under Tax Net, Says Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/post-notes-ban-91-lakh-more-came-under-tax-net-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/post-notes-ban-91-lakh-more-came-under-tax-net-says/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post notes ban, there has been a hike in collection of personal income tax, the finance minister said, adding that the new portal will help honest tax payer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finance Minister says number of assessees has gone up post notes ban&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal income tax collection has gone up post notes ban, he adds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr Jaitley expects further increase in tax returns going ahead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of persons under the tax net has increased by 91 lakh as unaccounted cash lost anonymity post note ban, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launching a new website on &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo;, a programme to bring illegal wealth on books, he said the fallout of the November 8 decision to demonetise higher denomination currency has increased movement towards digitisation, number of assessees going up and tax revenue jumping as also fear of dealing in cash being instilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stating that as many as 91 lakh persons have come under the tax net, Jaitley said he expects further increase in tax returns going ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post demonetisation, there has been a hike in collection of personal income tax, the finance minister said, adding that the new portal will help honest tax payer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT Chairman Sushil Chandra said there was 22 per cent growth in e-filed returns post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many as 17.92 lakh people were identified for unexplained deposits post demonetisation, he said, adding the tax department has identified one lakh suspected tax avoidance cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that an undisclosed income of Rs 16,398 crore was identified post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We identified around 17.92 lakh persons in whose case the cash transactions did not appear in line with the taxpayers&amp;rsquo; profiles. And online verifications of these transactions are underway,&amp;rdquo; Chandra said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 17.92 lakh, so far 9.72 lakh individuals responded to SMSes and e-mails sent by the income tax department.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WannaCry ransomware : 48,000 attempts in India, says Quick Heal</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-in-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While organisations and networks in over 150 countries were crippled by the WannaCry ransomware outbreak, India escaped from the malware spreading and causing damage, thanks to the timing of the incident, with offices being shut during the weekend.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While organisations and networks in over 150 countries were crippled by the WannaCry ransomware outbreak, India escaped from the malware spreading and causing damage, thanks to the timing of the incident, with offices being shut during the weekend. By Monday morning, everybody had become alert and it averted a lot of damage, Sanjay Katkar, MD and CTO of Quick Heal Technologies, an IT security solutions provider, said. Since Monday, Quick Heal has been receiving distress calls from customers but it was not clear whether they were affected or not, as this was not being disclosed by those calling, Katkar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick Heal detected over 48,000 attempts of WannaCry ransomware attack in India. Kolkata tops the list of cities with maximum detections, followed by Delhi, Bhubaneswar, Pune and Mumbai. The top five states with maximum detections are West Bengal, Maharashtra, Gujarat, Delhi (including NCR) and Odisha. Among the attempted attacks, 60% were targeted towards enterprises and 40% towards individual customers. In case of an attack, Katkar advises companies or users not to pay any ransom as this would go in funding the next attack.
“Hackers who are successful in collecting money will re-invest into new technologies. People who pay are funding the next attack,” warns Katkar. Protection was available if the users updated the anti-virus software and the patch was made available on March ’17 but many did not update their systems, Katkar said. Soon after the ransomware attack was spotted, Quick Heal Security Labs issued an advisory informing customer on ways to reduce the risk of infection by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry Ransomware. Quick Heal has also organized a webinar to educate businesses on how to protect their organization from the WannaCry Ransomware on Wednesday, May 17 at 4 pm. This kind of an incident helps increase awareness about security but their experience was that people go back to business as usual in quick time, says Katkar. This threat indicates people not serious about security but security has to be priority if they want to protect data, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outdated operating system and failure to use anti-virus software makes them vulnerable, he said. Some of the software in the enterprise could be running on older systems especially in the manufacturing sector and a shift would need upgrading hardware so they could be continuing with old systems, Katkar said. Banks in the country that have outsourced some of their systems/ functions to third-party service providers need to take a re-look at the security at their vendors especially their ATM networks, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The retail user are also casual so vulnerability is more on this front. A lot of data moving on the mobile phones and people are connected &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; on the net but the market is not keen on paying for security their phones so mobile security is not picking up, Katkar said. “Given their profitability, ransomware attacks are predicted to increase in the coming quarter. There can be a drastic increase in the number of Locky samples being distributed via spam emails or exploits. Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS) type attacks may increase due to its user friendliness,” a Quick Heal Security Labs Q12017 threat report had warned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>400 Benami Transactions Crackdown by Income Tax Department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/i-t-department-crackdown-yeilds-400-benami-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/i-t-department-crackdown-yeilds-400-benami-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Benami property includes movable or immovable assets and property which is in name of someone other than the beneficial owner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department today said it has identified over 400 benami transactions and attached properties worth Rs 600 crore in about 240 cases. Keen to implement the new Benami Act to ensure &amp;ldquo;visible outcomes on the ground&amp;rdquo;, the tax department last week set up 24 dedicated Benami Prohibition Units (BPUs) all over India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department started initiating actions under the new Benami Transactions (Prohibition) Amendment Act, 2016 from November 1 last year. The law provides for a maximum punishment of seven years in jail and a fine. Benami property includes movable or immovable, tangible or intangible, corporeal or incorporeal property which is in name of someone other than the beneficial owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Income-tax Directorates of Investigation have identified more than 400 benami transactions up to May 23, 2017. These include deposits in bank accounts, plots of land, flat and jewellery,&amp;rdquo; said an official release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provisional attachment of properties under the law has been done in more than 240 cases. The market value of properties under attachment is more than Rs 600 crore, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Immovable properties have been attached in 40 cases with total value of more than Rs 530 crore in Kolkata, Mumbai, Delhi, Gujarat, Rajasthan and Madhya Pradesh,&amp;rdquo; the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also undertaken searches on 10 &amp;ldquo;senior government officials&amp;rdquo; during the past one month, in line with its policy to &amp;ldquo;unearth black money earned through corrupt practices and introduce accountability and probity in public life&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving details, the department said in one case in Jabalpur, the &amp;ldquo;benamidar&amp;rdquo;, a driver, was found to be owner of land worth Rs 7.7 crore. The beneficial owner was a Madhya Pradesh based listed company, his employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mumbai, a professional was found to be holding several immovable properties in the name of shell companies which exist only on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another case in Sanganer, Rajasthan, a jeweller was found to be the beneficial owner of nine immovable properties in the name of his former employee, a man of no means. Certain properties purchased through shell companies have also been attached by the department in Kolkata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crackdown on all forms of illicit wealth is being spearheaded by the department to ensure that any economic misdeed is immediately identified and actions as per law follow, the release added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 24 dedicated units are under the overall supervision of the Principal Directors of Investigation in the Income-tax Department to enable swift action and follow up, especially in cases where criminality has been detected.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATM hacks are less about losing a few lakhs &amp; more about erosion of reputation.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bankers-atm-hacks-are-less-about-losing-a-few-lakhs-more-about-erosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bankers-atm-hacks-are-less-about-losing-a-few-lakhs-more-about-erosion/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last year, Vijay Kumar, an Indian Army sepoy, got the shock of his life when he discovered a shortfall of Rs 2 lakh in his SBI salary account. Subsequently drawing out of transaction details and CCTV footage revealed Kumar’s card was “cloned” by fraudsters several kilometers from his base in Delhi Cantonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kumar had never even travelled to Connaught Place where his card was used (or misused). Miscreants managed to get his bank details using a Malaysian-make card reader and a hidden camera (affixed to the ceiling of the rigged ATM, focused on the keypad) to capture the PIN. Card skimming – an old trick – is common in India, but on a waning curve as swindlers have moved on to more sophisticated technologies. Daring raids on ATM switches and payment gateways, in rising numbers, have turned fraudsters of yore into new-age hackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to India Forensic, an educational &amp;amp; research organisation specialising in banking frauds, roughly 37,000 ATM fraud cases have been reported in the country since 2014. Industry experts estimate over 8,000 ATMs got infected by bugs last year – a good number on account of mishandling by third party handlers. Most banks outsource ‘ATM management’ (software updates, hardware service and others) to external agencies. ATMs get infected when third party service engineers use (virus) infected pen drives. Eight dacoity cases were reported in 2014, according to the National Crime Records Bureau, a couple of which included uprooting ATM machines and trucking them into the woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ransomware-rears-up&#34;&gt;RANSOMWARE REARS UP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a response to the recent ‘WannaCry Ransomware’ malware attack, the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) asked banks to update software systems. There are unconfirmed reports of two south India based banks being infected, The Times of India stated recently. “Ample security measures have to be employed across all banks as customers use non-home ATMs as well. So only one bank with strong system or network may not really help. ATMs are easy targets,” explains Mahesh Patel, group CTO, AGS Transact Technologies, an ATM manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bankers, it appears, are not overly worried about individual ATMs as these hold only “a few lakhs of rupees” at any given time. But they are concerned about reputational risk associated with their ATMs getting hacked and plundered. Beyond that, banks are focused on securing pricier installations such as the ‘ATM or core banking switch,’ which link core accounts and clusters of ATMs. “Hackers are not interested in individual customers or ATMs anymore… they’re looking for larger gains and bigger play,” admits Johnson K Jose, head of IT at Federal Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Most ATM attacks happen at the (ATM) switch level these days… precisely for this reason, we don’t outsource switch-level operations to outsiders. But then securing individual ATMs is also important for banks… customers should feel safe when they transact on a particular bank’s ATM,” Johnson adds. ATM/debit card fraud complaints shot up 23% to 13,081 in 2015-16, as per the latest Banking Ombudsman Report. Of the 22,000 card-related complaints received, 8,300 pertain to failed ATM withdrawal transactions, short/non-dispensation and fraudulent removal of cash from customer accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;physical-attacks&#34;&gt;PHYSICAL ATTACKS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 2016, four youths uprooted an SBI ‘pass book updating machine’ thinking it was an ATM kiosk. Such instances of ‘ATM ramming’ are fairly common in Australia, where miscreants use tractors to pull out cash dispensers bolted to the ground. Physical attacks on ATMs are also on a rising curve in India. AnG India, an electronic security solutions company, receives over 100 alerts of “force” being exerted on ATMs every day. Of this, around 10 pertain to breakage or forced entry. “Not many ATMs have guards anymore… Banks mostly use e-surveillance systems,” says Pulkit Punj, director of AnG India. “Some kind of access restriction has to be there to keep away undesirable elements (near ATMs),” feels Mukul Shrivastava, partner – fraud investigation &amp;amp; dispute services, EY. “Also, there’s a lot of hardware (wires, connecting cables) lying around openly in ATMs. These have to be concealed properly… Such inlet points come handy for expert hackers to get through,” he warns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;defence-countermeasures&#34;&gt;DEFENCE, COUNTERMEASURES&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, when banks requisitioned for new ATMs, they did not ask for security packages that came at extra cost. This has changed now. Banks have started demanding whitelisting modules, antiskimming devices and hard disk encryption software along with new ATMs. “Multiple banking touchpoints — from net banking to mobile banking and ewallets — are vulnerable to cyber attacks. So banks should not look at security in a piecemeal fashion,” says Navroze Dastur, MD of NCR Corporation, an ATM manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operating system updation would go a long way to secure ATMs from minor hacks. Whitelisting modules would ring-fence the core (software) by restricting unauthorised reworking of programmes using malwares. Strong safe boxes (Cen-1 safes) are being installed inside most new ATMs. Cen-1 strong boxes take approximately 35 minutes to cut open (a unit of measure for safe boxes) while the previously used UL291 boxes could be forced open in 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instances of card skimming and cloning are likely to come down after the move to EMV (Europay, Mastercard, Visa) cards in two years. EMV or chip cards, according to experts, offer one of the most secure conduits for banking transactions. Some 300 million magstripe cards would be replaced with chip-embedded EMV cards by end-December 2018, as directed by RBI. If security experts are to be believed, six lakh new bugs are released into the “market” (thriving on internet) daily. Malwares such as Green dispenser, Suceful, Padpin and Tyupkin have cracked open ATMs of late. Some can be downloaded on a pen drive and their ‘spit-code’ sourced from Russian or American hack mafia for a price. Banks and security agencies will have to keep plugging the holes every single day to keep black hats at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government To Roll Out Aadhaar Pay For Cashless Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-roll-aadhaar-pay-cashless-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-roll-aadhaar-pay-cashless-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government will soon roll out Aadhaar Pay service that will enable people to make and receive payments using their Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are going to start Aadhaar Pay. With this people will not require to carry their phone for payments. They can visit any merchant, share their Aadhaar number and verify themselves using biometrics to pay and receive money,” Electronics and IT Minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, 14 banks have come on board for Aadhaar Pay and the service will be launched soon, Prasad told reporters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are in talks with other banks too. The service will be launched very soon,” he informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the Minister said, Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM), the common platform for making quick payments using the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), has also been integrated with Aadhaar Enabled Payment System on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 111 crore people in the country have Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are 49 crore bank accounts linked to Aadhaar. Every month 2 crore accounts are being seeded with Aadhaar,” Prasad said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>