<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar mandatory to avoid fake PAN cards: Government tells Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-to-avoid-fake-pan-cards-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government today defended in the Supreme Court its decisionto make Aadhaar mandatory for issuing of PAN cards, saying it was done to curb the use of fake PAN cards across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi told a bench comprising Justices A K Sikri and Ashok Bhushan that the programme of PAN had become suspect as it could be faked while Aadhaar is a &amp;ldquo;secure and robust&amp;rdquo; system by which the identity of an individual cannot be faked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AG said that due to Aadhaar, government has saved over Rs 50,000 crore on the schemes to benefit the poor as well as the pension schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that around 10 lakh PAN cards have been cancelled, while out of the 113.7 crore Aadhaar cards issued, no case of duplication has been found by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that Aadhaar was an effective tool to check the menace of terror funding and circulation of black money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The idea behind Aadhaar is to make a secure and robust system by which the identity of a person cannot be faked,&amp;rdquo; the Attorney General told the court, which would continue hearing the arguments tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court is hearing three petitions challenging the constitutional validity of Section 139 AA of the Income Tax Act which was introduced through the latest budget and the Finance Act 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Section 139AA provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns and making an application for allotment of PAN number with effect from July 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior counsel Shyam Divan, representing the petitioners, had earlier argued that section 139AA was unconstitutional and was in &amp;ldquo;direct collision&amp;rdquo; with the Aadhaar Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had also contended that there was no question of forcing a person to give his consent for Aadhaar and this was an issue which &amp;ldquo;alters the relationship of Republic of India with its citizens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The petitioner had also argued that a law-abiding tax payer cannot be forced to give his Aadhaar number while filing income tax returns and this was like an &amp;ldquo;electronic leash&amp;rdquo; as government would be able to keep a tab on its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nowhere in the world there is such a biometric system which can track a person 24X7. They (government) are doing it even before the age of consent,&amp;rdquo; he had said during the arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had earlier put a poser as to why there was no objection from the lawmakers on the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for making PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rohatgi had also clarified that nowhere in section 139AA of IT Act, was it mentioned that it would be effective with retrospective effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had earlier told the apex court that fake PAN cards were being used to &amp;ldquo;divert funds&amp;rdquo; to shell companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can now lock your Aadhaar data to keep it safe from hackers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-now-lock-aadhaar-data-keep-safe-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now, you can lock your Aadhaar biometric details to keep it safe and unlock it whenever you want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With digital payments using Aadhaar data on the rise and cases of misuse being reported, officials of the &lt;em&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India&lt;/em&gt; (UIDAI) have come out with the new security feature to lock the biometric details (fingerprint and retinal scan data).The UIDAI introduced the lock and unlock facility following an uproar that Aadhaar deprived people of their right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric data of citizens is being collected on various platforms for government schemes, often without much safeguards. Aadhaar identification has become almost compulsory in some cases. Banks, mobile phone operators and others have access to it. “People can hack into this data and access individuals’ details, including bank accounts,” a UIDAI official warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Each time you shop and pay using your fingerprint, the data processed by POS machines can be hacked. Fingerprint details can be captured as well,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lock and unlock facility is purely voluntary. “If a person wants to lock his data, he or she can do it. No other person can unlock it. One can keep it locked as long as one wishes,” the official said Once the Aadhaar data is locked, even banks cannot access the biometric information stored in the main server.This will lead to failed transactions due to non-verification or non-authentication of the Aadhaar. The UIDAI is also planning to introduce a mobile application to lockunlock biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very soon, you can do “iris” Aadhaar authentication from your smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheap in-built iris scanners will eradicate use of costly ones for mass adoption of Aadhaar verification.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID Inc., a consumer-grade iris scanning technology provider for mobile phones, proposed the introduction of iris integrated mobile phones as a cost-effective way of reducing the failure rates in Aadhaar biometric authentication, as recently reported in MGNREGA tests in Telangana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe iris integrated smartphones and tablets will address the issues reported with Aadhaar biometric authentication. The UIDAI and the worldwide biometric community have tested and found iris to have better reliability. We are confident the failure rates will be drastically lower once the cheaper iris integrated mobile devices are adopted in the market,” said Dr. Salil Prabhakar, President and CEO, Delta ID Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the government mandating the use of Aadhaar biometric authentication in more spheres of the society, the need for a biometric modality that works reliably is critical. Unlike fingerprints that are being reported to show high failure rates due to wear and tear, the iris, being a protected internal organ, is expected to be significantly more reliable. Additionally, since the iris is not affected with age, it works reliably across all age groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key impediments in the large-scale roll out of iris for Aadhaar has been the high cost of iris devices. This is being addressed with the rollout of iris integrated mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this regard, Samsung partnered with Delta ID to launch India’s first iris integrated tablet in May 2016. The technology is arriving in smartphones too, and not only in high end devices such as Samsung Galaxy S8, but also in low cost smartphones developed by Indian manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID’s ActiveIRIS technology passed the Standardisation Testing and Quality Certification’s (STQC) FRR test with better than 99 percent accuracy, and has been certified by the STQC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active IRIS and a combination of STQC-certified hardware components can be integrated by any mobile device to expeditiously introduce iris integrated mobile devices in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avoid Queue At SBI Branches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-avoid-queue-at-sbi-branches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is offering a virtual queue ticket or &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo; service through its newly-launched app No Queue, which enables customers to avail select banking services at its select branches without having to stand in queues. SBI customers &amp;ldquo;can book a virtual token&amp;hellip;and skip the queue,&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI said on Twitter. SBI&amp;rsquo;s No Queue app was launched by the bank&amp;rsquo;s chairperson Arundhati Bhattacharya in March this year. The mobile-based virtual queuing app can be downloaded free of cost from Google Play and Apple app stores. &amp;ldquo;The Application is designed to save customers&amp;rsquo; valuable time, avoid queue for Banking services and aims to provide the customers with a better customer service experience,&amp;rdquo; SBI had said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user can select a minimum of one and maximum five services in virtual ticket using No queueapp, as per the SBI website. Here are few other things to know about the No Queue app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers a variety of services under the &amp;lsquo;no queue&amp;rsquo; facility. Some of these include cheque deposit, cash deposit/withdrawal, demand draft, NEFT/RTGS and loan account opening/maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The No Queue app empowers those interested in SBI&amp;rsquo;s banking services to efficiently book a virtual token without being physically present in the branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app provides &amp;ldquo;real time status notification of your position in the queue&amp;rdquo;, as per its description on Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers can generate an e-token before being physically present in the branch. This way, he or she avoids waiting in a queue and saves time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app conveys the estimated waiting time, the number of customers ahead in the queue and the distance to the branch from the point of booking, SBI has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers will be updated about their position in the queue through alerts, according to the app&amp;rsquo;s description on Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-book-e-token&#34;&gt;Who can book &amp;ldquo;e-token&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals - SBI and non-SBI customers - registered on the No Queue app installed on their devices can avail this facility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-use&#34;&gt;How to use&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user can register on the No Queue app by entering basic information such as name and mobile number to start using the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a virtual ticket is generated through the No Queue app, the customer will receive a notification about his or her position in the queue. A button that says &amp;lsquo;Activate&amp;rsquo; will be available on the app when the customer reaches the fifth position in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reaching the branch, a customer activating the queue ticket will be &amp;ldquo;serviced immediately, thus avoiding waiting time at the Branch&amp;rdquo;, the press release added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;can-i-reschedule-my-visit&#34;&gt;Can I reschedule my visit?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After booking a virtual ticket, customers also have the facility of rescheduling or renewing the ticket in case they are running late. The rescheduling option will be available only until when the customer is within the first five positions in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-linked payment system will change the game for digital transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-the-aadhaar-linked-payment-system-will-change-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Unique Identification Authority of India is working with banks and the Reserve Bank of India to ensure that merchants who use its mobile-based application for digital transactions earn a commission of up to 1% of the transaction value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With UIDAI suggesting it is on path to get this in place in a couple of months, the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System could give debit cards and e-wallets a run for their money. In contrast to what UIDAI is advocating, all other forms of digital payments require merchants to pay a fee or commission for the use of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Aadhaar-based system is being used for PDS [public distribution system] in Andhra Pradesh, Rajasthan and Gujarat. We are also in discussions with Haryana,” said Ajay Bhushan Pandey, chief executive officer, UIDAI. “We are enrolling banks so that they start accepting Aadhaar-based payments. Two banks have already agreed. The process of integrating merchants with banks will be completed in the next few weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Merchants as business correspondents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once implemented, this model envisages doing away with all charges that are associated with a typical point-of-sale machine. Under the system, UIDAI would enlist merchants as business correspondents. These merchants would use their phones linked to biometric devices for the transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These require a customer to key in their Aadhaar number and verify their fingerprint on the biometric reader connected to the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable a wide acceptability, the government has pushed for linking all savings bank accounts to Aadhaar numbers against a stiff deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a customer transacts with a merchant through Aadhaar Enabled Payment System, the merchant would receive the same incentive that business correspondents employed by banks do, UIDAI has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different banks provide different incentives to business correspondents on the basis of their performance. For instance, the Vidharbha Konkan Gramin Bank, a regional rural bank provides Rs 10 for every new account opened by a business correspondent. If someone deposits money through PoS terminals, the correspondent gets 0.5% of the money. For mobilising a term deposit, the correspondent gets 0.25% of the amount. Similarly, various incentives, as a proportion of the transaction amount, are given to correspondents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Merchants will now be doing the job of a business correspondent,” said Pandey. “So what was being paid as incentives to the correspondent would be extended to merchants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, he suggested, this would reduce the need for banking correspondents as more and more merchants use the Aadhaar app on their phones for transactions. The app itself has been tested by a couple of banks and is being finalised, Pandey said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UIDAI business model would mean the banking system taking on the burden of incentivising the spread of Aadhaar-based payments through mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, at the moment, they earn from other digital transactions. But Pandey said UIDAI was convincing banks that the commission must be seen in the light of existing commission structures for correspondents and the cost of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Costs of going cashless&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A look at the fee structure of PoS machines used to carry out card transactions indicates a substantial cost for the merchant. A third-party PoS provider has multiple layers of charges. These machines are not sold but often given on rent by banks and third-party vendors. Some banks charge the merchants a monthly rental of Rs 400 for a portable PoS machine for two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some banks also recover something called a “commitment charge”. These charges can be a burden on smaller merchants with low volumes of sales. Merchants with a lower sale volume have to pay a higher commitment charge. Competition between different vendors and banks has been bringing down these costs, though, over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks such as the State Bank of India and its public-sector peers offer machines on more lenient terms than third-party vendors. SBI, for instance, says that it doesn’t take a one-time installation charge from any merchant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final layer of the cost of using a PoS machine is the merchant discount rate. This is the charge that banks collect from merchants whenever a card is swiped on the machine. Banks usually charge a lower rate if their own debit cards are used on their PoS machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before January 1, the charges were 0.75% for transactions of value up to Rs 2,000. For transactions above Rs 2,000, a rate of 1% of the transaction value was recovered from the merchant. Foreign cards attracted double the rate while credit card transactions were charged at 1.5%. This was either borne by the merchant or passed on to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After demonetisation, RBI introduced an additional layer of merchant discount rate through a notification issued on December 16, 2016. Between January 1 and March 31 this year, the merchant discount rate for transactions up to Rs 1,000 is to be 0.25%. All others would continue to be charged as before. The rate has been capped at 1%. Clearly, the multiple charges add up to a significant amount for a merchant who has little option but to either bear the cost or to pass it on to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game-changer?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RBI data show that PoS transactions through debit cards touched Rs 31,600 crore in November 2016. In November 2015, this figure stood at Rs 14,800 crore. Banks quite clearly stand to make a killing through these multiple layers of charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile wallets, too, are known to charge as high as 4% for certain types of transactions. Mobile wallet transactions were Rs 3,300 crore in November 2016 as compared to Rs 1,900 crore in November 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where the Aadhaar-linked payment system could be a major disruptor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the National Payments Corporation of India charges 1% on every financial transaction through the Aadhaar Enabled Payment System from the bank. The bank passes this on to the merchant. It’s unclear if these charges would be set off too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandey told Business Standard that a favourable decision could come soon. If it does, it would completely turn the digital transactions ecosystem on its head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change of the business model for digital transactions would require many banks to come on board. NPCI data show that of the 46 public-sector banks and private banks in India, 44 are classified as “member banks” of Aadhaar Enabled Payment System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI acts against 50 illegal websites</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-acts-50-illegal-websites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It came to the notice of UIDAI that websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) has ensured that 12 websites and 12 mobile applications available on the Google Playstore are shut down and has directed to close down 26 more such fraudulent and illegal websites/applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came to the notice of UIDAI that these websites and mobile applications downloadable through Google Playstore were providing unauthorised Aadhaar related services such as downloading online Aadhaar card, providing status of Aadhaar generation, PVC Aadhaar Card, etc. and in that process they were illegally obtaining the Aadhaar number/enrolment details.
“UIDAI has not authorised the owners of these mobile applications or websites to extend any Aadhaar related services on its behalf,” said UIDAI CEO Ajay Bhushan Pandey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, “Any Aadhaar-related demographic information can only be shared following the procedures laid down in the Aadhaar Act, 2016. Any such violation is punishable under Section 38 and Chapter VII of the Aadhaar Act.”
Warning unauthorised websites and mobile applications providers against illegal use of Aadhaar logo, Pandey said, “We are contemplating stern action against them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He cautioned people to be aware against all such unscrupulous entities that provide unauthorized Aadhaar related services and asked them to remain vigilant. “www.uidai.gov.in is the only authorised website of UIDAI. Any other website with Aadhaar in its name and providing Aadhaar related services is not authorized by us and hence, illegal. We are taking stern action against all such illegal sites,” said Pandey.
In case a person loses his Aadhaar card, he/she can download his Aadhaar card free of cost from the UIDAI’s official website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper published under Creative Commons is titled ‘Information Security Practices of Aadhaar (or lack thereof): A documentation of public availability of Aadhaar Numbers with sensitive personal financial information’ and was released on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha and Kodali looked at databases on four government portals — National Social Assistance Programme, National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme, Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh and Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We chose major government programmes that use Aadhaar for payments and banking transactions. We found sensitive and personal data and information accessible on these portals,” the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaked through portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Based on the numbers available on the websites, estimated number of Aadhaar numbers leaked through these 4 portals could be around 130-135 million and the number of bank account numbers leaked at around 100 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these numbers are only from two major government programmes of pensions and rural employment schemes, other major schemes, that have also used Aadhaar for DBT, could have leaked PII similarly due to lack of information security practices,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They fear that data of over 23 crore beneficiaries under DBT of LPG subsidies could be leaked also. Identity theft and financial fraud “risks increase multifold in India…,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar payments unsafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case a financial fraud takes place through Aadhaar enabled Payment System (AePS), the consumer may not be able to assert his claims for compensation due to the terms and conditions around liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These terms force the consumer to take liabilities onto oneself than the payment provider….. Regulations and standards around Aadhaar are at a very early and nascent stage causing (an) increase in financial risk for both consumers and banks to venture into AePS,” they added. The authors also pulled up UIDAI for their inability in providing strong legislation against such leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaky govt portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Social Assistance Programme&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII available – Access to Aadhaar no., name, bank account number, account frozen status  94,32,605&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bank accounts linked with Aadhaar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14,98,919  post office accounts linked with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though total Aadhaar number is 1,56,42,083, not all are linked to bank accounts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NREGA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII Details available: Job card no., Aadhaar number, bank/postal account number, no. of days worked, registration no., account frozen status&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;78,74,315  post office accounts of individual workers seeded with Aadhaar numbers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8,24,22,161 bank accounts of individual workers with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10,96,41,502 total number of Aadhaar numbers stored by portal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other websites&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Luxurious Maharajas&#39; Express Offers Free Seats On New Routes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Railways and IRCTC have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian Railways’ super-luxury trains, which cater to various tourist circuits throughout India have long been in demand with travellers with deep pockets looking to explore the cities, towns, villages and regional areas, while travelling in style along the world’s fourth largest rail network. Expanding the network of its super-luxury trains, the Indian Railways and Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation Ltd (IRCTC) have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of their promotional campaign, the Railways are offering one free ticket on the booking of first adult on twin sharing at full cost, for the newly-introduced Maharajas’ Express circuits during monsoon period of June-July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, for a ‘Deluxe Cabin’, you can get a chance to upgrade it to a ‘Junior Suite’ by paying 50 per cent of the difference in tariff, the Railways said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the new Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express routes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two new routes have been named as ‘Southern Sojourn’ and ‘Southern Jewels’ which will cover prominent destinations in West and South India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ‘Southern Sojourn’ will cover Goa, Hampi, Mysore, Ernakulam, Kumarakom and Trivandrum. And, the ‘Southern Jewels’ will cover Chettinad, Mahabalipuram, Mysore, Hampi and Goa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both the journeys will take about 8 Days and 7 Nights and IRCTC will organize visits to monuments and sight-seeing at each destination under these trips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regular trip of ‘Southern Sojourn’ will start from Mumbai on September 9 and ‘Southern Jewels’ will start from Trivandrum on September 16.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guests on the Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express shall also have an opportunity to enjoy traditional cultural performances at Cochin, visit a Coir Factory and enjoy a cruise with lunch at Alleppey, savour traditional Chettinad Cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trains will be equipped with two restaurants, two bars, lounge, LCD TVs, direct dial phone, internet, individual temperature controls and in suite bathroom as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 23 coach long Maharajas’ Express carries only 88 guests in one trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maharajas’ Express commenced its operations in 2010, and is the recipient of the coveted Leading Luxury Train of the World Award for the last five years in a row since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indian Railways also operates a number of other luxury trains such as Fairy Queen, Heritage on Wheels, The Indian Maharaja and Splendor of South&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The booking and other details for the super-luxury trains can either be done online on the official website of Maharajas’ Express or on the official website of IRCTC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why SBI Cut Its Fixed Deposit Rates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-sbi-cut-its-fixed-deposit-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-sbi-cut-its-fixed-deposit-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;According to SBI&amp;rsquo;s new rates, for two to less than three-year deposits, the bank will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank, cut its term deposit rates in select maturities from April 29, 2017. The government&amp;rsquo;s move in November last year to withdraw Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 bank notes from the financial system led to a &amp;ldquo;huge inflow of current account and savings bank deposits&amp;rdquo;, State Bank of India (SBI) chief financial officer Anshula Kant told NDTV Profit, while explaining the rationale behind her bank&amp;rsquo;s decision to lower its deposit rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Post-demonetisation gradually some of the deposits have started to go out of the system and roughly for us about 40 per cent of the deposits have gone out from the bank. We still have 60 per cent. That is one thing,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were not very keen to increase the MCLR (marginal cost of funds-based lending rates) at this point. As cost of deposit goes up, it has an upward pressure on the MCLR as well. To maintain MCLR for our borrower customers where it is, we have tweaked the rates in certain longer deposit buckets.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marginal cost of funds-based rate is a new benchmark which banks are using for pricing their home and car loans. They add a margin above their MCLR to price retail loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to SBI&amp;rsquo;s new rates, for two to less than three-year deposits, the bank will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has not changed its marginal cost of funds-based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She further said that &amp;ldquo;there has been a slight uptick in the cost of deposits&amp;rdquo; since its mega merger last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the merger, SBI entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why not have Aadhaar ear tags for humans also?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ear-tags-humans-also/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ear-tags-humans-also/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, however, the government is grappling with a tricky issue: what to call the UID for cows? Monu says that for the time being, they are calling it “Aadhaar-like” (instead of Aadhaar) because some right-wing cows took exception to their UID number being referred to by the same name as “the despicable surveillance operation unleashed on humans”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I confess I’m with the cows on this. There are sound reasons why the cow UID should not be referred to as Aadhaar. First of all, unlike humans, cows are not required to share their hoof prints or get their irises scanned, which I think is a fair move by the government aimed at protecting the dignity and privacy of the cow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, cows don’t need to authenticate their identity with their UID number in order to access their midday meals. This, too, is a fair decision, as it would be both petty and cruel to starve a cow just because it doesn’t have an UID number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given these critical differences from the Aadhaar, the UID for cows deserves its own name. My milkman Thodappam Kher (not related to any bald celebrity) says the Home Ministry may end up calling it ‘Cowdhaar’. Not a bad choice, though I would have simply gone with ‘Moo’, which is easier to pronounce for cows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>