<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/unique-identification-authority-of-india-uidai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>135 million Aadhaar numbers leaked by govt agencies, reveals new report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/million-aadhaar-numbers-leaked-govt-agencies-reveals-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lack of information security practices in key government websites which hosts Personally Identifiable Information (PII) has left citizens of the country more vulnerable to identity theft and financial fraud, a research paper has argued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paper by Amber Sinha and Srinivas Kodali of Centre for Internet and Society analysed four government websites and found that more than 13 crore Aadhaar numbers with related PII were available on the websites, exposing lax security features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper published under Creative Commons is titled ‘Information Security Practices of Aadhaar (or lack thereof): A documentation of public availability of Aadhaar Numbers with sensitive personal financial information’ and was released on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha and Kodali looked at databases on four government portals — National Social Assistance Programme, National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme, Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh and Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We chose major government programmes that use Aadhaar for payments and banking transactions. We found sensitive and personal data and information accessible on these portals,” the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaked through portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Based on the numbers available on the websites, estimated number of Aadhaar numbers leaked through these 4 portals could be around 130-135 million and the number of bank account numbers leaked at around 100 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these numbers are only from two major government programmes of pensions and rural employment schemes, other major schemes, that have also used Aadhaar for DBT, could have leaked PII similarly due to lack of information security practices,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They fear that data of over 23 crore beneficiaries under DBT of LPG subsidies could be leaked also. Identity theft and financial fraud “risks increase multifold in India…,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar payments unsafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case a financial fraud takes place through Aadhaar enabled Payment System (AePS), the consumer may not be able to assert his claims for compensation due to the terms and conditions around liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These terms force the consumer to take liabilities onto oneself than the payment provider….. Regulations and standards around Aadhaar are at a very early and nascent stage causing (an) increase in financial risk for both consumers and banks to venture into AePS,” they added. The authors also pulled up UIDAI for their inability in providing strong legislation against such leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaky govt portals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Social Assistance Programme&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII available – Access to Aadhaar no., name, bank account number, account frozen status  94,32,605&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bank accounts linked with Aadhaar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14,98,919  post office accounts linked with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though total Aadhaar number is 1,56,42,083, not all are linked to bank accounts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NREGA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PII Details available: Job card no., Aadhaar number, bank/postal account number, no. of days worked, registration no., account frozen status&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;78,74,315  post office accounts of individual workers seeded with Aadhaar numbers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8,24,22,161 bank accounts of individual workers with Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10,96,41,502 total number of Aadhaar numbers stored by portal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other websites&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandranna Bima Scheme, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily Online Payment Reports website of NREGA, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Luxurious Maharajas&#39; Express Offers Free Seats On New Routes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-maharajas-express-offers-free-seats-on-new-routes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Railways and IRCTC have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian Railways’ super-luxury trains, which cater to various tourist circuits throughout India have long been in demand with travellers with deep pockets looking to explore the cities, towns, villages and regional areas, while travelling in style along the world’s fourth largest rail network. Expanding the network of its super-luxury trains, the Indian Railways and Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation Ltd (IRCTC) have announced two new circuits of their flagship luxury train Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express, this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of their promotional campaign, the Railways are offering one free ticket on the booking of first adult on twin sharing at full cost, for the newly-introduced Maharajas’ Express circuits during monsoon period of June-July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, for a ‘Deluxe Cabin’, you can get a chance to upgrade it to a ‘Junior Suite’ by paying 50 per cent of the difference in tariff, the Railways said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the new Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express routes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two new routes have been named as ‘Southern Sojourn’ and ‘Southern Jewels’ which will cover prominent destinations in West and South India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ‘Southern Sojourn’ will cover Goa, Hampi, Mysore, Ernakulam, Kumarakom and Trivandrum. And, the ‘Southern Jewels’ will cover Chettinad, Mahabalipuram, Mysore, Hampi and Goa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both the journeys will take about 8 Days and 7 Nights and IRCTC will organize visits to monuments and sight-seeing at each destination under these trips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regular trip of ‘Southern Sojourn’ will start from Mumbai on September 9 and ‘Southern Jewels’ will start from Trivandrum on September 16.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guests on the Maharajas&amp;rsquo; Express shall also have an opportunity to enjoy traditional cultural performances at Cochin, visit a Coir Factory and enjoy a cruise with lunch at Alleppey, savour traditional Chettinad Cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trains will be equipped with two restaurants, two bars, lounge, LCD TVs, direct dial phone, internet, individual temperature controls and in suite bathroom as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 23 coach long Maharajas’ Express carries only 88 guests in one trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maharajas’ Express commenced its operations in 2010, and is the recipient of the coveted Leading Luxury Train of the World Award for the last five years in a row since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indian Railways also operates a number of other luxury trains such as Fairy Queen, Heritage on Wheels, The Indian Maharaja and Splendor of South&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The booking and other details for the super-luxury trains can either be done online on the official website of Maharajas’ Express or on the official website of IRCTC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University students must have Aadhaar number to get degrees: UGC</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/university-students-must-aadhaar-number-get-degrees-ugc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Aadhaar card is going places. Places like India’s colleges and universities. In a notice issued on March 21, University Grant Commission has asked all universities in India to include Aadhaar number on a degree before it is issued to a student. The move, UGC says, will help reduce the prevalence of fake degrees and frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I request you to introduce identification mechanisms like photograph and Unique ID/Aadhaar number in students’ certificates. Such inscription, you would agree, will go a long way in uniformly marking a student’s personal identity and other associate details,” reads the notice issued to all universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news about the UGC directive comes a day after Lok Sabha passed the Finance Bill with all its amendments, making Aadhaar number a mandatory requirement for filing taxes. In fact, the Aadhaar number has to be linked with the PAN card or else the PAN card will be invalidated after July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the move sounds contrary to the Supreme Court in 2015, which noted that Aadhaar couldn’t be a mandatory requirement before the court comes out with a final decision on its validity, the government is increasingly pushing for its mandatory use. The government says that Aadhaar number can be used to check fraud, tax evasion and end corruption in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has also been seen that the government is pushing Aadhaar despite opposition and cocerns related to the safety and privacy of Aadhaar data. During Lok Sabha debate on Wednesday when a BJD MP asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley if he the government was forcing Aaadhar on people in India, the minister replied “yes, we are”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar was originally conceived as an identification number that would help the government provide subsidies directly to beneficiaries. However, over the years its character has changed. Although it wasn’t originally supposed to be an ID card, increasingly it is now used as an identity card, required for a myriad of services. Not only it has become mandatory for filling tax returns but is also the preferred tool for identity for many private services like Jio and Airtel connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why SBI Cut Its Fixed Deposit Rates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-sbi-cut-its-fixed-deposit-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-sbi-cut-its-fixed-deposit-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;According to SBI&amp;rsquo;s new rates, for two to less than three-year deposits, the bank will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank, cut its term deposit rates in select maturities from April 29, 2017. The government&amp;rsquo;s move in November last year to withdraw Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 bank notes from the financial system led to a &amp;ldquo;huge inflow of current account and savings bank deposits&amp;rdquo;, State Bank of India (SBI) chief financial officer Anshula Kant told NDTV Profit, while explaining the rationale behind her bank&amp;rsquo;s decision to lower its deposit rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Post-demonetisation gradually some of the deposits have started to go out of the system and roughly for us about 40 per cent of the deposits have gone out from the bank. We still have 60 per cent. That is one thing,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were not very keen to increase the MCLR (marginal cost of funds-based lending rates) at this point. As cost of deposit goes up, it has an upward pressure on the MCLR as well. To maintain MCLR for our borrower customers where it is, we have tweaked the rates in certain longer deposit buckets.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marginal cost of funds-based rate is a new benchmark which banks are using for pricing their home and car loans. They add a margin above their MCLR to price retail loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to SBI&amp;rsquo;s new rates, for two to less than three-year deposits, the bank will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has not changed its marginal cost of funds-based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She further said that &amp;ldquo;there has been a slight uptick in the cost of deposits&amp;rdquo; since its mega merger last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the merger, SBI entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why not have Aadhaar ear tags for humans also?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ear-tags-humans-also/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ear-tags-humans-also/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, however, the government is grappling with a tricky issue: what to call the UID for cows? Monu says that for the time being, they are calling it “Aadhaar-like” (instead of Aadhaar) because some right-wing cows took exception to their UID number being referred to by the same name as “the despicable surveillance operation unleashed on humans”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I confess I’m with the cows on this. There are sound reasons why the cow UID should not be referred to as Aadhaar. First of all, unlike humans, cows are not required to share their hoof prints or get their irises scanned, which I think is a fair move by the government aimed at protecting the dignity and privacy of the cow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, cows don’t need to authenticate their identity with their UID number in order to access their midday meals. This, too, is a fair decision, as it would be both petty and cruel to starve a cow just because it doesn’t have an UID number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given these critical differences from the Aadhaar, the UID for cows deserves its own name. My milkman Thodappam Kher (not related to any bald celebrity) says the Home Ministry may end up calling it ‘Cowdhaar’. Not a bad choice, though I would have simply gone with ‘Moo’, which is easier to pronounce for cows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>67% jump in corruption complaints; railways tops: Central Vigilance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/67-jump-in-corruption-complaints-railways-tops-cvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/67-jump-in-corruption-complaints-railways-tops-cvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Corruption complaints against various government departments jumped by a whopping 67 per cent in 2016 over the previous year, with the Railways topping the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 11,000 complaints were received against the public sector behemoth, the Central Vigilance Commission (CVC) has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its annual report tabled in Parliament recently, the probity watchdog said it received a total of 49,847 complaints in 2016, as against 29,838 in 2015 &amp;ndash; an increase of 67 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Commission received a considerable number of complaints against public servants working in the state governments and other organisations who do not come under the jurisdiction of the Commission or which are of administrative nature,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of complaints received by the CVC in 2015 were 50 per cent less than a total of 62,363 received by it in 2014. The CVC had got 31,432 and 37,039 complaints of alleged corruption during 2013 and 2012 respectively, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving details, the CVC said the highest of 11,200 such complaints were against railway employees. Of these 8,852 were disposed of and 2,348 were pending. Further, a total of 1,054 complaints against railway employees were pending for more than six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of complaints against those under government of National Capital Territory of Delhi has declined with a total of 969 received last year as against 5,139 in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many as 6,513 complaints of alleged corruption were received against employees under Home Ministry, followed by 6,018 bank officials and 2,496 related to those working with the Ministry of Petroleum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 2,646 corruption complaints were received against officials of the Income Tax department, 2,514 against those in Urban Development Ministry and 2,393 related to employees working under Telecommunication Ministry, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 1,746 corruption complaints against employees under Labour Ministry, 1,668 in Food and Consumer Affairs department, 1,420 of customs and excise, 1,376 in public sector insurance companies and 1,369 against officials of Ministry of Steel, the CVC said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 759 complaints were against Coal Ministry employees, 724 of Information and Broadcasting Ministry, 689 in Defence, 571 related to employees of Health and Family Welfare department and 479 against officials of Shipping Ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards to be linked with university degrees, certificates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-to-be-linked-with-university-degrees-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-to-be-linked-with-university-degrees-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The proposal is currently under consideration by the &lt;em&gt;ministry of human resource development (MHRD)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to prevent forgery of university degrees and certificates in future, the University Grants Commission (UGC) is planning to link the Aadhaar card number and print the student’s photograph on the degree/certificate from next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposal is currently under consideration by the ministry of human resource development (MHRD). If the proposal gets approved, the commission would issue directions to the universities and educational institutions for the same by next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After receiving fraud degree-related complaints, the MHRD had sought suggestions from the UGC to tackle this issue. So, in the beginning of this month, the commission suggested a proposal of printing the Aadhaar card number and photograph of the student mandatorily on the degrees,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the proposal, having an Aadhar card number will not only prevent forgery, but will also make it easier to store the degrees in a digital format in the National Academic Depositary (NAD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The students will then just have to mention their Aadhaar card number, after which they will be able to access the degree/certificate from anywhere. If the experiment is successful for the universities, then the same will be implemented for Class 10 and 12,” the source added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar number with bank accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-number-bank-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Account holders with banks have been asked to link their accounts with their Aadhaar number and also provide mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead Bank Manager A. Sakthivel held a discussion with the representatives of all banks here on Monday to encourage their customers to provide the Aadhaar number and mobile phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A communication from the Union Finance Ministry said that only 44 per cent of the bank customers had provided their Aadhaar numbers. Similarly, the banks have mobile numbers of only 75 per cent of their account holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar numbers are mandatory for digital transactions. Hence, the customers had been asked to provide a self-attested photocopy of Aadhar card with their mobile number and account number, said Mr. Sakthivel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Aadhaar With PAN Made Mandatory: How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/linking-aadhaar-with-pan-made-mandatory-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the government insists that one&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar account and Permanent Account Number (PAN) should be linked by July 31 this year to pay income taxes, millions of Indians have faced issues with syncing the two accounts due to small differences in how their names are spelt. This problem can happen even if there are minor differences in how the name is recorded &amp;ndash; like the use of one&amp;rsquo;s full name in PAN and initials in Aadhaar. Issues have also cropped up due to use of special characters in the initials and punctuation that often form a person&amp;rsquo;s name as Aadhaar doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize such characters but PAN does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such cases, while one solution is to apply for a name correction in either Aadhaar or PAN card - both time consuming procedures - the government has stepped in to provide a simple solution for frustrated potential taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If an individual&amp;rsquo;s name on the Aadhaar does not match his/her name on the PAN card, the person can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A taxpayer can also log in to the Aadhaar website and request for a change in the name which will be verified using a one-time password on the phone number registered with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One-Time Passwords (OTP) will be used in cases where there are people who have gotten married and changed their surname. In such instances the tax department will give an OTP option wherein the password would be sent to the Aadhaar-registered mobile number. The tax department, on its part, would&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;match the year of birth of the taxpayer with the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department is also planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for OTP, provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tax department will start educating taxpayers from this week through media outreach on ways to link the PAN with Aadhaar, an official told news agency Press Trust of India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.08 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN, but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people. As per statistics with the tax department, only six crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar cards for kids now made easy by govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-cards-kids-now-made-easy-govt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worried in getting Aadhaar cards for your children? Need not anymore. Head to the common service centre recognised by Department of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India at 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, where it is done exclusively for children below five years from Mondays to Saturdays this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ‘News Today’, H Moorthy of MGM e-Governance Services said, ”We are doing Aadhaar card enrollment for newborns to children below five years. Parents either father or mother has come to with the child. He/she has to bring Aadhaar card and childs birth certificate. The child would be photographed and the fingerprint of the parent will be taken. After three to four days, the Aadhaar number would be generated and communicated to the parents mobile number. They can download them and take a print out after paying the due amount.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said the biometric (fingerprint and iris) and demographic (area, address) details of children will be collected when they are between six and years old. “Later, when they attain 15 years, there would be another updation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two operators to enroll details of the children and this will go on till this month end. “From March, we will enroll for seniors,” Moorthy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools can also make use of the opportunity, where we are ready to enroll them for Aadhaar card. Around 100 children can be covered per day,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MGM e-Governance Services Centre is located at No 3, 16th Avenue, Ashok Nagar (Opposite to Velankanni Matriculation School).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar to be mandatory for driving licence, effective from October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-driving-licence-effective-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As per an order issued by the central government, Aadhaar card will become mandatory for issuance of fresh driving licences or for renewal of the same. This rule will come into effect starting October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind the move is to eradicate the issuance of multiple driving licences across different states. It will help the government to enforce traffic regulations more effectively as drivers won’t have multiple driving licences to fall back on, which isn’t an uncommon practice in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linking Aadhaar card to the driver’s licence will enable the government to maintain a centralised database (known as Sarathi). Regional Transport Offices (RTO) from all over the country can log on and instantly check whether the applicant of a driver’s licence has another one in any other part of the country. The National Informatics Centre (NIC) has already uploaded almost all the data available in RTOs across the country on to the common database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union Road Transport Ministry is currently briefing the state governments about the changes that will eventually be incorporated in the process of issuing a driver’s licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This briefing also talks about citizens who do not have an Aadhaar card issued to their name. In that case, he/she will have to submit multiple documents, although it is unclear what those additional documents will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State governments across the nation have come up with hefty penalties for breaking traffic laws and regulations. One such penalty in many states is the confiscation of driver’s licence for a few months or indefinitely, depending on the severity of the law broken.  This move will will surely force citizens to take traffic laws a lot more seriously once their licences are linked to Sarathi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving sans licence to cost 900% more</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/motor-vehicles-amendment-bill-2016-driving-sans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Vehicles Amendment Bill 2016 has raised fines significantly to make roads safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill passed by the Lok Sabha last week makes Aadhaar mandatory for driving licences and vehicle registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It proposes alterations in vehicles, in order to make them suitable for specially abled people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It provides for a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund, which would provide compulsory insurance cover to all road users in India for certain types of accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers state governments to specify a multiplier, not less than one and not greater than 10, to be applied to each fine under this Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors, consultants and civic agencies will be accountable for faulty design, construction or poor maintenance of roads leading to accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A time limit of six months has been specified for an application of compensation to the Claims Tribunal with regard to road accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drive-safe-pay-less&#34;&gt;DRIVE SAFE, PAY LESS&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/traffic.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very soon, you can do “iris” Aadhaar authentication from your smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-can-iris-aadhaar-authentication-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheap in-built iris scanners will eradicate use of costly ones for mass adoption of Aadhaar verification.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID Inc., a consumer-grade iris scanning technology provider for mobile phones, proposed the introduction of iris integrated mobile phones as a cost-effective way of reducing the failure rates in Aadhaar biometric authentication, as recently reported in MGNREGA tests in Telangana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe iris integrated smartphones and tablets will address the issues reported with Aadhaar biometric authentication. The UIDAI and the worldwide biometric community have tested and found iris to have better reliability. We are confident the failure rates will be drastically lower once the cheaper iris integrated mobile devices are adopted in the market,” said Dr. Salil Prabhakar, President and CEO, Delta ID Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the government mandating the use of Aadhaar biometric authentication in more spheres of the society, the need for a biometric modality that works reliably is critical. Unlike fingerprints that are being reported to show high failure rates due to wear and tear, the iris, being a protected internal organ, is expected to be significantly more reliable. Additionally, since the iris is not affected with age, it works reliably across all age groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key impediments in the large-scale roll out of iris for Aadhaar has been the high cost of iris devices. This is being addressed with the rollout of iris integrated mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this regard, Samsung partnered with Delta ID to launch India’s first iris integrated tablet in May 2016. The technology is arriving in smartphones too, and not only in high end devices such as Samsung Galaxy S8, but also in low cost smartphones developed by Indian manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID’s ActiveIRIS technology passed the Standardisation Testing and Quality Certification’s (STQC) FRR test with better than 99 percent accuracy, and has been certified by the STQC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active IRIS and a combination of STQC-certified hardware components can be integrated by any mobile device to expeditiously introduce iris integrated mobile devices in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Mobile Users Will Have To Go For Aadhar Verification Soon, Says Industry Body</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-mobile-users-will-have-to-go-for-aadhar-verification-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All existing subscribers of mobile services will have to go for Aadhaar-based re-verification soon, with the government instructing telecom operators to initiate the process. Cellular operators&amp;rsquo; body COAI said its members may meet this week to discuss the modalities of rolling out the verification process for the existing one billion-plus mobile phone users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;all licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (pre-paid and post-paid) through Aadhaar-based eKYC process&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; a notification issued by the telecom department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further added that all licensees will have to inform existing subscribers &amp;ndash; through advertisements in print and electronic media as well as SMS &amp;ndash; about the order of the Supreme Court for re- verification activity. They have also been asked to upload the details of the exercise on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court, in an order in February this year, had observed that, &amp;ldquo;an effective process has been evolved to ensure the identity verification, as well as, the addresses of all mobile phone subscribers for the new subscribers. In the near future, and more particularly within one year from today, a similar verification will be completed, in case of existing subscribers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom department has said the operators will use and share common device eco-system through mutual agreements, and will work out mechanisms to avoid public inconvenience and long queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, cellular operators association COAI said that the industry supported the move, but pointed out that the entire exercise will cost Rs. 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated timeframe of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For re-verification through Aadhaar-based eKYC process, the operator will send a verification code to the mobile number of the subscriber. Prior to starting the eKYC, the operator will verify this code from the subscriber so as to confirm the SIM card of the mobile connection is physically available with the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After the completion of the eKYC process, before updating or overwriting the old subscriber detail in database with the data received through eKYC process, the licensee will seek confirmation from the subscriber about the re-verification of his/her mobile number after 24 hours through SMS,&amp;rdquo; the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator can re-verify more than one mobile connection in one service area through a single eKYC but not bulk connections. For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification of a subscriber would not be required in case of conversions - that is pre-paid to postpaid connections or vice versa, it clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not compulsory for obtaining marriage certificate: CIC to Govt</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-compulsory-obtaining-marriage-certificate-cic-govt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Chief Information Commission has asked the government and marriage registration authorities to raise awareness and provide publicity through various media that Aadhaar is not compulsory for the purpose of marriage registration scheme, reports LiveLaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commission ruled that the compulsory registration of marriages helps tackle various issues like child marriage, marriage without consent, bigamous marriages, etc., and as such, the government should make it easier and more convenient to facilitate the registration, by not requiring other documents like Aadhaar and making changes for online application for marriage under the Special Marriage Act etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CIC cited Supreme Court’s order from 2014, which ruled that the government should not restrict social benefits to those who are yet to receive their Aadhaar card. Last year, the SC had also said that the card scheme is purely voluntary and cannot be made mandatory for scholarships. However, contrary to its prior stance, the SC asked the Government to link all mobile numbers with Aadhaar card details within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;centre-s-push-to-increase-aadhaar-saturation&#34;&gt;Centre’s push to increase Aadhaar saturation?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usage of Aadhaar as a verification system has been on the rise where multiple services including the IIT JEE, employee provident funds, PDS food grain purchases, RTE admissions and Jharkhand’s food and public distribution systems also using it. Private companies have also started using Aadhaar for verification purposes, such as iris scans by DCB Bank for eKYC, Microsoft’s Skype Lite which supports Aadhaar based verification, etc. However, use of Aadhaar by making it compulsory to avail some services, has come under heavy criticism for not respecting user privacy or being very secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>