<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Technology on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latest Technology on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>18 specified financial transactions in which quoting of PAN is mandatory now</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</guid>
      <description>Although Aadhaar is gradually gaining more importance than PAN – a ten-digit unique alphanumeric number issued by the Income Tax Department – however, PAN is still important, especially for financial transactions. According to experts, PAN is a way for the Income Tax Department to keep tabs on your financial dealings whereas Aadhaar’s main purpose is to create a centralized database of each citizen residing in India. PAN, in fact, is a very useful tool to estimate the total tax revenue being generated in the country and to be used as an identification document is not its primary job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 financial tasks to do when a parent dies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</guid>
      <description>Goodbyes are the hardest when they are final. It’s worse if it involves one of your parents. The heartbreak is probably lesser in intensity only to that of your surviving parent, the spouse who is left grappling with a crippling emotional void at the fag end of life. Yet, it is critical to take a financial reality check and you, as progeny, are the best suited to do it.
Taking stock of the finances is an overwhelming task and it’s easy to be stumped by the maze of formalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get 224 GB For Rs. 509:Jio Releases New Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</guid>
      <description>As Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s promotional offers - Jio Summer Surprise and Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan - will expire for most users this month, the telecom operator has launched a new offer that provides customers up to 224 GB of 4G data along with other freebies. This comes as part of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive push to gain market share from entrenched players like Bharti Airtel and Vodafone. Jio&amp;rsquo;s new offer replaces its recharge packs priced Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to enrol your children for Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-enrol-your-children-for-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-enrol-your-children-for-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>After all the Aadhaar-PAN hype most people know how important Aadhaar is and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be incorrect to say that financial life in the future is going to be difficult without it.
As of now it is not mandatory for kids to possess an Aadhaar, but there&amp;rsquo;s no harm in enrolling them for the same. It could just make their life easier in the coming years. There would be instances when your child would be required to furnish a proof of identity, and Aadhaar could be of great help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.
Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 5 Recharge, Vodafone Offers Unlimited Data.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-s-special-campus-plan-1gb-per-day-at-rs-352/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-s-special-campus-plan-1gb-per-day-at-rs-352/</guid>
      <description>Locked in a fierce price war with Reliance Jio, Vodafone is targeting students with a new scheme that will offer unlimited calls with 1 gigabyte of 4G/3G data every day for 84 days, the company said in a press release. Under its Campus Survival Kit, Vodafone is offering many campus hacks to save pocket-money and a trendy messenger bag free. Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s offer comes a week after Reliance Jio announcing a new recharge priced at Rs 399, in which it is offering 84 GBs of 4G data for 84 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if you miss the Income Tax Return deadline on August 5: Here’s what to do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-if-you-miss-the-income-tax-return-deadline-on-august-5-heres/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-if-you-miss-the-income-tax-return-deadline-on-august-5-heres/</guid>
      <description>If you miss the extended deadline for filing I-T returns you can still do it till March 31 next year for assessment year 2017-18, though you cannot revise the return nor carry forward losses.
While the government has extended the last date for filing income tax returns to August 5 because of some technical glitches, if an assessee still misses the deadline, it does not mean that he cannot file his tax returns for the assessment year 2017-18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is exempt from PAN card Aadhaar card linking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link the existing Aadhaar numbers with the PAN cards of taxpayers with effect from July 1, 2017. In fact, Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar / Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from 1st July, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your company tracking what you type? Here’s how your company might be monitoring you at work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-employer-tracking-what-you-type-heres-how-your-company-might/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/your-employer-tracking-what-you-type-heres-how-your-company-might/</guid>
      <description>Are you dodging work at your current company? Beware, your low productivity might be getting tracked by your employer. But is keylogging legal? While internet logs are checked by many companies worldwide, there is a new trend where bosses might have been installing keyloggers on the office computers. According to reports, a German company decided to install a keylogging software on the PCs at the workplace. After this one of the employees were thrown out because he was found to be playing a computer game but for another company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government may hike BHIM referral bonus from Rs 10 to Rs 25</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-may-hike-bhim-referral-bonus-from-rs-10-to-rs-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-may-hike-bhim-referral-bonus-from-rs-10-to-rs-25/</guid>
      <description>Banks and the National Payments Corporation of India have asked the finance ministry to increase the referral bonus on payments app BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) since it has failed to attract consumers. The government is considering the request and may announce revised incentives soon.
Any person who refers BHIM to another gets Rs 10 as an incentive and the person who starts using it gets Rs 25 as an initiating cashback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.
The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said. The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to file income tax return for tax refunds and what precautions to take</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/claim-income-tax-refund-how-to-file-income-tax-return-for-tax-refunds-and-what-precautions-to-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/claim-income-tax-refund-how-to-file-income-tax-return-for-tax-refunds-and-what-precautions-to-take/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes an individual ends up paying more tax to the government than his/her actual tax liability. In such a scenario the individual becomes eligible for a tax refund. The government allows individuals to claim income tax refund while filing income tax return. An individual should make a point to understand the whole process in order to claim his/her tax refund from the tax authorities.
Having said so, there are several situations where a person becomes eligible for the same:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.
Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 500 4G VoLTE Reliance  jio handset</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-rs-500-4g-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-rs-500-4g-phone/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is likely to launch its much-awaited 4G VoLTE feature phone within this month, with brokerage HSBC putting the price at as low as Rs 500, a move which could bring in another wave of disruption in the telecom market.
The launch — which some believe could be announced at parent Reliance Industries’ annual general meeting on July 21— would follow Jio’s likely announcement of a new tariff plan with aggressive price-points over the next couple of days with its 84-day Dhan Dhana Dhan offer — announced on April 11 — drawing to a close, people familiar with the matter said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Rooted’ Phones May Soon Have No Place In Modi’s Cashless India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rooted-phones-may-soon-no-place-modis-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rooted-phones-may-soon-no-place-modis-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>India is considering a ban on smartphones with modified firmware from all of its cashless payment platforms due to security concerns, according to the chief of National Payments Corporation of India which manages all retail payment systems in the country. “These smartphones have a certain degree of vulnerability in the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), the Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) or any kind of financial system”, AP Hota, chief executive officer and managing director of NPCI told BloombergQuint.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>