<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Technology on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latest Technology on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much To Save A Day To Become A Crorepati. You Will Be Surprised!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-to-save-a-day-to-become-a-crorepati-you-will-be-surprised/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-to-save-a-day-to-become-a-crorepati-you-will-be-surprised/</guid>
      <description>Accumulating a corpus of Rs. 1 crore is a dream for many. But many individuals who are in their early twenties don&amp;rsquo;t follow a systematic investment habit, thinking that they will start when they earn more. But you will be surprised to know that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to save a lot of money every month to accumulate Rs. 1 crore, provided you start early.
   Time 6% 8% 10% 12%     20 Years Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI Says New Rs. 50 Notes Coming Shortly: Five Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-says-new-rs-50-notes-coming-shortly-five-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-says-new-rs-50-notes-coming-shortly-five-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Just a month after the announcement of new Rs. 20 notes in the Mahatma Gandhi Series-2005, Reserve Bank of India (RBI) on Friday said that it will also bring new Rs. 50 banknotes shortly in circulation. The new Rs. 50 notes will be in the Mahatma Gandhi (New) Series, bearing signatures of RBI governor Urjit R Patel, the central bank said in a press release. With &amp;ldquo;Fluorescent Blue&amp;rdquo; as the base colour, the new note &amp;ldquo;has motif of Hampi with Chariot on the reverse,&amp;rdquo; it added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airtel Rs 399 recharge vs Reliance Jio Rs 399 plan: 1GB per day and unlimited calling plan</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-399-recharge-vs-reliance-jio-rs-399-plan-1gb-per-day-and-unlimited-calling-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-399-recharge-vs-reliance-jio-rs-399-plan-1gb-per-day-and-unlimited-calling-plan/</guid>
      <description>Airtel has come up with a new Rs 399 offer for its customers. This offer is valid only for prepaid users. According to the new tariff, prepaid users can avail 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days at Rs 399. Apart from the data offers, Airtel will also provide unlimited calls (both local and STD) on all networks under this Rs 399 plan. This offer appears to be a direct effort by Airtel to take on rival Jio, as the latter has an almost similar plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM App: Cashback Scheme For Merchants Gets Extension Till March</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-cashback-scheme-for-merchants-gets-extension-till-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-cashback-scheme-for-merchants-gets-extension-till-march/</guid>
      <description>The government has extended till March a cashback scheme that offers incentives of up to Rs. 1,000 to merchants for accepting payments through mobile application BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money). &amp;ldquo;The BHIM cashback scheme for merchants will be operational till March 31, 2018,&amp;rdquo; a note by Ministry of Electronics and IT said. The scheme was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on April 14 for a period of six months for promoting cashless payments through the BHIM app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking Gas (LPG) Price Hiked By Rs. 7 Per Cylinder, ATF By 4%</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cooking-gas-lpg-price-hiked-by-rs-7-per-cylinder-atf-by-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cooking-gas-lpg-price-hiked-by-rs-7-per-cylinder-atf-by-4/</guid>
      <description>Subsidised cooking gas (LPG) price was today raised by over Rs. 7 per cylinder, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to hike prices every month so that all subsidises are eliminated by this fiscal-end.
A subsidised 14.2-kg LPG cylinder now costs Rs. 487.18 in Delhi as against Rs. 479.77 previously, according to Indian Oil Corporation, the nation&amp;rsquo;s largest fuel retailer.
Oil Minister Dharmendra Pradhan had on July 31 told the Lok Sabha that the government had asked state-owned oil companies to raise subsidised cooking gas (LPG) prices by Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Extends Aadhaar-Pan Linking Deadline To December 31</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-extends-aadhaar-pan-linking-deadline-by-four-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-extends-aadhaar-pan-linking-deadline-by-four-months/</guid>
      <description>In a relief to scores of taxpayers, the government on Thursday extended the deadline for linking income tax permanent account number (PAN) with Aadhaar by four months to December 31, according to news agency Press Trust of India. August 31, Thursday, was supposed to be the last day for linking of Aadhaar and PAN cards. People who do not have Aadhaar can file their Income Tax returns, but their returns will not be processed till they submit their Aadhaar number, PTI reported quoting a source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Rules On Mutual Fund Gains Explained In 10 Point</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-on-mutual-fund-sip-gain-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-on-mutual-fund-sip-gain-profit/</guid>
      <description>The asset under management of Indian mutual fund industry touched record high of Rs 20 lakh crore in July, driven by strong inflows into both debt and equity segments. Retail investors have been pumping record amount into mutual funds through SIPs. It is estimated that investors are putting in nearly Rs 5,000 crore every month through SIPs. Systematic Investment Plan or SIP as it is commonly known, is an investment plan offered by mutual funds, wherein one could invest a fixed amount in a mutual fund scheme at fixed intervals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PPF Withdrawal, Loan, Transfer And Other Rules In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ppf-public-provident-fund-rules-interest-rate-withdrawal-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ppf-public-provident-fund-rules-interest-rate-withdrawal-loan/</guid>
      <description>Despite falling interest rates, PPF (public provident fund) remains one of the popular small savings schemes. Interest rate on PPF and other small savings scheme are being reset every quarter from April last year, as compared to the annual mode earlier. Investors in PPF currently get an interest rate of 7.8 per cent. The interest rate on PPF and other small savings schemes are benchmarked to yields on government bonds, with a small mark-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 200 Notes To Be Ramped Up: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/supply-of-rs-200-notes-to-be-ramped-up-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/supply-of-rs-200-notes-to-be-ramped-up-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>In order to smoothen the process of lower denomination transactions, Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has introduced new Rs. 200 notes. The Reserve Bank, earlier, stated that the production of the new notes will be increased as currently the Rs. 200 notes are only available through select RBI offices and banks. &amp;ldquo;The production of these notes (Rs. 200) is being ramped up by the currency printing presses and over time as more notes are printed, it will be distributed across the country through the banking channels and will be available for public in adequate quantity,&amp;rdquo; RBI said in a statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18 specified financial transactions in which quoting of PAN is mandatory now</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</guid>
      <description>Although Aadhaar is gradually gaining more importance than PAN – a ten-digit unique alphanumeric number issued by the Income Tax Department – however, PAN is still important, especially for financial transactions. According to experts, PAN is a way for the Income Tax Department to keep tabs on your financial dealings whereas Aadhaar’s main purpose is to create a centralized database of each citizen residing in India. PAN, in fact, is a very useful tool to estimate the total tax revenue being generated in the country and to be used as an identification document is not its primary job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 financial tasks to do when a parent dies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</guid>
      <description>Goodbyes are the hardest when they are final. It’s worse if it involves one of your parents. The heartbreak is probably lesser in intensity only to that of your surviving parent, the spouse who is left grappling with a crippling emotional void at the fag end of life. Yet, it is critical to take a financial reality check and you, as progeny, are the best suited to do it.
Taking stock of the finances is an overwhelming task and it’s easy to be stumped by the maze of formalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI ATM Withdrawal Rules And Charges For Other Services</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-atm-withdrawal-rules-and-charges-for-other-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-atm-withdrawal-rules-and-charges-for-other-services/</guid>
      <description>State Bank of India or SBI has in recent months revised its charges on various services like ATM withdrawal , cash transactions, issuance of cheque books, exchange of soiled notes and online transfer of funds through Immediate Payment Service (IMPS). SBI has clarified that customers of its mobile wallet State Bank Buddy will be charged 3 per cent plus GST of 18 per cent on transfer from Buddy to bank account using IMPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Reduces Term Deposit Rates By Up To 0.5%</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</guid>
      <description>SBI said the rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.
Country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India has cut its term deposit rates by up to 50 basis points for various maturities.
The rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.
According to the new structure, for two to less than three years deposits, SBI will offer a rate of 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.
The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.
Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>