<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want A New Jio SIM? Here&#39;s What You Pay To Get &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in getting a new Reliance Jio SIM and availing the &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer? Rs 408 is the minimum amount you need to spend. For Jio non-Prime and new users, the recharge amount is Rs 309 along with an additional Rs 99. Similarly, to get the Rs 509 plan, the amount needed will be Rs 608.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has extensively provided free data services with unlimited calls for several months and with the telecom operator starting paid services, one can expect the firm to provide the &amp;lsquo;most affordable&amp;rsquo; plans. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rs. 408 is the minimum amount needed to avail Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has provided free services with unlimited calls for last few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has been in the controversy for stretching its free trial run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-dhan.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बिजली बिल: आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को जरूरी सेवाओं के लिए अनिवार्य किए जाने का मामला अभी सुप्रीम कोर्ट में लंबित है। इस बीच बिजली बिल के भुगतान को भी आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी शुरू कर दी गई है। केंद्र सरकार ने राज्यों से बिजली के बिलों का डिजिटल भुगतान आधार से जुड़े बैंक खातों के माध्यम से सुनिश्चित करने को कहा है। केंद्रीय ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा है कि बिजली बिल को आधार से जोड़ना ग्राहकों के लिए फायदेमंद साबित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;राज्यों और केंद्र शासित प्रदेशों के ऊर्जा और खदान मंत्रियों की कॉन्फ्रेंस में गोयल ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह जरूरी नहीं है, लेकिन सभी के हित में है क्योंकि अगर आप बिल का भुगतान डिजिटल माध्यम से करेंगे तो आपके पास यह ठीक-ठीक सबूत होगा कि आपने बिल का भुगतान किया है। यह पहल जनता को मदद करेगी और इस संबंध में कोशिश की जानी चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि इसका फैसला राज्यों को लेना है कि वे बिजली बिलों के भुगतान की प्रणाली को आधार से जुड़े खातों से जोड़ें या नहीं, लेकिन निश्चित तौर पर यह कहा जा सकता है कि यह ग्राहकों के हित में है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि सरकार ने हाल में आयकर रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को जरूरी कर दिया है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट में भी सरकार ने अपनी तरफ से साफ किया है कि पैन नंबर के जरिए होने वाले फ्रॉड को रोकने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य किया जाना जरूरी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गोयल ने यह भी कहा कि सरकार राज्यों को बिजली आवंटन के मसौदे को फिर तैयार कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम फॉर्म्युले पर काम कर रहे हैं। हम इस बात पर फिर से विचार कर रहे हैं कि हम इसे (पावर आवंटन पॉलिसी) किस तरह मजबूत बना सकते हैं। फिलहाल गाडगिल फॉर्म्युले पर बिजली का बंटवारा होता है। इसके तहत राज्यों के प्लान के लिए केंद्रीय मदद के लिए नियम और शर्तों को तय किया जाता है। उनका यह भी कहना था कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा बिजली उन को दी जाएगी, जो न्यूक्लियर प्लांट्स स्थापित करने को बढ़ावा देंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिजली के कमर्शल नुकसान में गिरावट और कॉस्ट की बेहतर कवरेज से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन कंपनियों में मामूली बेहतरी से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रिब्यूशन कंपनियों के ऑपरेशनल परफॉर्मेंस में सुधार हुआ है। पावर फाइनेंस कॉर्पोरेशन (PFC) की एक रिपोर्ट में यह बात कही गई है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Imposes Fee On Cheque Payments For Credit Card Dues. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card is levying a charge on payments made by cheques. This came into effect from April 1, according to SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s website. The card company said payments made below Rs 2,000 through cheques will attract a fee of Rs 100. &amp;ldquo;A fee of Rs.100 will be charged for payments made by cheque for an amount less than or equal to Rs.2000 w.e.f. 1st April &amp;lsquo;17. No additional fee will be charged for cheque payments greater than Rs. 2000,&amp;rdquo; SBI Card said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen that the majority of payments (over 90 per cent) are made through non-cheque modes. We have observed a trend of payment related disputes arising in small cheque payments, causing inconvenience to customers as well. We offer several seamless digital modes of payment which we are seeking to encourage, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s focus towards digital payments and this step will facilitate the same,&amp;rdquo; said SBI Card CEO Vijay Jasuja.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, payments made through SBI cheques will not incur the extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost. It is also likely to provide a boost to digital payments. SBI, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, entered credit card business in 1998 by roping GE Capital India, the consumer finance arm of US-based GE Capital. SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s latest offering &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; is targeted at all State Bank of India customers, including Jan Dhan account holders throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has introduced the &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; card in an effort to bring new users into the fold of cashless transactions. The card is issued to persons with a balance of Rs 25,000 in their SBI accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No such charge on cheque payments will be levied on holders of SBI Card Unnati which is targeted at first time credit card users and aimed at inclusion of people into the organised financial stream,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jasuja added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 5G on Trial Samsung Network </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arqiva-and-samsung-to-trial-5g-network-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arqiva-and-samsung-to-trial-5g-network-in-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung has already undertaken some early tests of the technology on its campus in South Korea, and mobile operators and vendors have announced 5G trials in countries ranging from the United States to Japan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communications group Arqiva and Samsung Electronics will trial Britain&amp;rsquo;s first 5G network in London this year, the companies said, with the capability of delivering ultra-fast broadband to mobile devices and potentially autonomous vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advent of the fifth generation of mobile telecoms is viewed as essential to expected growth in demand for ever-higher speeds, capacity and reliability, with global operators such as Vodafone, Telefonica and Verizon working with network equipment makers to develop the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arqiva, which provides TV broadcast and mobile infrastructure, said the fixed wireless access network would operate in its own 28GHz band spectrum using Samsung&amp;rsquo;s 5G base stations and equipment installed in premises in central London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Over time, smarter network infrastructure and an enhanced ability to support exponential scale for connectivity will open the doors to further applications across a variety of markets such as IoT (Internet of Things), industrial applications and the full promise of autonomous vehicles,&amp;rdquo; Arqiva Chief Executive Simon Beresford-Wylie said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung has already undertaken some early tests of the technology on its campus in South Korea, and mobile operators and vendors have announced 5G trials in countries ranging from the United States to Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arqiva, which counts the Canada Pension Plan Investment Board and Macquarie as investors, is considering a stock market listing and is seeking new investors, sources said this month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>200 Airports To Be Brought Under UDAN Scheme: Jayanta Sinha</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jayanta Sinha said government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central government has embarked upon a plan to bring 200 airports under the regional air connectivity scheme, Union Minister of State for Aviation Jayanta Sinha said here today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Under the UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) regional air connectivity scheme, 33 airports have been already included since its launch last year in addition to 75 taking the total to 108. We intend to take the number to 200,&amp;rdquo; Mr Sinha said at an interaction at Bharat Chamber of Commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this, we will have multiple rounds of bidding, he said, adding the government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Sinha said so far the subsidy burden was only Rs 200 crore and 13 lakh seats have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pointing out that regional air connectivity was both pro-poor and pro-markets, he said that this twin objective had been met by offering seats at Rs 2,500 per seat per hour of flying and reducing the cost of flying by bringing down the costs of ATF and service charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding Bagdogra airport in West Bengal, he said talks were on for getting land with the state government for building a new modern terminal. He said that all greenfield airports would be built through the PPP route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding unruly behaviour while flying it is expected that both passengers and the cabin crew would adhere with the laid-down guidelines, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Pension Fund To Go Digital On Payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-pension-fund-to-go-digital-on-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-pension-fund-to-go-digital-on-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The EPFO has over four crore subscribers and receives 1 crore claims every year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labour ministry has amended the social security schemes run by the retirement fund body EPFO to enable it to make all payments &amp;ndash; pension, provident fund and insurance &amp;ndash; to members electronically. &amp;ldquo;The labour ministry has amended the schemes run by the EPFO by a notification. This will enable the Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) to make all payments like EPF and pension through digital mode,&amp;rdquo; an official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was provided in the schemes run by the EPFO that the body can make payments to its subscribers through various modes like money order, cheques or electronically. The official said, &amp;ldquo;The scheme has been completely amended and the provision of making payments through money order or cheques has been omitted from the schemes. Thus all payments would be made through electronic mode.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining further, the official said, &amp;ldquo;Though the EPFO had been making 98 per cent of its payments through electronic mode, there were some field offices which were using other modes like cheque and money orders.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official also informed that the decision to go 100 per cent digital for payments, was taken after some complaints were received for ensuring complete transparency. The EPFO has over four crore subscribers and receives 1 crore claims every year including that of EPF withdrawal, pension fixation and insurance claims.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test To Check Call Drops Likely From This Month: TRAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/test-to-check-call-drops-likely-from-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/test-to-check-call-drops-likely-from-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Independent drive tests are going to begin. Actually, there was some gap (problem) which has been removed&amp;hellip;they should start probably from this month on,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom regulator Trai is likely to resume from this month its independent drive tests to check call drops and service quality of operators, after a gap of more than five months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Independent drive tests are going to begin. Actually, there was some gap (problem) which has been removed&amp;hellip;they should start probably from this month on,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the telecom operators submit performance monitoring reports to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) regularly, the regulator also undertakes audit and assessment of service quality through independent agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agencies conduct sample &amp;lsquo;drive tests&amp;rsquo; across various cities in the country, as part of audit and assessment of the operators&amp;rsquo; performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The independent drive tests are distinct from operator-assisted tests, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were doing drive tests in 11-12 cities, we will be doing it in more cities (this time). This will be different from the operator-assisted tests,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator-assisted drive test captures real-time data to monitor the level of call drops and voice quality, similar to Trai&amp;rsquo;s independent drive tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, unlike independent drive tests that are conducted by the regulator itself, the &amp;lsquo;operator-assisted&amp;rsquo; tests are conducted in co-ordination with telecom service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator-assisted tests, a new concept, involves the telecom firms&amp;rsquo; equipment and costs, with the regulator monitoring and supervising the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, all drive tests &amp;ndash; be it independent or operator-assisted tests &amp;ndash; assess the performance of networks on various quality benchmarks, including call set-up success rate, call drop, blocked calls and Radio Frequency (RF) coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last round of independent drive tests were conducted by Trai in Amritsar, Delhi, Hyderabad, Bhopal, Chandigarh, Mumbai, Lucknow, Kanpur, Ahmedabad, Ranchi, Darjeeling, Sikkim and Trivandrum in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the last few months that Trai did not undertake independent tests, the operator-assisted tests were conducted in cities including Mathura (UP-West circle), Jaisalmer, (Rajasthan), Ujjain (Madhya Pradesh) and Mangalore (Karnataka) and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the regulator and the Department of Telecom (DoT) have been keeping a vigil on service quality issues such as call drops and call failures through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort to tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of efforts to keep the call quality in check, the Trai plans to roll-out, by the month-end, an app that will enable subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call, once the call is complete. The data will, thereafter, be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to media, the senior Congress leader said there was a need to upgrade all post offices in the country with latest infrastructure since there was &amp;ldquo;vast availability of post offices&amp;hellip;one can find it in every nook and corner of the country, even in remote villages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said passports could be applied from post offices shortly, adding around 86 post offices have already started work in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation, including eight MPs, paid obeisance at the sanctum sanctorum of the Golden Temple here. They also visited the historic Jallianwala Bagh, where they paid tributes to the martyrs who had sacrificed their lives for the freedom of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation thereafter visited the Integrated Check Post (ICP) Attari/Wagah border where they held a meeting with the Custom and BSF officials in order to have a &amp;ldquo;first hand information with regard to the required infrastructure at ICP, import/export activities with Pakistan and problems faced by the officials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members also witnessed the evening beating retreat ceremony at Wagah border.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp:10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार को संजीवनी बूटी की तरह पेश कर रही सरकार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-linking-only-curb-pan-card-duplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-linking-only-curb-pan-card-duplication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को इनकम टैक्स के पर्मानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के साथ जोड़ना जरूरी करने के सरकार के कदम का विरोध कर रहे लोगों ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट से कहा कि सरकार आधार को सभी बुराइयों के लिए संजीवनी बूटी के तौर पर पेश कर रही है। आधार को PAN के साथ जोड़ने के लिए इनकम टैक्स एक्ट में संशोधन को चुनौती देने वाली याचिकाओं की सुनवाई कर रही दो जजों की बेंच से सीनियर ऐडवोकेट अरविंद पी दातार ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार उन हर्बल दवाओं में से एक बन गया है, जो सभी का उपचार कर सकती हैं&amp;hellip;आतंकवाद, ब्लैक मनी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस संशोधन के जरिए 1 जुलाई से आधार कार्ड से लिंक्ड न होने वाला PAN अवैध हो जाएगा। सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने गुरुवार को इस पर अपना फैसला सुरक्षित रखा। इससे पहले हुई सुनवाइयों में सरकार ने कानून का पक्ष लेते हुए इस बात को गलत बताया था कि इस कदम से प्रिवेसी को खतरा होगा। दातार ने गुरुवार को सरकार के इस नजरिए पर सवाल उठाया कि आधार और PAN को लिंक करने से ब्लैक मनी पर रोक लगेगी। उनका कहना था, &amp;lsquo;इससे पैन कार्ड के डुप्लिकेशन पर रोक लगेगी, ब्लैक मनी पर नहीं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;सरकार के 2005 के डेटा के अनुसार केवल 0.4 पर्सेंट PAN कार्ड डुप्लिकेटेड हैं और इसे देखते हुए इस तरह का कदम उठाना उचित नहीं है। 0.4 पर्सेंट के लिए 99.6 पर्सेंट को परेशान करने का क्या मतलब है? इस बदलाव की जरूरत दिखाने वाला नया डेटा कहां है?&amp;rsquo; उनकी दलील थी कि नए सिस्टम से वे छोटे कारोबारी बर्बाद हो जाएंगे जिनके पास किसी कारण से आधार या PAN नहीं होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि इन दोनों को लिंक न करने वाले लोग अपना इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न नहीं भर सकेंगे और इस वजह से उन्हें भारी पेनल्टी चुकानी पड़ सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दातार ने कहा कि कानून में इस तरह के महत्वपूर्ण बदलाव को लेकर संसद में कोई बहस नहीं की गई और न ही इसे एक कमेटी के पास भेजा गया है। उन्होंने बताया कि फाइनेंस बिल पर केवल एक सामान्य चर्चा हुई है। उन्होंने सरकार पर आधार को चरणों में नागरिकों पर थोपने का आरोप लगाया। उनका कहना था कि कानून में कोई भी बदलाव आधार ऐक्ट में संशोधन के जरिए किया जाना चाहिए था, इनकम टैक्स ऐक्ट में नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;याचिकाकर्ताओं ने दलील दी थी कि फिंगरप्रिंट और आइरिस स्कैन लेने वाले आधार को PAN के साथ जोड़ने से व्यक्तियों के शरीर को लेकर अधिकार का उल्लंघन हुआ है। हालांकि, इसे लेकर सरकार के वकील ने पिछले सप्ताह कहा था कि व्यक्ति का शरीर को लेकर अधिकार संपूर्ण नहीं है। सीनियर एडवोकेट सलमान खुर्शीद ने सरकार के इस नजरिए के विरोध में कहा कि कुछ मूल मानवाधिकारों को छीना नहीं जा सकता।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department has launched a massive hunt for black money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The massive hunt for undeclared cash launched across the country post demonetisation has revealed that these was either converted into gold or routed through shell companies to make it legal tender, IT sleuths have told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income Tax officials said black money holders avoided the bank-deposit route because they wanted to conceal their identities and somehow had &amp;ldquo;managed to get many jewellers&amp;rdquo; to convert their unaudited cash into gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They bought gold and jewellery from jewellers across the cities on November 8 (the night Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced the demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 currency notes from midnight) and, thereafter. Jewellers camouflaged the identities of the actual buyers and offered split bills,&amp;rdquo; an Income Tax official, who was part of the investigations, told IANS on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to him, jewellers saw in demonetisation an opportunity to ramp up their sales and thought &amp;ldquo;they could get away&amp;rdquo; by showing these amounts as sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jewellers offered a platform to convert unreported cash into gold,&amp;rdquo; the official said, adding that split bills were below the value of Rs 2 lakh, the threshold above which buyers have to provide the permanent account number (PAN) issued by the income tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The buyers&amp;rsquo; lists provided by the jewellers were false. After verification, it emerged that many of the buyers were financially weak and not in a position to spend such huge amounts shown in the invoices,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen tried to find an answer to a common question: How did jewellers meet the huge spurt in demand following the announcement of demonetisation, particularly after the festival season?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We found many of these sales were booked as advance collection for future sales. Due to preceding sales during Dhanteras and Diwali, jewellers had a stock crunch and they delivered gold later,&amp;rdquo; another IT official told IANS, asking not to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen said they have stumbled upon records which suggested many shops &amp;ndash; as many as 90 per cent across cities &amp;ndash; were closed at the time of the demonetisation announcement and sales at the day&amp;rsquo;s closing had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Still, we found sales were registered in the accounting system either on November 8 or a date prior to that after the closing sales were reported. These sales were manipulated,&amp;rdquo; another IT official said, also requesting anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sankar Sen, Chairman and MD, Senco Gold Ltd, which was one of the jewellery houses under the I-T department scanner, told IANS: &amp;ldquo;We keep records of all buyers on the basis of the names and contacts provided by the customers. We cooperated with officials and provided all the documents, including the CCTV footage that we had.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is difficult for jewellers to verify whether the customers have provided a legitimate identity or not, particularly when the sale value is less than Rs 2 lakh,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hunt for black money by the IT officials picked up after November 29 as they waited for some time to collect information from the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) or other agencies about the movement of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked how taxmen identified jewellers, an official told IANS: &amp;ldquo;The first set of information showed that jewellers deposited huge amounts of money into banks. Then, we went after jewellers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IT sleuths were able to identify legitimate transactions, easily. &amp;ldquo;We also had given options to the jewellers to disclose the name of actual buyers or declare that the amount is your money,&amp;rdquo; the official said, pointing out that such moves proved successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many actual buyers and jewellers contributed to the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY), an amnesty scheme to declare unreported wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a robust and quick information-sharing system among state and central agencies been in place, the hunt for black money would have been more effective, the officials lamented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A compilation of unique features found in transactions post-demonetisation across states is expected soon,&amp;rdquo; an IT official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Union Finance Ministry, the CBDT has detected undisclosed income of over Rs 9,334 crore between November 9, 2016, and February 28 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under Operation Clean Money (OCM), more than 60,000 persons, including 1,300 high-risk persons, have been identified for investigation into claims of excessive cash sales after demonetisation was announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to officials, shell companies provided a strong support system for black money after demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials found dummy directors of these companies included a cancer patient who signed documents for a Rs 10,000 monthly fee or charges of Rs 200 for every signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials said reporting of cash seizures was relatively less in Kolkata because of the existence of the shell companies as an established channel to stash ill-gotten money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining how active the channel was, the official said: &amp;ldquo;Many cash handlers with whom we interacted told us that the money does not stay for more than half-an-hour at a particular point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shell companies were also used as instruments to buy bullion. &amp;ldquo;We found invoices for bullion sales were generated against such companies while actual beneficiaries received the bullion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>