<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 540 Crore Black Money Detect Over In Last Fortnight by Income Tax Officials  </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/detect-over-rs-540-crore-black-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/detect-over-rs-540-crore-black-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax department has detected over Rs. 540 crore black money in the next 15 days as part of its nationwide operations to check tax evasion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the PMGKY black money window closed on March 31, the Income Tax department has detected over Rs. 540 crore black money in the next 15 days as part of its nationwide operations to check tax evasion. Officials said the tax sleuths, in the first fortnight of the new financial year that began on April 1, have conducted multiple search and survey operations on entry operators (agents using banking channels to launder funds), shell firms, government officials, real estate players and other sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per an official data compiled till April 15, the department has carried out &amp;ldquo;over 250 search and survey operations where the taxman raided at least 300 shell firms and detected more than Rs. 540 crore of black money.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action is significant as it comes after the closure of the third black money declaration window of the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), provided by the government to people holding stash funds to come clean and pay due taxes and penalty, that ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had brought the first black money declaration window in 2015 for people who held illegal assets abroad followed by the Income Declaration Scheme (IDS) last year where individuals and entities could declare their domestic black funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMGKY was brought by the government in order to check hidden money in the wake of the demonetisation that was announced by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on November 8 last
year. A senior official said three major searches were conducted in Noida near here during the said period against an entry operator who was &amp;ldquo;managing&amp;rdquo; about 200 shell firms for providing entries of bogus sale and purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;More than 20 beneficiaries who have received entries of over Rs. 1 crore have been identified and the total undisclosed income in this case is about Rs. 300 crore,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official added that a real estate broker in the national capital region, dealing in &amp;ldquo;unaccounted cash
transactions on sale of property&amp;rdquo;, was also covered by the department during the said period and tax sleuths have seized documents leading to tax evasion of more than Rs. 50 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior government official of Uttar Pradesh was also searched during the same period after which, the official said, unaccounted cash payments of Rs. 2 crore were detected while four hidden immovable properties in the name of the officer&amp;rsquo;s wife were unearthed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I-T department officials also searched an Ahmedabad-based real estate and infrastructure player where tax evasion to the tune of Rs. 120 crore has been detected, the official said, adding the investigations in this case are still on as the case involves multiple layers of bogus entities. As part of a similar search in Pune against a business group, the entity surrendered Rs. 19 crore income to the department as the black money was generated &amp;ldquo;on account of profit not recorded in the books of account.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Hyderabad-based business group engaged in digital printing was also raided by the department which led to the eizure of over Rs. 1 crore cash, the official said. The official added that these actions will continue in the coming days as after the closure of the PMGKY window all those cases where black money and tax evasion has been detected will have to be &amp;ldquo;thoroughly&amp;rdquo; investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Imposes Fee On Cheque Payments For Credit Card Dues. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card is levying a charge on payments made by cheques. This came into effect from April 1, according to SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s website. The card company said payments made below Rs 2,000 through cheques will attract a fee of Rs 100. &amp;ldquo;A fee of Rs.100 will be charged for payments made by cheque for an amount less than or equal to Rs.2000 w.e.f. 1st April &amp;lsquo;17. No additional fee will be charged for cheque payments greater than Rs. 2000,&amp;rdquo; SBI Card said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen that the majority of payments (over 90 per cent) are made through non-cheque modes. We have observed a trend of payment related disputes arising in small cheque payments, causing inconvenience to customers as well. We offer several seamless digital modes of payment which we are seeking to encourage, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s focus towards digital payments and this step will facilitate the same,&amp;rdquo; said SBI Card CEO Vijay Jasuja.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, payments made through SBI cheques will not incur the extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost. It is also likely to provide a boost to digital payments. SBI, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, entered credit card business in 1998 by roping GE Capital India, the consumer finance arm of US-based GE Capital. SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s latest offering &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; is targeted at all State Bank of India customers, including Jan Dhan account holders throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has introduced the &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; card in an effort to bring new users into the fold of cashless transactions. The card is issued to persons with a balance of Rs 25,000 in their SBI accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No such charge on cheque payments will be levied on holders of SBI Card Unnati which is targeted at first time credit card users and aimed at inclusion of people into the organised financial stream,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jasuja added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visa, Mastercard Threatened By Meteoric Rise of Aadhaar Pay &amp; UPI;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/visa-mastercard-threatened-meteoric-rise-aadhaar-pay-rs-6000-cr-market-danger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/visa-mastercard-threatened-meteoric-rise-aadhaar-pay-rs-6000-cr-market-danger/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Traditional payment processing and payment card companies, Visa and Mastercard, are feeling threatened now, and the reason is the exponential rise of Govt. backed digital payment platforms: Aadhaar Pay and UPI, which combined with BHIM App is giving these companies sleepless nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports emerging, representatives of these companies are trying to meet with senior Govt. officials, to make sure that they are not ignored in this cashless mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One senior Govt. official said, “Aadhaar Pay will be like India’s own solution to the cashless economy. Lots of players such as Visa, MasterCard are shaken up and there is a big war going on. But the government is very clear and wants to just bulldoze ahead with it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, Rs 6000 crore is at stake here, which is estimated to be Visa and Mastercard’s potential market size in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems that Govt is in no mood to assist private players in this highly competitive niche. Earlier, these companies were threatened with the rise of RuPay cards in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will Visa and Mastercard do now, to protect their territory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visa-mastercard-shaken-stirred-due-to-aadhaar-pay-upi-bhim&#34;&gt;Visa, Mastercard Shaken &amp;amp; Stirred Due To Aadhaar Pay, UPI &amp;amp; BHIM&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;payment-processing-companies-like-visa-and-mastercard-charge-1-on-every-transaction-which-is-happening-on-their-platform-and-currently-rs-6-lakh-crore-is-the-size-of-digital-transactions-as-estimated-by-the-govt&#34;&gt;Payment processing companies like Visa and Mastercard charge 1% on every transaction which is happening on their platform. And currently, Rs 6 lakh crore is the size of digital transactions, as estimated by the Govt.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the market size and potential of revenues for Visa and Mastercard is Rs 6000 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But due to the immense popularity of UPI-based transactions, and the recent launch of Aadhaar-based BHIM Appfor merchants have induced fear among these traditional payment processing companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the reason is that UPI and Aadhaar Pay doesn’t give any transactions fees to Visa or Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Govt. official said, “Card companies get 1% commission is which is around Rs 6,000 crore market for the likes of Visa, MasterCard and Rupay. Since UPI, BHIM and Aadhaar Pay don’t give this commission to them, they think it’s a big loss to them of the potential business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, these companies are feeling ignored, and out of the digital ecosystem of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports coming in, officials from these companies are making rounds of Niti Ayog office, and Finance Department for seeking more collaboration and partnerships. But Govt. is in no mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One official from Niti Aayog said, “We are not in the process of protecting the revenue of private players. The government will continue to provide alternate and cheaper options to end users to enable them to board our digital payment drive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note here, that earlier this month, Amitabh Kant, CEO of Niti Aayog had declared that in future, ATMs and Credit/Debit cards will disappear; and only mobile wallets and Aadhaar based payment mechanism will survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that Aadhaar Pay is supported by 27 banks and 715,000 merchants within weeks of its launch, 19 million people are already using BHIM App is not good news for Visa and Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visa-mastercard-puts-up-a-brave-face&#34;&gt;Visa, Mastercard Puts Up A Brave Face&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;meanwhile-both-mastercard-and-visa-officials-in-india-have-put-up-a-brave-face-and-have-assured-that-there-is-nothing-to-worry-despite-the-fact-that-aadhaar-already-covers-99-of-indian-population-40-banks-are-already-linked-with-aadhaar&#34;&gt;Meanwhile, both Mastercard and Visa officials in India have put up a brave face and have assured that there is nothing to worry, despite the fact that Aadhaar already covers 99% of Indian population, 40 banks are already linked with Aadhaar.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porush Singh, divisional president for MasterCard in South Asia said, “We don’t see it as a loss of business. There is enough opportunity for multiple players. Otherwise, you wouldn’t have had more banks in the ecosystem or wallet operators or payment solutions. We haven’t seen it yet (possible impact), but yes if the consumer finds it more relevant, then we will have to start evaluating.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Visa is devising plans to work with the Govt., in order to take the digital story forward. TR Ramachandran, group country manager, India and South Asia said, “We will continue working with the government, our clients and merchants to expand access to electronic payments in support of India’s drive to a less-cash society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to stay relevant in the market, both of these companies have launched innovative schemes, such as QR Code based payments, and contactless payment interface. Last year, talks were on regarding a massive collaboration to combine forces of Visa, Mastercard and BharatQR code into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Govt. estimates, cashless payment ecosystem will increase from Rs 6 lakh to Rs 90 lakh crore in few years. But, will Visa and Mastercard be relevant then?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can Win Up To 168 GB Of 4G Data In Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-win-up-to-168-gb-of-4g/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-win-up-to-168-gb-of-4g/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio subscribers with Vivo smartphones can participate in the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania scheme &amp;ldquo;only once&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within days of announcing its &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans, Jio is offering up to 168GB of 4G data to Vivo smartphone users. &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania - exciting new contest for all cricket fans out there! Win extra 4G data by supporting your favourite IPL team,&amp;rdquo; Jio said on its website. Under its &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania&amp;rdquo; scheme, IPL or Indian Premier League 2017 fans can pick their favourite team and bag &amp;ldquo;extra 4G data&amp;rdquo; every time the selected team wins, loses or draws a league match &amp;ldquo;because winning and losing is part of the game&amp;rdquo;, said Jio - the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries. (Also read: Jio helps Reliance Industries to become India&amp;rsquo;s most valued company)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-avail-vivo-jio-cricket-mania-offer&#34;&gt;Who can avail Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be a Jio subscriber with a Vivo smartphone to be able to participate in the scheme. You can avail the offer only once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users are required to register by May 10, 2017 to enjoy the full benefit of the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, those registering to Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer after April 30 will get 50 per cent of complimentary 4G data accumulated. The amount of 4G data on offer will be based on the outcome of the league matches played by the selected team till the end of the first round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-much-data-if-my-team-wins-loses-draws-an-ipl-2017-match&#34;&gt;How much data if my team wins/loses/draws an IPL 2017 match?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering 3GB of 4G data for a win, 2GB for a draw and 1GB for a loss. If your favourite IPL 2017 team wins more than one time, &amp;ldquo;your 4G Data multiply&amp;rdquo;, according to Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-subscribe&#34;&gt;How to subscribe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those using a Vivo smartphone with a Jio connection need to select their favourite IPL 2017 team on or before May 10, 2017. Customers need to send their entries by an SMS from their Jio number to 59009 in a format specified by Jio on its website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/vivo-jio-cricket-mania-sms-format-650_650x400_61492496761.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now, support your favourite team and every time it wins, VIVO and JIO WILL WALK THE EXTRA MILE FOR YOU to support your passion,&amp;rdquo; Jio added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-will-i-get-my-data&#34;&gt;When will I get my data?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users will accumulate all the 4G data under the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer at the end of the series. The 4G data on offer under this scheme can be as much as 168GB. Users will have to recharge with Rs. 303 or more every month to be eligible for this extra data benefit. Jio will credit the GBs earned under the &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania&amp;rdquo; offer over the next 10 recharges as data boosters, starting from June 1, 2017 to March 31, 2018, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio Ahead In Network Coverage But Trails In 4G Speeds: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-ahead-in-network-coverage-but-trails-in-4g-speeds-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-ahead-in-network-coverage-but-trails-in-4g-speeds-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio carries 90 per cent plus of all data traffic in the country currently while its network capacity share is closer to 35 per cent, the report said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio network coverage is significantly ahead of the other operators but the newcomer trails Airtel in 4G speeds given the high load on its network during the free offer period, says a report by Credit Suisse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our conclusion is that Jio&amp;rsquo;s network coverage is significantly ahead of the other operators. Jio has good coverage in 80 per cent plus of cities surveyed, compared to less than 30 per cent for the others. The difference is even more stark when compared only with 4G networks of incumbents (sub-15 per cent of cities),&amp;rdquo; the latest report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the newcomer did not fare as well when it came to speeds - the survey concluded that Airtel offered the best 4G speeds, while Jio was &amp;ldquo;probably bogged down by load&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We also studied the network speed results across all these locations. Airtel 4G offers the best download speeds in general (12Mbps plus). Jio, Vodafone and Idea are close to each other (7-8Mbps). We suspect Jio&amp;rsquo;s speeds are impacted by the high load on the network in the free offer period,&amp;rdquo; Credit Suisse said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio carries 90 per cent plus of all data traffic in the country currently while its network capacity share is closer to 35 per cent, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competitive pressure is expected to sustain, the report said adding that significant pressure on fundamentals will continue in coming quarters from Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already started seeing the impact of Jio on the incumbents&amp;rsquo; numbers (Bharti 3Q). Our study here shows Jio has built a significant lead in terms of network coverage, and the incumbents have a fair amount of catch up to do (especially on 4G). Importantly, going by recently announced enhanced capex plans, the company continues to invest,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study covers over 30 Indian cities that represent a &amp;ldquo;significant chunk of current data demand and revenues&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2GB Data Per Day For Rs. 339:BSNL&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnls-latest-offer-to-counter-jio-airtel-2gb-data-per-day-for-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnls-latest-offer-to-counter-jio-airtel-2gb-data-per-day-for-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a month, consumer will get 30 GB data and 25 minutes free call per day under the offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) on Tuesday launched a plan that will provide 2GB data per day for Rs. 339 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To compete with Jio and other private players, we have introduced the cheapest plan with a rental value of Rs. 339 per month. Under this plan, the consumer will get 2GB per day,&amp;rdquo; said Sanjiv Tyagi, General Manager, BSNL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a month, the consumer will get 30 GB data and 25 minutes free call per day. After consumption of 25 minutes a levy of 25 paisa per minute will be imposed,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan will be effective from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not mandatory for train tickets of senior citizens</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets but the Railways have initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens, Lok Sabha was informed today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu made it clear that Aadhaar number has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, however, said the Railway has initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens through pre-verification of senior citizens based on Aadhaar details on voluntary basis with effect from January 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The system is intended to ensure that the senior citizen concession is not misused by unscrupulous elements by giving fictitious names and to use the data for decision making,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prabhu said to promote cashless ticketing system, various initiatives have been taken by the Indian Railways.
“Our ultimate destination is cashless ticket booking. But the immediate priority is less cash transaction,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cash Transaction Limit, Aadhaar: How It Will Impact You</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/latest-updates-on-cash-transaction-limit-aadhaar-how-it-will-impact-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/latest-updates-on-cash-transaction-limit-aadhaar-how-it-will-impact-you/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For any cash transaction exceeding the limit, an amount equal to the transaction will be charged. Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said, &amp;ldquo;In the official amendment to Finance Bill, the government has proposed that limit of 3 lakh for cash transaction, beyond which it is illegal, will be reduced to 2 lakhs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Penalty for violating the limit is a fine equal to the transaction amount&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fine will be payable by person or establishment receiving cash&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has called for reducing the limit to 2 lakh from April 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government on Tuesday moved a proposal to cap the cash transaction limit at Rs 2 lakh instead of Rs 3 lakh, as mentioned earlier by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Union Budget 2017 speech. For any cash transaction exceeding the limit, an amount equal to the transaction will be charged. Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said, &amp;ldquo;In the official amendment to Finance Bill, the government has proposed that limit of 3 lakh for cash transaction, beyond which it is illegal, will be reduced to 2 lakhs.&amp;rdquo; The penalty for violating this is a fine equivalent to the amount of transaction, he added. The fine will be payable by person or establishment receiving cash. The government has called for reducing the limit to 2 lakh from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the cash restrictions will not apply to the government, any banking company, post office savings bank or co-operative bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government also proposed to make Aadhaar card mandatory for filing income tax returns and applying for a Permanent Account Number (PAN). Any application for a PAN, which is a unique ID assigned to each tax payer, a person will also have to mention your Aadhaar or 12-digit unique ID, which is backed by biometrics like finger prints and iris scans stored in a central repository. From July 1 onwards, any PAN card not linked to an Aadhaar identity will be considered invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply for an Aadhaar card now, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a PAN card or want to file tax returns. The government is working on linking all bank accounts to Aadhaar numbers. From April 1 onwards, Aadhaar IDs will be a pre-requisite for opening an Employee Provident Fund (EPF) account that helps you collate a pension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two (cash transaction limit and Aadhaar) are among the 40 amendments proposed by Mr Jaitley in Lok Sabha yesterday. The move is aimed to curb the black money flow and push the country towards digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp, From April: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Announces Free Incoming Calls On Domestic Roaming To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move comes after different offers introduced by rival telecom firms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular today announced free incoming calls on domestic roaming and unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers come on the heels of the larger rival Bharti Airtel announcing removal of all roaming charges for outgoing and incoming calls as well as SMSes and data usage within India, to take on competition from newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Effective April 1, 2017, Idea&amp;rsquo;s 200 million customers will enjoy free incoming calls while roaming on company&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G and 4G network across 400,000 towns and villages in the country. Idea customers will be able to make outgoing calls, SMS freely at affordable rates while roaming anywhere in India,&amp;rdquo; an Idea release said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further said mobile data tariffs and data pack benefits of home circle will be available while roaming within India at no extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facility of free incoming calls on domestic roaming will be extended to both prepaid and postpaid customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For international travellers, the company is offering international roaming value packs with free bundled usage of up to 400 outgoing minutes, 100 SMSes per day, 3GB bundled data and unlimited incoming calls for Rs 2,499 for Asia, and Rs 5,999 for Europe for 30 days validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These international roaming packs also come bundled with free 1GB/2GB/3GB data and overage charges as low as Rs 3 per MB to avoid bill shock to travelling customers,&amp;rdquo; Idea said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company said it has done a study of customer&amp;rsquo;s travel destinations, usage patterns and bill shock complaints to design a new range of value packs for select destinations across Europe, Asia, America, UK and Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For value conscious customers, the packs start at Rs 1,199 for 10 days validity and go up to Rs 5,999 for 30 days validity, giving up to 85 per cent savings on international roaming charges,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;Idea is now set to enable over 200 million customers to use their mobile phones freely, without having to worry about roaming charges, while they travel anywhere in the country,&amp;rdquo; Sashi Shankar, Chief Marketing Officer of Idea Cellular said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges on calls and data, and said international call rates will be cut by up to 90 per cent to as low as Rs 3 per minute and data charges by up to 99 per cent to Rs 3 per MB across popular roaming destinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press statement, &amp;lsquo;Airtel Declares War on Roaming&amp;rsquo;, the company had then said the move will lead to &amp;ldquo;death of National Roaming&amp;rdquo; from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Communications New Offer: 1 GB 4G Data For Rs 49, 3 GB for Rs 149</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-communications-new-offer-1-gb-4g-data-for-rs-49-3-gb-for-rs-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-communications-new-offer-1-gb-4g-data-for-rs-49-3-gb-for-rs-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Communications also introduced a competitive 3G offer of unlimited data access at Rs 99, while unlimited 2G data access will be available for Rs 49.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Communications (RCOM) on Friday launched a &amp;lsquo;Joy of Holi&amp;rsquo; offer in which it will provide its 4G customers with 1GB of data access for Rs 49 and 3GB for Rs 149, along with free and unlimited on-net local and STD calls, valid for 28 days, a company statement said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also introduced a competitive 3G offer of unlimited data access at Rs 99, while unlimited 2G data access will be available for Rs 49.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Regardless of the type of smartphone or feature phone being used, customers will get best-in-class data and voice services without any additional recharge or membership-across 4G, 3G and 2G,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At RCOM, we have been overwhelmed by the response that our Unlimited Plan received last year - a validation of our efforts to constantly enhance customer experience and delight. We now take a new leap with additional benefits being offered to our 4G customers, with the &amp;lsquo;Joy of Holi&amp;rsquo; offer,&amp;rdquo; said Gurdeep Singh, Co-CEO, Reliance Communications, and Chief Executive Officer of RCOM&amp;rsquo;s Consumer Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Additionally, we still see immense potential in the 3G and 2G markets, which boast of 750 million smartphones and data-ready feature phones. We have, therefore, customized special offerings in this space as well, with segmented and value-creating propositions,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the new business plan 2017-18, unveiled by Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu on Thursday, besides the Aadhaar-based ticketing system, the Railways will move towards cashless ticketing system by installing 6,000 point-of-sale machines and 1,000 automatic ticket vending machines across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An integrated ticketing app will also be launched by May to promote cashless transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar number will be required for one-time registration at the IRCTC ticketing site. The step is aimed at eliminating touts from registering with fake identities,&amp;rdquo; a senior Railway Ministry official said, adding the Railways is preparing a software for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite taking several steps, touts corner a bulk of tickets and sell those at much higher prices and this is becoming a serious problem for the Railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new business plan also envisages launching of new tourist trains connecting hill stations and enhancing passenger comfort and providing pleasurable journey experience through improving amenities and catering service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 GB Data For Rs 345: Airtel&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer offers comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tariff battle in the Indian telecom sector has further intensified with Bharti Airtel launching an aggressive mobile data plan to counter Reliance Jio. Market leader Bharti Airtel has announced a plan for select customers wherein its subscribers will be offered 28 GBs of  data along with free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;local and STD calls for a period of 28 days under a pack priced at Rs 345. Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer, though it will charge for its services from April 1. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;continues the benefits that the telecom arm of Reliance Industries had offered under its Happy New Year scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 303 Prime offer, for example, gives Jio subscribers free voice calls and a daily cap of 1 GB of internet data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel has also placed a limit on internet usage at 1 GB per day. Airtel customers can use 500 MBs of data during day and the remaining 500 MB data can be consumed between 12 am and 6 am, said a customer care executive of Bharti Airtel. Recently, Bharti Airtel chairman Sunil Mittal said that the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new tariff announced by Reliance Jio is very aggressive and unsustainable, and the industry will respond to it with more competitive plans and additional data offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tariffs that they (Jio) have announced are still very aggressive, which means you got to respond. You got to do more packages&amp;hellip; you have to throw in more data. All those things need to be done,&amp;rdquo; he had said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel had on February 27, 2017 waived domestic roaming charges to compete with free voice calls and roaming offered by Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has promised to match the best mobile data usage plan in the market and also add 20 per cent more data to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPhone 6 32GB Variant Offered At Discount On Amazon India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon India is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/iphone-6-32-gb-amazon-in-650-400_650x400_61488796030.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Apple iPhone 6 32GB variant in Space Grey option is being sold for Rs 28,999, instead of Rs 30,700, under a limited period scheme on Amazon India&amp;rsquo;s website. The iPhone 6 32GB variant scheme is open till March 7, 2017, Amazon India said. Amazon India, the Indian operations of American e-commerce giant Amazon, is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-few-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are few things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 32GB variant of iPhone 6 is being offered by third-party retailers, not by Apple Inc itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers will be able to save Rs 1,701 or 6 per cent (inclusive of all taxes) under the scheme, the Amazon India website noted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the exchange option, customers can avail up to Rs 8,550 off for delivery to select locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orders can be placed via credit/debit cards and net banking. However cash on delivery or COD option is not available, as per the Amazon India website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;lsquo;One-Day Delivery&amp;rsquo; option is also available under the scheme, which guarantees delivery under one working day in select cities for items Fulfilled by Amazon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to analysts, sale of the 32GB variant is likely to attract good demand for Cupertino, California-based Apple Inc, which had launched iPhone 6 only in 16GB, 64GB and 128GB storage variants initially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers can also avail EMI options. &amp;ldquo;EMI available on HDFC Bank, Citibank, ICICI Bank, SBI Card, Standard Chartered Bank, Kotak Mahindra Bank, Axis Bank and HSBC credit cards&amp;hellip;Banks may charge you pre-closure and interest charges when you cancel/return an EMI order,&amp;rdquo; the Amazon India website     added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 32GB variant of iPhone 6 comes with a one-year manufacturer warranty for device and 6-month manufacturer warranty for in-box accessories including batteries from the date of purchase, it added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>