<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Antivirus firm warns of cyberattacks on home appliances</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/antivirus-firm-warns-of-cyberattacks-on-home-appliances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/antivirus-firm-warns-of-cyberattacks-on-home-appliances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avast, the company behind the leading antivirus software, warned today against attacks on home appliances connected to the internet, calling hackers targeting home routers a major threat to consumers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avast, the company behind the leading antivirus software, warned today against attacks on home appliances connected to the internet, calling hackers targeting home routers a major threat to consumers. “It’s a trivial thing to do and there’s nothing the user can do to fix it, other than to throw the router away and put in a new router,” Avast chief executive Vincent Steckler told reporters. Avast chief technology officer Ondrej Vlcek said that more and more people were using internet-enabled appliances which he described as “a total nightmare when it comes to security”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerable appliances include TV sets, audio systems, coffee machines and toys, according to the Prague-based company, which every month registers 444 million users and prevents 3.5 billion malware attacks and 500 million visits to harmful websites. In February, London police arrested a Briton suspected of staging a cyberattack on household routers run by Deutsche Telekom in November 2016, which knocked an estimated million German households offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steckler said his company had hacked into a router at a recent show in the United States to demonstrate the harm such attacks can do. Avast changed the router’s firmware, took control of a TV set and made it play a Barack Obama speech over and over. “Even if you turn off the TV, the router turns the TV back on and the user can’t see anything other than the Obama speech,” Steckler said, adding that the hacker could then hold the TV for ransom.
“I know most people, especially Americans, care much more about their TV than they do about their data. They’d probably be much more willing to pay ransom for it,” he said, chuckling. Internet security became a hot topic last Friday when a ransomware attack hit more than 300,000 computers worldwide, affecting the likes of Britain’s National Health Service, US package delivery giant FedEx and Germany’s Deutsche Bahn rail network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Data Safe From Cyber Attacks Assures Aadhaar Body Chairman</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allaying concerns about the security of data in Aadhaar servers in the wake of &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo; ransomware attack, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) today said its database was completely secured and immune to attacks from any kind of malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The data in the Aadhaar servers is in the encrypted form. You cannot do anything with that information, which is in an encrypted form. Aadhaar main systems, which are really so very well-designed and robustly designed that there is no concern about security in Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; UIDAI chairman J Satyanarayana said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just 48 hours back we had big scare all over the world about this ransomware. So, in Aadhaar, people were sleeping peacefully (as they are sure of its security features)&amp;hellip; that it is 100 per cent sure that nothing would happen. Such robust systems were put in place in Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; he said in a programme organised by the Institution of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the government has spent Rs. 7,000 crore on establishment of Aadhaar and reaped benefits of over Rs. 50,000 crore in the form of weeding out bogus beneficiaries of government schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are geared up to do 10 crore transactions per day. And we are increasing up to 40 crore transactions per day. Our servers are capable of taking that load,&amp;rdquo; he further said. According to Satyanarayana, the Telangana government has saved Rs. 55.7 crore between January and July 2016 by deleting 38.63 lakh duplicate or ghost ration cards units using Aadhaar authentication while Andhra Pradesh saved 4,03,142 tonnes of rice and 5,000 kilo litres of kerosene by reducing 8.58 lakh cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said Reliance Jio is one of the largest private players which used Aadhaar data for its subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filing Income Tax Returns? Things To Keep In Mind As Deadline Approaches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The income tax filing website typically has lots of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the close of the financial year, most individuals have completed their tax planning and tax deduction exercise for the year. This leaves the final step in completing one&amp;rsquo;s income tax process - filing ITR or income tax return. Often regarded as a painful formality, you must remember that this is one of the most important income document for any individual. While July 31, 2017 is the last day to file I-T returns, remember that the income tax filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - typically has a lot of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Income Tax returns acts as an important income document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From this year on Aadhaar card is necessary to file I-T returns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I-T returns must be filed if your annual income is over Rs. 2.5 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some important things to remember when filing for tax returns according to leading share trading company and financial consultant Motilal Oswal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Anyone with an annual income of over Rs 2.5 lakh needs to file I-T returns whether the income is taxable or not. The Income Tax Department tracks lifestyle expenses, asset purchases, investments and foreign travel through your PAN card and Aadhaar number so try to be as transparent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Remember that all your sources of income must be filed as part of your I-T returns. Even if your dividends are tax-free, it is still essential to disclose all these details in your I-T returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) If you have made losses on shares or equity-oriented mutual funds, you need to show the loss when you file returns. If you do not disclose the loss in your I-T returns, you lose the benefit of setting off the losses against other gains and also lose the benefit of carrying forward these losses for a period of 8 years, says Motilal Oswal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) You are required to file your returns online on the website of the Income Tax Department. However, your job does not end there. The returns need to be e-verified which can be done by linking it to your registered bank account having the same name details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) While refunds below Rs. 50,000 are directly credited to your bank account via RTGS, refunds above Rs. 50,000 are only paid out by cheque. Hence if your refund is above Rs. 50,000 ensure that your address is updated in the I-T records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Remember that effective July 1, 2017, an Aadhaar card is a prerequisite for filing income tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) If you forget to file returns before the due date of July 31 and do not have any tax payable then you can file the returns by March 31 next year. But refund cases will not be entertained if returns are filed after the cut-off date of July 31.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Group Issues New Threat</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-as-cyberattack-eases-hacking-group-issues-new-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-as-cyberattack-eases-hacking-group-issues-new-threat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shadow Brokers, the group that has taken credit for that leak, threatened on Tuesday to release more recent code to enable hackers to break into the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used computers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governments turned their attention to possible new wave of cyber threats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber extortion campaign has infected more than 300,000 computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The attack has caused most damage in Russia, Taiwan and Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments turned their attention to a possible new wave of cyber threats on Tuesday after the group that leaked U.S. hacking tools used to launch the global WannaCry &amp;ldquo;ransomware&amp;rdquo; attack warned it would release more malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fast-spreading cyber extortion campaign, which has infected more than 300,000 computers worldwide since Friday, eased for second day on Tuesday, but the identity and motive of its creators remain unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack includes elements that belong to the U.S. National Security Agency and were leaked online last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shadow Brokers, the group that has taken credit for that leak, threatened on Tuesday to release more recent code to enable hackers to break into the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used computers, software and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog post written by the group promised from June to release tools every month to anyone willing to pay for access to some of the tech world&amp;rsquo;s biggest commercial secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also threatened to dump data from banks using the SWIFT international money transfer network and from Russian, Chinese, Iranian or North Korean nuclear and missile programs. &amp;ldquo;More details in June,&amp;rdquo; it promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spread of the WannaCry attack - which encrypts a user&amp;rsquo;s data and demands a &amp;ldquo;ransom&amp;rdquo; be paid electronically to free it up again - slowed to a trickle on Tuesday, with few, isolated examples being reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Canada, the Universite de Montreal was hit, with 120 of the French-language university&amp;rsquo;s 8,300 computers affected, according to a university spokeswoman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no new, major incidents in the United States. Fewer than 10 U.S. organizations have reported attacks to the Department of Homeland Security since Friday, a U.S. official told reporters on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack has caused most damage in Russia, Taiwan and Ukraine, according to Czech security firm Avast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States likely avoided greater harm as the attack targeted older versions of Microsoft Corp&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, and more U.S. users have licensed, up-to-date, patched versions of the software, compared to other regions of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Homeland Security began an &amp;ldquo;aggressive awareness campaign&amp;rdquo; to alert the tech industry to the importance of installing the patch that Microsoft issued in March that protected users from the vulnerability exploited by the attack, a U.S. official working on the attack told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft said on Tuesday it was aware of Shadow Brokers&amp;rsquo; most recent claim and that its security teams monitor potential threats in order to &amp;ldquo;help us prioritize and take appropriate action.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft President and Chief Legal Officer Brad Smith said earlier this week the WannaCry attack used elements stolen from the NSA. The U.S. government has not commented directly on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;north-korea-link-probed&#34;&gt;North Korea Link Probed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyber security researchers around the world have said they have found evidence that could link North Korea with the WannaCry cyber attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A researcher from South Korea&amp;rsquo;s Hauri Labs said on Tuesday their own findings matched those of Symantec and Kaspersky Lab, who said on Monday that some code in an earlier version of the WannaCry software had also appeared in programs used by the Lazarus Group, identified by some researchers as a North Korea-run hacking operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is similar to North Korea&amp;rsquo;s backdoor malicious codes,&amp;rdquo; said Simon Choi, a senior researcher with Hauri who has done extensive research into North Korea&amp;rsquo;s hacking capabilities and advises South Korean police and National Intelligence Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Symantec and Kaspersky said it was too early to tell whether North Korea was involved in the attacks, based on the evidence that was published on Twitter by Google security researcher Neel Mehta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FireEye Inc, another large cyber security firm, said it was also investigating, but it was cautious about drawing a link to North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The similarities we see between malware linked to that group and WannaCry are not unique enough to be strongly suggestive of a common operator,&amp;rdquo; FireEye researcher John Miller said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. and European security officials told Reuters on condition of anonymity that it was too early to say who might be behind the attacks, but they did not rule out North Korea as a suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lazarus hackers, acting for impoverished North Korea, have been more brazen in their pursuit of financial gain than others, and have been blamed for the theft of $81 million from the Bangladesh central bank, according to some cyber security firms. The United States accused it of being behind a cyber attack on Sony Pictures in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Korea has denied being behind the Sony and banking attacks. North Korean officials were not immediately available for comment and its state media has been quiet about the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-information-to-share&#34;&gt;No Information To Share&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In China, foreign ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said she had no information to share, when asked about the origin of the attack and whether North Korea might be connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several Asian countries have been affected by the malware, although the impact has not been as widespread as some had feared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Malaysia, cyber security firm LE Global Services said it identified 12 cases so far, including a large government-linked corporation, a government-linked investment firm and an insurance company. It did not name any of the entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We may not see the real picture yet, as companies are not mandated to disclose security breaches to authorities in Malaysia,&amp;rdquo; said LE Global CEO Fong Choong Fook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The real situation may be serious. In one of the cases, the attack was traced back to early April.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s state media said on Tuesday more than 200 computers had been affected, but one of the country&amp;rsquo;s leading anti-virus companies, Bkav, later put the figure at 1,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taiwan Power Co. said that nearly 800 of its computers were affected, although these were used for administration, not for systems involved in electricity generation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: Airtel Doubles Data Benefits In Its Broadband Plans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-airtel-doubles-data-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-airtel-doubles-data-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bharti Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 899 plan in Delhi - which offered 30 GB of high speed data earlier - now offers 60 GB data, the company said a press release.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid India&amp;rsquo;s telecom sector abuzz with talk about Jio&amp;rsquo;s broadband services, Bharti Airtel has announced new broadband plans under which it is offering up to 100 per cent additional high speed data benefits within the same monthly rental plan. Bharti Airtel whose broadband internet plans in the national capital start from Rs 899 a month, said its new plans were aimed at driving India&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation. The announcement by India&amp;rsquo;s largest telecom company comes after rollout of its &amp;lsquo;V-Fiber&amp;rsquo; broadband &amp;ldquo;to serve the exploding demand for reliable high speed data solutions in Indian homes&amp;rdquo;, Airtel said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharti Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 899 plan in Delhi, which offered 30 GB of high speed data earlier, now offers 60 GB data. Also, its Rs 1,099 plan will now offer 90 GB of high speed data compared to 50 GB earlier, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, its Rs 1,299 plan now offers 125 GB compared to 75 GB earlier while the Rs 1,499 plan offers 160 GB instead of 100 GB, the statement noted. &amp;ldquo;Similar large increments in data benefits have been effected at every price point in every city with unlimited calling to any network available across all plans,&amp;rdquo; Bharti Airtel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our new plans are aimed at putting India onto the digital superhighway and complement our superfast broadband offerings like &amp;lsquo;V-Fiber&amp;rsquo;. At Airtel, our mission is to enable a superior digital experience and offer great value to our customers&amp;hellip;We believe these new plans will also drive the adoption of high speed broadband in the country,&amp;rdquo; Bharti Airtel (India) CEO-homes Hemanth Kumar Guruswamy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing customers will be upgraded to new benefits automatically within current bill cycle while new customers can choose from a host of plans that offer great value backed by best-in-class high speed broadband experience, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing operators in the country&amp;rsquo;s telecom industry are witnessing heightened competition due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, say some analysts. Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services - called &amp;ldquo;JioFiber&amp;rdquo; - are being launched in some parts of cities like Mumbai, Delhi and Vadodara. Jio is testing a &amp;ldquo;JioFiber Preview Offer&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;select areas of Mumbai, Delhi-NCR, Ahmedabad, Jamnagar, Surat and Vadodara&amp;rdquo;, Jio Care, the official customer support of the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, had said on microblogging site Twitter earlier this month. (Read: &amp;lsquo;Preview offer&amp;rsquo; of Jio broadband (JioFiber) in these cities)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to a query posted by an individual on Twitter, Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care handle also said the company&amp;rsquo;s network was in the process of being rolled out to other cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customers can check their data balance on &amp;lsquo;My Airtel&amp;rsquo; app,&amp;rdquo; Bharti Airtel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;V-Fiber&amp;rsquo; delivers consistently superfast broadband speeds of up to 100 Mbps to homes. &amp;ldquo;The &amp;lsquo;V-Fiber&amp;rsquo; high speed broadband experience is available to customers within the same plan rentals and requires only a quick modem switch,&amp;rdquo; it noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Delhi-headquartered Bharti Airtel has operations in 17 countries across Asia and Africa. It had over 372 million customers across its operations at the end of March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said.
The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report also says that both prepaid and postpaid customers will have to be re-verified by the telecom companies. It can be done by SMSes. Telecom companies will send verification codes to its customers.
Aadhaar may become the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future, he added.
Recently, Supreme Court has also asked the Central government to link all mobile numbers to Aadhaar within a period of one year. The Apex Court urged Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led government to frame policies regarding rules and regulations to ensure the fact that the SIMs (Subscriber
Identification Module) are not misused by anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apex court has said that its mandatory for all mobile subscribers including pre-paid SIM card users to link their SIM cards to Aadhaar cards. The Court asked the Centre to devise a plan for pre-paid SIM card users so that each person will have to fill and deposit a form whenever he or she recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Imposes Fee On Cheque Payments For Credit Card Dues. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card is levying a charge on payments made by cheques. This came into effect from April 1, according to SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s website. The card company said payments made below Rs 2,000 through cheques will attract a fee of Rs 100. &amp;ldquo;A fee of Rs.100 will be charged for payments made by cheque for an amount less than or equal to Rs.2000 w.e.f. 1st April &amp;lsquo;17. No additional fee will be charged for cheque payments greater than Rs. 2000,&amp;rdquo; SBI Card said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen that the majority of payments (over 90 per cent) are made through non-cheque modes. We have observed a trend of payment related disputes arising in small cheque payments, causing inconvenience to customers as well. We offer several seamless digital modes of payment which we are seeking to encourage, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s focus towards digital payments and this step will facilitate the same,&amp;rdquo; said SBI Card CEO Vijay Jasuja.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, payments made through SBI cheques will not incur the extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost. It is also likely to provide a boost to digital payments. SBI, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, entered credit card business in 1998 by roping GE Capital India, the consumer finance arm of US-based GE Capital. SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s latest offering &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; is targeted at all State Bank of India customers, including Jan Dhan account holders throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has introduced the &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; card in an effort to bring new users into the fold of cashless transactions. The card is issued to persons with a balance of Rs 25,000 in their SBI accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No such charge on cheque payments will be levied on holders of SBI Card Unnati which is targeted at first time credit card users and aimed at inclusion of people into the organised financial stream,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jasuja added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been reported that a new ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; is spreading widely, the RBI advisory to the banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wannacry encrypts the files on infected Windows system and spreads by exploiting vulnerabilities, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI also asked all banks to put in place a software update at ATMs to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate malware attack last year, 3.2 lakh debit cards were compromised in the country. Data of the users who transacted from ATM machines of Hitachi were compromised during May, June and July last year. The Hitachi ATMs deployed by many White Label ATM players and Yes Bank were impacted by the malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, ATMs or automated teller machines are highly vulnerable to such malware attacks as they currently run on old version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, making a software security patch update a necessary exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a total of 2.2 lakh ATMs in India, of which many old ones run on Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, the ransomware has hit systems in more than 150 countries, including Russia and the UK, in one of the most widespread cyber attacks in history. It infected computers running on older versions of Microsoft operating systems like XP, locking access to files on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cyber criminals have demanded a fee of about $300 in crypto-currencies like Bitcoin for unlocking the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has introduced a security patch to tackle the situation, and consumers across the globe have been advised to download the solution at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CERT-In on Monday said it has not received any formal report of cyber attack on India&amp;rsquo;s vital networks by the crippling global ransomware, &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) had said on Sunday that a few systems of the Police Department in Andhra Pradesh were impacted and that the state government has been informed to follow the advisory by the CERT-In.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the Maharashtra Police department said it was partially hit by the ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the alert, the Gujarat government began equipping its state computer systems with anti-virus software and upgrading its Microsoft operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the advisory issued by CERT-In, the ransomware infects other computers on the same network and is also spreading through malicious attachments to e-mails. Security firms have suggested that users immediately disconnect the infected device from the local network to contain the spread of infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, major companies including telecommunications firm Telefonica have been infected. The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks limit functions to a minimum to avoid hack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/amid-wannacry-chaos-banks-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/amid-wannacry-chaos-banks-limit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Indian banks ordered a ban on staff using internet in office except for essential banking services, while the leader, State Bank of India, has installed new software and ordered branches to follow instructions to prevent Wannacry malware from crippling operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bankers were barred from accessing various websites, including Gmail and Yahoo. Those in non-sensitive departments were also told not to visit social media sites like Facebook and Twitter. The use of internet was permitted only for clearing operations and necessary businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is to be taken most seriously. Please ensure these are percolated to the last mile up to every employee having access to the network, including staff working in offices/departments/TCs/call centres, etc,&amp;rdquo; Union Bank of India chairman Arun Tiwary said in a message to departmental heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian Banks&amp;rsquo; Association warned its members to take precaution in a way that would protect the individual banks as well as the system from the attack, which is threatening to stall businesses. &amp;ldquo;We have advised banks to take utmost precaution in light of the reports of a global cyber attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This advisory is just precautionary in nature and we are confident that banks are well equipped to deal with any challenges that come,&amp;rdquo; said an IBA official. He cannot be named because he is not allowed to speak to media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks, in general, use dedicated computers to access internet so that their core banking solutions remain immune to outside threats, but these dedicated machines are now being used with restrictions, senior officials of three state-run banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are being extremely vigilant because of this new threat. Though we have found nothing extraordinary in our systems so far, our IT teams are on high alert because of this heightened threat,&amp;rdquo; said the chief operating officer at a private sector bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The malware spreads by exploiting vulnerable systems running on Windows operating system. The Indian Computer Emergency Response Team has issued advisory for prevention of this threat. &amp;ldquo;So far, there is nothing damaging coming out of India, but there is considerable risk for the large databases of KYC and Aadhaar, which banks will have to be careful about,&amp;rdquo; said Ashvin Parekh, an independent banking consultant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October last year, a malwarerelated security breach had forced SBI to block six-lakh debit cards as a precaution after it was alerted by card network companies such as Mastercard and Visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Digital transactions in financial services have grown at a rapid pace in India, but investment in security is not commensurate with the risk the transactions pose,&amp;rdquo; said Piyush Singh, managing director, financial services - Asia Pacific, Accenture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks in India will not only have to look at investment in technology infrastructure, but also operations management and contagion of risks posed by technology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Banks Cut Home Loans Rates, Special Discounts for Women</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ICICI and HDFC&amp;rsquo;s decision comes close on the heels of the State Bank of India and LIC Housing Finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICICI Bank cut home loan rates by 0.3% for loans up to Rs 30 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDFC lowers rate to 8.35% for new home loan up to 30 lakh for women&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest private sector lender ICICI Bank cut its home loan rates by 0.3 per cent for loans up to Rs 30 lakh, a move that was matched by HDFC Bank on Monday bringing them in line with the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India. SBI is the biggest player in the home loan segment with around 26 per cent market share, followed by HDFC. With the cut in interest rates, salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40 per cent while salaried women borrowers will get home loans at 8.35 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the move, ICICI Bank managing director Chanda Kochhar said the bank is committed to supporting the government&amp;rsquo;s vision to provide housing for all by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In line with this commitment, we have reduced the home loan interest rates for the affordable housing segment. With this announcement, customers of Economically Weaker Section (EWS) and Low Income Group (LIG) can avail the dual benefit of low interest rates from us and the Credit Linked Subsidy under the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICICI Bank also said that its customers taking home loans in the affordable segment will also have the option to select the type of interest rate. In both these cases, the reduction in interest rates is 30 basis points from the previous rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can enjoy the benefit of floating interest rate or a fixed interest rate for the initial two/three years followed by floating rate, ICICI Bank said, claiming to be the first to offer such flexibility to customers. &amp;ldquo;The reduced rate will be effective from May 15, 2017 for new borrowers,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI and LIC Housing Finance had dialed back interest rates on housing loans last week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware Virus WannaCry Hits Gujarat Government&#39;s IT Network</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-virus-affects-gujarat-government-it-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-virus-affects-gujarat-government-it-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The virus has affected around 120 computers linked to the Gujarat State Wide Area Network.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 120 computers connected to the Gujarat government&amp;rsquo;s information technology network were hit by ransomware virus &amp;lsquo;Wannacry&amp;rsquo; though no &amp;ldquo;valuable&amp;rdquo; data was compromised, a senior government official said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As per our information, so far the virus has affected around 120 computers in different government departments linked to the Gujarat State Wide Area Network (GSWAN),&amp;rdquo; said Science and Technology Department Secretary Dhananjay Dwivedi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But none of the affected computer has any valuable data or important information that could adversely impact the government&amp;rsquo;s functioning,&amp;rdquo; said Dwivedi. Many computers linked to the district collectorate across the state were affected by the virus even though no major data loss was reported.
Following the attack, computers that were functioning were shut down as precautionary measure, crippling the work, the officials said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six computers at Mehsana district collectorate were affected by the ransomware virus with the message reflecting on the screen saying that the data of the computer has been &amp;ldquo;encrypted&amp;rdquo; and one will have to pay a certain amount in bitcoins to get the data back, an official of the National Informatics Centre said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mehsana Collector Alok Pandey said following the attack, all computers connected to the district collectorate were shut down as precautionary measure. &amp;ldquo;All computers have been shut down after the attack was reported in some computers. These were the computers operating independently and there is no data loss as such due to the attack,&amp;rdquo; said Pandey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several collectorates across the state reported instances of computers getting affected by the virus. At least three computers of Jamnagar Regional Transport Office were also affected by the virus, leading to shutting down of the RTO&amp;rsquo;s entire operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The computers which were linked to the works related to the registration certificate (RC) books were affected by the virus, which sent out the message that the data have been encrypted, said Assistant RTO F U Jakhra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affected computers, however, were not linked to GSWAN network, and were being handled by a private agency, added Jakhra. State&amp;rsquo;s Crime Records Bureau (CRB) issued advisory for the police stations and public to take precautionary measures to prevent the attack and said reports have been sought from individual police stations where computers were affected by the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have sought reports from police stations on what kind of problem they have faced with their computer with regards to data. We will analyse the report and take corrective actions accordingly,&amp;rdquo; said SCRB SP Ashok Kumar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, anti-virus software was being installed and operating system upgraded in computers connected to GSWAN to prevent such hacking attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>