<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Completely Digitise Air Travel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-completely-digitise-air-travel-says-jayant-sinha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-completely-digitise-air-travel-says-jayant-sinha/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government plans to use Aadhaar to ‘completely digitise’ air travel amid a raging debate on privacy concerns regarding the world’s largest biometric ID database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through verification by Aadhaar, travellers will be able to get a digital boarding pass long before their flight, Minister of State for Civil Aviation Jayant Sinha said in an interview with BloombergQuint’s Sanjay Pugalia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reaching the airport, Aadhaar biometrics would allow seamless entry through the security and check-in points, avoiding the need for a hard copy of the boarding pass, Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application programming interface will be similar to India Stack, which is part of the government’s ‘Digital India’ efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan comes as the Supreme Court hears a batch of petitions challenging the government’s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for filing taxes. There are concerns regarding security of data on government websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent report by non-profit research organisation, the Centre For Internet &amp;amp; Society, pointed out that up to 13.5 crore Aadhaar numbers can be easily accessed through government portals and nearly three-fourths of these are linked to bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government also plans to bring in a Unified Security Architecture (USA) with the help of the Central Industrial Security Force (CISF) to standardise security systems throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unified force will secure all airports, including the regional ones, in a way that the Transport Security Administration works for all U.S. airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;regional-connectivity&#34;&gt;Regional Connectivity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha expects to deploy the USA at more than 200 airports through the UDAN (Ude Desh Ke Aam Naagrik) initiative. It has already increased the number of airports from 75 to 108, Sinha added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UDAN scheme aims to boost regional connectivity with flights covering smaller distances through a market-based mechanism. The flying price has been capped at Rs 2,500 per hour to allow more flyers while airlines will get tax concessions to ensure feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo Airlines, owned by InterGlobe Aviation Ltd., has invested Rs 10,000 crore to acquire 50 turbojets for short-distance flights. Sinha said that national airlines such as IndiGo, SpiceJet, and others, are expected to handle regional routes through subsidiaries. He hopes that this will help shape up the regional aviation industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filing Income Tax Returns? Things To Keep In Mind As Deadline Approaches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The income tax filing website typically has lots of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the close of the financial year, most individuals have completed their tax planning and tax deduction exercise for the year. This leaves the final step in completing one&amp;rsquo;s income tax process - filing ITR or income tax return. Often regarded as a painful formality, you must remember that this is one of the most important income document for any individual. While July 31, 2017 is the last day to file I-T returns, remember that the income tax filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - typically has a lot of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Income Tax returns acts as an important income document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From this year on Aadhaar card is necessary to file I-T returns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I-T returns must be filed if your annual income is over Rs. 2.5 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some important things to remember when filing for tax returns according to leading share trading company and financial consultant Motilal Oswal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Anyone with an annual income of over Rs 2.5 lakh needs to file I-T returns whether the income is taxable or not. The Income Tax Department tracks lifestyle expenses, asset purchases, investments and foreign travel through your PAN card and Aadhaar number so try to be as transparent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Remember that all your sources of income must be filed as part of your I-T returns. Even if your dividends are tax-free, it is still essential to disclose all these details in your I-T returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) If you have made losses on shares or equity-oriented mutual funds, you need to show the loss when you file returns. If you do not disclose the loss in your I-T returns, you lose the benefit of setting off the losses against other gains and also lose the benefit of carrying forward these losses for a period of 8 years, says Motilal Oswal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) You are required to file your returns online on the website of the Income Tax Department. However, your job does not end there. The returns need to be e-verified which can be done by linking it to your registered bank account having the same name details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) While refunds below Rs. 50,000 are directly credited to your bank account via RTGS, refunds above Rs. 50,000 are only paid out by cheque. Hence if your refund is above Rs. 50,000 ensure that your address is updated in the I-T records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Remember that effective July 1, 2017, an Aadhaar card is a prerequisite for filing income tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) If you forget to file returns before the due date of July 31 and do not have any tax payable then you can file the returns by March 31 next year. But refund cases will not be entertained if returns are filed after the cut-off date of July 31.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>your Aadhaar is safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amidst concerns regarding Aadhaar data leak, a look at how the unique identification system actually adheres to the principles of privacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy and data protection concerns have become serious in a digital world due to ease of search and aggregation, with or without Aadhaar. Type any name in Google and it will throw up thousands of results, giving data/information publicly available. Hence, the responsibility falls on organisations which collect data from individuals to protect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a state government puts bank account details of MNREGA workers or the PAN details on its portal then one doesn’t need an Aadhaar number to find any information – simply the name will do. There may be multiple people with that name. But so what! You can always find the person with their other attributes, if available publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, each data custodian must become conscious of their responsibility to protect their customer’s data. Aadhaar has been designed as a digital identity platform, which is inclusive, unique and authenticable to participate in any digital transaction. This has transformed service delivery in our country, providing huge convenience to citizens and substantial reduction of leakages. Direct benefit transfer, subscription to various services and authentication at the point of service delivery are some benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UID project has been aware of privacy and data protection issues since the very beginning and has taken every step, as per the best practices available in the world, to ensure they are not violated. The general law on privacy is beyond the ambit of the UIDAI. With the Aadhaar Act in place, let us discuss the provisions relating to privacy and data protection in the Act.
UIDAI’s strategy document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many countries, India does not have a law on privacy. The law relating to it has been evolved by the courts through various judicial pronouncements over the years. Interestingly, the former UIDAI chairman, Nandan Nilekani, had written to the PM as early as in May 2010 suggesting a need for the privacy law. The government prepared a draft bill on Right to Privacy but it was not turned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 1 Lakh Investment Turned Into Rs 1 Crore In 21 Years. Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-lakh-investment-turned-into-rs-1-crore-in-21-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-lakh-investment-turned-into-rs-1-crore-in-21-years/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund, a mid-cap oriented fund, is primarily invested in financial, information technology, industrials and healthcare companies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Capital Asset Management&amp;rsquo;s open-ended equity growth scheme, Reliance Growth Fund, has achieved a net asset value (NAV) of Rs 1,000. This is the first fund in the industry to achieve this NAV level. The fund was launched 21 years ago in October 1995.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It gives us immense satisfaction that Rs 1 lakh invested in our fund is valued at Rs 1 crore today, an endorsement of our belief that MFs are best investment option for long term value creation,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Mutual Fund CEO Sundeep Sikka said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This growth of NAV &amp;ndash; from Rs 10 to Rs 1,000 &amp;ndash; which is a growth of 100 times in 21 years, also substantiates our view that AMCs with long term track record of 15-20 years like Reliance MF after sailing through volatile market condition will continue creating wealth for investors,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NAV is the value per share of a mutual fund on a specific date or time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Growth Fund, a mid-cap oriented fund, is primarily invested in financial, information technology,
industrials and healthcare companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors that stayed with the fund since inception have been benefited by growing their wealth 100-times till date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fund has a corpus of over Rs 5,000 crore from more than six lakh investors. As of March quarter, Reliance Mutual Fund has an assets base of Rs 2,10,890 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance is the first fund in the industry to achieve NAV level of 1,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance Mutual Fund was launched 21 years ago in October 1995&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fund&amp;rsquo;s initial investors have increased their wealth by 100 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on &lt;em&gt;Rs 3,050&lt;/em&gt; crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.
He did not give further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department, on April 5, wrote to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) asking it to give a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo; on the penalty issue, and also outline the basis and provisions of law under which the said amount had been recommended by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources familiar with the matter said that DoT, in its communication, has also asked the Trai to provide information on the number of subscribers acquired by Reliance Jio during the testing phase (that is prior to its commercial launch). The incumbent operators and the Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio clashed last year over the issue of call connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio cried foul that its customers were suffering from call failures as the incumbent operators were not giving it sufficient interconnect capacity. The operators, in turn, charged the newcomer of unleashing a &amp;ldquo;tsunami&amp;rdquo; of free traffic on their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interconnection enables mobile users to make calls to customers of other telecom networks and is, therefore, crucial for smooth functioning of mobile services. In October last year, Trai recommended to the Telecom Department, the imposition of total penalty of Rs 3,050 crore on the three incumbent operators Bharti Airtel, Vodafone and Idea Cellular for allegedly denying interconnectivity to the
new entrant that led to deterioration in the quality of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Trai&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, the penalty for Airtel and Vodafone worked out to about Rs 1,050 crore each, while in case of Idea Cellular stood at about Rs 950 crore. The regulator, in fact, had stopped short of recommending cancellation of their telecom licences saying it may lead to significant consumer inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the issue was placed before the Telecom Commission earlier this year, the highest policy-making body of the telecom department, it favoured referring the matter back to Trai for a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Commission asked DoT to seek clarification from Trai on nearly a dozen points, including whether the stipulated 90-day period was given to the three telecom operators for providing point of interconnection to the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Offers Education Loan At 8.5% Interest Rate. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI is offering an interest rate of 8.5 per cent on education loans for studying in select business schools. As part of SBI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Scholar Loan&amp;rdquo; scheme, select leading institutions where Indian students can get the concessional rate of interest include Indian Institute of Management (IIM)-Ahmedabad, IIM-Calcutta and Indian School of Business-Hyderabad or ISB-Hyderabad. This was said in a tweet by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI which recently unveiled a new brand identity after merging its operations with six other banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years. Scholar loans offer an interest rate between 8.5 per cent and 10.6 per cent and cover higher education courses in select 120 premier Indian institutions, as per SBI&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-scholar-loan-rates_650x400_81492094420.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education loan at rate of interest of 8.5%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s scholar loans cover a multitude of courses from institutions under four categories: &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;. An effective rate of interest of 8.5 per cent is offered on institutes listed by SBI under the AA category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Institutes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has listed seven &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo; institutions - for which Indian students can apply for up to Rs. 30 lakh of loans - including four IIMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These Indian institutions are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Ahmedabad IIM-Calcutta IIM-Bangalore IIM-Kozhikode Indian School of Business, Hyderabad Indian School of Business, Mohali Campus Xavier Labour Relations Institute, Jamshedpur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is covered?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The loans disbursed under SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme covers college fees (including examination, hostel, library and laboratory fees), purchase of books, equipment and instrument as well as travel expenses and expenses on exchange programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approval time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers quick sanctioning of scholar loans at designated campus branches or more than 5,000 select branches, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Reduces Term Deposit Rates By Up To 0.5%</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI said the rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India has cut its term deposit rates by up to 50 basis points for various maturities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the new structure, for two to less than three years deposits, SBI will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier, the bank said. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For deposits maturing between three years and 10 years, the rates have been lowered by 25 basis points to 6.50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lender will be offering the new rates for fresh deposits and renewals and are applicable from April 29, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short term deposits, that is, for deposits maturing between seven days to less than two years, the rates have been left unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank is offering highest rates of 6.90 per cent for one year to 455 days term deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also not changed its marginal cost of funds based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मशीन सूंघकर बताएगी आप बीमार है या नहीं!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ऐसी मशीन आपके सामने होगी जो सूंघकर बता देगी कि आप बीमार हैं या नहीं। रिसर्चर्स एक ऐसी मशीन पर काम कर रहे हैं जो आपकी सांस, ब्लड और यूरीन से आपका रोग पहचान लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हम सभी की एक यूनीक स्मेल होती है जो हजारों कार्बनिक यौगिक से मिलकर बनती है। इस महक से हमारी उम्र, जेनटिक, लाइफस्टाइल, होमटाउन और यहां तक की हमारे मेटाबॉलिक प्रोसेस के बारे में भी पता चलता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्राचीन यूनानी और चीनी चिकित्सक रोग को पहचानने के लिए मरीज की खुश्बू का इस्तेमाल किया करते थे। मॉर्डन मेडिकल रिचर्स में भी यह बात सामने आई है कि किसी की त्वचा और सांस की गंध बीमारी का सूचक हो सकते हैं। एक्सपर्ट रिपोर्ट्स की मानें तो मधुमेह रोगियों की सांस कभी-कभी सड़े हुए सेब जैसी, वहीं टाइफाइड रोगियों की त्वचा बेकिंग ब्रेड जैसी गंध देती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वैसे तो हर डॉक्टर भी कुछ बीमारियों को किसी हद तक सूंघ सकता है, लेकिन यह इस पर निर्भर करता है कि उसकी नाक कितनी संवेदनशील है और वह सूंघ कर बीमारियां पहचानने का कितना अनुभवी है। इस वजह से रिसर्चर्स कम खर्च में एक ऐसे सेंसर पर काम कर रहे हैं जो रोग को पहचान ले।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह सेंसर एक सिलिकॉन चिप है जिस पर कई मेटल लेयर्स और छोटे गोल्ड इलेक्ट्रॉड्स लगे होंगे। यह मोबाइल फोन के सिम कार्ड जैसा दिखाई देगा और केमिकल फिल्टर जैसे काम करेगा। इस मशीन को इलेक्ट्रॉनिक नाक कहें तो गलत नहीं होगा, जो आदमी की नाक की तुलना में कहीं सटीक और बेहतर ढंग से रोग की पहचान कर लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार को संजीवनी बूटी की तरह पेश कर रही सरकार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-linking-only-curb-pan-card-duplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-linking-only-curb-pan-card-duplication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को इनकम टैक्स के पर्मानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के साथ जोड़ना जरूरी करने के सरकार के कदम का विरोध कर रहे लोगों ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट से कहा कि सरकार आधार को सभी बुराइयों के लिए संजीवनी बूटी के तौर पर पेश कर रही है। आधार को PAN के साथ जोड़ने के लिए इनकम टैक्स एक्ट में संशोधन को चुनौती देने वाली याचिकाओं की सुनवाई कर रही दो जजों की बेंच से सीनियर ऐडवोकेट अरविंद पी दातार ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार उन हर्बल दवाओं में से एक बन गया है, जो सभी का उपचार कर सकती हैं&amp;hellip;आतंकवाद, ब्लैक मनी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस संशोधन के जरिए 1 जुलाई से आधार कार्ड से लिंक्ड न होने वाला PAN अवैध हो जाएगा। सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने गुरुवार को इस पर अपना फैसला सुरक्षित रखा। इससे पहले हुई सुनवाइयों में सरकार ने कानून का पक्ष लेते हुए इस बात को गलत बताया था कि इस कदम से प्रिवेसी को खतरा होगा। दातार ने गुरुवार को सरकार के इस नजरिए पर सवाल उठाया कि आधार और PAN को लिंक करने से ब्लैक मनी पर रोक लगेगी। उनका कहना था, &amp;lsquo;इससे पैन कार्ड के डुप्लिकेशन पर रोक लगेगी, ब्लैक मनी पर नहीं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;सरकार के 2005 के डेटा के अनुसार केवल 0.4 पर्सेंट PAN कार्ड डुप्लिकेटेड हैं और इसे देखते हुए इस तरह का कदम उठाना उचित नहीं है। 0.4 पर्सेंट के लिए 99.6 पर्सेंट को परेशान करने का क्या मतलब है? इस बदलाव की जरूरत दिखाने वाला नया डेटा कहां है?&amp;rsquo; उनकी दलील थी कि नए सिस्टम से वे छोटे कारोबारी बर्बाद हो जाएंगे जिनके पास किसी कारण से आधार या PAN नहीं होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि इन दोनों को लिंक न करने वाले लोग अपना इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न नहीं भर सकेंगे और इस वजह से उन्हें भारी पेनल्टी चुकानी पड़ सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दातार ने कहा कि कानून में इस तरह के महत्वपूर्ण बदलाव को लेकर संसद में कोई बहस नहीं की गई और न ही इसे एक कमेटी के पास भेजा गया है। उन्होंने बताया कि फाइनेंस बिल पर केवल एक सामान्य चर्चा हुई है। उन्होंने सरकार पर आधार को चरणों में नागरिकों पर थोपने का आरोप लगाया। उनका कहना था कि कानून में कोई भी बदलाव आधार ऐक्ट में संशोधन के जरिए किया जाना चाहिए था, इनकम टैक्स ऐक्ट में नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;याचिकाकर्ताओं ने दलील दी थी कि फिंगरप्रिंट और आइरिस स्कैन लेने वाले आधार को PAN के साथ जोड़ने से व्यक्तियों के शरीर को लेकर अधिकार का उल्लंघन हुआ है। हालांकि, इसे लेकर सरकार के वकील ने पिछले सप्ताह कहा था कि व्यक्ति का शरीर को लेकर अधिकार संपूर्ण नहीं है। सीनियर एडवोकेट सलमान खुर्शीद ने सरकार के इस नजरिए के विरोध में कहा कि कुछ मूल मानवाधिकारों को छीना नहीं जा सकता।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Wifi, LCD Screens, Tejas Express To Redefine Rail Travel. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wifi-lcd-screens-tejas-express-to-redefine-rail-travel-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wifi-lcd-screens-tejas-express-to-redefine-rail-travel-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 20-coach Tejas Express will be fitted with automatic doors, LCD screens, onboard wifi, tea/coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Railways is set to launch a premium train service called Tejas Express between Mumbai and Goa this summer. Fitted with automatic doors, LCD screens, onboard wifi, tea/coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables, the 20-coach Tejas Express will also serve cuisine curated by celebrity chefs. The premium Tejas Express service was announced in Rail Budget 2016-17. Tejas will showcase the future of train travel in India, Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu has said. &amp;ldquo;Mumbai-Goa train journey will get as exciting as air travel from June&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; the Ministry of Railways said on microblogging site Twitter on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the upcoming Tejas express:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tejas Express will operate at speeds of 130 kmph and above, according to the Rail Budget 2016-17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train &amp;ldquo;will showcase the future of train travel in India&amp;rdquo;, offering onboard services such as entertainment, local cuisine, WiFi etc. through one service provider for ensuring accountability and improved customer satisfaction, it said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/tejas-express-pti_650x400_51493538210.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Mumbai-Goa Tejas Express will have 20 coaches comprising executive class and chair cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering service will be part of Tejas fares like Rajdhani and Shatabdi trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coaches will have automatic doors and secured gangways for all coaches, a first for the Indian Railways. Currently automatic doors are operational in Metro trains only, while gangways, corridors between coaches, are not closed from the sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onboard facilities will include tea and coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables, news agency Press Trust of India said citing a senior Railway Ministry official, adding that the LCD screens meant for entertainment purpose will also be used for disseminating passenger-related information and safety instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features on Tejas coaches will include integrated braille displays, digital destination boards, and electronic passenger reservation charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will also be water level indicators in bio-vacuum toilets, sensorised taps and hand driers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train&amp;rsquo;s interior colour scheme will match the exterior to give the passengers a feel of world class travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Mumbai-Goa route, the Tejas service is likely to be pressed on the Delhi-Chandigarh route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said.
The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report also says that both prepaid and postpaid customers will have to be re-verified by the telecom companies. It can be done by SMSes. Telecom companies will send verification codes to its customers.
Aadhaar may become the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future, he added.
Recently, Supreme Court has also asked the Central government to link all mobile numbers to Aadhaar within a period of one year. The Apex Court urged Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led government to frame policies regarding rules and regulations to ensure the fact that the SIMs (Subscriber
Identification Module) are not misused by anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apex court has said that its mandatory for all mobile subscribers including pre-paid SIM card users to link their SIM cards to Aadhaar cards. The Court asked the Centre to devise a plan for pre-paid SIM card users so that each person will have to fill and deposit a form whenever he or she recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>