<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to media, the senior Congress leader said there was a need to upgrade all post offices in the country with latest infrastructure since there was &amp;ldquo;vast availability of post offices&amp;hellip;one can find it in every nook and corner of the country, even in remote villages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said passports could be applied from post offices shortly, adding around 86 post offices have already started work in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation, including eight MPs, paid obeisance at the sanctum sanctorum of the Golden Temple here. They also visited the historic Jallianwala Bagh, where they paid tributes to the martyrs who had sacrificed their lives for the freedom of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation thereafter visited the Integrated Check Post (ICP) Attari/Wagah border where they held a meeting with the Custom and BSF officials in order to have a &amp;ldquo;first hand information with regard to the required infrastructure at ICP, import/export activities with Pakistan and problems faced by the officials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members also witnessed the evening beating retreat ceremony at Wagah border.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आधार को संजीवनी बूटी की तरह पेश कर रही सरकार</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-linking-only-curb-pan-card-duplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-linking-only-curb-pan-card-duplication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को इनकम टैक्स के पर्मानेंट अकाउंट नंबर (PAN) के साथ जोड़ना जरूरी करने के सरकार के कदम का विरोध कर रहे लोगों ने सुप्रीम कोर्ट से कहा कि सरकार आधार को सभी बुराइयों के लिए संजीवनी बूटी के तौर पर पेश कर रही है। आधार को PAN के साथ जोड़ने के लिए इनकम टैक्स एक्ट में संशोधन को चुनौती देने वाली याचिकाओं की सुनवाई कर रही दो जजों की बेंच से सीनियर ऐडवोकेट अरविंद पी दातार ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधार उन हर्बल दवाओं में से एक बन गया है, जो सभी का उपचार कर सकती हैं&amp;hellip;आतंकवाद, ब्लैक मनी।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस संशोधन के जरिए 1 जुलाई से आधार कार्ड से लिंक्ड न होने वाला PAN अवैध हो जाएगा। सुप्रीम कोर्ट ने गुरुवार को इस पर अपना फैसला सुरक्षित रखा। इससे पहले हुई सुनवाइयों में सरकार ने कानून का पक्ष लेते हुए इस बात को गलत बताया था कि इस कदम से प्रिवेसी को खतरा होगा। दातार ने गुरुवार को सरकार के इस नजरिए पर सवाल उठाया कि आधार और PAN को लिंक करने से ब्लैक मनी पर रोक लगेगी। उनका कहना था, &amp;lsquo;इससे पैन कार्ड के डुप्लिकेशन पर रोक लगेगी, ब्लैक मनी पर नहीं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;सरकार के 2005 के डेटा के अनुसार केवल 0.4 पर्सेंट PAN कार्ड डुप्लिकेटेड हैं और इसे देखते हुए इस तरह का कदम उठाना उचित नहीं है। 0.4 पर्सेंट के लिए 99.6 पर्सेंट को परेशान करने का क्या मतलब है? इस बदलाव की जरूरत दिखाने वाला नया डेटा कहां है?&amp;rsquo; उनकी दलील थी कि नए सिस्टम से वे छोटे कारोबारी बर्बाद हो जाएंगे जिनके पास किसी कारण से आधार या PAN नहीं होगा। उन्होंने कहा कि इन दोनों को लिंक न करने वाले लोग अपना इनकम टैक्स रिटर्न नहीं भर सकेंगे और इस वजह से उन्हें भारी पेनल्टी चुकानी पड़ सकती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दातार ने कहा कि कानून में इस तरह के महत्वपूर्ण बदलाव को लेकर संसद में कोई बहस नहीं की गई और न ही इसे एक कमेटी के पास भेजा गया है। उन्होंने बताया कि फाइनेंस बिल पर केवल एक सामान्य चर्चा हुई है। उन्होंने सरकार पर आधार को चरणों में नागरिकों पर थोपने का आरोप लगाया। उनका कहना था कि कानून में कोई भी बदलाव आधार ऐक्ट में संशोधन के जरिए किया जाना चाहिए था, इनकम टैक्स ऐक्ट में नहीं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;याचिकाकर्ताओं ने दलील दी थी कि फिंगरप्रिंट और आइरिस स्कैन लेने वाले आधार को PAN के साथ जोड़ने से व्यक्तियों के शरीर को लेकर अधिकार का उल्लंघन हुआ है। हालांकि, इसे लेकर सरकार के वकील ने पिछले सप्ताह कहा था कि व्यक्ति का शरीर को लेकर अधिकार संपूर्ण नहीं है। सीनियर एडवोकेट सलमान खुर्शीद ने सरकार के इस नजरिए के विरोध में कहा कि कुछ मूल मानवाधिकारों को छीना नहीं जा सकता।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बिजली बिल: आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को जरूरी सेवाओं के लिए अनिवार्य किए जाने का मामला अभी सुप्रीम कोर्ट में लंबित है। इस बीच बिजली बिल के भुगतान को भी आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी शुरू कर दी गई है। केंद्र सरकार ने राज्यों से बिजली के बिलों का डिजिटल भुगतान आधार से जुड़े बैंक खातों के माध्यम से सुनिश्चित करने को कहा है। केंद्रीय ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा है कि बिजली बिल को आधार से जोड़ना ग्राहकों के लिए फायदेमंद साबित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;राज्यों और केंद्र शासित प्रदेशों के ऊर्जा और खदान मंत्रियों की कॉन्फ्रेंस में गोयल ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह जरूरी नहीं है, लेकिन सभी के हित में है क्योंकि अगर आप बिल का भुगतान डिजिटल माध्यम से करेंगे तो आपके पास यह ठीक-ठीक सबूत होगा कि आपने बिल का भुगतान किया है। यह पहल जनता को मदद करेगी और इस संबंध में कोशिश की जानी चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि इसका फैसला राज्यों को लेना है कि वे बिजली बिलों के भुगतान की प्रणाली को आधार से जुड़े खातों से जोड़ें या नहीं, लेकिन निश्चित तौर पर यह कहा जा सकता है कि यह ग्राहकों के हित में है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि सरकार ने हाल में आयकर रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को जरूरी कर दिया है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट में भी सरकार ने अपनी तरफ से साफ किया है कि पैन नंबर के जरिए होने वाले फ्रॉड को रोकने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य किया जाना जरूरी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गोयल ने यह भी कहा कि सरकार राज्यों को बिजली आवंटन के मसौदे को फिर तैयार कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम फॉर्म्युले पर काम कर रहे हैं। हम इस बात पर फिर से विचार कर रहे हैं कि हम इसे (पावर आवंटन पॉलिसी) किस तरह मजबूत बना सकते हैं। फिलहाल गाडगिल फॉर्म्युले पर बिजली का बंटवारा होता है। इसके तहत राज्यों के प्लान के लिए केंद्रीय मदद के लिए नियम और शर्तों को तय किया जाता है। उनका यह भी कहना था कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा बिजली उन को दी जाएगी, जो न्यूक्लियर प्लांट्स स्थापित करने को बढ़ावा देंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिजली के कमर्शल नुकसान में गिरावट और कॉस्ट की बेहतर कवरेज से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन कंपनियों में मामूली बेहतरी से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रिब्यूशन कंपनियों के ऑपरेशनल परफॉर्मेंस में सुधार हुआ है। पावर फाइनेंस कॉर्पोरेशन (PFC) की एक रिपोर्ट में यह बात कही गई है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department has launched a massive hunt for black money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The massive hunt for undeclared cash launched across the country post demonetisation has revealed that these was either converted into gold or routed through shell companies to make it legal tender, IT sleuths have told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income Tax officials said black money holders avoided the bank-deposit route because they wanted to conceal their identities and somehow had &amp;ldquo;managed to get many jewellers&amp;rdquo; to convert their unaudited cash into gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They bought gold and jewellery from jewellers across the cities on November 8 (the night Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced the demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 currency notes from midnight) and, thereafter. Jewellers camouflaged the identities of the actual buyers and offered split bills,&amp;rdquo; an Income Tax official, who was part of the investigations, told IANS on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to him, jewellers saw in demonetisation an opportunity to ramp up their sales and thought &amp;ldquo;they could get away&amp;rdquo; by showing these amounts as sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jewellers offered a platform to convert unreported cash into gold,&amp;rdquo; the official said, adding that split bills were below the value of Rs 2 lakh, the threshold above which buyers have to provide the permanent account number (PAN) issued by the income tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The buyers&amp;rsquo; lists provided by the jewellers were false. After verification, it emerged that many of the buyers were financially weak and not in a position to spend such huge amounts shown in the invoices,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen tried to find an answer to a common question: How did jewellers meet the huge spurt in demand following the announcement of demonetisation, particularly after the festival season?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We found many of these sales were booked as advance collection for future sales. Due to preceding sales during Dhanteras and Diwali, jewellers had a stock crunch and they delivered gold later,&amp;rdquo; another IT official told IANS, asking not to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen said they have stumbled upon records which suggested many shops &amp;ndash; as many as 90 per cent across cities &amp;ndash; were closed at the time of the demonetisation announcement and sales at the day&amp;rsquo;s closing had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Still, we found sales were registered in the accounting system either on November 8 or a date prior to that after the closing sales were reported. These sales were manipulated,&amp;rdquo; another IT official said, also requesting anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sankar Sen, Chairman and MD, Senco Gold Ltd, which was one of the jewellery houses under the I-T department scanner, told IANS: &amp;ldquo;We keep records of all buyers on the basis of the names and contacts provided by the customers. We cooperated with officials and provided all the documents, including the CCTV footage that we had.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is difficult for jewellers to verify whether the customers have provided a legitimate identity or not, particularly when the sale value is less than Rs 2 lakh,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hunt for black money by the IT officials picked up after November 29 as they waited for some time to collect information from the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) or other agencies about the movement of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked how taxmen identified jewellers, an official told IANS: &amp;ldquo;The first set of information showed that jewellers deposited huge amounts of money into banks. Then, we went after jewellers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IT sleuths were able to identify legitimate transactions, easily. &amp;ldquo;We also had given options to the jewellers to disclose the name of actual buyers or declare that the amount is your money,&amp;rdquo; the official said, pointing out that such moves proved successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many actual buyers and jewellers contributed to the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY), an amnesty scheme to declare unreported wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a robust and quick information-sharing system among state and central agencies been in place, the hunt for black money would have been more effective, the officials lamented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A compilation of unique features found in transactions post-demonetisation across states is expected soon,&amp;rdquo; an IT official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Union Finance Ministry, the CBDT has detected undisclosed income of over Rs 9,334 crore between November 9, 2016, and February 28 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under Operation Clean Money (OCM), more than 60,000 persons, including 1,300 high-risk persons, have been identified for investigation into claims of excessive cash sales after demonetisation was announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to officials, shell companies provided a strong support system for black money after demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials found dummy directors of these companies included a cancer patient who signed documents for a Rs 10,000 monthly fee or charges of Rs 200 for every signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials said reporting of cash seizures was relatively less in Kolkata because of the existence of the shell companies as an established channel to stash ill-gotten money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining how active the channel was, the official said: &amp;ldquo;Many cash handlers with whom we interacted told us that the money does not stay for more than half-an-hour at a particular point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shell companies were also used as instruments to buy bullion. &amp;ldquo;We found invoices for bullion sales were generated against such companies while actual beneficiaries received the bullion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want A New Jio SIM? Here&#39;s What You Pay To Get &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in getting a new Reliance Jio SIM and availing the &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer? Rs 408 is the minimum amount you need to spend. For Jio non-Prime and new users, the recharge amount is Rs 309 along with an additional Rs 99. Similarly, to get the Rs 509 plan, the amount needed will be Rs 608.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has extensively provided free data services with unlimited calls for several months and with the telecom operator starting paid services, one can expect the firm to provide the &amp;lsquo;most affordable&amp;rsquo; plans. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rs. 408 is the minimum amount needed to avail Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has provided free services with unlimited calls for last few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has been in the controversy for stretching its free trial run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-dhan.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramdev&#39;s Warning: Will Wipe Out Foreign Firms In 5 Years</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ramdevs-warning-will-wipe-out-foreign-firms-in-5-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ramdevs-warning-will-wipe-out-foreign-firms-in-5-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comparing them to the East India Company that had entered the country with a purpose to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo;, Ramdev said that he aims to make India free from the MNCs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yoga guru Ramdev said today that Patanjali Ayurveda, promoted by him, will steal the march over multinational firms manufacturing consumer products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing them to the East India Company that had entered the country with a purpose to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo;, Ramdev said that he aims to make India free from the MNCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that the MNCs here were not working for the country&amp;rsquo;s development, rather their sole objective was to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo; India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Patanjali agle panch varshon mein in videshi kampaniyon ko moksh de degi (Patanjali will finish the MNCs up from the Indian market in next five years),&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was speaking at a function organised here to mark the birth anniversary of Yogi Bharat Bhushan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the next five years, Patanjali would educate the farmers about the latest techniques in farming to boost production. We will also offer decent prices for the produce,&amp;rdquo; Ramdev, who also happens to be the founder of Patanjali, said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ramdev also hailed the Uttar Pradesh government under Yogi Adityanath, who he said, establishes a good connect with the public.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 1 Lakh Investment Turned Into Rs 1 Crore In 21 Years. Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-lakh-investment-turned-into-rs-1-crore-in-21-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-lakh-investment-turned-into-rs-1-crore-in-21-years/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund, a mid-cap oriented fund, is primarily invested in financial, information technology, industrials and healthcare companies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Capital Asset Management&amp;rsquo;s open-ended equity growth scheme, Reliance Growth Fund, has achieved a net asset value (NAV) of Rs 1,000. This is the first fund in the industry to achieve this NAV level. The fund was launched 21 years ago in October 1995.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It gives us immense satisfaction that Rs 1 lakh invested in our fund is valued at Rs 1 crore today, an endorsement of our belief that MFs are best investment option for long term value creation,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Mutual Fund CEO Sundeep Sikka said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This growth of NAV &amp;ndash; from Rs 10 to Rs 1,000 &amp;ndash; which is a growth of 100 times in 21 years, also substantiates our view that AMCs with long term track record of 15-20 years like Reliance MF after sailing through volatile market condition will continue creating wealth for investors,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NAV is the value per share of a mutual fund on a specific date or time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Growth Fund, a mid-cap oriented fund, is primarily invested in financial, information technology,
industrials and healthcare companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors that stayed with the fund since inception have been benefited by growing their wealth 100-times till date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fund has a corpus of over Rs 5,000 crore from more than six lakh investors. As of March quarter, Reliance Mutual Fund has an assets base of Rs 2,10,890 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance is the first fund in the industry to achieve NAV level of 1,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance Mutual Fund was launched 21 years ago in October 1995&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fund&amp;rsquo;s initial investors have increased their wealth by 100 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on &lt;em&gt;Rs 3,050&lt;/em&gt; crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.
He did not give further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department, on April 5, wrote to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) asking it to give a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo; on the penalty issue, and also outline the basis and provisions of law under which the said amount had been recommended by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources familiar with the matter said that DoT, in its communication, has also asked the Trai to provide information on the number of subscribers acquired by Reliance Jio during the testing phase (that is prior to its commercial launch). The incumbent operators and the Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio clashed last year over the issue of call connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio cried foul that its customers were suffering from call failures as the incumbent operators were not giving it sufficient interconnect capacity. The operators, in turn, charged the newcomer of unleashing a &amp;ldquo;tsunami&amp;rdquo; of free traffic on their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interconnection enables mobile users to make calls to customers of other telecom networks and is, therefore, crucial for smooth functioning of mobile services. In October last year, Trai recommended to the Telecom Department, the imposition of total penalty of Rs 3,050 crore on the three incumbent operators Bharti Airtel, Vodafone and Idea Cellular for allegedly denying interconnectivity to the
new entrant that led to deterioration in the quality of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Trai&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, the penalty for Airtel and Vodafone worked out to about Rs 1,050 crore each, while in case of Idea Cellular stood at about Rs 950 crore. The regulator, in fact, had stopped short of recommending cancellation of their telecom licences saying it may lead to significant consumer inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the issue was placed before the Telecom Commission earlier this year, the highest policy-making body of the telecom department, it favoured referring the matter back to Trai for a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Commission asked DoT to seek clarification from Trai on nearly a dozen points, including whether the stipulated 90-day period was given to the three telecom operators for providing point of interconnection to the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Offers Education Loan At 8.5% Interest Rate. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI is offering an interest rate of 8.5 per cent on education loans for studying in select business schools. As part of SBI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Scholar Loan&amp;rdquo; scheme, select leading institutions where Indian students can get the concessional rate of interest include Indian Institute of Management (IIM)-Ahmedabad, IIM-Calcutta and Indian School of Business-Hyderabad or ISB-Hyderabad. This was said in a tweet by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI which recently unveiled a new brand identity after merging its operations with six other banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years. Scholar loans offer an interest rate between 8.5 per cent and 10.6 per cent and cover higher education courses in select 120 premier Indian institutions, as per SBI&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-scholar-loan-rates_650x400_81492094420.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education loan at rate of interest of 8.5%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s scholar loans cover a multitude of courses from institutions under four categories: &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;. An effective rate of interest of 8.5 per cent is offered on institutes listed by SBI under the AA category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Institutes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has listed seven &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo; institutions - for which Indian students can apply for up to Rs. 30 lakh of loans - including four IIMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These Indian institutions are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Ahmedabad IIM-Calcutta IIM-Bangalore IIM-Kozhikode Indian School of Business, Hyderabad Indian School of Business, Mohali Campus Xavier Labour Relations Institute, Jamshedpur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is covered?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The loans disbursed under SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme covers college fees (including examination, hostel, library and laboratory fees), purchase of books, equipment and instrument as well as travel expenses and expenses on exchange programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approval time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers quick sanctioning of scholar loans at designated campus branches or more than 5,000 select branches, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Reduces Term Deposit Rates By Up To 0.5%</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI said the rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India has cut its term deposit rates by up to 50 basis points for various maturities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the new structure, for two to less than three years deposits, SBI will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier, the bank said. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For deposits maturing between three years and 10 years, the rates have been lowered by 25 basis points to 6.50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lender will be offering the new rates for fresh deposits and renewals and are applicable from April 29, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short term deposits, that is, for deposits maturing between seven days to less than two years, the rates have been left unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank is offering highest rates of 6.90 per cent for one year to 455 days term deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also not changed its marginal cost of funds based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Wifi, LCD Screens, Tejas Express To Redefine Rail Travel. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wifi-lcd-screens-tejas-express-to-redefine-rail-travel-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wifi-lcd-screens-tejas-express-to-redefine-rail-travel-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 20-coach Tejas Express will be fitted with automatic doors, LCD screens, onboard wifi, tea/coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Railways is set to launch a premium train service called Tejas Express between Mumbai and Goa this summer. Fitted with automatic doors, LCD screens, onboard wifi, tea/coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables, the 20-coach Tejas Express will also serve cuisine curated by celebrity chefs. The premium Tejas Express service was announced in Rail Budget 2016-17. Tejas will showcase the future of train travel in India, Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu has said. &amp;ldquo;Mumbai-Goa train journey will get as exciting as air travel from June&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; the Ministry of Railways said on microblogging site Twitter on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the upcoming Tejas express:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tejas Express will operate at speeds of 130 kmph and above, according to the Rail Budget 2016-17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train &amp;ldquo;will showcase the future of train travel in India&amp;rdquo;, offering onboard services such as entertainment, local cuisine, WiFi etc. through one service provider for ensuring accountability and improved customer satisfaction, it said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/tejas-express-pti_650x400_51493538210.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Mumbai-Goa Tejas Express will have 20 coaches comprising executive class and chair cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering service will be part of Tejas fares like Rajdhani and Shatabdi trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coaches will have automatic doors and secured gangways for all coaches, a first for the Indian Railways. Currently automatic doors are operational in Metro trains only, while gangways, corridors between coaches, are not closed from the sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onboard facilities will include tea and coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables, news agency Press Trust of India said citing a senior Railway Ministry official, adding that the LCD screens meant for entertainment purpose will also be used for disseminating passenger-related information and safety instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features on Tejas coaches will include integrated braille displays, digital destination boards, and electronic passenger reservation charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will also be water level indicators in bio-vacuum toilets, sensorised taps and hand driers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train&amp;rsquo;s interior colour scheme will match the exterior to give the passengers a feel of world class travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Mumbai-Goa route, the Tejas service is likely to be pressed on the Delhi-Chandigarh route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मशीन सूंघकर बताएगी आप बीमार है या नहीं!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ऐसी मशीन आपके सामने होगी जो सूंघकर बता देगी कि आप बीमार हैं या नहीं। रिसर्चर्स एक ऐसी मशीन पर काम कर रहे हैं जो आपकी सांस, ब्लड और यूरीन से आपका रोग पहचान लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हम सभी की एक यूनीक स्मेल होती है जो हजारों कार्बनिक यौगिक से मिलकर बनती है। इस महक से हमारी उम्र, जेनटिक, लाइफस्टाइल, होमटाउन और यहां तक की हमारे मेटाबॉलिक प्रोसेस के बारे में भी पता चलता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्राचीन यूनानी और चीनी चिकित्सक रोग को पहचानने के लिए मरीज की खुश्बू का इस्तेमाल किया करते थे। मॉर्डन मेडिकल रिचर्स में भी यह बात सामने आई है कि किसी की त्वचा और सांस की गंध बीमारी का सूचक हो सकते हैं। एक्सपर्ट रिपोर्ट्स की मानें तो मधुमेह रोगियों की सांस कभी-कभी सड़े हुए सेब जैसी, वहीं टाइफाइड रोगियों की त्वचा बेकिंग ब्रेड जैसी गंध देती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वैसे तो हर डॉक्टर भी कुछ बीमारियों को किसी हद तक सूंघ सकता है, लेकिन यह इस पर निर्भर करता है कि उसकी नाक कितनी संवेदनशील है और वह सूंघ कर बीमारियां पहचानने का कितना अनुभवी है। इस वजह से रिसर्चर्स कम खर्च में एक ऐसे सेंसर पर काम कर रहे हैं जो रोग को पहचान ले।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह सेंसर एक सिलिकॉन चिप है जिस पर कई मेटल लेयर्स और छोटे गोल्ड इलेक्ट्रॉड्स लगे होंगे। यह मोबाइल फोन के सिम कार्ड जैसा दिखाई देगा और केमिकल फिल्टर जैसे काम करेगा। इस मशीन को इलेक्ट्रॉनिक नाक कहें तो गलत नहीं होगा, जो आदमी की नाक की तुलना में कहीं सटीक और बेहतर ढंग से रोग की पहचान कर लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 540 Crore Black Money Detect Over In Last Fortnight by Income Tax Officials  </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/detect-over-rs-540-crore-black-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/detect-over-rs-540-crore-black-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax department has detected over Rs. 540 crore black money in the next 15 days as part of its nationwide operations to check tax evasion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the PMGKY black money window closed on March 31, the Income Tax department has detected over Rs. 540 crore black money in the next 15 days as part of its nationwide operations to check tax evasion. Officials said the tax sleuths, in the first fortnight of the new financial year that began on April 1, have conducted multiple search and survey operations on entry operators (agents using banking channels to launder funds), shell firms, government officials, real estate players and other sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per an official data compiled till April 15, the department has carried out &amp;ldquo;over 250 search and survey operations where the taxman raided at least 300 shell firms and detected more than Rs. 540 crore of black money.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action is significant as it comes after the closure of the third black money declaration window of the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), provided by the government to people holding stash funds to come clean and pay due taxes and penalty, that ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had brought the first black money declaration window in 2015 for people who held illegal assets abroad followed by the Income Declaration Scheme (IDS) last year where individuals and entities could declare their domestic black funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMGKY was brought by the government in order to check hidden money in the wake of the demonetisation that was announced by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on November 8 last
year. A senior official said three major searches were conducted in Noida near here during the said period against an entry operator who was &amp;ldquo;managing&amp;rdquo; about 200 shell firms for providing entries of bogus sale and purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;More than 20 beneficiaries who have received entries of over Rs. 1 crore have been identified and the total undisclosed income in this case is about Rs. 300 crore,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official added that a real estate broker in the national capital region, dealing in &amp;ldquo;unaccounted cash
transactions on sale of property&amp;rdquo;, was also covered by the department during the said period and tax sleuths have seized documents leading to tax evasion of more than Rs. 50 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior government official of Uttar Pradesh was also searched during the same period after which, the official said, unaccounted cash payments of Rs. 2 crore were detected while four hidden immovable properties in the name of the officer&amp;rsquo;s wife were unearthed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I-T department officials also searched an Ahmedabad-based real estate and infrastructure player where tax evasion to the tune of Rs. 120 crore has been detected, the official said, adding the investigations in this case are still on as the case involves multiple layers of bogus entities. As part of a similar search in Pune against a business group, the entity surrendered Rs. 19 crore income to the department as the black money was generated &amp;ldquo;on account of profit not recorded in the books of account.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Hyderabad-based business group engaged in digital printing was also raided by the department which led to the eizure of over Rs. 1 crore cash, the official said. The official added that these actions will continue in the coming days as after the closure of the PMGKY window all those cases where black money and tax evasion has been detected will have to be &amp;ldquo;thoroughly&amp;rdquo; investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>