<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to media, the senior Congress leader said there was a need to upgrade all post offices in the country with latest infrastructure since there was &amp;ldquo;vast availability of post offices&amp;hellip;one can find it in every nook and corner of the country, even in remote villages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said passports could be applied from post offices shortly, adding around 86 post offices have already started work in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation, including eight MPs, paid obeisance at the sanctum sanctorum of the Golden Temple here. They also visited the historic Jallianwala Bagh, where they paid tributes to the martyrs who had sacrificed their lives for the freedom of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation thereafter visited the Integrated Check Post (ICP) Attari/Wagah border where they held a meeting with the Custom and BSF officials in order to have a &amp;ldquo;first hand information with regard to the required infrastructure at ICP, import/export activities with Pakistan and problems faced by the officials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members also witnessed the evening beating retreat ceremony at Wagah border.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been reported that a new ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; is spreading widely, the RBI advisory to the banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wannacry encrypts the files on infected Windows system and spreads by exploiting vulnerabilities, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI also asked all banks to put in place a software update at ATMs to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate malware attack last year, 3.2 lakh debit cards were compromised in the country. Data of the users who transacted from ATM machines of Hitachi were compromised during May, June and July last year. The Hitachi ATMs deployed by many White Label ATM players and Yes Bank were impacted by the malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, ATMs or automated teller machines are highly vulnerable to such malware attacks as they currently run on old version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, making a software security patch update a necessary exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a total of 2.2 lakh ATMs in India, of which many old ones run on Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, the ransomware has hit systems in more than 150 countries, including Russia and the UK, in one of the most widespread cyber attacks in history. It infected computers running on older versions of Microsoft operating systems like XP, locking access to files on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cyber criminals have demanded a fee of about $300 in crypto-currencies like Bitcoin for unlocking the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has introduced a security patch to tackle the situation, and consumers across the globe have been advised to download the solution at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CERT-In on Monday said it has not received any formal report of cyber attack on India&amp;rsquo;s vital networks by the crippling global ransomware, &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) had said on Sunday that a few systems of the Police Department in Andhra Pradesh were impacted and that the state government has been informed to follow the advisory by the CERT-In.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the Maharashtra Police department said it was partially hit by the ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the alert, the Gujarat government began equipping its state computer systems with anti-virus software and upgrading its Microsoft operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the advisory issued by CERT-In, the ransomware infects other computers on the same network and is also spreading through malicious attachments to e-mails. Security firms have suggested that users immediately disconnect the infected device from the local network to contain the spread of infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, major companies including telecommunications firm Telefonica have been infected. The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department has launched a massive hunt for black money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The massive hunt for undeclared cash launched across the country post demonetisation has revealed that these was either converted into gold or routed through shell companies to make it legal tender, IT sleuths have told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income Tax officials said black money holders avoided the bank-deposit route because they wanted to conceal their identities and somehow had &amp;ldquo;managed to get many jewellers&amp;rdquo; to convert their unaudited cash into gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They bought gold and jewellery from jewellers across the cities on November 8 (the night Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced the demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 currency notes from midnight) and, thereafter. Jewellers camouflaged the identities of the actual buyers and offered split bills,&amp;rdquo; an Income Tax official, who was part of the investigations, told IANS on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to him, jewellers saw in demonetisation an opportunity to ramp up their sales and thought &amp;ldquo;they could get away&amp;rdquo; by showing these amounts as sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jewellers offered a platform to convert unreported cash into gold,&amp;rdquo; the official said, adding that split bills were below the value of Rs 2 lakh, the threshold above which buyers have to provide the permanent account number (PAN) issued by the income tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The buyers&amp;rsquo; lists provided by the jewellers were false. After verification, it emerged that many of the buyers were financially weak and not in a position to spend such huge amounts shown in the invoices,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen tried to find an answer to a common question: How did jewellers meet the huge spurt in demand following the announcement of demonetisation, particularly after the festival season?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We found many of these sales were booked as advance collection for future sales. Due to preceding sales during Dhanteras and Diwali, jewellers had a stock crunch and they delivered gold later,&amp;rdquo; another IT official told IANS, asking not to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxmen said they have stumbled upon records which suggested many shops &amp;ndash; as many as 90 per cent across cities &amp;ndash; were closed at the time of the demonetisation announcement and sales at the day&amp;rsquo;s closing had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Still, we found sales were registered in the accounting system either on November 8 or a date prior to that after the closing sales were reported. These sales were manipulated,&amp;rdquo; another IT official said, also requesting anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sankar Sen, Chairman and MD, Senco Gold Ltd, which was one of the jewellery houses under the I-T department scanner, told IANS: &amp;ldquo;We keep records of all buyers on the basis of the names and contacts provided by the customers. We cooperated with officials and provided all the documents, including the CCTV footage that we had.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is difficult for jewellers to verify whether the customers have provided a legitimate identity or not, particularly when the sale value is less than Rs 2 lakh,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hunt for black money by the IT officials picked up after November 29 as they waited for some time to collect information from the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) or other agencies about the movement of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked how taxmen identified jewellers, an official told IANS: &amp;ldquo;The first set of information showed that jewellers deposited huge amounts of money into banks. Then, we went after jewellers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IT sleuths were able to identify legitimate transactions, easily. &amp;ldquo;We also had given options to the jewellers to disclose the name of actual buyers or declare that the amount is your money,&amp;rdquo; the official said, pointing out that such moves proved successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many actual buyers and jewellers contributed to the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana (PMGKY), an amnesty scheme to declare unreported wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a robust and quick information-sharing system among state and central agencies been in place, the hunt for black money would have been more effective, the officials lamented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A compilation of unique features found in transactions post-demonetisation across states is expected soon,&amp;rdquo; an IT official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Union Finance Ministry, the CBDT has detected undisclosed income of over Rs 9,334 crore between November 9, 2016, and February 28 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under Operation Clean Money (OCM), more than 60,000 persons, including 1,300 high-risk persons, have been identified for investigation into claims of excessive cash sales after demonetisation was announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to officials, shell companies provided a strong support system for black money after demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials found dummy directors of these companies included a cancer patient who signed documents for a Rs 10,000 monthly fee or charges of Rs 200 for every signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officials said reporting of cash seizures was relatively less in Kolkata because of the existence of the shell companies as an established channel to stash ill-gotten money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining how active the channel was, the official said: &amp;ldquo;Many cash handlers with whom we interacted told us that the money does not stay for more than half-an-hour at a particular point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shell companies were also used as instruments to buy bullion. &amp;ldquo;We found invoices for bullion sales were generated against such companies while actual beneficiaries received the bullion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Data Safe From Cyber Attacks Assures Aadhaar Body Chairman</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allaying concerns about the security of data in Aadhaar servers in the wake of &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo; ransomware attack, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) today said its database was completely secured and immune to attacks from any kind of malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The data in the Aadhaar servers is in the encrypted form. You cannot do anything with that information, which is in an encrypted form. Aadhaar main systems, which are really so very well-designed and robustly designed that there is no concern about security in Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; UIDAI chairman J Satyanarayana said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just 48 hours back we had big scare all over the world about this ransomware. So, in Aadhaar, people were sleeping peacefully (as they are sure of its security features)&amp;hellip; that it is 100 per cent sure that nothing would happen. Such robust systems were put in place in Aadhaar,&amp;rdquo; he said in a programme organised by the Institution of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the government has spent Rs. 7,000 crore on establishment of Aadhaar and reaped benefits of over Rs. 50,000 crore in the form of weeding out bogus beneficiaries of government schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are geared up to do 10 crore transactions per day. And we are increasing up to 40 crore transactions per day. Our servers are capable of taking that load,&amp;rdquo; he further said. According to Satyanarayana, the Telangana government has saved Rs. 55.7 crore between January and July 2016 by deleting 38.63 lakh duplicate or ghost ration cards units using Aadhaar authentication while Andhra Pradesh saved 4,03,142 tonnes of rice and 5,000 kilo litres of kerosene by reducing 8.58 lakh cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said Reliance Jio is one of the largest private players which used Aadhaar data for its subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the new business plan 2017-18, unveiled by Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu on Thursday, besides the Aadhaar-based ticketing system, the Railways will move towards cashless ticketing system by installing 6,000 point-of-sale machines and 1,000 automatic ticket vending machines across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An integrated ticketing app will also be launched by May to promote cashless transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar number will be required for one-time registration at the IRCTC ticketing site. The step is aimed at eliminating touts from registering with fake identities,&amp;rdquo; a senior Railway Ministry official said, adding the Railways is preparing a software for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite taking several steps, touts corner a bulk of tickets and sell those at much higher prices and this is becoming a serious problem for the Railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new business plan also envisages launching of new tourist trains connecting hill stations and enhancing passenger comfort and providing pleasurable journey experience through improving amenities and catering service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar saved Rs 90, 000 crore of public money since 2014: Centre</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An affidavit filed by the central government in the Supreme Court has stated that Aadhaar has saved Rs 90,000 crore of public money since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further said that the total recorded savings through Direct Benefit Transfer scheme alone have been Rs 49,560 crore in just two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit filed by the centre provided official statistics on the impact Aadhaar on a multitude of welfare schemes and benefits across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government quoted a World Bank report of 2016 titled “Digital Dividends” stating that Aadhaar would save $11 billion annually if applied to social programmes and welfare distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit further added that the total recorded savings to the Government of India through DBT scheme alone has been Rs 49,560 crore in just two years i.e 2014-15 and 2015-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government also provided detail on the instances of how Aadhaar has benefited welfare and pension schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Centre said that seeding of Aadhaar in the targeted delivery of food grains under Public Distribution System (PDS) has led to the deletion of 2.33 crore fake ration cards and saved Rs 14,000 crore up to December 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The implementation of Aadhaar based DBT in the PAHAL scheme has enabled residents to receive the subsidy amount directly into their Aadhaar-linked bank account. In this process more than three crore fake/duplicate LPG connections were weeded out. This has resulted in saving over Rs 26,000 crore up to December 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeding of Aadhaar with Jeevan Pramaan has seen 71.17 lakh pensioners use the scheme in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“With the initiation of e-KYC, over 7.35 crore bank accounts were opened. Total bank accounts seeded with Aadhaar as on May 31, 2017 is 47.25 crore. Jandhan accounts are estimated to cover 99.9 per cent of the households in the country. Of the newly opened 28.44 crore Jandhan accounts, over 18.97 crore accounts have used Aadhaar,” the government said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar have been linked to over 8.80 crore active MNREGS workers of the existing database of 10.38 crore active workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the National Social Assistance Programme (SAP), Aadhaar have been linked to over 1.47 crore pensioners of the existing database of 2.83 crore. Aadhaar has been linked to over 1.71 crore UAN of the existing database of 11.18 crore UAN,” the government added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar-based digital signatures are allowed to be used in National Pension Scheme (NPS) accounts and for getting a new or updated Permanent Account Number (PAN) card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 73 lakh individuals have availed digi-lockers and uploaded over 83 lakh documents online. Over 47.25 crore people are enabled with door-step banking and this system currently processes over 5 crore transactions every month. Over 1.36 crore residents have received passport using their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar has helped Income Tax payers to e-verify their I-T returns using Aadhaar One Time Password authentication. Over 24 crore SIMs have been issued using the Aadhaar e-KYC service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Biometric Attendance System (AEBAS) is now across at 660 organisations with over 2.24 lakh registered employees and over 6000 active devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp:10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on &lt;em&gt;Rs 3,050&lt;/em&gt; crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.
He did not give further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department, on April 5, wrote to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) asking it to give a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo; on the penalty issue, and also outline the basis and provisions of law under which the said amount had been recommended by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources familiar with the matter said that DoT, in its communication, has also asked the Trai to provide information on the number of subscribers acquired by Reliance Jio during the testing phase (that is prior to its commercial launch). The incumbent operators and the Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio clashed last year over the issue of call connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio cried foul that its customers were suffering from call failures as the incumbent operators were not giving it sufficient interconnect capacity. The operators, in turn, charged the newcomer of unleashing a &amp;ldquo;tsunami&amp;rdquo; of free traffic on their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interconnection enables mobile users to make calls to customers of other telecom networks and is, therefore, crucial for smooth functioning of mobile services. In October last year, Trai recommended to the Telecom Department, the imposition of total penalty of Rs 3,050 crore on the three incumbent operators Bharti Airtel, Vodafone and Idea Cellular for allegedly denying interconnectivity to the
new entrant that led to deterioration in the quality of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Trai&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, the penalty for Airtel and Vodafone worked out to about Rs 1,050 crore each, while in case of Idea Cellular stood at about Rs 950 crore. The regulator, in fact, had stopped short of recommending cancellation of their telecom licences saying it may lead to significant consumer inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the issue was placed before the Telecom Commission earlier this year, the highest policy-making body of the telecom department, it favoured referring the matter back to Trai for a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Commission asked DoT to seek clarification from Trai on nearly a dozen points, including whether the stipulated 90-day period was given to the three telecom operators for providing point of interconnection to the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No PAN Card Without Aadhaar From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-pan-card-without-aadhaar-from-july-1-says-taxman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-pan-card-without-aadhaar-from-july-1-says-taxman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT), The policy-making body of the Income Tax Department made it clear that Aadhaar will be a &amp;ldquo;must&amp;rdquo; for filing of Income Tax Returns or for obtaining a new PAN from July 1. CBDT issued the statements after the Supreme Court offered a temporary relief ruling that those who already possess the Aadhaar number will have to link it with PAN to file I-T returns, but it cannot be insisted upon in case of people not possessing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBDT issued a three-point &amp;ldquo;effect of the judgement&amp;rdquo; of the apex court statement saying that From July 1, 2017 onwards every person eligible to obtain Aadhaar must quote their Aadhaar number or their Aadhaar enrolment ID number for filing of income tax returns as well as for applications for PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the I-T department maintained that in keeping with the Supreme Court ruling, those who do not have Aadhaar and who do not wish to obtain Aadhaar for the time being, that their PAN will not be cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the PAN is cancelled, then a person cannot do his normal banking and financial operations and hence this relief is given, income tax authorities said adding that for filing of income tax returns or to obtain a new PAN, Aadhaar will be mandatory from July 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The I-T Department also urged taxpayers to link the two numbers - PAN and Aadhaar - as soon as possible saying it will be useful for E-Verification of Income Tax returns using Aadhaar OTP (One-Time Password).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 5 Recharge, Vodafone Offers Unlimited Data.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone said in a press release that the 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid a telecom industry witnessing Jio&amp;rsquo;s highly competitive tariff pricing, Vodafone India on Tuesday announced unlimited data plans with free local and STD calls priced from Rs 5 per day in the UP West telecom circle. Aimed at the Ramzan festival, Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively, according to a press release by the telecom company. Vodafone customers in these areas can subscribe to &amp;ldquo;Ramzan Special Pack&amp;rdquo; by dialing USSD or Unstructured Supplementary Service Data codes - *444*5# in case of 2G customers and *444*19# for 3G, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dilip Kumar Ganta, business head, UP West &amp;amp; Uttarakhand, Vodafone India said: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;With new data and calling packs, we aim to provide a service which can help customers seamlessly connect with their families and friends and enjoy internet at an affordable cost and share their emotional and spiritual experiences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 5 Ramzan Special Pack offers unlimited mobile data in 2G speed for a validity of one hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next Ramzan Special Pack priced at Rs 19 offers the same benefit in 3G speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 17&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom operator is also offering a calls-only pack at Rs 17. This recharge pack offers local and STD calls at the rate of 30 paise per minute over a validity period of 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 253&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 253 pack in the regions comes with a validity of 28 days and offers unlimited calls (local and STD) and unlimited data in 2G speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 345&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also valid for 28 days, Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 recharge pack in these circles comes with a daily data limit of 1GB along with free local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Fine If Your SBI Account Has No Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest lender, has decided to increase manifold the minimum balance required for maintaining savings account from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Savings bank account holders of SBI and its five associates - which will merge with it on April 1 - will have to maintain the monthly balance or else they will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs 100 (in metro cities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India has 31 crore savings bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, the monthly average balance (MAB) for a savings bank account is Rs 500 without facility of cheque book and Rs 1,000 with cheque book across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank has now decided to fix separate MABs for &amp;lsquo;metro&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;urban&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;semi-urban&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;rural&amp;rsquo; areas from the beginning of next financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benchmark for MAB and penalties are likely to be followed by other public sector banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance for metro branches will be Rs 5,000 and penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance will be between Rs 50 and Rs 100. For urban and semi-urban branches, the monthly average balance has been fixed at Rs 3,000 and Rs 2,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of rural branches, the minimum balance has been fixed at Rs 1,000. Breach of MAB will attract a penalty ranging between Rs 20 and Rs 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five associates banks of SBI - State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur (SBBJ), State Bank of Mysore (SBM), State Bank of Travancore (SBT), State Bank of Patiala (SBP) and State Bank of Hyderabad (SBH) - will merge with the parent on April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>