<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio Ahead In Network Coverage But Trails In 4G Speeds: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-ahead-in-network-coverage-but-trails-in-4g-speeds-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-ahead-in-network-coverage-but-trails-in-4g-speeds-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio carries 90 per cent plus of all data traffic in the country currently while its network capacity share is closer to 35 per cent, the report said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio network coverage is significantly ahead of the other operators but the newcomer trails Airtel in 4G speeds given the high load on its network during the free offer period, says a report by Credit Suisse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our conclusion is that Jio&amp;rsquo;s network coverage is significantly ahead of the other operators. Jio has good coverage in 80 per cent plus of cities surveyed, compared to less than 30 per cent for the others. The difference is even more stark when compared only with 4G networks of incumbents (sub-15 per cent of cities),&amp;rdquo; the latest report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the newcomer did not fare as well when it came to speeds - the survey concluded that Airtel offered the best 4G speeds, while Jio was &amp;ldquo;probably bogged down by load&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We also studied the network speed results across all these locations. Airtel 4G offers the best download speeds in general (12Mbps plus). Jio, Vodafone and Idea are close to each other (7-8Mbps). We suspect Jio&amp;rsquo;s speeds are impacted by the high load on the network in the free offer period,&amp;rdquo; Credit Suisse said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio carries 90 per cent plus of all data traffic in the country currently while its network capacity share is closer to 35 per cent, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competitive pressure is expected to sustain, the report said adding that significant pressure on fundamentals will continue in coming quarters from Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already started seeing the impact of Jio on the incumbents&amp;rsquo; numbers (Bharti 3Q). Our study here shows Jio has built a significant lead in terms of network coverage, and the incumbents have a fair amount of catch up to do (especially on 4G). Importantly, going by recently announced enhanced capex plans, the company continues to invest,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study covers over 30 Indian cities that represent a &amp;ldquo;significant chunk of current data demand and revenues&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2GB Data Per Day For Rs. 339:BSNL&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnls-latest-offer-to-counter-jio-airtel-2gb-data-per-day-for-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnls-latest-offer-to-counter-jio-airtel-2gb-data-per-day-for-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a month, consumer will get 30 GB data and 25 minutes free call per day under the offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) on Tuesday launched a plan that will provide 2GB data per day for Rs. 339 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To compete with Jio and other private players, we have introduced the cheapest plan with a rental value of Rs. 339 per month. Under this plan, the consumer will get 2GB per day,&amp;rdquo; said Sanjiv Tyagi, General Manager, BSNL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a month, the consumer will get 30 GB data and 25 minutes free call per day. After consumption of 25 minutes a levy of 25 paisa per minute will be imposed,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan will be effective from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not mandatory for train tickets of senior citizens</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets but the Railways have initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens, Lok Sabha was informed today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu made it clear that Aadhaar number has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, however, said the Railway has initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens through pre-verification of senior citizens based on Aadhaar details on voluntary basis with effect from January 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The system is intended to ensure that the senior citizen concession is not misused by unscrupulous elements by giving fictitious names and to use the data for decision making,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prabhu said to promote cashless ticketing system, various initiatives have been taken by the Indian Railways.
“Our ultimate destination is cashless ticket booking. But the immediate priority is less cash transaction,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cash Transaction Limit, Aadhaar: How It Will Impact You</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/latest-updates-on-cash-transaction-limit-aadhaar-how-it-will-impact-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/latest-updates-on-cash-transaction-limit-aadhaar-how-it-will-impact-you/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For any cash transaction exceeding the limit, an amount equal to the transaction will be charged. Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said, &amp;ldquo;In the official amendment to Finance Bill, the government has proposed that limit of 3 lakh for cash transaction, beyond which it is illegal, will be reduced to 2 lakhs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Penalty for violating the limit is a fine equal to the transaction amount&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fine will be payable by person or establishment receiving cash&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has called for reducing the limit to 2 lakh from April 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government on Tuesday moved a proposal to cap the cash transaction limit at Rs 2 lakh instead of Rs 3 lakh, as mentioned earlier by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Union Budget 2017 speech. For any cash transaction exceeding the limit, an amount equal to the transaction will be charged. Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said, &amp;ldquo;In the official amendment to Finance Bill, the government has proposed that limit of 3 lakh for cash transaction, beyond which it is illegal, will be reduced to 2 lakhs.&amp;rdquo; The penalty for violating this is a fine equivalent to the amount of transaction, he added. The fine will be payable by person or establishment receiving cash. The government has called for reducing the limit to 2 lakh from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the cash restrictions will not apply to the government, any banking company, post office savings bank or co-operative bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government also proposed to make Aadhaar card mandatory for filing income tax returns and applying for a Permanent Account Number (PAN). Any application for a PAN, which is a unique ID assigned to each tax payer, a person will also have to mention your Aadhaar or 12-digit unique ID, which is backed by biometrics like finger prints and iris scans stored in a central repository. From July 1 onwards, any PAN card not linked to an Aadhaar identity will be considered invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply for an Aadhaar card now, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a PAN card or want to file tax returns. The government is working on linking all bank accounts to Aadhaar numbers. From April 1 onwards, Aadhaar IDs will be a pre-requisite for opening an Employee Provident Fund (EPF) account that helps you collate a pension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two (cash transaction limit and Aadhaar) are among the 40 amendments proposed by Mr Jaitley in Lok Sabha yesterday. The move is aimed to curb the black money flow and push the country towards digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp, From April: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Announces Free Incoming Calls On Domestic Roaming To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move comes after different offers introduced by rival telecom firms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular today announced free incoming calls on domestic roaming and unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers come on the heels of the larger rival Bharti Airtel announcing removal of all roaming charges for outgoing and incoming calls as well as SMSes and data usage within India, to take on competition from newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Effective April 1, 2017, Idea&amp;rsquo;s 200 million customers will enjoy free incoming calls while roaming on company&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G and 4G network across 400,000 towns and villages in the country. Idea customers will be able to make outgoing calls, SMS freely at affordable rates while roaming anywhere in India,&amp;rdquo; an Idea release said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further said mobile data tariffs and data pack benefits of home circle will be available while roaming within India at no extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facility of free incoming calls on domestic roaming will be extended to both prepaid and postpaid customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For international travellers, the company is offering international roaming value packs with free bundled usage of up to 400 outgoing minutes, 100 SMSes per day, 3GB bundled data and unlimited incoming calls for Rs 2,499 for Asia, and Rs 5,999 for Europe for 30 days validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These international roaming packs also come bundled with free 1GB/2GB/3GB data and overage charges as low as Rs 3 per MB to avoid bill shock to travelling customers,&amp;rdquo; Idea said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company said it has done a study of customer&amp;rsquo;s travel destinations, usage patterns and bill shock complaints to design a new range of value packs for select destinations across Europe, Asia, America, UK and Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For value conscious customers, the packs start at Rs 1,199 for 10 days validity and go up to Rs 5,999 for 30 days validity, giving up to 85 per cent savings on international roaming charges,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;Idea is now set to enable over 200 million customers to use their mobile phones freely, without having to worry about roaming charges, while they travel anywhere in the country,&amp;rdquo; Sashi Shankar, Chief Marketing Officer of Idea Cellular said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges on calls and data, and said international call rates will be cut by up to 90 per cent to as low as Rs 3 per minute and data charges by up to 99 per cent to Rs 3 per MB across popular roaming destinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press statement, &amp;lsquo;Airtel Declares War on Roaming&amp;rsquo;, the company had then said the move will lead to &amp;ldquo;death of National Roaming&amp;rdquo; from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Communications New Offer: 1 GB 4G Data For Rs 49, 3 GB for Rs 149</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-communications-new-offer-1-gb-4g-data-for-rs-49-3-gb-for-rs-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-communications-new-offer-1-gb-4g-data-for-rs-49-3-gb-for-rs-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Communications also introduced a competitive 3G offer of unlimited data access at Rs 99, while unlimited 2G data access will be available for Rs 49.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Communications (RCOM) on Friday launched a &amp;lsquo;Joy of Holi&amp;rsquo; offer in which it will provide its 4G customers with 1GB of data access for Rs 49 and 3GB for Rs 149, along with free and unlimited on-net local and STD calls, valid for 28 days, a company statement said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also introduced a competitive 3G offer of unlimited data access at Rs 99, while unlimited 2G data access will be available for Rs 49.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Regardless of the type of smartphone or feature phone being used, customers will get best-in-class data and voice services without any additional recharge or membership-across 4G, 3G and 2G,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At RCOM, we have been overwhelmed by the response that our Unlimited Plan received last year - a validation of our efforts to constantly enhance customer experience and delight. We now take a new leap with additional benefits being offered to our 4G customers, with the &amp;lsquo;Joy of Holi&amp;rsquo; offer,&amp;rdquo; said Gurdeep Singh, Co-CEO, Reliance Communications, and Chief Executive Officer of RCOM&amp;rsquo;s Consumer Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Additionally, we still see immense potential in the 3G and 2G markets, which boast of 750 million smartphones and data-ready feature phones. We have, therefore, customized special offerings in this space as well, with segmented and value-creating propositions,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the new business plan 2017-18, unveiled by Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu on Thursday, besides the Aadhaar-based ticketing system, the Railways will move towards cashless ticketing system by installing 6,000 point-of-sale machines and 1,000 automatic ticket vending machines across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An integrated ticketing app will also be launched by May to promote cashless transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar number will be required for one-time registration at the IRCTC ticketing site. The step is aimed at eliminating touts from registering with fake identities,&amp;rdquo; a senior Railway Ministry official said, adding the Railways is preparing a software for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite taking several steps, touts corner a bulk of tickets and sell those at much higher prices and this is becoming a serious problem for the Railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new business plan also envisages launching of new tourist trains connecting hill stations and enhancing passenger comfort and providing pleasurable journey experience through improving amenities and catering service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 GB Data For Rs 345: Airtel&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer offers comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tariff battle in the Indian telecom sector has further intensified with Bharti Airtel launching an aggressive mobile data plan to counter Reliance Jio. Market leader Bharti Airtel has announced a plan for select customers wherein its subscribers will be offered 28 GBs of  data along with free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;local and STD calls for a period of 28 days under a pack priced at Rs 345. Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer, though it will charge for its services from April 1. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;continues the benefits that the telecom arm of Reliance Industries had offered under its Happy New Year scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 303 Prime offer, for example, gives Jio subscribers free voice calls and a daily cap of 1 GB of internet data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel has also placed a limit on internet usage at 1 GB per day. Airtel customers can use 500 MBs of data during day and the remaining 500 MB data can be consumed between 12 am and 6 am, said a customer care executive of Bharti Airtel. Recently, Bharti Airtel chairman Sunil Mittal said that the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new tariff announced by Reliance Jio is very aggressive and unsustainable, and the industry will respond to it with more competitive plans and additional data offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tariffs that they (Jio) have announced are still very aggressive, which means you got to respond. You got to do more packages&amp;hellip; you have to throw in more data. All those things need to be done,&amp;rdquo; he had said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel had on February 27, 2017 waived domestic roaming charges to compete with free voice calls and roaming offered by Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has promised to match the best mobile data usage plan in the market and also add 20 per cent more data to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPhone 6 32GB Variant Offered At Discount On Amazon India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon India is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/iphone-6-32-gb-amazon-in-650-400_650x400_61488796030.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Apple iPhone 6 32GB variant in Space Grey option is being sold for Rs 28,999, instead of Rs 30,700, under a limited period scheme on Amazon India&amp;rsquo;s website. The iPhone 6 32GB variant scheme is open till March 7, 2017, Amazon India said. Amazon India, the Indian operations of American e-commerce giant Amazon, is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-few-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are few things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 32GB variant of iPhone 6 is being offered by third-party retailers, not by Apple Inc itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers will be able to save Rs 1,701 or 6 per cent (inclusive of all taxes) under the scheme, the Amazon India website noted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the exchange option, customers can avail up to Rs 8,550 off for delivery to select locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orders can be placed via credit/debit cards and net banking. However cash on delivery or COD option is not available, as per the Amazon India website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;lsquo;One-Day Delivery&amp;rsquo; option is also available under the scheme, which guarantees delivery under one working day in select cities for items Fulfilled by Amazon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to analysts, sale of the 32GB variant is likely to attract good demand for Cupertino, California-based Apple Inc, which had launched iPhone 6 only in 16GB, 64GB and 128GB storage variants initially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers can also avail EMI options. &amp;ldquo;EMI available on HDFC Bank, Citibank, ICICI Bank, SBI Card, Standard Chartered Bank, Kotak Mahindra Bank, Axis Bank and HSBC credit cards&amp;hellip;Banks may charge you pre-closure and interest charges when you cancel/return an EMI order,&amp;rdquo; the Amazon India website     added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 32GB variant of iPhone 6 comes with a one-year manufacturer warranty for device and 6-month manufacturer warranty for in-box accessories including batteries from the date of purchase, it added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Average Download Speed Doubles In January, Says Telecom Regulator</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-average-download-speed-doubles-in-january-says-telecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-average-download-speed-doubles-in-january-says-telecom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRAI collects and computes speed of mobile data from subscribers across the country with the help of the MySpeed application on a real time basis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average peak download speed on Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s network more than doubled to &lt;em&gt;17.42&lt;/em&gt; megabit per second at the end of January, according to data by the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average mobile broadband speed published by the telecom regulator showed that the download speed on Jio network reached &lt;em&gt;17.42&lt;/em&gt; mbps in January from &lt;em&gt;8.34 mbps&lt;/em&gt; at the end of December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this speed, a user can download a movie in less than three minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second place was Idea at 8.53 mbps, up from 6.6 mbps at the end of December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The download speed on Airtel network dropped slightly to 8.15 mbps compared to 8.42 mbps in the previous month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other networks, download speed on Vodafone and BSNL also dipped marginally to 6.13 mbps and 2.89 mbps from 6.8 mbps and 3.16 mbps, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data showed average download speed of 2.3 mbps on Tata Docomo network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average download speeds of other networks were not available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRAI collects and computes speed of mobile data from subscribers across the country with the help of the MySpeed application on a real time basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Fine If Your SBI Account Has No Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest lender, has decided to increase manifold the minimum balance required for maintaining savings account from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Savings bank account holders of SBI and its five associates - which will merge with it on April 1 - will have to maintain the monthly balance or else they will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs 100 (in metro cities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India has 31 crore savings bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, the monthly average balance (MAB) for a savings bank account is Rs 500 without facility of cheque book and Rs 1,000 with cheque book across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank has now decided to fix separate MABs for &amp;lsquo;metro&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;urban&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;semi-urban&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;rural&amp;rsquo; areas from the beginning of next financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benchmark for MAB and penalties are likely to be followed by other public sector banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance for metro branches will be Rs 5,000 and penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance will be between Rs 50 and Rs 100. For urban and semi-urban branches, the monthly average balance has been fixed at Rs 3,000 and Rs 2,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of rural branches, the minimum balance has been fixed at Rs 1,000. Breach of MAB will attract a penalty ranging between Rs 20 and Rs 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five associates banks of SBI - State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur (SBBJ), State Bank of Mysore (SBM), State Bank of Travancore (SBT), State Bank of Patiala (SBP) and State Bank of Hyderabad (SBH) - will merge with the parent on April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 5G on Trial Samsung Network </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arqiva-and-samsung-to-trial-5g-network-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arqiva-and-samsung-to-trial-5g-network-in-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung has already undertaken some early tests of the technology on its campus in South Korea, and mobile operators and vendors have announced 5G trials in countries ranging from the United States to Japan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communications group Arqiva and Samsung Electronics will trial Britain&amp;rsquo;s first 5G network in London this year, the companies said, with the capability of delivering ultra-fast broadband to mobile devices and potentially autonomous vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advent of the fifth generation of mobile telecoms is viewed as essential to expected growth in demand for ever-higher speeds, capacity and reliability, with global operators such as Vodafone, Telefonica and Verizon working with network equipment makers to develop the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arqiva, which provides TV broadcast and mobile infrastructure, said the fixed wireless access network would operate in its own 28GHz band spectrum using Samsung&amp;rsquo;s 5G base stations and equipment installed in premises in central London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Over time, smarter network infrastructure and an enhanced ability to support exponential scale for connectivity will open the doors to further applications across a variety of markets such as IoT (Internet of Things), industrial applications and the full promise of autonomous vehicles,&amp;rdquo; Arqiva Chief Executive Simon Beresford-Wylie said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung has already undertaken some early tests of the technology on its campus in South Korea, and mobile operators and vendors have announced 5G trials in countries ranging from the United States to Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arqiva, which counts the Canada Pension Plan Investment Board and Macquarie as investors, is considering a stock market listing and is seeking new investors, sources said this month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra 5GB Free Data, Jio Sweetens Offer For Prime Members </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-sweetens-offer-for-prime-members-adds-extra-5gb-free-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-sweetens-offer-for-prime-members-adds-extra-5gb-free-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under the new offer announced, Jio has decided to load an extra 5GB data (worth Rs 201) to those recharging with Rs 303.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio on Friday sweetened the offering for its &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; members saying those recharging with Rs 303 will get an extra 5GB data beyond the 28GB promised under the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, Prime members &amp;ndash; on payment of Rs 303 per month and a one-time joining fee of Rs 99 &amp;ndash; would be entitled to unlimited free voice calls (STD and roaming) and text messages, 28GB data at 4G speeds, subject to a usage cap of 1GB a day, the breach of which would slow down the speed unless more data was bought. The plan comes with a 28 day validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime membership offer requires customers to enrol by March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the new offer announced today, Jio has decided to load an extra 5GB data (worth Rs 201) to those recharging with Rs 303.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This essentially means that subscribers who breach the 1GB daily limit would not face slowdown in speeds given the new 5GB data pool being made available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, those recharging with Rs 499 and above would now get additional 10GB data extra, over the already promised 56GB (or 2GB per day limit). The extra data pool is only valid for the first month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 21, while announcing that it has crossed the 100 million customers mark in 170 days of launch, Reliance Industries&amp;rsquo; Chairman Mukesh Ambani had announced a slew of offers, including 20 per cent more data than any rival from April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio, he had said, will continue to offer free voice calls and national roaming post April 1, when its promotional free voice and data offer ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For existing customers, he had announced a Jio &amp;lsquo;Prime Membership programme&amp;rsquo; wherein customers could enrol by paying one-time fee of Rs 99 and continue to get the existing benefits till March 2018 at &amp;ldquo;a rock-bottom introductory price of only Rs 303 per month&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>