<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Technology on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latest Technology on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Data Safe From Cyber Attacks Assures Aadhaar Body Chairman</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</guid>
      <description>UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.
Allaying concerns about the security of data in Aadhaar servers in the wake of &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo; ransomware attack, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) today said its database was completely secured and immune to attacks from any kind of malware.
&amp;ldquo;The data in the Aadhaar servers is in the encrypted form. You cannot do anything with that information, which is in an encrypted form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.
Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.
The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department has launched a massive hunt for black money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gold-to-shell-companies-inside-the-tax-departments-hunt/</guid>
      <description>The massive hunt for undeclared cash launched across the country post demonetisation has revealed that these was either converted into gold or routed through shell companies to make it legal tender, IT sleuths have told Indo-Asian News Service.
Income Tax officials said black money holders avoided the bank-deposit route because they wanted to conceal their identities and somehow had &amp;ldquo;managed to get many jewellers&amp;rdquo; to convert their unaudited cash into gold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.
The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.
Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar saved Rs 90, 000 crore of public money since 2014: Centre</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</guid>
      <description>An affidavit filed by the central government in the Supreme Court has stated that Aadhaar has saved Rs 90,000 crore of public money since 2014.
It further said that the total recorded savings through Direct Benefit Transfer scheme alone have been Rs 49,560 crore in just two years.
The affidavit filed by the centre provided official statistics on the impact Aadhaar on a multitude of welfare schemes and benefits across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.
Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp:10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on Rs 3,050 crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.
&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI. He did not give further details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.
The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.
Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No PAN Card Without Aadhaar From July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-pan-card-without-aadhaar-from-july-1-says-taxman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-pan-card-without-aadhaar-from-july-1-says-taxman/</guid>
      <description>The Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT), The policy-making body of the Income Tax Department made it clear that Aadhaar will be a &amp;ldquo;must&amp;rdquo; for filing of Income Tax Returns or for obtaining a new PAN from July 1. CBDT issued the statements after the Supreme Court offered a temporary relief ruling that those who already possess the Aadhaar number will have to link it with PAN to file I-T returns, but it cannot be insisted upon in case of people not possessing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 5 Recharge, Vodafone Offers Unlimited Data.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone said in a press release that the 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively.
Amid a telecom industry witnessing Jio&amp;rsquo;s highly competitive tariff pricing, Vodafone India on Tuesday announced unlimited data plans with free local and STD calls priced from Rs 5 per day in the UP West telecom circle. Aimed at the Ramzan festival, Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively, according to a press release by the telecom company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.
After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Fine If Your SBI Account Has No Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.
State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest lender, has decided to increase manifold the minimum balance required for maintaining savings account from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.
The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>your Aadhaar is safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</guid>
      <description>Amidst concerns regarding Aadhaar data leak, a look at how the unique identification system actually adheres to the principles of privacy
Privacy and data protection concerns have become serious in a digital world due to ease of search and aggregation, with or without Aadhaar. Type any name in Google and it will throw up thousands of results, giving data/information publicly available. Hence, the responsibility falls on organisations which collect data from individuals to protect it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 19 A Day 4G Data, Unlimited Calls In New Plans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-offers-4g-data-unlimited-calls-in-new-plans-starting-rs-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-offers-4g-data-unlimited-calls-in-new-plans-starting-rs-19/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone SuperWeek is priced at Rs 49 and will come with a validity of seven days.
Vodafone India on Thursday announced integrated plans offering unlimited voice and bonus data to its prepaid customers starting from Rs 19 per day. Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s two integrated &amp;ldquo;Voice plus Data&amp;rdquo; plans - Vodafone SuperDay and Vodafone SuperWeek - will enable its prepaid customers to enjoy benefits of unlimited local and STD calling with free data up to 250 MB for seven days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बिजली बिल: आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>आधार को जरूरी सेवाओं के लिए अनिवार्य किए जाने का मामला अभी सुप्रीम कोर्ट में लंबित है। इस बीच बिजली बिल के भुगतान को भी आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी शुरू कर दी गई है। केंद्र सरकार ने राज्यों से बिजली के बिलों का डिजिटल भुगतान आधार से जुड़े बैंक खातों के माध्यम से सुनिश्चित करने को कहा है। केंद्रीय ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा है कि बिजली बिल को आधार से जोड़ना ग्राहकों के लिए फायदेमंद साबित होगा।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.
The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said. The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.
Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>