<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to media, the senior Congress leader said there was a need to upgrade all post offices in the country with latest infrastructure since there was &amp;ldquo;vast availability of post offices&amp;hellip;one can find it in every nook and corner of the country, even in remote villages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said passports could be applied from post offices shortly, adding around 86 post offices have already started work in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation, including eight MPs, paid obeisance at the sanctum sanctorum of the Golden Temple here. They also visited the historic Jallianwala Bagh, where they paid tributes to the martyrs who had sacrificed their lives for the freedom of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegation thereafter visited the Integrated Check Post (ICP) Attari/Wagah border where they held a meeting with the Custom and BSF officials in order to have a &amp;ldquo;first hand information with regard to the required infrastructure at ICP, import/export activities with Pakistan and problems faced by the officials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members also witnessed the evening beating retreat ceremony at Wagah border.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want A New Jio SIM? Here&#39;s What You Pay To Get &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in getting a new Reliance Jio SIM and availing the &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer? Rs 408 is the minimum amount you need to spend. For Jio non-Prime and new users, the recharge amount is Rs 309 along with an additional Rs 99. Similarly, to get the Rs 509 plan, the amount needed will be Rs 608.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has extensively provided free data services with unlimited calls for several months and with the telecom operator starting paid services, one can expect the firm to provide the &amp;lsquo;most affordable&amp;rsquo; plans. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rs. 408 is the minimum amount needed to avail Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has provided free services with unlimited calls for last few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has been in the controversy for stretching its free trial run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-dhan.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramdev&#39;s Warning: Will Wipe Out Foreign Firms In 5 Years</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ramdevs-warning-will-wipe-out-foreign-firms-in-5-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ramdevs-warning-will-wipe-out-foreign-firms-in-5-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comparing them to the East India Company that had entered the country with a purpose to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo;, Ramdev said that he aims to make India free from the MNCs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yoga guru Ramdev said today that Patanjali Ayurveda, promoted by him, will steal the march over multinational firms manufacturing consumer products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing them to the East India Company that had entered the country with a purpose to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo;, Ramdev said that he aims to make India free from the MNCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that the MNCs here were not working for the country&amp;rsquo;s development, rather their sole objective was to &amp;ldquo;loot&amp;rdquo; India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Patanjali agle panch varshon mein in videshi kampaniyon ko moksh de degi (Patanjali will finish the MNCs up from the Indian market in next five years),&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was speaking at a function organised here to mark the birth anniversary of Yogi Bharat Bhushan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the next five years, Patanjali would educate the farmers about the latest techniques in farming to boost production. We will also offer decent prices for the produce,&amp;rdquo; Ramdev, who also happens to be the founder of Patanjali, said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ramdev also hailed the Uttar Pradesh government under Yogi Adityanath, who he said, establishes a good connect with the public.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 1 Lakh Investment Turned Into Rs 1 Crore In 21 Years. Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-lakh-investment-turned-into-rs-1-crore-in-21-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-lakh-investment-turned-into-rs-1-crore-in-21-years/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund, a mid-cap oriented fund, is primarily invested in financial, information technology, industrials and healthcare companies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Capital Asset Management&amp;rsquo;s open-ended equity growth scheme, Reliance Growth Fund, has achieved a net asset value (NAV) of Rs 1,000. This is the first fund in the industry to achieve this NAV level. The fund was launched 21 years ago in October 1995.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It gives us immense satisfaction that Rs 1 lakh invested in our fund is valued at Rs 1 crore today, an endorsement of our belief that MFs are best investment option for long term value creation,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Mutual Fund CEO Sundeep Sikka said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This growth of NAV &amp;ndash; from Rs 10 to Rs 1,000 &amp;ndash; which is a growth of 100 times in 21 years, also substantiates our view that AMCs with long term track record of 15-20 years like Reliance MF after sailing through volatile market condition will continue creating wealth for investors,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NAV is the value per share of a mutual fund on a specific date or time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Growth Fund, a mid-cap oriented fund, is primarily invested in financial, information technology,
industrials and healthcare companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors that stayed with the fund since inception have been benefited by growing their wealth 100-times till date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fund has a corpus of over Rs 5,000 crore from more than six lakh investors. As of March quarter, Reliance Mutual Fund has an assets base of Rs 2,10,890 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance is the first fund in the industry to achieve NAV level of 1,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance Mutual Fund was launched 21 years ago in October 1995&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fund&amp;rsquo;s initial investors have increased their wealth by 100 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs3,050 crore penalty was levied on Airtel, Vodafone andIdea </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-regulator-to-clarify-on-penalising-airtel-vodafone-and-idea-this-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sectoral regulator Trai will &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; send to the Telecom Ministry its clarification on &lt;em&gt;Rs 3,050&lt;/em&gt; crore penalty it had sought from Airtel, Vodafone and Idea for denying call connectivity to newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we have not written to them (Department of Telecom) yet. But we will be writing soon&amp;hellip; We will be responding certainly this month. It will happen very quickly,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.
He did not give further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department, on April 5, wrote to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) asking it to give a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo; on the penalty issue, and also outline the basis and provisions of law under which the said amount had been recommended by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources familiar with the matter said that DoT, in its communication, has also asked the Trai to provide information on the number of subscribers acquired by Reliance Jio during the testing phase (that is prior to its commercial launch). The incumbent operators and the Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio clashed last year over the issue of call connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio cried foul that its customers were suffering from call failures as the incumbent operators were not giving it sufficient interconnect capacity. The operators, in turn, charged the newcomer of unleashing a &amp;ldquo;tsunami&amp;rdquo; of free traffic on their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interconnection enables mobile users to make calls to customers of other telecom networks and is, therefore, crucial for smooth functioning of mobile services. In October last year, Trai recommended to the Telecom Department, the imposition of total penalty of Rs 3,050 crore on the three incumbent operators Bharti Airtel, Vodafone and Idea Cellular for allegedly denying interconnectivity to the
new entrant that led to deterioration in the quality of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Trai&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, the penalty for Airtel and Vodafone worked out to about Rs 1,050 crore each, while in case of Idea Cellular stood at about Rs 950 crore. The regulator, in fact, had stopped short of recommending cancellation of their telecom licences saying it may lead to significant consumer inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the issue was placed before the Telecom Commission earlier this year, the highest policy-making body of the telecom department, it favoured referring the matter back to Trai for a &amp;ldquo;reconsidered opinion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Commission asked DoT to seek clarification from Trai on nearly a dozen points, including whether the stipulated 90-day period was given to the three telecom operators for providing point of interconnection to the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Offers Education Loan At 8.5% Interest Rate. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-offers-education-loan-at-8-5-interest-rate-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI is offering an interest rate of 8.5 per cent on education loans for studying in select business schools. As part of SBI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Scholar Loan&amp;rdquo; scheme, select leading institutions where Indian students can get the concessional rate of interest include Indian Institute of Management (IIM)-Ahmedabad, IIM-Calcutta and Indian School of Business-Hyderabad or ISB-Hyderabad. This was said in a tweet by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI which recently unveiled a new brand identity after merging its operations with six other banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI currently offers 100 per cent financing on education loans up to Rs 30 lakh with a repayment period of up to 15 years. Scholar loans offer an interest rate between 8.5 per cent and 10.6 per cent and cover higher education courses in select 120 premier Indian institutions, as per SBI&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-scholar-loan-rates_650x400_81492094420.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education loan at rate of interest of 8.5%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s scholar loans cover a multitude of courses from institutions under four categories: &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;. An effective rate of interest of 8.5 per cent is offered on institutes listed by SBI under the AA category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Institutes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has listed seven &amp;ldquo;AA&amp;rdquo; institutions - for which Indian students can apply for up to Rs. 30 lakh of loans - including four IIMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These Indian institutions are:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Ahmedabad IIM-Calcutta IIM-Bangalore IIM-Kozhikode Indian School of Business, Hyderabad Indian School of Business, Mohali Campus Xavier Labour Relations Institute, Jamshedpur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is covered?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The loans disbursed under SBI&amp;rsquo;s Scholar Loan scheme covers college fees (including examination, hostel, library and laboratory fees), purchase of books, equipment and instrument as well as travel expenses and expenses on exchange programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approval time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI offers quick sanctioning of scholar loans at designated campus branches or more than 5,000 select branches, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Reduces Term Deposit Rates By Up To 0.5%</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI said the rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India has cut its term deposit rates by up to 50 basis points for various maturities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the new structure, for two to less than three years deposits, SBI will offer a rate of 6.25 per cent as compared to 6.75 per cent earlier, the bank said. For the similar maturity, the deposit rates for senior citizen have been cut to 6.75 per cent from 7.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For deposits maturing between three years and 10 years, the rates have been lowered by 25 basis points to 6.50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lender will be offering the new rates for fresh deposits and renewals and are applicable from April 29, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short term deposits, that is, for deposits maturing between seven days to less than two years, the rates have been left unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank is offering highest rates of 6.90 per cent for one year to 455 days term deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also not changed its marginal cost of funds based lending rates. Its one-year MCLR is at eight per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Wifi, LCD Screens, Tejas Express To Redefine Rail Travel. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wifi-lcd-screens-tejas-express-to-redefine-rail-travel-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wifi-lcd-screens-tejas-express-to-redefine-rail-travel-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 20-coach Tejas Express will be fitted with automatic doors, LCD screens, onboard wifi, tea/coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Railways is set to launch a premium train service called Tejas Express between Mumbai and Goa this summer. Fitted with automatic doors, LCD screens, onboard wifi, tea/coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables, the 20-coach Tejas Express will also serve cuisine curated by celebrity chefs. The premium Tejas Express service was announced in Rail Budget 2016-17. Tejas will showcase the future of train travel in India, Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu has said. &amp;ldquo;Mumbai-Goa train journey will get as exciting as air travel from June&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; the Ministry of Railways said on microblogging site Twitter on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the upcoming Tejas express:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tejas Express will operate at speeds of 130 kmph and above, according to the Rail Budget 2016-17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train &amp;ldquo;will showcase the future of train travel in India&amp;rdquo;, offering onboard services such as entertainment, local cuisine, WiFi etc. through one service provider for ensuring accountability and improved customer satisfaction, it said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/tejas-express-pti_650x400_51493538210.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Mumbai-Goa Tejas Express will have 20 coaches comprising executive class and chair cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering service will be part of Tejas fares like Rajdhani and Shatabdi trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coaches will have automatic doors and secured gangways for all coaches, a first for the Indian Railways. Currently automatic doors are operational in Metro trains only, while gangways, corridors between coaches, are not closed from the sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onboard facilities will include tea and coffee vending machines, magazines and snack tables, news agency Press Trust of India said citing a senior Railway Ministry official, adding that the LCD screens meant for entertainment purpose will also be used for disseminating passenger-related information and safety instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features on Tejas coaches will include integrated braille displays, digital destination boards, and electronic passenger reservation charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will also be water level indicators in bio-vacuum toilets, sensorised taps and hand driers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train&amp;rsquo;s interior colour scheme will match the exterior to give the passengers a feel of world class travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Mumbai-Goa route, the Tejas service is likely to be pressed on the Delhi-Chandigarh route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अब मशीन सूंघकर बताएगी आप बीमार है या नहीं!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-machines-to-smell-whether-youre-sick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ऐसी मशीन आपके सामने होगी जो सूंघकर बता देगी कि आप बीमार हैं या नहीं। रिसर्चर्स एक ऐसी मशीन पर काम कर रहे हैं जो आपकी सांस, ब्लड और यूरीन से आपका रोग पहचान लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हम सभी की एक यूनीक स्मेल होती है जो हजारों कार्बनिक यौगिक से मिलकर बनती है। इस महक से हमारी उम्र, जेनटिक, लाइफस्टाइल, होमटाउन और यहां तक की हमारे मेटाबॉलिक प्रोसेस के बारे में भी पता चलता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्राचीन यूनानी और चीनी चिकित्सक रोग को पहचानने के लिए मरीज की खुश्बू का इस्तेमाल किया करते थे। मॉर्डन मेडिकल रिचर्स में भी यह बात सामने आई है कि किसी की त्वचा और सांस की गंध बीमारी का सूचक हो सकते हैं। एक्सपर्ट रिपोर्ट्स की मानें तो मधुमेह रोगियों की सांस कभी-कभी सड़े हुए सेब जैसी, वहीं टाइफाइड रोगियों की त्वचा बेकिंग ब्रेड जैसी गंध देती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वैसे तो हर डॉक्टर भी कुछ बीमारियों को किसी हद तक सूंघ सकता है, लेकिन यह इस पर निर्भर करता है कि उसकी नाक कितनी संवेदनशील है और वह सूंघ कर बीमारियां पहचानने का कितना अनुभवी है। इस वजह से रिसर्चर्स कम खर्च में एक ऐसे सेंसर पर काम कर रहे हैं जो रोग को पहचान ले।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यह सेंसर एक सिलिकॉन चिप है जिस पर कई मेटल लेयर्स और छोटे गोल्ड इलेक्ट्रॉड्स लगे होंगे। यह मोबाइल फोन के सिम कार्ड जैसा दिखाई देगा और केमिकल फिल्टर जैसे काम करेगा। इस मशीन को इलेक्ट्रॉनिक नाक कहें तो गलत नहीं होगा, जो आदमी की नाक की तुलना में कहीं सटीक और बेहतर ढंग से रोग की पहचान कर लेगी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 540 Crore Black Money Detect Over In Last Fortnight by Income Tax Officials  </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/detect-over-rs-540-crore-black-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/detect-over-rs-540-crore-black-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax department has detected over Rs. 540 crore black money in the next 15 days as part of its nationwide operations to check tax evasion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the PMGKY black money window closed on March 31, the Income Tax department has detected over Rs. 540 crore black money in the next 15 days as part of its nationwide operations to check tax evasion. Officials said the tax sleuths, in the first fortnight of the new financial year that began on April 1, have conducted multiple search and survey operations on entry operators (agents using banking channels to launder funds), shell firms, government officials, real estate players and other sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per an official data compiled till April 15, the department has carried out &amp;ldquo;over 250 search and survey operations where the taxman raided at least 300 shell firms and detected more than Rs. 540 crore of black money.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action is significant as it comes after the closure of the third black money declaration window of the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojna (PMGKY), provided by the government to people holding stash funds to come clean and pay due taxes and penalty, that ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government had brought the first black money declaration window in 2015 for people who held illegal assets abroad followed by the Income Declaration Scheme (IDS) last year where individuals and entities could declare their domestic black funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMGKY was brought by the government in order to check hidden money in the wake of the demonetisation that was announced by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on November 8 last
year. A senior official said three major searches were conducted in Noida near here during the said period against an entry operator who was &amp;ldquo;managing&amp;rdquo; about 200 shell firms for providing entries of bogus sale and purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;More than 20 beneficiaries who have received entries of over Rs. 1 crore have been identified and the total undisclosed income in this case is about Rs. 300 crore,&amp;rdquo; the official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official added that a real estate broker in the national capital region, dealing in &amp;ldquo;unaccounted cash
transactions on sale of property&amp;rdquo;, was also covered by the department during the said period and tax sleuths have seized documents leading to tax evasion of more than Rs. 50 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior government official of Uttar Pradesh was also searched during the same period after which, the official said, unaccounted cash payments of Rs. 2 crore were detected while four hidden immovable properties in the name of the officer&amp;rsquo;s wife were unearthed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I-T department officials also searched an Ahmedabad-based real estate and infrastructure player where tax evasion to the tune of Rs. 120 crore has been detected, the official said, adding the investigations in this case are still on as the case involves multiple layers of bogus entities. As part of a similar search in Pune against a business group, the entity surrendered Rs. 19 crore income to the department as the black money was generated &amp;ldquo;on account of profit not recorded in the books of account.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Hyderabad-based business group engaged in digital printing was also raided by the department which led to the eizure of over Rs. 1 crore cash, the official said. The official added that these actions will continue in the coming days as after the closure of the PMGKY window all those cases where black money and tax evasion has been detected will have to be &amp;ldquo;thoroughly&amp;rdquo; investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visa, Mastercard Threatened By Meteoric Rise of Aadhaar Pay &amp; UPI;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/visa-mastercard-threatened-meteoric-rise-aadhaar-pay-rs-6000-cr-market-danger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/visa-mastercard-threatened-meteoric-rise-aadhaar-pay-rs-6000-cr-market-danger/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Traditional payment processing and payment card companies, Visa and Mastercard, are feeling threatened now, and the reason is the exponential rise of Govt. backed digital payment platforms: Aadhaar Pay and UPI, which combined with BHIM App is giving these companies sleepless nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports emerging, representatives of these companies are trying to meet with senior Govt. officials, to make sure that they are not ignored in this cashless mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One senior Govt. official said, “Aadhaar Pay will be like India’s own solution to the cashless economy. Lots of players such as Visa, MasterCard are shaken up and there is a big war going on. But the government is very clear and wants to just bulldoze ahead with it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, Rs 6000 crore is at stake here, which is estimated to be Visa and Mastercard’s potential market size in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems that Govt is in no mood to assist private players in this highly competitive niche. Earlier, these companies were threatened with the rise of RuPay cards in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will Visa and Mastercard do now, to protect their territory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visa-mastercard-shaken-stirred-due-to-aadhaar-pay-upi-bhim&#34;&gt;Visa, Mastercard Shaken &amp;amp; Stirred Due To Aadhaar Pay, UPI &amp;amp; BHIM&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;payment-processing-companies-like-visa-and-mastercard-charge-1-on-every-transaction-which-is-happening-on-their-platform-and-currently-rs-6-lakh-crore-is-the-size-of-digital-transactions-as-estimated-by-the-govt&#34;&gt;Payment processing companies like Visa and Mastercard charge 1% on every transaction which is happening on their platform. And currently, Rs 6 lakh crore is the size of digital transactions, as estimated by the Govt.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the market size and potential of revenues for Visa and Mastercard is Rs 6000 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But due to the immense popularity of UPI-based transactions, and the recent launch of Aadhaar-based BHIM Appfor merchants have induced fear among these traditional payment processing companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the reason is that UPI and Aadhaar Pay doesn’t give any transactions fees to Visa or Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Govt. official said, “Card companies get 1% commission is which is around Rs 6,000 crore market for the likes of Visa, MasterCard and Rupay. Since UPI, BHIM and Aadhaar Pay don’t give this commission to them, they think it’s a big loss to them of the potential business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, these companies are feeling ignored, and out of the digital ecosystem of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports coming in, officials from these companies are making rounds of Niti Ayog office, and Finance Department for seeking more collaboration and partnerships. But Govt. is in no mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One official from Niti Aayog said, “We are not in the process of protecting the revenue of private players. The government will continue to provide alternate and cheaper options to end users to enable them to board our digital payment drive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note here, that earlier this month, Amitabh Kant, CEO of Niti Aayog had declared that in future, ATMs and Credit/Debit cards will disappear; and only mobile wallets and Aadhaar based payment mechanism will survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that Aadhaar Pay is supported by 27 banks and 715,000 merchants within weeks of its launch, 19 million people are already using BHIM App is not good news for Visa and Mastercard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visa-mastercard-puts-up-a-brave-face&#34;&gt;Visa, Mastercard Puts Up A Brave Face&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;meanwhile-both-mastercard-and-visa-officials-in-india-have-put-up-a-brave-face-and-have-assured-that-there-is-nothing-to-worry-despite-the-fact-that-aadhaar-already-covers-99-of-indian-population-40-banks-are-already-linked-with-aadhaar&#34;&gt;Meanwhile, both Mastercard and Visa officials in India have put up a brave face and have assured that there is nothing to worry, despite the fact that Aadhaar already covers 99% of Indian population, 40 banks are already linked with Aadhaar.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porush Singh, divisional president for MasterCard in South Asia said, “We don’t see it as a loss of business. There is enough opportunity for multiple players. Otherwise, you wouldn’t have had more banks in the ecosystem or wallet operators or payment solutions. We haven’t seen it yet (possible impact), but yes if the consumer finds it more relevant, then we will have to start evaluating.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Visa is devising plans to work with the Govt., in order to take the digital story forward. TR Ramachandran, group country manager, India and South Asia said, “We will continue working with the government, our clients and merchants to expand access to electronic payments in support of India’s drive to a less-cash society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to stay relevant in the market, both of these companies have launched innovative schemes, such as QR Code based payments, and contactless payment interface. Last year, talks were on regarding a massive collaboration to combine forces of Visa, Mastercard and BharatQR code into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Govt. estimates, cashless payment ecosystem will increase from Rs 6 lakh to Rs 90 lakh crore in few years. But, will Visa and Mastercard be relevant then?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Imposes Fee On Cheque Payments For Credit Card Dues. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card is levying a charge on payments made by cheques. This came into effect from April 1, according to SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s website. The card company said payments made below Rs 2,000 through cheques will attract a fee of Rs 100. &amp;ldquo;A fee of Rs.100 will be charged for payments made by cheque for an amount less than or equal to Rs.2000 w.e.f. 1st April &amp;lsquo;17. No additional fee will be charged for cheque payments greater than Rs. 2000,&amp;rdquo; SBI Card said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen that the majority of payments (over 90 per cent) are made through non-cheque modes. We have observed a trend of payment related disputes arising in small cheque payments, causing inconvenience to customers as well. We offer several seamless digital modes of payment which we are seeking to encourage, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s focus towards digital payments and this step will facilitate the same,&amp;rdquo; said SBI Card CEO Vijay Jasuja.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, payments made through SBI cheques will not incur the extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost. It is also likely to provide a boost to digital payments. SBI, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, entered credit card business in 1998 by roping GE Capital India, the consumer finance arm of US-based GE Capital. SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s latest offering &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; is targeted at all State Bank of India customers, including Jan Dhan account holders throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has introduced the &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; card in an effort to bring new users into the fold of cashless transactions. The card is issued to persons with a balance of Rs 25,000 in their SBI accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No such charge on cheque payments will be levied on holders of SBI Card Unnati which is targeted at first time credit card users and aimed at inclusion of people into the organised financial stream,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jasuja added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can Win Up To 168 GB Of 4G Data In Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-win-up-to-168-gb-of-4g/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-win-up-to-168-gb-of-4g/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio subscribers with Vivo smartphones can participate in the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania scheme &amp;ldquo;only once&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within days of announcing its &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans, Jio is offering up to 168GB of 4G data to Vivo smartphone users. &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania - exciting new contest for all cricket fans out there! Win extra 4G data by supporting your favourite IPL team,&amp;rdquo; Jio said on its website. Under its &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania&amp;rdquo; scheme, IPL or Indian Premier League 2017 fans can pick their favourite team and bag &amp;ldquo;extra 4G data&amp;rdquo; every time the selected team wins, loses or draws a league match &amp;ldquo;because winning and losing is part of the game&amp;rdquo;, said Jio - the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries. (Also read: Jio helps Reliance Industries to become India&amp;rsquo;s most valued company)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-avail-vivo-jio-cricket-mania-offer&#34;&gt;Who can avail Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be a Jio subscriber with a Vivo smartphone to be able to participate in the scheme. You can avail the offer only once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users are required to register by May 10, 2017 to enjoy the full benefit of the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, those registering to Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer after April 30 will get 50 per cent of complimentary 4G data accumulated. The amount of 4G data on offer will be based on the outcome of the league matches played by the selected team till the end of the first round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-much-data-if-my-team-wins-loses-draws-an-ipl-2017-match&#34;&gt;How much data if my team wins/loses/draws an IPL 2017 match?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering 3GB of 4G data for a win, 2GB for a draw and 1GB for a loss. If your favourite IPL 2017 team wins more than one time, &amp;ldquo;your 4G Data multiply&amp;rdquo;, according to Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-subscribe&#34;&gt;How to subscribe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those using a Vivo smartphone with a Jio connection need to select their favourite IPL 2017 team on or before May 10, 2017. Customers need to send their entries by an SMS from their Jio number to 59009 in a format specified by Jio on its website.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/vivo-jio-cricket-mania-sms-format-650_650x400_61492496761.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now, support your favourite team and every time it wins, VIVO and JIO WILL WALK THE EXTRA MILE FOR YOU to support your passion,&amp;rdquo; Jio added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-will-i-get-my-data&#34;&gt;When will I get my data?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users will accumulate all the 4G data under the Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania offer at the end of the series. The 4G data on offer under this scheme can be as much as 168GB. Users will have to recharge with Rs. 303 or more every month to be eligible for this extra data benefit. Jio will credit the GBs earned under the &amp;ldquo;Vivo-Jio Cricket Mania&amp;rdquo; offer over the next 10 recharges as data boosters, starting from June 1, 2017 to March 31, 2018, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>