<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Banks Cut Home Loans Rates, Special Discounts for Women</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ICICI and HDFC&amp;rsquo;s decision comes close on the heels of the State Bank of India and LIC Housing Finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICICI Bank cut home loan rates by 0.3% for loans up to Rs 30 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDFC lowers rate to 8.35% for new home loan up to 30 lakh for women&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest private sector lender ICICI Bank cut its home loan rates by 0.3 per cent for loans up to Rs 30 lakh, a move that was matched by HDFC Bank on Monday bringing them in line with the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India. SBI is the biggest player in the home loan segment with around 26 per cent market share, followed by HDFC. With the cut in interest rates, salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40 per cent while salaried women borrowers will get home loans at 8.35 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the move, ICICI Bank managing director Chanda Kochhar said the bank is committed to supporting the government&amp;rsquo;s vision to provide housing for all by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In line with this commitment, we have reduced the home loan interest rates for the affordable housing segment. With this announcement, customers of Economically Weaker Section (EWS) and Low Income Group (LIG) can avail the dual benefit of low interest rates from us and the Credit Linked Subsidy under the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICICI Bank also said that its customers taking home loans in the affordable segment will also have the option to select the type of interest rate. In both these cases, the reduction in interest rates is 30 basis points from the previous rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can enjoy the benefit of floating interest rate or a fixed interest rate for the initial two/three years followed by floating rate, ICICI Bank said, claiming to be the first to offer such flexibility to customers. &amp;ldquo;The reduced rate will be effective from May 15, 2017 for new borrowers,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI and LIC Housing Finance had dialed back interest rates on housing loans last week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Indian companies pay WannaCry ransom</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/despite-legal-implication-some-companies-pay-the-ransom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/despite-legal-implication-some-companies-pay-the-ransom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A top executive working with an Indian conglomerate couldn&amp;rsquo;t fathom how a bill of $300 (Rs 19,000) landed up at his company for using a free Wi-Fi at a five-star hotel coffee shop. The CEO of another New Delhibased manufacturing company clicked on an unknown link — a mistake that would come back to haunt him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laptops of the executive and the CEO were compromised by ransomware WannaCry, the malicious fast-spreading virus that has confounded cyber security experts around the world. The malware demands $300 in bitcoins to release the infected system and its data, causing hundreds of millions of dollars in business damage to corporations and government utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though lawyers and experts have been advising companies to not pay bitcoins, some Indian companies are believed to have gone ahead and paid the ransom to get their systems unlocked. &amp;ldquo;There would be some companies that may have paid the ransom in haste to retrieve their encrypted data. As of Monday morning, the hackers seem to have globally collected 23 bitcoins, which is around $41,400,&amp;rdquo; said Amit Jaju, executive director, Fraud Investigation &amp;amp; Dispute Services (FIDS), EY India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most legal experts and cybercrime experts are cautioning companies not to pay as this could also have legal implications. &amp;ldquo;PwC never recommends paying ransomware ransom — unless there is a threat to life. Doing so fuels the ransomware economy, funding development of additional ransomware techniques and campaigns. In many cases, we have seen that when money is paid, larger attack happens a few days or weeks later,&amp;rdquo; said Sivarama Krishnan, leader -cyber security at PwC India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Twitter handle, @actual_ransom, that describes itself as &amp;ldquo;a bot that is watching the bitcoin wallets tied to WannaCry ransomware attack&amp;rdquo; is also providing live updates of bitcoins paid by companies globally. &amp;ldquo;While we are monitoring this Twitter handle, you can&amp;rsquo;t trust the authenticity of this,&amp;rdquo; said a cybercrime expert with a consultancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports of corporations crippled by the attack are pouring in three days after the hackers stunned the world and showed the impotence of cyber security networks. The ransomware locked about 200 computers of a Mumbai-headquartered company, which did not have any backup for its crucial income tax data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The company worried that the income tax department would come after it if it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the data readily available,&amp;rdquo; said a person in the know. Legal experts are cautioning companies against paying the ransom as this could land them in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While some companies may consider making payment to obtain the decryption key to unlock their computers that have been locked by the WCry virus, one must consider the legal implications of this action,&amp;rdquo; said Tushar Ajinkya, partner, DSK Legal, a law firm. &amp;ldquo;In the event it is concluded that the actions of the ransomware WCry in demanding payment for release of the encrypted data tantamount to extortion, then in addition to a FEMA violation, facilitators and recipients of such payment may also attract provisions of the PMLA,&amp;rdquo; Ajinkya said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies are believed to have paid the bitcoins with the help of third-party service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Typically, the process involves creating a bitcoin wallet and then making the payment. However, this should ideally be done in consultation with legal, forensic and cyber expert advisors as there tends to be little or no guarantee of regaining access to the data once the ransom is paid,&amp;rdquo; said Jaju of EY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time a ransomware has attacked India Inc. ET on January 11 reported that hackers seized control of computers at three banks and a pharmaceutical company and then demanded a ransom in bitcoins for the decryption keys to unfreeze them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases, Indian companies do not wish to report the cases or file a complaint with the investigative authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even Indian banks, which are required to make a mandatory disclosure to the regulator of any cyberattack, seldom do this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want A New Jio SIM? Here&#39;s What You Pay To Get &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in getting a new Reliance Jio SIM and availing the &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer? Rs 408 is the minimum amount you need to spend. For Jio non-Prime and new users, the recharge amount is Rs 309 along with an additional Rs 99. Similarly, to get the Rs 509 plan, the amount needed will be Rs 608.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has extensively provided free data services with unlimited calls for several months and with the telecom operator starting paid services, one can expect the firm to provide the &amp;lsquo;most affordable&amp;rsquo; plans. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rs. 408 is the minimum amount needed to avail Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has provided free services with unlimited calls for last few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has been in the controversy for stretching its free trial run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-dhan.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is WannaCry ransomware? How can it affect India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-is-wannacry-ransomware-how-can-it-affect-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-is-wannacry-ransomware-how-can-it-affect-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware, also known as WannaCrypt, has affected over 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on May 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware, also known as WannaCrypt, has affected over 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on May 12. Termed as one of the biggest ransomware attacks the world has ever seen, this bug has slept open dark signs of vulnerabilities in the digital era. Governments and experts are expecting a possible worsening of the ransomware cyber-attack. The indiscriminate attack began Friday and struck banks, hospitals and government agencies, exploiting known vulnerabilities in older Microsoft computer operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the attack about?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware that is also called WannaCrypt, affected at least 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on Friday. The WanaCrypt0r 2.0 bug basically encrypts data on a computer within seconds and displays a message asking the user to pay a ransom of $ 300 in Bitcoins to restore access to the device and the data inside. Even FedEx, European car factories, Spanish telecoms giant Telefonica, Britain’s health service and Germany’s Deutsche Bahn rail network have been hit. Payment is demanded within three days or the price is doubled, and if none is received within seven days the locked files will be deleted, according to the screen message, agencies reported.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/cZ543_0bjbw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is India safe? Is you Aadhaar card save?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack was specifically targeted at Microsoft Windows devices. Microsoft claims it “released a security update which addresses the vulnerability that these attacks are exploiting” in March itself, and advised users to update their systems in order to deploy the latest patches. However, Indians usually have the Windows running on office desktops, which makes the data vulnerable. A lot of personal data online are now connected to the Aadhaar data of over a billion Indians. “Since the user’s bank account is linked with his Aadhaar number, the ransomware can potentially lock down the account and make it unusable unless a ransom is paid,” Pradipto Chakrabarty, Regional Director, CompTIA India.
F-Secure highlighted the need for a four-phase approach to cybersecurity: Predict, Prevent, Detect, and Respond; and detect by monitoring infrastructure for signs of intrusion or suspicious behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Group Issues New Threat</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-as-cyberattack-eases-hacking-group-issues-new-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/even-as-cyberattack-eases-hacking-group-issues-new-threat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shadow Brokers, the group that has taken credit for that leak, threatened on Tuesday to release more recent code to enable hackers to break into the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used computers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governments turned their attention to possible new wave of cyber threats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber extortion campaign has infected more than 300,000 computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The attack has caused most damage in Russia, Taiwan and Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments turned their attention to a possible new wave of cyber threats on Tuesday after the group that leaked U.S. hacking tools used to launch the global WannaCry &amp;ldquo;ransomware&amp;rdquo; attack warned it would release more malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fast-spreading cyber extortion campaign, which has infected more than 300,000 computers worldwide since Friday, eased for second day on Tuesday, but the identity and motive of its creators remain unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack includes elements that belong to the U.S. National Security Agency and were leaked online last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shadow Brokers, the group that has taken credit for that leak, threatened on Tuesday to release more recent code to enable hackers to break into the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used computers, software and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog post written by the group promised from June to release tools every month to anyone willing to pay for access to some of the tech world&amp;rsquo;s biggest commercial secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also threatened to dump data from banks using the SWIFT international money transfer network and from Russian, Chinese, Iranian or North Korean nuclear and missile programs. &amp;ldquo;More details in June,&amp;rdquo; it promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spread of the WannaCry attack - which encrypts a user&amp;rsquo;s data and demands a &amp;ldquo;ransom&amp;rdquo; be paid electronically to free it up again - slowed to a trickle on Tuesday, with few, isolated examples being reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Canada, the Universite de Montreal was hit, with 120 of the French-language university&amp;rsquo;s 8,300 computers affected, according to a university spokeswoman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no new, major incidents in the United States. Fewer than 10 U.S. organizations have reported attacks to the Department of Homeland Security since Friday, a U.S. official told reporters on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack has caused most damage in Russia, Taiwan and Ukraine, according to Czech security firm Avast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States likely avoided greater harm as the attack targeted older versions of Microsoft Corp&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, and more U.S. users have licensed, up-to-date, patched versions of the software, compared to other regions of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Homeland Security began an &amp;ldquo;aggressive awareness campaign&amp;rdquo; to alert the tech industry to the importance of installing the patch that Microsoft issued in March that protected users from the vulnerability exploited by the attack, a U.S. official working on the attack told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft said on Tuesday it was aware of Shadow Brokers&amp;rsquo; most recent claim and that its security teams monitor potential threats in order to &amp;ldquo;help us prioritize and take appropriate action.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft President and Chief Legal Officer Brad Smith said earlier this week the WannaCry attack used elements stolen from the NSA. The U.S. government has not commented directly on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;north-korea-link-probed&#34;&gt;North Korea Link Probed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyber security researchers around the world have said they have found evidence that could link North Korea with the WannaCry cyber attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A researcher from South Korea&amp;rsquo;s Hauri Labs said on Tuesday their own findings matched those of Symantec and Kaspersky Lab, who said on Monday that some code in an earlier version of the WannaCry software had also appeared in programs used by the Lazarus Group, identified by some researchers as a North Korea-run hacking operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is similar to North Korea&amp;rsquo;s backdoor malicious codes,&amp;rdquo; said Simon Choi, a senior researcher with Hauri who has done extensive research into North Korea&amp;rsquo;s hacking capabilities and advises South Korean police and National Intelligence Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Symantec and Kaspersky said it was too early to tell whether North Korea was involved in the attacks, based on the evidence that was published on Twitter by Google security researcher Neel Mehta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FireEye Inc, another large cyber security firm, said it was also investigating, but it was cautious about drawing a link to North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The similarities we see between malware linked to that group and WannaCry are not unique enough to be strongly suggestive of a common operator,&amp;rdquo; FireEye researcher John Miller said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. and European security officials told Reuters on condition of anonymity that it was too early to say who might be behind the attacks, but they did not rule out North Korea as a suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lazarus hackers, acting for impoverished North Korea, have been more brazen in their pursuit of financial gain than others, and have been blamed for the theft of $81 million from the Bangladesh central bank, according to some cyber security firms. The United States accused it of being behind a cyber attack on Sony Pictures in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Korea has denied being behind the Sony and banking attacks. North Korean officials were not immediately available for comment and its state media has been quiet about the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-information-to-share&#34;&gt;No Information To Share&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In China, foreign ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said she had no information to share, when asked about the origin of the attack and whether North Korea might be connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several Asian countries have been affected by the malware, although the impact has not been as widespread as some had feared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Malaysia, cyber security firm LE Global Services said it identified 12 cases so far, including a large government-linked corporation, a government-linked investment firm and an insurance company. It did not name any of the entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We may not see the real picture yet, as companies are not mandated to disclose security breaches to authorities in Malaysia,&amp;rdquo; said LE Global CEO Fong Choong Fook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The real situation may be serious. In one of the cases, the attack was traced back to early April.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s state media said on Tuesday more than 200 computers had been affected, but one of the country&amp;rsquo;s leading anti-virus companies, Bkav, later put the figure at 1,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taiwan Power Co. said that nearly 800 of its computers were affected, although these were used for administration, not for systems involved in electricity generation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 19 A Day 4G Data, Unlimited Calls In New Plans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-offers-4g-data-unlimited-calls-in-new-plans-starting-rs-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-vodafone-offers-4g-data-unlimited-calls-in-new-plans-starting-rs-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone SuperWeek is priced at Rs 49 and will come with a validity of seven days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India on Thursday announced integrated plans offering unlimited voice and bonus data to its prepaid customers starting from Rs 19 per day. Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s two integrated &amp;ldquo;Voice plus Data&amp;rdquo; plans - Vodafone SuperDay and Vodafone SuperWeek - will enable its prepaid customers to enjoy benefits of unlimited local and STD calling with free data up to 250 MB for seven days. Under its Vodafone SuperDay plan, Vodafone is offering unlimited local and STD Vodafone-to-Vodafone calls and 100 MB data on 4G handsets at Rs 19 per day, the company said in a press release. Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s move comes amid heightened competition witnessed by existing operators in India&amp;rsquo;s telecom industry due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, say analysts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priced at Rs 19, Vodafone SuperDay will come with a validity of one day. Vodafone SuperWeek is priced at Rs 49 and will be valid for seven days. Under the Vodafone SuperWeek plan, the prepaid customers of the telecom operator will get 250 MB of data on 4G handsets, besides unlimited local and STD Vodafone-to-Vodafone calls, the company further said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India, a wholly-owned subsidiary of British telecom company Vodafone Group Plc, is also offering 100 minutes of calls to other networks as an additional benefits in a separate Vodafone SuperWeek plan priced at Rs 89. Vodafone prepaid customers recharging with the Rs 89 plan will get free local and STD calls on its own network, 100 minutes of local and STD calls on other networks and 250 MB of data on 4G devices, the press release added.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/vodafone-prepaid-650-400_650x400_51495700068.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At Vodafone, it is our constant endeavour to provide the best network, service experience and value to our customers. We are delighted to launch SuperDay andSuperWeek under our &amp;lsquo;Super&amp;rsquo; umbrella with the key objective of offering pocket friendly and affordable integrated plans that will appeal to the prepaid customers,&amp;rdquo; said Sandeep Kataria, director-commercial at Vodafone India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The SuperDay and SuperWeek packs are available across all retail outlets, website and the MyVodafone app,&amp;rdquo; the Vodafone India statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These plans will further enable our customers to remain confidently connected and enjoy a worry free Vodafone SuperNetTM4G experience on our best network ever. Moreover, these integrated plans come with unrestricted repeat purchase options ensuring more value to the customer,&amp;rdquo; Mr Kataria added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, another telecom operator Bharti Airtel announced new broadband plans, offering up to 100 per cent additional high speed data benefits. Bharti Airtel, whose broadband internet plans in the national capital start from Rs. 899 a month, said its new plans were aimed at driving India&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Jio, the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a variety of recharge options starting from Rs 19 to its prepaid subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s telecom customer base grew by about half a per cent to 119.45 crore in March, data from telecom regulator TRAI (Telecom Regulatory Authority of India) showed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Imposes Fee On Cheque Payments For Credit Card Dues. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card is levying a charge on payments made by cheques. This came into effect from April 1, according to SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s website. The card company said payments made below Rs 2,000 through cheques will attract a fee of Rs 100. &amp;ldquo;A fee of Rs.100 will be charged for payments made by cheque for an amount less than or equal to Rs.2000 w.e.f. 1st April &amp;lsquo;17. No additional fee will be charged for cheque payments greater than Rs. 2000,&amp;rdquo; SBI Card said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen that the majority of payments (over 90 per cent) are made through non-cheque modes. We have observed a trend of payment related disputes arising in small cheque payments, causing inconvenience to customers as well. We offer several seamless digital modes of payment which we are seeking to encourage, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s focus towards digital payments and this step will facilitate the same,&amp;rdquo; said SBI Card CEO Vijay Jasuja.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, payments made through SBI cheques will not incur the extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost. It is also likely to provide a boost to digital payments. SBI, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, entered credit card business in 1998 by roping GE Capital India, the consumer finance arm of US-based GE Capital. SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s latest offering &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; is targeted at all State Bank of India customers, including Jan Dhan account holders throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has introduced the &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; card in an effort to bring new users into the fold of cashless transactions. The card is issued to persons with a balance of Rs 25,000 in their SBI accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No such charge on cheque payments will be levied on holders of SBI Card Unnati which is targeted at first time credit card users and aimed at inclusion of people into the organised financial stream,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jasuja added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the new business plan 2017-18, unveiled by Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu on Thursday, besides the Aadhaar-based ticketing system, the Railways will move towards cashless ticketing system by installing 6,000 point-of-sale machines and 1,000 automatic ticket vending machines across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An integrated ticketing app will also be launched by May to promote cashless transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar number will be required for one-time registration at the IRCTC ticketing site. The step is aimed at eliminating touts from registering with fake identities,&amp;rdquo; a senior Railway Ministry official said, adding the Railways is preparing a software for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite taking several steps, touts corner a bulk of tickets and sell those at much higher prices and this is becoming a serious problem for the Railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new business plan also envisages launching of new tourist trains connecting hill stations and enhancing passenger comfort and providing pleasurable journey experience through improving amenities and catering service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar not mandatory for train tickets of senior citizens</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-train-tickets-senior-citizens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets but the Railways have initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens, Lok Sabha was informed today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu made it clear that Aadhaar number has not been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, however, said the Railway has initiated a process to create a database of senior citizens through pre-verification of senior citizens based on Aadhaar details on voluntary basis with effect from January 1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The system is intended to ensure that the senior citizen concession is not misused by unscrupulous elements by giving fictitious names and to use the data for decision making,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prabhu said to promote cashless ticketing system, various initiatives have been taken by the Indian Railways.
“Our ultimate destination is cashless ticket booking. But the immediate priority is less cash transaction,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rail Reservation System, Vikalp:10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-rail-reservation-system-vikalp-from-april-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Railways has announced the scaling up of a new reservation system called &amp;lsquo;Vikalp&amp;rsquo;, or alternate train accommodation scheme (ATAS), from April 1, 2017. Under the Vikalp scheme, wait-listed passengers can avail the opportunity of travelling in Rajdhani, Shatabdi or other premium/special trains even if they have booked tickets in other mail/express trains for the same destinations - at no extra cost. The Vikalp scheme aims to utilise vacant berths in many premier trains in all major routes. Currently, Railways is running the scheme on a pilot basis on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know about the Vikalp scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The Vikalp scheme will be initially available for e-tickets only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Under this scheme, wait-listed passengers will be given a choice to opt for the Vikalp scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Vikalp-opted passengers who remain fully wait-listed after charting will only be considered for allotment in the alternate train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No extra charges will be taken from passenger or any refund shall be provided for difference of fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Passengers once provided alternate accommodation in alternate train will be treated as normal passengers in alternate train and will be eligible for upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The Railways said that the Vikalp scheme will optimise berth utilisation across all trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Wait-listed passengers who opt for the Vikalp scheme should check PNR status after charting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Wait-listed passengers of original train will not be allowed to board the original train if allotted alternate accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The Vikalp-opted passengers who have been provided accommodation in the alternate train will not figure in the wait-listed charts of their original train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) When a Vikalp-opted passenger opts to cancel, after he/she has been given an alternate accommodation, he/she will be treated as a confirmed passenger and the cancellation rules will apply accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how do I protect my PC from WannaCry?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-do-i-protect-my-pc-from-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-do-i-protect-my-pc-from-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything you need to know about ransomware including the WannaCry attack, how to protect your PCs and laptops and what to do if you&amp;rsquo;re affected.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How does WannaCry work?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a lot of malware, it can arrive as an email attachment. This method relies on computer users opening the attachment, or clicking on a link in an email, which causes the program to run.
People often open these attachments or click links out of curiosity, because the sender is someone in their address book.
WannaCry then encrypts all the files and documents on the computer so the user cannot open them.
It displays a message saying “Ooops, your files have been encrypted!” and says you have three days to pay a $300 or $600 ransom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which versions of Windows are affected?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your computer runs Windows 10, it wasn’t targeted by WannaCry according to Microsoft’s blog post.
Also, up-to-date Windows 10 PCs would have been protected from the attack in any case.
The same security update in March would have protected Windows Vista, Windows 7 and Windows 8.1 systems, as long as you had automatic updates turned on (which is the default).
Only older versions of Windows which are no longer supported were vulnerable, including Windows XP and Windows 8.
It’s worth noting, though, that in general home users should not be affected by this particular piece of ransomware. It mainly targeted computers running the business version of Windows, specifically those using the SMB network file system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can I protect my files from WannaCry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has issued a security patch for Windows XP and Windows 8 – a very unusual step for unsupported operating systems – which you can download from the links on Microsoft’s blog.
If you have Windows Update enabled on other versions then you will already be protected against WannaCry and any other attacks which use the same vulnerability.
If you’re not sure, then open the Control Panel (you’ll find a link in the Start menu) and search for Windows Update. Click through to Windows Update and you’ll be able to check if it’s enabled or not.
There should be a button ‘Check for updates’ which you can click to force Windows to search and install critical updates.
Back up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, as we always recommend, you should have at least one (if not two) copies of any files you can’t afford to lose. Photos, home videos, financial documents and other files that can’t be replaced should be backed up regularly.
Ransomware is often clever enough to scan your home network and infect other computers and even network storage drives (NAS drives) so it’s really important to make a backup on an external hard drive that you disconnect and keep safely somewhere.
You can find our pick of the best backup software here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t open attachments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, as the computer user, are often the weak link in the chain. Windows and antivirus software – see below – can help to protect you from ransomware attacks, but you can help yourself by being extremely cautious about which email attachments you open and which links you click.
Typically, emails from hackers won’t contain a personal message, or it will be so generic that you can’t be sure it’s really from the person in the ‘sender’ field.
In WannaCry’s case, at least some of the emails pretended to be an important email from a bank about a money transfer.
Either just delete the email, or call the sender and ask them if they sent the email and what is in the attachment, or on the other end of the link. Unless you are absolutely sure the attachment is safe, don’t click on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Won’t antivirus software protect me from WannaCry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most but not all antivirus software now contains ‘anti-ransomware’ that should help protect your PCs and laptops from WannaCry and other ransomware.
That’s why it’s important not to rely just on Windows’ own security but to add an extra layer of protection.
Check out our list of the best antivirus to make sure you’re running one of our recommended packages. Our favourite is BitDefender, but there are plenty of other great options to choose from too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My PC is infected with WannaCry. What should I do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, don’t pay the ransom. It only encourages the criminals – getting paid is their end game.
Some security experts predict there could be a free ‘fix’ to decrypt the files in a few days and remove the malware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>200 Airports To Be Brought Under UDAN Scheme: Jayanta Sinha</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/200-airports-to-be-brought-under-udan-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jayanta Sinha said government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central government has embarked upon a plan to bring 200 airports under the regional air connectivity scheme, Union Minister of State for Aviation Jayanta Sinha said here today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Under the UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) regional air connectivity scheme, 33 airports have been already included since its launch last year in addition to 75 taking the total to 108. We intend to take the number to 200,&amp;rdquo; Mr Sinha said at an interaction at Bharat Chamber of Commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this, we will have multiple rounds of bidding, he said, adding the government was also keen to reduce the subsidy burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Sinha said so far the subsidy burden was only Rs 200 crore and 13 lakh seats have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pointing out that regional air connectivity was both pro-poor and pro-markets, he said that this twin objective had been met by offering seats at Rs 2,500 per seat per hour of flying and reducing the cost of flying by bringing down the costs of ATF and service charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding Bagdogra airport in West Bengal, he said talks were on for getting land with the state government for building a new modern terminal. He said that all greenfield airports would be built through the PPP route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding unruly behaviour while flying it is expected that both passengers and the cabin crew would adhere with the laid-down guidelines, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test To Check Call Drops Likely From This Month: TRAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/test-to-check-call-drops-likely-from-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/test-to-check-call-drops-likely-from-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Independent drive tests are going to begin. Actually, there was some gap (problem) which has been removed&amp;hellip;they should start probably from this month on,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom regulator Trai is likely to resume from this month its independent drive tests to check call drops and service quality of operators, after a gap of more than five months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Independent drive tests are going to begin. Actually, there was some gap (problem) which has been removed&amp;hellip;they should start probably from this month on,&amp;rdquo; Trai Chairman RS Sharma told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the telecom operators submit performance monitoring reports to the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) regularly, the regulator also undertakes audit and assessment of service quality through independent agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agencies conduct sample &amp;lsquo;drive tests&amp;rsquo; across various cities in the country, as part of audit and assessment of the operators&amp;rsquo; performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The independent drive tests are distinct from operator-assisted tests, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were doing drive tests in 11-12 cities, we will be doing it in more cities (this time). This will be different from the operator-assisted tests,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator-assisted drive test captures real-time data to monitor the level of call drops and voice quality, similar to Trai&amp;rsquo;s independent drive tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, unlike independent drive tests that are conducted by the regulator itself, the &amp;lsquo;operator-assisted&amp;rsquo; tests are conducted in co-ordination with telecom service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operator-assisted tests, a new concept, involves the telecom firms&amp;rsquo; equipment and costs, with the regulator monitoring and supervising the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, all drive tests &amp;ndash; be it independent or operator-assisted tests &amp;ndash; assess the performance of networks on various quality benchmarks, including call set-up success rate, call drop, blocked calls and Radio Frequency (RF) coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last round of independent drive tests were conducted by Trai in Amritsar, Delhi, Hyderabad, Bhopal, Chandigarh, Mumbai, Lucknow, Kanpur, Ahmedabad, Ranchi, Darjeeling, Sikkim and Trivandrum in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the last few months that Trai did not undertake independent tests, the operator-assisted tests were conducted in cities including Mathura (UP-West circle), Jaisalmer, (Rajasthan), Ujjain (Madhya Pradesh) and Mangalore (Karnataka) and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the regulator and the Department of Telecom (DoT) have been keeping a vigil on service quality issues such as call drops and call failures through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort to tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Department has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of efforts to keep the call quality in check, the Trai plans to roll-out, by the month-end, an app that will enable subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call, once the call is complete. The data will, thereafter, be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Completely Digitise Air Travel</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-completely-digitise-air-travel-says-jayant-sinha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-completely-digitise-air-travel-says-jayant-sinha/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government plans to use Aadhaar to ‘completely digitise’ air travel amid a raging debate on privacy concerns regarding the world’s largest biometric ID database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through verification by Aadhaar, travellers will be able to get a digital boarding pass long before their flight, Minister of State for Civil Aviation Jayant Sinha said in an interview with BloombergQuint’s Sanjay Pugalia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reaching the airport, Aadhaar biometrics would allow seamless entry through the security and check-in points, avoiding the need for a hard copy of the boarding pass, Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application programming interface will be similar to India Stack, which is part of the government’s ‘Digital India’ efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan comes as the Supreme Court hears a batch of petitions challenging the government’s decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for filing taxes. There are concerns regarding security of data on government websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent report by non-profit research organisation, the Centre For Internet &amp;amp; Society, pointed out that up to 13.5 crore Aadhaar numbers can be easily accessed through government portals and nearly three-fourths of these are linked to bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government also plans to bring in a Unified Security Architecture (USA) with the help of the Central Industrial Security Force (CISF) to standardise security systems throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unified force will secure all airports, including the regional ones, in a way that the Transport Security Administration works for all U.S. airports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;regional-connectivity&#34;&gt;Regional Connectivity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha expects to deploy the USA at more than 200 airports through the UDAN (Ude Desh Ke Aam Naagrik) initiative. It has already increased the number of airports from 75 to 108, Sinha added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UDAN scheme aims to boost regional connectivity with flights covering smaller distances through a market-based mechanism. The flying price has been capped at Rs 2,500 per hour to allow more flyers while airlines will get tax concessions to ensure feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo Airlines, owned by InterGlobe Aviation Ltd., has invested Rs 10,000 crore to acquire 50 turbojets for short-distance flights. Sinha said that national airlines such as IndiGo, SpiceJet, and others, are expected to handle regional routes through subsidiaries. He hopes that this will help shape up the regional aviation industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filing Income Tax Returns? Things To Keep In Mind As Deadline Approaches</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/filing-income-tax-returns-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-deadline-approaches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The income tax filing website typically has lots of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the close of the financial year, most individuals have completed their tax planning and tax deduction exercise for the year. This leaves the final step in completing one&amp;rsquo;s income tax process - filing ITR or income tax return. Often regarded as a painful formality, you must remember that this is one of the most important income document for any individual. While July 31, 2017 is the last day to file I-T returns, remember that the income tax filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - typically has a lot of server downtime due to last minute rush so ensure that you do not wait until the last day to file your returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Income Tax returns acts as an important income document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From this year on Aadhaar card is necessary to file I-T returns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I-T returns must be filed if your annual income is over Rs. 2.5 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some important things to remember when filing for tax returns according to leading share trading company and financial consultant Motilal Oswal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Anyone with an annual income of over Rs 2.5 lakh needs to file I-T returns whether the income is taxable or not. The Income Tax Department tracks lifestyle expenses, asset purchases, investments and foreign travel through your PAN card and Aadhaar number so try to be as transparent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Remember that all your sources of income must be filed as part of your I-T returns. Even if your dividends are tax-free, it is still essential to disclose all these details in your I-T returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) If you have made losses on shares or equity-oriented mutual funds, you need to show the loss when you file returns. If you do not disclose the loss in your I-T returns, you lose the benefit of setting off the losses against other gains and also lose the benefit of carrying forward these losses for a period of 8 years, says Motilal Oswal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) You are required to file your returns online on the website of the Income Tax Department. However, your job does not end there. The returns need to be e-verified which can be done by linking it to your registered bank account having the same name details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) While refunds below Rs. 50,000 are directly credited to your bank account via RTGS, refunds above Rs. 50,000 are only paid out by cheque. Hence if your refund is above Rs. 50,000 ensure that your address is updated in the I-T records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Remember that effective July 1, 2017, an Aadhaar card is a prerequisite for filing income tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) If you forget to file returns before the due date of July 31 and do not have any tax payable then you can file the returns by March 31 next year. But refund cases will not be entertained if returns are filed after the cut-off date of July 31.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>