<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Technology on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latest Technology on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.
The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.
Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.
The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said. The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.
Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18 specified financial transactions in which quoting of PAN is mandatory now</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</guid>
      <description>Although Aadhaar is gradually gaining more importance than PAN – a ten-digit unique alphanumeric number issued by the Income Tax Department – however, PAN is still important, especially for financial transactions. According to experts, PAN is a way for the Income Tax Department to keep tabs on your financial dealings whereas Aadhaar’s main purpose is to create a centralized database of each citizen residing in India. PAN, in fact, is a very useful tool to estimate the total tax revenue being generated in the country and to be used as an identification document is not its primary job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 financial tasks to do when a parent dies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</guid>
      <description>Goodbyes are the hardest when they are final. It’s worse if it involves one of your parents. The heartbreak is probably lesser in intensity only to that of your surviving parent, the spouse who is left grappling with a crippling emotional void at the fag end of life. Yet, it is critical to take a financial reality check and you, as progeny, are the best suited to do it.
Taking stock of the finances is an overwhelming task and it’s easy to be stumped by the maze of formalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks on Strike 22 August</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-strike-on-august-22-to-protest-against-proposed-reforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-strike-on-august-22-to-protest-against-proposed-reforms/</guid>
      <description>United Forum of Banking Unions (UFBU), the umbrella body of trade unions in the banking sector, has called a nation-wide strike on August 22 to protest against the reforms proposed by the Centre.
West Bengal convenor of UFBU, Siddhartha Khan said that the government is ushering in privatisation and consolidation in the Indian banking sector in the garb of reforms.
He said that the Bank Board Bureau had been formed to bring all the public sector banks (PSBs) under a banking investment company and get the government&amp;rsquo;s share in PSBs below 50 per cent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is exempt from PAN card Aadhaar card linking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link the existing Aadhaar numbers with the PAN cards of taxpayers with effect from July 1, 2017. In fact, Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar / Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from 1st July, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card: How to Verify Your Phone Number.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-verify-phone-number-email-address-aadhaarcard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-verify-phone-number-email-address-aadhaarcard/</guid>
      <description>Are you sure that the contact information registered with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) for your Aadhaar Card is correct? If not, we would advise you to head to the UIDAI website and check it out for yourself. Aadhaar card is increasingly becoming the most important proof of identification and considering that the government has made it mandatory to link your Aadhaar cards with PAN card for filing income tax returns, its importance has grown further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EPFO To Launch Online PF Withdrawal Facility Soon: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-to-launch-online-pf-withdrawal-facility-soon-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-to-launch-online-pf-withdrawal-facility-soon-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>The launch of this facility will not only ease the process for subscribers but also speed up the processing time.
The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation or EPFO is expected to soon launch an online facility for withdrawal of provident fund (PF) money and pension fixation. The launch of this facility will not only ease the process for subscribers but also speed up the processing time. &amp;ldquo;The process of connecting all field offices with a central server is going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Slash Prices Of Knee Implants. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-caps-prices-of-knee-implants-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-caps-prices-of-knee-implants-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Drug pricing regulator NPPA (National Pharmaceutical Pricing Authority) on Wednesday announced a price cap on knee replacements. NPPA, which had earlier put limits on the prices of coronary stents, slashed the prices of total knee replacement systems and their individual components by as much as 69 per cent, an official notification issued by NPPA said. According to the price ceiling notice, the price of total knee implants made of cobalt chromium has now been capped at Rs 54,720, down 65 per cent from its average maximum retail price of Rs 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Army will get Apache attack choppers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-approves-procuring-six-apache-attack-choppers-for-indian-army/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-approves-procuring-six-apache-attack-choppers-for-indian-army/</guid>
      <description>In a major decision, the defence ministry approved procurement of six Apache helicopters along with weapons systems from American giant Boeing at a cost of Rs 4,168 crore for the Army which will be its first fleet of attack choppers. It will be a follow on order to the deal India had signed with Boeing and the US government for 22 Apache helicopters and 15 Chinook heavy-lift choppers in September 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Phone Offline Bookings Begin: Delivery Date, Documents You Need, Price, and More Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-bookings-offline-pre-order-registration-delivery-date-price-aadhaar-card-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-bookings-offline-pre-order-registration-delivery-date-price-aadhaar-card-document/</guid>
      <description>Jio Phone bookings have opened in certain offline retail stores in the Delhi-NCR area, ahead of the scheduled August 24 date that was announced at the Reliance AGM on July 21. If you have such an offline retailer taking Jio Phone bookings right now, you can be ahead of the millions who are expected to buy the handset when bookings officially open. Gadgets 360 spoke to one such retailer to find out the details of the pre-order process, the documents needed, how many units a person can order, delivery date, and when the Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAN Migration: Do You Need It? And How To Do It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pan-migration-do-you-need-it-and-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pan-migration-do-you-need-it-and-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>PAN or Permanent Account Number is issued by the Income Tax department with details including date of birth, name and PAN number of the individual. A PAN number allotted to a person is a 10-digit alphanumeric number used in to link all of his or her financial transactions with the unique ID such as tax payments, income tax return and wealth tax return. PAN, thus, acts as a financial identifier for the person with the tax department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vodafone Offers Unlimited Voice Calling, 1GB Data Per Day at Rs. 348</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-348-prepaid-recharge-offer-rajasthan-unlimited-voice-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-348-prepaid-recharge-offer-rajasthan-unlimited-voice-calling/</guid>
      <description>HIGHLIGHTS
 Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s new prepaid plan offers unlimited voice calling It is priced at Rs. 348 and offers 1GB per day of data benefits The recharge plan is available for Rajasthan subscribers only  In a bid to combat the Reliance Jio competition, Vodafone has now launched a special recharge plan for prepaid users in Rajasthan. The Vodafone 348 Prepaid Recharge offer comes with unlimited voice calling benefits and 1GB of 4G data per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>your Aadhaar is safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</guid>
      <description>Amidst concerns regarding Aadhaar data leak, a look at how the unique identification system actually adheres to the principles of privacy
Privacy and data protection concerns have become serious in a digital world due to ease of search and aggregation, with or without Aadhaar. Type any name in Google and it will throw up thousands of results, giving data/information publicly available. Hence, the responsibility falls on organisations which collect data from individuals to protect it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>