<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Technology on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latest Technology on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonetisation: Opening another window to deposit Rs 500, Rs 1000 notes will be good; here is why</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-opening-another-window-to-deposit-rs-500-rs-1000-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-opening-another-window-to-deposit-rs-500-rs-1000-notes/</guid>
      <description>Seven months after demonetisation, the controversies around it aren’t going away. Apart from the debate over whether it was desirable, the government did all manner of flip-flops—given that this was the first such exercise anywhere in the world, and so there was no playbook to go by, though, that may have been unavoidable. What was not was the time given for people to exchange their old notes, given the rush at banks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.
After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.
Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 5 Recharge, Vodafone Offers Unlimited Data.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-in-rs-5-recharge-vodafone-offers-unlimited-data-in-some/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone said in a press release that the 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively.
Amid a telecom industry witnessing Jio&amp;rsquo;s highly competitive tariff pricing, Vodafone India on Tuesday announced unlimited data plans with free local and STD calls priced from Rs 5 per day in the UP West telecom circle. Aimed at the Ramzan festival, Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s 2G and 3G customers in UP West and Uttarakhand regions can enjoy unlimited data for Rs 5 and Rs 19 per hour respectively, according to a press release by the telecom company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 500 4G VoLTE Reliance  jio handset</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-rs-500-4g-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-rs-500-4g-phone/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is likely to launch its much-awaited 4G VoLTE feature phone within this month, with brokerage HSBC putting the price at as low as Rs 500, a move which could bring in another wave of disruption in the telecom market.
The launch — which some believe could be announced at parent Reliance Industries’ annual general meeting on July 21— would follow Jio’s likely announcement of a new tariff plan with aggressive price-points over the next couple of days with its 84-day Dhan Dhana Dhan offer — announced on April 11 — drawing to a close, people familiar with the matter said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea stall where PM Modi sold tea to be placed on tourism map</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tea-stall-where-pm-modi-sold-tea-to-be-placed-on-tourism-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tea-stall-where-pm-modi-sold-tea-to-be-placed-on-tourism-map/</guid>
      <description>Converting the stall into a tourist spot is part of a larger project of putting PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s birthplace Vadnagar in Mehsana district of Gujarat on the global tourism map
The tea stall in Gujarat’s Vadnagar where Prime Minister Narendra Modi once sold tea during his childhood is set to become a tourist spot with the government deciding to give it a face-lift. The stall is located on one of the platforms of the Vadnagar Railway station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>your Aadhaar is safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dont-panic-aadhaar-safe-writes-rs-sharma/</guid>
      <description>Amidst concerns regarding Aadhaar data leak, a look at how the unique identification system actually adheres to the principles of privacy
Privacy and data protection concerns have become serious in a digital world due to ease of search and aggregation, with or without Aadhaar. Type any name in Google and it will throw up thousands of results, giving data/information publicly available. Hence, the responsibility falls on organisations which collect data from individuals to protect it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Rooted’ Phones May Soon Have No Place In Modi’s Cashless India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rooted-phones-may-soon-no-place-modis-cashless-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rooted-phones-may-soon-no-place-modis-cashless-india/</guid>
      <description>India is considering a ban on smartphones with modified firmware from all of its cashless payment platforms due to security concerns, according to the chief of National Payments Corporation of India which manages all retail payment systems in the country. “These smartphones have a certain degree of vulnerability in the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), the Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) or any kind of financial system”, AP Hota, chief executive officer and managing director of NPCI told BloombergQuint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 दिन में ही 3.20 रुपये सस्ता हो गया पेट्रोल और डीजल की कीमत में आई 2.41 रुपये प्रति लीटर की कमी</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/per-litre-and-diesal-price-cut-2-42-rupees-per-liter-in-just-over-10-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/per-litre-and-diesal-price-cut-2-42-rupees-per-liter-in-just-over-10-days/</guid>
      <description>16 जून से पूरे भारत में अंतरराष्ट्रीय मार्केट के मुताबिक डीजल और पेट्रोल की कीमतें तय होने लगी हैं। अभी तेल की कीमतों में रोजाना कुछ पैसे की कमी आ रही है। 3-4 दिन में महसूस होता है कि तेल की कीमतें कम हुई हैं। 16 जून से लेकर 26 जून तक तेल की कीमतों में काफी कमी आई है। पिछले 11 दिन में दिल्ली में पेट्रोल की कीमत में</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar-PAN can still be linked; June 30th deadline was for filing tax returns without Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pan-can-still-linked-june-30th-deadline-filing-tax-returns-without-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pan-can-still-linked-june-30th-deadline-filing-tax-returns-without-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>Reports that June 30 was the last date to link your PAN card with Aadhaar have proved to be untrue. While you can still link your PAN card with the Aadhaar on the Income Tax e-filing website, getting a new PAN card would now require Aadhaar.
“From July 1, linking Aadhaar with your PAN card is mandatory to file Income Tax returns. And to apply for a new PAN card, you would need an Aadhaar first,” Nidhi Shrivastava, a Chartered Accountant, said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get 224 GB For Rs. 509:Jio Releases New Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</guid>
      <description>As Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s promotional offers - Jio Summer Surprise and Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan - will expire for most users this month, the telecom operator has launched a new offer that provides customers up to 224 GB of 4G data along with other freebies. This comes as part of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive push to gain market share from entrenched players like Bharti Airtel and Vodafone. Jio&amp;rsquo;s new offer replaces its recharge packs priced Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten rules you must follow while filing income tax returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ten-rules-you-must-follow-while-filing-income-tax-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/ten-rules-you-must-follow-while-filing-income-tax-return/</guid>
      <description>Who needs to file tax returns?
If the gross taxable income after exemptions, but before deductions, exceeds the basic limit, or if a tax refund has to be claimed, you need to file your tax return.
 _I: THOU SHALL FILE RETURNS IF INCOME EXCEEDS BASIC LIMIT _
Do you have to file your tax return? Taxpayers hold many misconceptions about this. Some think if their income is not taxable, they needn’t file their return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is exempt from PAN card Aadhaar card linking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link the existing Aadhaar numbers with the PAN cards of taxpayers with effect from July 1, 2017. In fact, Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar / Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from 1st July, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>petrol price has fallen Rs 3.5 per litre in just 12 days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-diesel-price-today-falls-11-days-daily-fuel-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-diesel-price-today-falls-11-days-daily-fuel-price/</guid>
      <description>Petrol and diesel prices are falling since the daily fuel price revision was implemented. But unlike earlier, when there would be significant noticeable changes every fortnight, this time, the prices have fallen by just a few paise everyday, barely to the notice of many people across the nation. Put together, however, the change is huge over the last 12 days, since July 16, when the daily revision in retail fuel prices began nationwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.
The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.
Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar saved Rs 90, 000 crore of public money since 2014: Centre</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</guid>
      <description>An affidavit filed by the central government in the Supreme Court has stated that Aadhaar has saved Rs 90,000 crore of public money since 2014.
It further said that the total recorded savings through Direct Benefit Transfer scheme alone have been Rs 49,560 crore in just two years.
The affidavit filed by the centre provided official statistics on the impact Aadhaar on a multitude of welfare schemes and benefits across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SIM card without Aadhar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-sim-card-without-aadhar-card/</guid>
      <description>The Government is planning to ask telecom companies to link customers&amp;rsquo; SIM Cards with their Aadhar number, according to a report by a news channel.
The Department of Telecom has already issued notices to telecom companies asking them to ensure that the SIM card of the mobile subscribers is linked to his/her Aadhaar card,&amp;rdquo; the report said. The DoT has also asked the telcos to complete the process within a year,&amp;rdquo; the report added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Data Safe From Cyber Attacks Assures Aadhaar Body Chairman</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/citizens-personal-data-safe-from-cyber-attacks-assures/</guid>
      <description>UIDAI presently maintains the data of about 114 crore Indians in over 6,000 servers located in Bengaluru and Manesar.
Allaying concerns about the security of data in Aadhaar servers in the wake of &amp;ldquo;WannaCry&amp;rdquo; ransomware attack, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) today said its database was completely secured and immune to attacks from any kind of malware.
&amp;ldquo;The data in the Aadhaar servers is in the encrypted form. You cannot do anything with that information, which is in an encrypted form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.
The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>