<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Technology on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latest Technology on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>18 specified financial transactions in which quoting of PAN is mandatory now</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/18-specified-financial-transactions-in-which-quoting-of-pan-is-mandatory-now/</guid>
      <description>Although Aadhaar is gradually gaining more importance than PAN – a ten-digit unique alphanumeric number issued by the Income Tax Department – however, PAN is still important, especially for financial transactions. According to experts, PAN is a way for the Income Tax Department to keep tabs on your financial dealings whereas Aadhaar’s main purpose is to create a centralized database of each citizen residing in India. PAN, in fact, is a very useful tool to estimate the total tax revenue being generated in the country and to be used as an identification document is not its primary job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 financial tasks to do when a parent dies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-financial-formalities-you-should-perform-when-your-parent-die/</guid>
      <description>Goodbyes are the hardest when they are final. It’s worse if it involves one of your parents. The heartbreak is probably lesser in intensity only to that of your surviving parent, the spouse who is left grappling with a crippling emotional void at the fag end of life. Yet, it is critical to take a financial reality check and you, as progeny, are the best suited to do it.
Taking stock of the finances is an overwhelming task and it’s easy to be stumped by the maze of formalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSNL Offers &#39;Unlimited Data Plan&#39; At Rs. 249</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-offers-unlimited-data-plan-at-rs-249/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-offers-unlimited-data-plan-at-rs-249/</guid>
      <description>India’s state-owned telecom operator Bharat Sanchar Nigam Ltd. (BSNL) has announced an entry level ‘Unlimited Broadband at Rs. 249’ plan for its users in India under which they will get up to 300GB data per month. The new plan also offers free calls during night time on certain days. The introductory offer which is only for new customers is valid for one year after which it will be changed to &amp;lsquo;BBG Combo ULD Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.
The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Recharge: Now, Get Flat Rs. 75 Cashback. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-recharge-now-get-flat-rs-75-cashback-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-recharge-now-get-flat-rs-75-cashback-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Recharge your Jio number and get Rs. 75 cashback. This is a new limited-period offer from PhonePe, a Flipkart-owned mobile wallet, which is giving a flat Rs. 75 cashback on Jio prepaid recharge. Reliance Jio had a total subscriber base of 12.3 crore after adding over 6 million customers in June, according to latest figures released by telecom regulator. With revised &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, which Jio launched last month, Jio customers can get 1 GB data per day for 84 days at a recharge of Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.
Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI ATM Withdrawal Rules And Charges For Other Services</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-atm-withdrawal-rules-and-charges-for-other-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-atm-withdrawal-rules-and-charges-for-other-services/</guid>
      <description>State Bank of India or SBI has in recent months revised its charges on various services like ATM withdrawal , cash transactions, issuance of cheque books, exchange of soiled notes and online transfer of funds through Immediate Payment Service (IMPS). SBI has clarified that customers of its mobile wallet State Bank Buddy will be charged 3 per cent plus GST of 18 per cent on transfer from Buddy to bank account using IMPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is exempt from PAN card Aadhaar card linking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-pan-card-linking-find-out-who-are-exempted/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link the existing Aadhaar numbers with the PAN cards of taxpayers with effect from July 1, 2017. In fact, Section 139AA of the Income-tax Act, 1961, as introduced by the Finance Act, 2017, provides for mandatory quoting of Aadhaar / Enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form, for filing of return of income and for making an application for allotment of Permanent Account Number with effect from 1st July, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.
The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.
Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar saved Rs 90, 000 crore of public money since 2014: Centre</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-saved-rs-90-000-crore-public-money-since-2014-centre/</guid>
      <description>An affidavit filed by the central government in the Supreme Court has stated that Aadhaar has saved Rs 90,000 crore of public money since 2014.
It further said that the total recorded savings through Direct Benefit Transfer scheme alone have been Rs 49,560 crore in just two years.
The affidavit filed by the centre provided official statistics on the impact Aadhaar on a multitude of welfare schemes and benefits across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply For a Passport At A Post Office</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apply-for-a-passport-at-a-post-office/</guid>
      <description>86 post offices have already started work so that people can apply for passports there, Shashi Tharoor said.
Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who led a 15-member delegation of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs here, today stated that passports could be applied from post offices shortly. During their stay in the city, the parliamentary committee members visited the Amritsar Passport office, where Tharoor interacted with passport seekers besides holding discussions with the officials at the passport office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Reduces Term Deposit Rates By Up To 0.5%</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-reduces-term-deposit-rates-by-up-to/</guid>
      <description>SBI said the rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.
Country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India has cut its term deposit rates by up to 50 basis points for various maturities.
The rates have been revised for medium and long term deposits and for amount below Rs 1 crore.
According to the new structure, for two to less than three years deposits, SBI will offer a rate of 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get 224 GB For Rs. 509:Jio Releases New Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-releases-new-offers-get-up-to-224-gb-for-rs-509/</guid>
      <description>As Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s promotional offers - Jio Summer Surprise and Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan - will expire for most users this month, the telecom operator has launched a new offer that provides customers up to 224 GB of 4G data along with other freebies. This comes as part of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive push to gain market share from entrenched players like Bharti Airtel and Vodafone. Jio&amp;rsquo;s new offer replaces its recharge packs priced Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to enrol your children for Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-enrol-your-children-for-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-enrol-your-children-for-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>After all the Aadhaar-PAN hype most people know how important Aadhaar is and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be incorrect to say that financial life in the future is going to be difficult without it.
As of now it is not mandatory for kids to possess an Aadhaar, but there&amp;rsquo;s no harm in enrolling them for the same. It could just make their life easier in the coming years. There would be instances when your child would be required to furnish a proof of identity, and Aadhaar could be of great help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.
Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>