<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Announces Free Incoming Calls On Domestic Roaming To Counter Jio, Airtel</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-announces-free-incoming-calls-on-domestic-roaming-to-counter-jio-airtel/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea also unveiled international roaming value packs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move comes after different offers introduced by rival telecom firms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular today announced free incoming calls on domestic roaming and unveiled international roaming value packs that, it claimed, would prevent &amp;ldquo;bill shocks&amp;rdquo; to those travelling abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers come on the heels of the larger rival Bharti Airtel announcing removal of all roaming charges for outgoing and incoming calls as well as SMSes and data usage within India, to take on competition from newcomer Reliance Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Effective April 1, 2017, Idea&amp;rsquo;s 200 million customers will enjoy free incoming calls while roaming on company&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G and 4G network across 400,000 towns and villages in the country. Idea customers will be able to make outgoing calls, SMS freely at affordable rates while roaming anywhere in India,&amp;rdquo; an Idea release said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further said mobile data tariffs and data pack benefits of home circle will be available while roaming within India at no extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facility of free incoming calls on domestic roaming will be extended to both prepaid and postpaid customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For international travellers, the company is offering international roaming value packs with free bundled usage of up to 400 outgoing minutes, 100 SMSes per day, 3GB bundled data and unlimited incoming calls for Rs 2,499 for Asia, and Rs 5,999 for Europe for 30 days validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These international roaming packs also come bundled with free 1GB/2GB/3GB data and overage charges as low as Rs 3 per MB to avoid bill shock to travelling customers,&amp;rdquo; Idea said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company said it has done a study of customer&amp;rsquo;s travel destinations, usage patterns and bill shock complaints to design a new range of value packs for select destinations across Europe, Asia, America, UK and Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For value conscious customers, the packs start at Rs 1,199 for 10 days validity and go up to Rs 5,999 for 30 days validity, giving up to 85 per cent savings on international roaming charges,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;Idea is now set to enable over 200 million customers to use their mobile phones freely, without having to worry about roaming charges, while they travel anywhere in the country,&amp;rdquo; Sashi Shankar, Chief Marketing Officer of Idea Cellular said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 27, Bharti Airtel had removed domestic roaming charges on calls and data, and said international call rates will be cut by up to 90 per cent to as low as Rs 3 per minute and data charges by up to 99 per cent to Rs 3 per MB across popular roaming destinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press statement, &amp;lsquo;Airtel Declares War on Roaming&amp;rsquo;, the company had then said the move will lead to &amp;ldquo;death of National Roaming&amp;rdquo; from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Communications New Offer: 1 GB 4G Data For Rs 49, 3 GB for Rs 149</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-communications-new-offer-1-gb-4g-data-for-rs-49-3-gb-for-rs-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-communications-new-offer-1-gb-4g-data-for-rs-49-3-gb-for-rs-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Communications also introduced a competitive 3G offer of unlimited data access at Rs 99, while unlimited 2G data access will be available for Rs 49.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Communications (RCOM) on Friday launched a &amp;lsquo;Joy of Holi&amp;rsquo; offer in which it will provide its 4G customers with 1GB of data access for Rs 49 and 3GB for Rs 149, along with free and unlimited on-net local and STD calls, valid for 28 days, a company statement said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also introduced a competitive 3G offer of unlimited data access at Rs 99, while unlimited 2G data access will be available for Rs 49.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Regardless of the type of smartphone or feature phone being used, customers will get best-in-class data and voice services without any additional recharge or membership-across 4G, 3G and 2G,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At RCOM, we have been overwhelmed by the response that our Unlimited Plan received last year - a validation of our efforts to constantly enhance customer experience and delight. We now take a new leap with additional benefits being offered to our 4G customers, with the &amp;lsquo;Joy of Holi&amp;rsquo; offer,&amp;rdquo; said Gurdeep Singh, Co-CEO, Reliance Communications, and Chief Executive Officer of RCOM&amp;rsquo;s Consumer Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Additionally, we still see immense potential in the 3G and 2G markets, which boast of 750 million smartphones and data-ready feature phones. We have, therefore, customized special offerings in this space as well, with segmented and value-creating propositions,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Will Be Soon Mandatory For Booking Train Tickets Online</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-will-be-soon-mandatory-for-booking-train-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Railways will soon move towards Aadhaar-based online ticketing system to prevent touts from blocking a bulk of tickets, end fraudulent bookings and curb cases of impersonation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar number has been made mandatory for senior citizens to avail concessions in train tickets from April 1. A three-month trial run for this is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the new business plan 2017-18, unveiled by Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu on Thursday, besides the Aadhaar-based ticketing system, the Railways will move towards cashless ticketing system by installing 6,000 point-of-sale machines and 1,000 automatic ticket vending machines across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An integrated ticketing app will also be launched by May to promote cashless transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar number will be required for one-time registration at the IRCTC ticketing site. The step is aimed at eliminating touts from registering with fake identities,&amp;rdquo; a senior Railway Ministry official said, adding the Railways is preparing a software for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite taking several steps, touts corner a bulk of tickets and sell those at much higher prices and this is becoming a serious problem for the Railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new business plan also envisages launching of new tourist trains connecting hill stations and enhancing passenger comfort and providing pleasurable journey experience through improving amenities and catering service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 GB Data For Rs 345: Airtel&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer offers comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tariff battle in the Indian telecom sector has further intensified with Bharti Airtel launching an aggressive mobile data plan to counter Reliance Jio. Market leader Bharti Airtel has announced a plan for select customers wherein its subscribers will be offered 28 GBs of  data along with free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;local and STD calls for a period of 28 days under a pack priced at Rs 345. Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer, though it will charge for its services from April 1. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;continues the benefits that the telecom arm of Reliance Industries had offered under its Happy New Year scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 303 Prime offer, for example, gives Jio subscribers free voice calls and a daily cap of 1 GB of internet data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel has also placed a limit on internet usage at 1 GB per day. Airtel customers can use 500 MBs of data during day and the remaining 500 MB data can be consumed between 12 am and 6 am, said a customer care executive of Bharti Airtel. Recently, Bharti Airtel chairman Sunil Mittal said that the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new tariff announced by Reliance Jio is very aggressive and unsustainable, and the industry will respond to it with more competitive plans and additional data offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tariffs that they (Jio) have announced are still very aggressive, which means you got to respond. You got to do more packages&amp;hellip; you have to throw in more data. All those things need to be done,&amp;rdquo; he had said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel had on February 27, 2017 waived domestic roaming charges to compete with free voice calls and roaming offered by Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has promised to match the best mobile data usage plan in the market and also add 20 per cent more data to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPhone 6 32GB Variant Offered At Discount On Amazon India</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon India is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/images/iphone-6-32-gb-amazon-in-650-400_650x400_61488796030.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Apple iPhone 6 32GB variant in Space Grey option is being sold for Rs 28,999, instead of Rs 30,700, under a limited period scheme on Amazon India&amp;rsquo;s website. The iPhone 6 32GB variant scheme is open till March 7, 2017, Amazon India said. Amazon India, the Indian operations of American e-commerce giant Amazon, is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-few-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are few things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 32GB variant of iPhone 6 is being offered by third-party retailers, not by Apple Inc itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers will be able to save Rs 1,701 or 6 per cent (inclusive of all taxes) under the scheme, the Amazon India website noted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the exchange option, customers can avail up to Rs 8,550 off for delivery to select locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orders can be placed via credit/debit cards and net banking. However cash on delivery or COD option is not available, as per the Amazon India website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;lsquo;One-Day Delivery&amp;rsquo; option is also available under the scheme, which guarantees delivery under one working day in select cities for items Fulfilled by Amazon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to analysts, sale of the 32GB variant is likely to attract good demand for Cupertino, California-based Apple Inc, which had launched iPhone 6 only in 16GB, 64GB and 128GB storage variants initially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers can also avail EMI options. &amp;ldquo;EMI available on HDFC Bank, Citibank, ICICI Bank, SBI Card, Standard Chartered Bank, Kotak Mahindra Bank, Axis Bank and HSBC credit cards&amp;hellip;Banks may charge you pre-closure and interest charges when you cancel/return an EMI order,&amp;rdquo; the Amazon India website     added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 32GB variant of iPhone 6 comes with a one-year manufacturer warranty for device and 6-month manufacturer warranty for in-box accessories including batteries from the date of purchase, it added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Average Download Speed Doubles In January, Says Telecom Regulator</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-average-download-speed-doubles-in-january-says-telecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-average-download-speed-doubles-in-january-says-telecom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRAI collects and computes speed of mobile data from subscribers across the country with the help of the MySpeed application on a real time basis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average peak download speed on Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s network more than doubled to &lt;em&gt;17.42&lt;/em&gt; megabit per second at the end of January, according to data by the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average mobile broadband speed published by the telecom regulator showed that the download speed on Jio network reached &lt;em&gt;17.42&lt;/em&gt; mbps in January from &lt;em&gt;8.34 mbps&lt;/em&gt; at the end of December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this speed, a user can download a movie in less than three minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second place was Idea at 8.53 mbps, up from 6.6 mbps at the end of December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The download speed on Airtel network dropped slightly to 8.15 mbps compared to 8.42 mbps in the previous month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other networks, download speed on Vodafone and BSNL also dipped marginally to 6.13 mbps and 2.89 mbps from 6.8 mbps and 3.16 mbps, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data showed average download speed of 2.3 mbps on Tata Docomo network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average download speeds of other networks were not available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRAI collects and computes speed of mobile data from subscribers across the country with the help of the MySpeed application on a real time basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Fine If Your SBI Account Has No Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest lender, has decided to increase manifold the minimum balance required for maintaining savings account from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Savings bank account holders of SBI and its five associates - which will merge with it on April 1 - will have to maintain the monthly balance or else they will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs 100 (in metro cities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India has 31 crore savings bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, the monthly average balance (MAB) for a savings bank account is Rs 500 without facility of cheque book and Rs 1,000 with cheque book across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank has now decided to fix separate MABs for &amp;lsquo;metro&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;urban&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;semi-urban&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;rural&amp;rsquo; areas from the beginning of next financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benchmark for MAB and penalties are likely to be followed by other public sector banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance for metro branches will be Rs 5,000 and penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance will be between Rs 50 and Rs 100. For urban and semi-urban branches, the monthly average balance has been fixed at Rs 3,000 and Rs 2,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of rural branches, the minimum balance has been fixed at Rs 1,000. Breach of MAB will attract a penalty ranging between Rs 20 and Rs 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five associates banks of SBI - State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur (SBBJ), State Bank of Mysore (SBM), State Bank of Travancore (SBT), State Bank of Patiala (SBP) and State Bank of Hyderabad (SBH) - will merge with the parent on April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 5G on Trial Samsung Network </title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/arqiva-and-samsung-to-trial-5g-network-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/arqiva-and-samsung-to-trial-5g-network-in-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung has already undertaken some early tests of the technology on its campus in South Korea, and mobile operators and vendors have announced 5G trials in countries ranging from the United States to Japan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communications group Arqiva and Samsung Electronics will trial Britain&amp;rsquo;s first 5G network in London this year, the companies said, with the capability of delivering ultra-fast broadband to mobile devices and potentially autonomous vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advent of the fifth generation of mobile telecoms is viewed as essential to expected growth in demand for ever-higher speeds, capacity and reliability, with global operators such as Vodafone, Telefonica and Verizon working with network equipment makers to develop the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arqiva, which provides TV broadcast and mobile infrastructure, said the fixed wireless access network would operate in its own 28GHz band spectrum using Samsung&amp;rsquo;s 5G base stations and equipment installed in premises in central London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Over time, smarter network infrastructure and an enhanced ability to support exponential scale for connectivity will open the doors to further applications across a variety of markets such as IoT (Internet of Things), industrial applications and the full promise of autonomous vehicles,&amp;rdquo; Arqiva Chief Executive Simon Beresford-Wylie said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung has already undertaken some early tests of the technology on its campus in South Korea, and mobile operators and vendors have announced 5G trials in countries ranging from the United States to Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arqiva, which counts the Canada Pension Plan Investment Board and Macquarie as investors, is considering a stock market listing and is seeking new investors, sources said this month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra 5GB Free Data, Jio Sweetens Offer For Prime Members </title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-sweetens-offer-for-prime-members-adds-extra-5gb-free-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-sweetens-offer-for-prime-members-adds-extra-5gb-free-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under the new offer announced, Jio has decided to load an extra 5GB data (worth Rs 201) to those recharging with Rs 303.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio on Friday sweetened the offering for its &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; members saying those recharging with Rs 303 will get an extra 5GB data beyond the 28GB promised under the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, Prime members &amp;ndash; on payment of Rs 303 per month and a one-time joining fee of Rs 99 &amp;ndash; would be entitled to unlimited free voice calls (STD and roaming) and text messages, 28GB data at 4G speeds, subject to a usage cap of 1GB a day, the breach of which would slow down the speed unless more data was bought. The plan comes with a 28 day validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime membership offer requires customers to enrol by March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the new offer announced today, Jio has decided to load an extra 5GB data (worth Rs 201) to those recharging with Rs 303.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This essentially means that subscribers who breach the 1GB daily limit would not face slowdown in speeds given the new 5GB data pool being made available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, those recharging with Rs 499 and above would now get additional 10GB data extra, over the already promised 56GB (or 2GB per day limit). The extra data pool is only valid for the first month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 21, while announcing that it has crossed the 100 million customers mark in 170 days of launch, Reliance Industries&amp;rsquo; Chairman Mukesh Ambani had announced a slew of offers, including 20 per cent more data than any rival from April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio, he had said, will continue to offer free voice calls and national roaming post April 1, when its promotional free voice and data offer ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For existing customers, he had announced a Jio &amp;lsquo;Prime Membership programme&amp;rsquo; wherein customers could enrol by paying one-time fee of Rs 99 and continue to get the existing benefits till March 2018 at &amp;ldquo;a rock-bottom introductory price of only Rs 303 per month&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Prepaid, Postpaid Plans For Prime, Non-Prime Users: Here Are The Details</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-prepaid-postpaid-plans-for-prime-non-prime-users-here-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-prepaid-postpaid-plans-for-prime-non-prime-users-here-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The enrolment programme for Reliance Jio Prime membership will be open till March 31 for an enrolment fee of Rs 99.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio will now start charging users for its services from April 1. It has already commenced enrolment for Prime membership which is open for its existing subscribers and those who join its network before March 31. The enrolment programme for Prime membership will be open till March 31 for a fee of Rs 99. For prepaid users, the recharge options start from Rs 11. What if a Jio Prime member does not recharge after March 31? &amp;ldquo;If you have not recharged with any plan, your services will stop. You will be able to get incoming voice calls and SMS for certain period,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Jio says on its website. (Note: Domestic voice calls to all operators are free under every plan, only the SMS and data limit changes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#For prepaid users, here are the following plans:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 19 (1-day validity): For Prime users, unlimited SMS and 200 MB 4G data. For non-Prime user, only the 4G data gets reduced to 100 MB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 49 (3-day validity): For Prime, unlimited SMS, 600 MB 4G data; non-Prime data gets lowered to 300 MB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 96 (7-day validity): Free SMS and 7 GB 4G data with FUP (Fair Usage Policy) at 1 GB per day for Prime users; data limited to 0.6 GB with FUP at 0.6 GB per day for non-Prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 149 (28-day validity): 100 SMS and 2 GB 4G data for Prime; 1 GB 4G data for non-Prime with 100 SMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 303 (28-day validity): Unlimited SMS with 28 GB data at 1 GB per day FUP for Prime; non-Prime users data lowered to 2.5 GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 499 (28-day validity): Prime users get free SMS with 56 GB data at 2 GB per day FUP; data limit reduced to 5 GB for non-Prime users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999: Validity of 60 days, free SMS with 60 GB data with no FUP for Prime; data limit lowered to 12.5 GB with a validity of 30 days for non-Prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 1,999: Unlimited SMS with 125 GB data with 90-day validity for Prime; data limit lowered to 30 GB with a validity of 30-day for non-Prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 4,999: Validity of 180-day with 350 GB data, free SMS for Prime users; data limit reduced to 100 GB with 30-day validity for non-Prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,999: 360-day validity with 750 GB data, unlimited SMS; data reduced to 200 GB with 30-day validity for non-Prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Booster packs: Rs 11 for 0.1 GB, Rs 51 for 1 GB, Rs 91 for 2 GB, Rs 201 for 5 GB and Rs 301 for 10 GB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top ups: These provide monetary value in your core account that can be used to make international calls and SMS (beyond particular limit) etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 10: Talktime of Rs 7.7, Rs 20: Talktime of Rs 15.39 and Rs 50: Talktime of Rs 40.48.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full talktime on the top up of Rs 100, Rs 150, Rs 200, Rs 300, Rs 500, Rs 750, Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000 and Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For postpaid users, here are the plans:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 303: Free SMS with 30 GB 4G data at 1 GB per day FUP for Prime users; data limit reduced to 2.5 GB for non-Prime users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 499: 60 GB data at 2 GB per day FUP, free SMS for Prime; data limit lowered at 5 GB for non-Prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999: Free SMS with 60 GB data for Prime users; data limit gets reduced to 12.5 GB for non-Prime users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Booster packs: Rs 51 for 1 GB, Rs 91 for 2 GB, Rs 201 for 5 GB and Rs 301 for 10 GB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Prime membership plans: How to subscribe and recharge</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-prime-membership-plans-subscribe-recharge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-prime-membership-plans-subscribe-recharge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio has rolled out its Jio Prime membership plan. Here’s how to subscribe and recharge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio has rolled out its Jio Prime membership plan. The Prime membership plan is an extension of Reliance Jio’s Happy New Year plan which will end on March 31. Reliance had introduced the Jio network last year and had been very aggressive with its tariff plans, which were basically free. But after March 31, users will not get everything for free. But in order to minimise the effect, Reliance Jio has introduced the Prime membership plan where users will have to pay a certain amount, which is essentially much less than other incumbents. In order to continue using the previous ‘Happy New Year’ offer, Jio users will have to pay a subscription fee of Rs 99. Additionally, they will have to shell out Rs 303 every month to continue accessing Jio’s 4G services and also the full bouquet of Jio’s media services for one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-enrol-for-jio-prime-membership&#34;&gt;How to enrol for Jio Prime membership?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do so by paying a one-time fee of Rs 99 via MyJio app, the company’s website as well as via Jio offline stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-can-you-enrol-for-jio-prime-membership&#34;&gt;When can you enrol for Jio Prime membership?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can enrol for Jio Prime membership between March 1 to March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-get-the-prime-membership&#34;&gt;How to get the Prime membership?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers who do not want to change their number can also become a Jio prime user by following four steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1: You need to send a text message, writing ‘PORT’ from your mobile phone through the existing network to the central number for mobile number portability which is 1900. The message will be delivered to TRAI’s for verification and authentication.
For example: Write ‘PORT 9999xxxxxxx’ in the message box and send to 1900. After sending, you will receive an SMS with a reference code of portability.
Step 2: Android users need to download the Jio App bundle on your smartphone and then generate an offer code.
Step 3: Buy a Jio SIM from any Reliance Digital Xpress and Reliance Digital Xpress mini stores by providing them with an eKYC verification through your Aadhar number and get a Jio SIM. You also need to provide the person assisting you with the reference code.
Step 4: You need to make due payment of your old telecom provider and get your number ported to Reliance Jio.
Step 5: After clearing your dues, you will receive an SMS of successful portability followed by various exciting Jio offers. After the portability is done, You are set to enjoy the 4G digital revolution from your existing phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-much-will-it-cost&#34;&gt;How much will it cost?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jio Prime membership program incurs a one-time fee of Rs 99. Under Jio Prime plan, you will continue to get all services that are available under the Jio ‘Happy New Year’ plan for a period of one year. That means you can get 1 GB data per day after paying Rs 303 for a month until March 31, 2018. Moreover, there will be no voice call and roaming charges. You can do so by paying a one-time fee of Rs 99 via MyJio app, the company’s website as well as via Jio offline stores and same with the Rs 303 every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;till-when-can-you-avail-the-offer&#34;&gt;Till when can you avail the offer?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio Prime Members can continue enjoying the unlimited benefits of JIO HAPPY NEW YEAR OFFER until 31st March 2018. And if you are still not a Jio prime user, then in such a case easily switch your operator and become a Jio prime user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vodafone to offer 28GB data with unlimited calling at Rs 346, offer valid until March 15</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-to-offer-28gb-data-with-unlimited-calling-at-rs-346-offer-valid-until-march-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-to-offer-28gb-data-with-unlimited-calling-at-rs-346-offer-valid-until-march-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to take on Reliance Jio, Vodafone has launched new plans which will offer the same benefits as JioPrime.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to take on Reliance Jio, Vodafone has launched new plans which will offer the same benefits as JioPrime. As part of the ‘Welcome Back Offers’, the telecom major will offer two new plans of Rs 342 and Rs 346. Sanjay Bafna first broke the news of Vodafone’s ‘Welcome Back Offers’ on Twitter and posted about the new plan. However, the telco has now confirmed to Indianexpress.com regarding its new plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rs 342 offers unlimited calling along with 28GB of data per month along with FUP of 1GB per day. The Rs. 346 plan will offer unlimited calling with just 10GB of data for 28 days, allowing users to make voice calls up to 300 minutes per day , which will be charged at standard rates, post the limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Vodafone customers are diverse as are their wants. To satisfy these diverse needs and wants, Vodafone offers various segmented propositions. This is one such segmented offering and the offer is valid only till 15 March”, the company said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone will be testing these products till March 15. The customers who recharge with the plans before March 15 will get additional 28 days of same benefits at free of cost. The schemes are exclusively available for prepaid customers and every customer that recharges with these plans will be whitelisted and can recharge with the same plan for the next 11 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, RIL Chairman Mukesh Ambani announced Jio’s Rs 303 plan which is available for those who take up the Jio Prime membership. Under this plan, a user will get 28GB 4G data and unlimited voice calls without any roaming charges, the FUP is 1GB per day.
Jio Prime members will be able to enjoy unlimited benefits of the existing services for another year or till March 31, 2018. There is also a Rs 499 per month plan which offers 2GB of 4G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio Prime: Plans, Recharge, Subscription And More</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-prime-plans-recharge-subscription-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-prime-plans-recharge-subscription-and-more/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under the Prime offer, Jio customers get a one-year extension of current unlimited data benefits, which are available under Happy New Year offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newly offered plans under Reliance Jio Prime are open for enrolment. The Prime subscription can be availed by both existing Jio users and those who subscribe to Jio&amp;rsquo;s services till March 31, 2017. Jio subscribers can opt Prime for a one-time membership fee of Rs 99. Under the Prime offer, Jio customers get a one-year extension of current unlimited data benefits, which are available under Happy New Year offer. Since its launch in September, Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s subscriber base has grown at a scorching pace. Reliance Industries (RIL) chairman Mukesh Ambani, who is also the country&amp;rsquo;s richest man, said Jio amassed 10 crore subscribers in just 170 days of its launch and expects to cover most of the country&amp;rsquo;s population by end of this year. Jio will charge for its services from April 1, 2017, ending free services that shook up the telecom sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;plans-under-reliance-jio-prime&#34;&gt;Plans Under Reliance Jio Prime:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For prepaid users, the plans offered starts from Rs 19 which is valid for a day and offers 200 MB 4G data for Prime customers while 100 MB for non-Prime subscribers. Rs 49 (3-day validity) offers 600 MB for Prime and 300 MB for non-Prime users. Other plans are of Rs 96 (7-day validity), Rs 149 (28-day), Rs 303 (28-day), Rs 499 (28-day), Rs 999 (30-day), Rs 1,999 (90-day), Rs 4,999 (180-day) and Rs 9,999 (360-day) offering different data packs depending on the type of the recharge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For postpaid users, the plans are of Rs 303 (28 GB 4G data for a month with 1 GB daily data limit), Rs 499 (58 GB data with 2 GB data limit per day), and Rs 999 (60 GB data for a month).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reliance-jio-prime-plans&#34;&gt;reliance jio prime plans&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jioss.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;All Jio Prime plans offer unlimited voice calls to all operators as well as free roaming. Booster packs are also there for users if they exceed the data limit of the plan. Rs 51 booster pack offers 1 GB 4G data. Others include Rs 91 (2 GB data), Rs 201 (5 GB data), and Rs 301 (10 GB data).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;subscription-for-jio-prime&#34;&gt;Subscription For Jio Prime:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recharge of Rs 99 needs to be done before March 31, 2017 from MyJio, JioMoney, Jio.com or nearest retailer. The Jio Prime plans come into effect from April 1, 2017, the day the existing Jio Happy New Year Offer expires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-recharge-for-jio-prime-offer&#34;&gt;How To Recharge For Jio Prime Offer:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, launch the MyJio app and see whether if it is asking for update. If yes, then update it and sign in to the account. Look for the recharge under Jio Prime and select Rs 99 option. Choose the payment mode and pay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things to know on the Jio Prime membership scheme</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-prime-membership-enrolment-starts-today-10-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-prime-membership-enrolment-starts-today-10-things/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime membership opened for enrolment today. The new Reliance Jio Prime plan continues the unlimited benefits that Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s current Happy New Year plan offers. Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani had earlier announced that Jio crossed the 100 million customer base mark in 170 days of its launch. Under the Prime offer, existing Jio customers get a one-year extension of current unlimited data benefits, beginning April 2017, at a one-time enrolment fee of Rs 99 and &amp;ldquo;a rock-bottom introductory price of only Rs 303 per month&amp;rdquo;.  Many analysts are hopeful that the aggressive Prime offering will enable Reliance Jio to retain most of the customers after the free offer ends this month end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know-on-the-jio-prime-membership-scheme&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know on the Jio Prime membership scheme:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Reliance Jio will continue to offer domestic calls to any network including STD and roaming for free beyond April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &amp;ldquo;Jio promises to provide world-class data at prices affordable to all Indians.&amp;rdquo; Mr Ambani said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership will enable members to enjoy &amp;ldquo;the full bouquet of Jio&amp;rsquo;s applications&amp;rdquo; till March 31, 2018, extending the Jio Happy New Year Offer by a full year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) The membership is available for existing Jio customers as well as those who join the network before March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) They can sign up for Prime membership from March 1 to March 31, 2017, for a one-time fee of Rs 99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For Prime subscribers, free 4G data usage would be capped at 1 GB per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Enrolment for Jio Prime Membership can be done through MyJio app, the www.jio.com website or by simply walking into any Jio or Jio partner store, Reliance Industries Limited or RIL added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The extension of Jio Happy New Year Offer - which was similar to Jio&amp;rsquo;s initial promotional offer of free voice and data - for another full year will also translate to additional benefit worth over Rs 10,000 for Prime membership subscribers, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Promising to be the most value-for-money telecom operator in India, Jio said it will monitor publicly announced plans from all operators across the country on a regular basis and provide 20 per cent more data than the respective highest-selling plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Analysts welcomed Jio&amp;rsquo;s shift to paid services under the Prime offering, saying it would bring more rational competition to the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 150 After 4 Free Cash Transactions A Month</title>
      <link>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/hdfc-bank-icici-and-axis-resume-levy-on-cash-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aadhaarcardnews.in/hdfc-bank-icici-and-axis-resume-levy-on-cash-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Axis, ICICI Bank to charge Rs 5 per per thousand rupees for cash transactions after 4 Free in a month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some banks, including HDFC Bank, have begun charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new charges are applicable to savings as well as salary accounts effective from Wednesday, leading private sector player HDFC Bank said in a circular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank would also cap the third party cash transactions at Rs 25,000 per day, while cash handling charges would be withdrawn effective Wednesday, the circular added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of several banks, including ICICI Bank and Axis Bank, these charges came into effect early in January and are same as they were before the demonetisation move announced on November 8, while there is an increase in such fees in case of some others, including HDFC Bank, from March 1 onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These charges are for cash transactions in the branches, and not through ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move was seen in some quarters as aimed at discouraging cash transactions and furthering the digital payment drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the basic no-frills accounts, maximum four cash withdrawals would continue to remain free and there would be no fees for cash deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to details on ICICI Bank website, there will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while Rs 5 per thousand rupees would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150 in the same month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third party limit would be Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For non-home branches, ICICI Bank would not charge anything for first cash withdrawal of a calendar month and Rs 5 per thousand rupees thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anywhere cash deposit, ICICI Bank would charge Rs 5 per thousand rupees (subject to a minimum of 150) at branches, while deposit at Cash Acceptance Machine would be free of charge for first cash deposit of a calendar month and Rs 5 per thousand thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ATM intercharge charges have also been re-introduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Axis Bank, the first five transactions or Rs 10 lakh of cash deposits or withdrawals would be free and charged at Rs 5 per thousand rupees or Rs 150, whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could not be ascertained whether the public sector banks have also begun imposing such charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When contacted, a senior official said there has been no directive from the government to the banks regarding levy of such charges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>