<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/categories/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Asked To Update ATM Software To Prevent &#39;WannaCry&#39; Cyberattack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-asked-to-update-atm-software-to-prevent-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RBI asked banks to put in place a software update at automated teller machines to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India has asked banks to follow the instructions of the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In), a government organisation, to prevent attack by ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; which has impacted various IT networks in over 150 countries. CERT-In has come out with a list of dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts and webcast on how to protect networks from the global ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been reported that a new ransomware &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo; is spreading widely, the RBI advisory to the banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wannacry encrypts the files on infected Windows system and spreads by exploiting vulnerabilities, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI also asked all banks to put in place a software update at ATMs to prevent their systems from a malware that has attacked payment systems across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate malware attack last year, 3.2 lakh debit cards were compromised in the country. Data of the users who transacted from ATM machines of Hitachi were compromised during May, June and July last year. The Hitachi ATMs deployed by many White Label ATM players and Yes Bank were impacted by the malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to reports, ATMs or automated teller machines are highly vulnerable to such malware attacks as they currently run on old version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system, making a software security patch update a necessary exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a total of 2.2 lakh ATMs in India, of which many old ones run on Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, the ransomware has hit systems in more than 150 countries, including Russia and the UK, in one of the most widespread cyber attacks in history. It infected computers running on older versions of Microsoft operating systems like XP, locking access to files on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cyber criminals have demanded a fee of about $300 in crypto-currencies like Bitcoin for unlocking the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has introduced a security patch to tackle the situation, and consumers across the globe have been advised to download the solution at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CERT-In on Monday said it has not received any formal report of cyber attack on India&amp;rsquo;s vital networks by the crippling global ransomware, &amp;lsquo;WannaCry&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) had said on Sunday that a few systems of the Police Department in Andhra Pradesh were impacted and that the state government has been informed to follow the advisory by the CERT-In.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the Maharashtra Police department said it was partially hit by the ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the alert, the Gujarat government began equipping its state computer systems with anti-virus software and upgrading its Microsoft operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the advisory issued by CERT-In, the ransomware infects other computers on the same network and is also spreading through malicious attachments to e-mails. Security firms have suggested that users immediately disconnect the infected device from the local network to contain the spread of infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, major companies including telecommunications firm Telefonica have been infected. The most disruptive attacks were reported in the UK, where hospitals and clinics were forced to turn away patients after losing access to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks limit functions to a minimum to avoid hack</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/amid-wannacry-chaos-banks-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/amid-wannacry-chaos-banks-limit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Indian banks ordered a ban on staff using internet in office except for essential banking services, while the leader, State Bank of India, has installed new software and ordered branches to follow instructions to prevent Wannacry malware from crippling operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bankers were barred from accessing various websites, including Gmail and Yahoo. Those in non-sensitive departments were also told not to visit social media sites like Facebook and Twitter. The use of internet was permitted only for clearing operations and necessary businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is to be taken most seriously. Please ensure these are percolated to the last mile up to every employee having access to the network, including staff working in offices/departments/TCs/call centres, etc,&amp;rdquo; Union Bank of India chairman Arun Tiwary said in a message to departmental heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian Banks&amp;rsquo; Association warned its members to take precaution in a way that would protect the individual banks as well as the system from the attack, which is threatening to stall businesses. &amp;ldquo;We have advised banks to take utmost precaution in light of the reports of a global cyber attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This advisory is just precautionary in nature and we are confident that banks are well equipped to deal with any challenges that come,&amp;rdquo; said an IBA official. He cannot be named because he is not allowed to speak to media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks, in general, use dedicated computers to access internet so that their core banking solutions remain immune to outside threats, but these dedicated machines are now being used with restrictions, senior officials of three state-run banks said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are being extremely vigilant because of this new threat. Though we have found nothing extraordinary in our systems so far, our IT teams are on high alert because of this heightened threat,&amp;rdquo; said the chief operating officer at a private sector bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The malware spreads by exploiting vulnerable systems running on Windows operating system. The Indian Computer Emergency Response Team has issued advisory for prevention of this threat. &amp;ldquo;So far, there is nothing damaging coming out of India, but there is considerable risk for the large databases of KYC and Aadhaar, which banks will have to be careful about,&amp;rdquo; said Ashvin Parekh, an independent banking consultant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October last year, a malwarerelated security breach had forced SBI to block six-lakh debit cards as a precaution after it was alerted by card network companies such as Mastercard and Visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Digital transactions in financial services have grown at a rapid pace in India, but investment in security is not commensurate with the risk the transactions pose,&amp;rdquo; said Piyush Singh, managing director, financial services - Asia Pacific, Accenture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks in India will not only have to look at investment in technology infrastructure, but also operations management and contagion of risks posed by technology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Banks Cut Home Loans Rates, Special Discounts for Women</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-hdfc-lower-home-loan-rates-for-affordable/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ICICI and HDFC&amp;rsquo;s decision comes close on the heels of the State Bank of India and LIC Housing Finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICICI Bank cut home loan rates by 0.3% for loans up to Rs 30 lakh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDFC lowers rate to 8.35% for new home loan up to 30 lakh for women&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s largest private sector lender ICICI Bank cut its home loan rates by 0.3 per cent for loans up to Rs 30 lakh, a move that was matched by HDFC Bank on Monday bringing them in line with the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender State Bank of India. SBI is the biggest player in the home loan segment with around 26 per cent market share, followed by HDFC. With the cut in interest rates, salaried borrowers can avail home loans at 8.40 per cent while salaried women borrowers will get home loans at 8.35 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the move, ICICI Bank managing director Chanda Kochhar said the bank is committed to supporting the government&amp;rsquo;s vision to provide housing for all by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In line with this commitment, we have reduced the home loan interest rates for the affordable housing segment. With this announcement, customers of Economically Weaker Section (EWS) and Low Income Group (LIG) can avail the dual benefit of low interest rates from us and the Credit Linked Subsidy under the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICICI Bank also said that its customers taking home loans in the affordable segment will also have the option to select the type of interest rate. In both these cases, the reduction in interest rates is 30 basis points from the previous rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can enjoy the benefit of floating interest rate or a fixed interest rate for the initial two/three years followed by floating rate, ICICI Bank said, claiming to be the first to offer such flexibility to customers. &amp;ldquo;The reduced rate will be effective from May 15, 2017 for new borrowers,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI and LIC Housing Finance had dialed back interest rates on housing loans last week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Avail 100% Cashback In Jio&#39;s New Offer For JioFi</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-new-exchange-offer-buy-jiofi-for-rs-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer, newcomer Reliance Jio has launched new offers to attract dongle, data card and wifi router users. The Mukesh Ambani-owned telecom venture is offering up to 100 per cent cash back (10 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) on JioFi device if you buy it with exchange of your old dongle. If you do not want to avail the exchange facility, then you will get free data worth Rs 1,005 (5 top-up vouchers worth Rs 201 each) or nearly 50 per cent cash back on the JioFi device value of Rs 1,999. However, this offer is applicable only if you buy the JioFi device from Jio.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to avail the offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First you need to buy the JioFi router from the Jio.com website by paying Rs 1,999. You can also avail an equated monthly installment (EMI) facility to buy this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After buying the device online, you need to visit a Jio Store with the original invoice, JioFi Box and your old dongle if you want to avail the exchange facility (See the list of old dongles eligible for exchange offer). You also need to carry original and copy of Proof of Address (POA), Proof of Identity (POI), and a passport size colour photograph. For availing Jio SIM through eKYC, a local Aadhaar card is must.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After availing the Jio SIM, which will be used in the device, you need to do a recharge of Rs 408 (Rs 309+Rs 99) or Rs 608 (Rs 309+Rs 99) for availing the Jio Prime membership along with Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, customer has to recharge with minimum Rs. 149 and above to be eligible for free vouchers of Rs 201, which gives 5GB of 4G data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, which is for 84 days, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 2,010 (10 vouchers worth Rs. 201 each) if you had availed the exchange offer. Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 10 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not avail the exchange offer, then post expiry of Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer period, you will get free 4G data worth up to Rs. 1005 (5 vouchers worth Rs. 201 top up). Customers will be entitled for 5GB of 4G data worth Rs 201 top up with each recharge (up to 5 recharges) done before March 31, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer is applicable under both pre-paid and postpaid plans&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware Virus WannaCry Hits Gujarat Government&#39;s IT Network</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-virus-affects-gujarat-government-it-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/wannacry-virus-affects-gujarat-government-it-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The virus has affected around 120 computers linked to the Gujarat State Wide Area Network.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 120 computers connected to the Gujarat government&amp;rsquo;s information technology network were hit by ransomware virus &amp;lsquo;Wannacry&amp;rsquo; though no &amp;ldquo;valuable&amp;rdquo; data was compromised, a senior government official said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As per our information, so far the virus has affected around 120 computers in different government departments linked to the Gujarat State Wide Area Network (GSWAN),&amp;rdquo; said Science and Technology Department Secretary Dhananjay Dwivedi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But none of the affected computer has any valuable data or important information that could adversely impact the government&amp;rsquo;s functioning,&amp;rdquo; said Dwivedi. Many computers linked to the district collectorate across the state were affected by the virus even though no major data loss was reported.
Following the attack, computers that were functioning were shut down as precautionary measure, crippling the work, the officials said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six computers at Mehsana district collectorate were affected by the ransomware virus with the message reflecting on the screen saying that the data of the computer has been &amp;ldquo;encrypted&amp;rdquo; and one will have to pay a certain amount in bitcoins to get the data back, an official of the National Informatics Centre said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mehsana Collector Alok Pandey said following the attack, all computers connected to the district collectorate were shut down as precautionary measure. &amp;ldquo;All computers have been shut down after the attack was reported in some computers. These were the computers operating independently and there is no data loss as such due to the attack,&amp;rdquo; said Pandey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several collectorates across the state reported instances of computers getting affected by the virus. At least three computers of Jamnagar Regional Transport Office were also affected by the virus, leading to shutting down of the RTO&amp;rsquo;s entire operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The computers which were linked to the works related to the registration certificate (RC) books were affected by the virus, which sent out the message that the data have been encrypted, said Assistant RTO F U Jakhra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affected computers, however, were not linked to GSWAN network, and were being handled by a private agency, added Jakhra. State&amp;rsquo;s Crime Records Bureau (CRB) issued advisory for the police stations and public to take precautionary measures to prevent the attack and said reports have been sought from individual police stations where computers were affected by the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have sought reports from police stations on what kind of problem they have faced with their computer with regards to data. We will analyse the report and take corrective actions accordingly,&amp;rdquo; said SCRB SP Ashok Kumar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, anti-virus software was being installed and operating system upgraded in computers connected to GSWAN to prevent such hacking attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Indian companies pay WannaCry ransom</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/despite-legal-implication-some-companies-pay-the-ransom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/despite-legal-implication-some-companies-pay-the-ransom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A top executive working with an Indian conglomerate couldn&amp;rsquo;t fathom how a bill of $300 (Rs 19,000) landed up at his company for using a free Wi-Fi at a five-star hotel coffee shop. The CEO of another New Delhibased manufacturing company clicked on an unknown link — a mistake that would come back to haunt him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laptops of the executive and the CEO were compromised by ransomware WannaCry, the malicious fast-spreading virus that has confounded cyber security experts around the world. The malware demands $300 in bitcoins to release the infected system and its data, causing hundreds of millions of dollars in business damage to corporations and government utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though lawyers and experts have been advising companies to not pay bitcoins, some Indian companies are believed to have gone ahead and paid the ransom to get their systems unlocked. &amp;ldquo;There would be some companies that may have paid the ransom in haste to retrieve their encrypted data. As of Monday morning, the hackers seem to have globally collected 23 bitcoins, which is around $41,400,&amp;rdquo; said Amit Jaju, executive director, Fraud Investigation &amp;amp; Dispute Services (FIDS), EY India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most legal experts and cybercrime experts are cautioning companies not to pay as this could also have legal implications. &amp;ldquo;PwC never recommends paying ransomware ransom — unless there is a threat to life. Doing so fuels the ransomware economy, funding development of additional ransomware techniques and campaigns. In many cases, we have seen that when money is paid, larger attack happens a few days or weeks later,&amp;rdquo; said Sivarama Krishnan, leader -cyber security at PwC India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Twitter handle, @actual_ransom, that describes itself as &amp;ldquo;a bot that is watching the bitcoin wallets tied to WannaCry ransomware attack&amp;rdquo; is also providing live updates of bitcoins paid by companies globally. &amp;ldquo;While we are monitoring this Twitter handle, you can&amp;rsquo;t trust the authenticity of this,&amp;rdquo; said a cybercrime expert with a consultancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports of corporations crippled by the attack are pouring in three days after the hackers stunned the world and showed the impotence of cyber security networks. The ransomware locked about 200 computers of a Mumbai-headquartered company, which did not have any backup for its crucial income tax data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The company worried that the income tax department would come after it if it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the data readily available,&amp;rdquo; said a person in the know. Legal experts are cautioning companies against paying the ransom as this could land them in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While some companies may consider making payment to obtain the decryption key to unlock their computers that have been locked by the WCry virus, one must consider the legal implications of this action,&amp;rdquo; said Tushar Ajinkya, partner, DSK Legal, a law firm. &amp;ldquo;In the event it is concluded that the actions of the ransomware WCry in demanding payment for release of the encrypted data tantamount to extortion, then in addition to a FEMA violation, facilitators and recipients of such payment may also attract provisions of the PMLA,&amp;rdquo; Ajinkya said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies are believed to have paid the bitcoins with the help of third-party service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Typically, the process involves creating a bitcoin wallet and then making the payment. However, this should ideally be done in consultation with legal, forensic and cyber expert advisors as there tends to be little or no guarantee of regaining access to the data once the ransom is paid,&amp;rdquo; said Jaju of EY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time a ransomware has attacked India Inc. ET on January 11 reported that hackers seized control of computers at three banks and a pharmaceutical company and then demanded a ransom in bitcoins for the decryption keys to unfreeze them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases, Indian companies do not wish to report the cases or file a complaint with the investigative authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even Indian banks, which are required to make a mandatory disclosure to the regulator of any cyberattack, seldom do this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is WannaCry ransomware? How can it affect India?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-is-wannacry-ransomware-how-can-it-affect-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-is-wannacry-ransomware-how-can-it-affect-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware, also known as WannaCrypt, has affected over 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on May 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware, also known as WannaCrypt, has affected over 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on May 12. Termed as one of the biggest ransomware attacks the world has ever seen, this bug has slept open dark signs of vulnerabilities in the digital era. Governments and experts are expecting a possible worsening of the ransomware cyber-attack. The indiscriminate attack began Friday and struck banks, hospitals and government agencies, exploiting known vulnerabilities in older Microsoft computer operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the attack about?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WannaCry, a crypto-ransomware that is also called WannaCrypt, affected at least 1,00,000 computers spread over 100-150 countries, including India, on Friday. The WanaCrypt0r 2.0 bug basically encrypts data on a computer within seconds and displays a message asking the user to pay a ransom of $ 300 in Bitcoins to restore access to the device and the data inside. Even FedEx, European car factories, Spanish telecoms giant Telefonica, Britain’s health service and Germany’s Deutsche Bahn rail network have been hit. Payment is demanded within three days or the price is doubled, and if none is received within seven days the locked files will be deleted, according to the screen message, agencies reported.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/cZ543_0bjbw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is India safe? Is you Aadhaar card save?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack was specifically targeted at Microsoft Windows devices. Microsoft claims it “released a security update which addresses the vulnerability that these attacks are exploiting” in March itself, and advised users to update their systems in order to deploy the latest patches. However, Indians usually have the Windows running on office desktops, which makes the data vulnerable. A lot of personal data online are now connected to the Aadhaar data of over a billion Indians. “Since the user’s bank account is linked with his Aadhaar number, the ransomware can potentially lock down the account and make it unusable unless a ransom is paid,” Pradipto Chakrabarty, Regional Director, CompTIA India.
F-Secure highlighted the need for a four-phase approach to cybersecurity: Predict, Prevent, Detect, and Respond; and detect by monitoring infrastructure for signs of intrusion or suspicious behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how do I protect my PC from WannaCry?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-do-i-protect-my-pc-from-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-do-i-protect-my-pc-from-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything you need to know about ransomware including the WannaCry attack, how to protect your PCs and laptops and what to do if you&amp;rsquo;re affected.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How does WannaCry work?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a lot of malware, it can arrive as an email attachment. This method relies on computer users opening the attachment, or clicking on a link in an email, which causes the program to run.
People often open these attachments or click links out of curiosity, because the sender is someone in their address book.
WannaCry then encrypts all the files and documents on the computer so the user cannot open them.
It displays a message saying “Ooops, your files have been encrypted!” and says you have three days to pay a $300 or $600 ransom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which versions of Windows are affected?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your computer runs Windows 10, it wasn’t targeted by WannaCry according to Microsoft’s blog post.
Also, up-to-date Windows 10 PCs would have been protected from the attack in any case.
The same security update in March would have protected Windows Vista, Windows 7 and Windows 8.1 systems, as long as you had automatic updates turned on (which is the default).
Only older versions of Windows which are no longer supported were vulnerable, including Windows XP and Windows 8.
It’s worth noting, though, that in general home users should not be affected by this particular piece of ransomware. It mainly targeted computers running the business version of Windows, specifically those using the SMB network file system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can I protect my files from WannaCry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has issued a security patch for Windows XP and Windows 8 – a very unusual step for unsupported operating systems – which you can download from the links on Microsoft’s blog.
If you have Windows Update enabled on other versions then you will already be protected against WannaCry and any other attacks which use the same vulnerability.
If you’re not sure, then open the Control Panel (you’ll find a link in the Start menu) and search for Windows Update. Click through to Windows Update and you’ll be able to check if it’s enabled or not.
There should be a button ‘Check for updates’ which you can click to force Windows to search and install critical updates.
Back up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, as we always recommend, you should have at least one (if not two) copies of any files you can’t afford to lose. Photos, home videos, financial documents and other files that can’t be replaced should be backed up regularly.
Ransomware is often clever enough to scan your home network and infect other computers and even network storage drives (NAS drives) so it’s really important to make a backup on an external hard drive that you disconnect and keep safely somewhere.
You can find our pick of the best backup software here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t open attachments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, as the computer user, are often the weak link in the chain. Windows and antivirus software – see below – can help to protect you from ransomware attacks, but you can help yourself by being extremely cautious about which email attachments you open and which links you click.
Typically, emails from hackers won’t contain a personal message, or it will be so generic that you can’t be sure it’s really from the person in the ‘sender’ field.
In WannaCry’s case, at least some of the emails pretended to be an important email from a bank about a money transfer.
Either just delete the email, or call the sender and ask them if they sent the email and what is in the attachment, or on the other end of the link. Unless you are absolutely sure the attachment is safe, don’t click on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Won’t antivirus software protect me from WannaCry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most but not all antivirus software now contains ‘anti-ransomware’ that should help protect your PCs and laptops from WannaCry and other ransomware.
That’s why it’s important not to rely just on Windows’ own security but to add an extra layer of protection.
Check out our list of the best antivirus to make sure you’re running one of our recommended packages. Our favourite is BitDefender, but there are plenty of other great options to choose from too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My PC is infected with WannaCry. What should I do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, don’t pay the ransom. It only encourages the criminals – getting paid is their end game.
Some security experts predict there could be a free ‘fix’ to decrypt the files in a few days and remove the malware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund Transfer To Get Faster From July 10: 5 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fund-transfer-to-get-faster-from-july-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fund transfer via NEFT or National Electronic Funds Transfer is set to get faster from July 10. NEFT is an electronic fund transfer system that allows individuals to transfer funds between banks. This fund transfer system is maintained by the Reserve Bank of India. Introduction of additional 11 NEFT settlements from July 10 was announced by RBI on Monday. Fund transfer under NEFT is settled in batches which means settlement takes place with all transactions received till the particular cut-off time. On the other hand, settlement happens on a real-time basis in RTGS or Real-Time Gross Settlement Systems, which is also an fund transfer system maintained by the RBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are five things to know about the new NEFT rules that will come into effect from July 10:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the introduction of 11 additional NEFT settlements, the total number will increase to 23 at half hourly settlement batches during the day. Currently there are twelve settlements from 8 am to 7 pm at hourly intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall NEFT timings - between 8.00 am and 7.00 pm - will remain the same as earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s bank is unable to credit the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s account for any reason, the former will return the money to the remitting bank within two hours of completion of the batch in which the transaction was processed. Once the amount is received by the remitting bank, it is credited to the remitter&amp;rsquo;s account by the branch concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more number of settlement batches means that the fund transfer will happen at a quicker pace. This will improve the efficiency and add to customer convenience, the RBI said. However, the timings that the banks follow may vary depending on the customer timings of the bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NEFT charges are typically lower for internet banking as compared to carrying out the transaction through bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no minimum amount for funds remitted via NEFT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Department Launches Facility To Correct PAN, Aadhaar Card Errors</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-department-launches-facility-to-correct-pan-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website &amp;ndash; one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for data update request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 1.22 crore assessees already have Aadhaar-linked PAN but the number is abysmally low as there are over 25 crore PAN card holders in the country, while Aadhaar has been issued to 111 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per statistics with the tax department, only 6 crore people file income tax returns at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, through an amendment to the Finance Bill for 2017-18, had made Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns and provided for linking of PAN with Aadhaar to curb tax evasion through use of multiple PAN cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the income tax department launched a facility to enable a taxpayer to link his Aadhaar and PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It required a person to put in PAN and Aadhaar number along with his name as per the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After verification from the UIDAI, the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP will be sent to the mobile number registered with the UIDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the income tax department has now launched a facility to correct anomalies in PAN or Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want A New Jio SIM? Here&#39;s What You Pay To Get &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/want-a-new-jio-sim-heres-what-you-pay-to-get-dhan-dhana/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in getting a new Reliance Jio SIM and availing the &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer? Rs 408 is the minimum amount you need to spend. For Jio non-Prime and new users, the recharge amount is Rs 309 along with an additional Rs 99. Similarly, to get the Rs 509 plan, the amount needed will be Rs 608.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has extensively provided free data services with unlimited calls for several months and with the telecom operator starting paid services, one can expect the firm to provide the &amp;lsquo;most affordable&amp;rsquo; plans. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mukesh Ambani said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rs. 408 is the minimum amount needed to avail Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has provided free services with unlimited calls for last few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio has been in the controversy for stretching its free trial run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-dhan.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>बिजली बिल: आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plan-to-link-power-bill-to-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आधार को जरूरी सेवाओं के लिए अनिवार्य किए जाने का मामला अभी सुप्रीम कोर्ट में लंबित है। इस बीच बिजली बिल के भुगतान को भी आधार से जोड़ने की तैयारी शुरू कर दी गई है। केंद्र सरकार ने राज्यों से बिजली के बिलों का डिजिटल भुगतान आधार से जुड़े बैंक खातों के माध्यम से सुनिश्चित करने को कहा है। केंद्रीय ऊर्जा मंत्री पीयूष गोयल ने कहा है कि बिजली बिल को आधार से जोड़ना ग्राहकों के लिए फायदेमंद साबित होगा।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;राज्यों और केंद्र शासित प्रदेशों के ऊर्जा और खदान मंत्रियों की कॉन्फ्रेंस में गोयल ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;यह जरूरी नहीं है, लेकिन सभी के हित में है क्योंकि अगर आप बिल का भुगतान डिजिटल माध्यम से करेंगे तो आपके पास यह ठीक-ठीक सबूत होगा कि आपने बिल का भुगतान किया है। यह पहल जनता को मदद करेगी और इस संबंध में कोशिश की जानी चाहिए।&amp;rsquo; उन्होंने कहा कि इसका फैसला राज्यों को लेना है कि वे बिजली बिलों के भुगतान की प्रणाली को आधार से जुड़े खातों से जोड़ें या नहीं, लेकिन निश्चित तौर पर यह कहा जा सकता है कि यह ग्राहकों के हित में है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बता दें कि सरकार ने हाल में आयकर रिटर्न फाइल करने के लिए आधार को जरूरी कर दिया है। सुप्रीम कोर्ट में भी सरकार ने अपनी तरफ से साफ किया है कि पैन नंबर के जरिए होने वाले फ्रॉड को रोकने के लिए आधार को अनिवार्य किया जाना जरूरी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;गोयल ने यह भी कहा कि सरकार राज्यों को बिजली आवंटन के मसौदे को फिर तैयार कर रही है। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम फॉर्म्युले पर काम कर रहे हैं। हम इस बात पर फिर से विचार कर रहे हैं कि हम इसे (पावर आवंटन पॉलिसी) किस तरह मजबूत बना सकते हैं। फिलहाल गाडगिल फॉर्म्युले पर बिजली का बंटवारा होता है। इसके तहत राज्यों के प्लान के लिए केंद्रीय मदद के लिए नियम और शर्तों को तय किया जाता है। उनका यह भी कहना था कि ज्यादा से ज्यादा बिजली उन को दी जाएगी, जो न्यूक्लियर प्लांट्स स्थापित करने को बढ़ावा देंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिजली के कमर्शल नुकसान में गिरावट और कॉस्ट की बेहतर कवरेज से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन कंपनियों में मामूली बेहतरी से राज्यों की पावर डिस्ट्रिब्यूशन कंपनियों के ऑपरेशनल परफॉर्मेंस में सुधार हुआ है। पावर फाइनेंस कॉर्पोरेशन (PFC) की एक रिपोर्ट में यह बात कही गई है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Banks Accounts To Be Blocked: 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fatca-compliance-banks-accounts-to-be-blocked-10-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts that were opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 and are not in compliance with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions will be blocked. The Income Tax Department had set a deadline of April 30 for FATCA compliance for these accounts. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT had earlier said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Account holders are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) In a statement last month, the government had said that financial institutions are advised that all efforts should be made by the financial institutions to obtain the self-certification. The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016 extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Imposes Fee On Cheque Payments For Credit Card Dues. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-imposes-fee-on-cheque-payments-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card is levying a charge on payments made by cheques. This came into effect from April 1, according to SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s website. The card company said payments made below Rs 2,000 through cheques will attract a fee of Rs 100. &amp;ldquo;A fee of Rs.100 will be charged for payments made by cheque for an amount less than or equal to Rs.2000 w.e.f. 1st April &amp;lsquo;17. No additional fee will be charged for cheque payments greater than Rs. 2000,&amp;rdquo; SBI Card said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen that the majority of payments (over 90 per cent) are made through non-cheque modes. We have observed a trend of payment related disputes arising in small cheque payments, causing inconvenience to customers as well. We offer several seamless digital modes of payment which we are seeking to encourage, in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s focus towards digital payments and this step will facilitate the same,&amp;rdquo; said SBI Card CEO Vijay Jasuja.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, payments made through SBI cheques will not incur the extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move is largely seen disincentivizing cheque payments, where the card company incurs additional processing cost. It is also likely to provide a boost to digital payments. SBI, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, entered credit card business in 1998 by roping GE Capital India, the consumer finance arm of US-based GE Capital. SBI Card&amp;rsquo;s latest offering &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; is targeted at all State Bank of India customers, including Jan Dhan account holders throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has introduced the &amp;lsquo;Unnati&amp;rsquo; card in an effort to bring new users into the fold of cashless transactions. The card is issued to persons with a balance of Rs 25,000 in their SBI accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No such charge on cheque payments will be levied on holders of SBI Card Unnati which is targeted at first time credit card users and aimed at inclusion of people into the organised financial stream,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jasuja added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 5G on Trial Samsung Network </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arqiva-and-samsung-to-trial-5g-network-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arqiva-and-samsung-to-trial-5g-network-in-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung has already undertaken some early tests of the technology on its campus in South Korea, and mobile operators and vendors have announced 5G trials in countries ranging from the United States to Japan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communications group Arqiva and Samsung Electronics will trial Britain&amp;rsquo;s first 5G network in London this year, the companies said, with the capability of delivering ultra-fast broadband to mobile devices and potentially autonomous vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advent of the fifth generation of mobile telecoms is viewed as essential to expected growth in demand for ever-higher speeds, capacity and reliability, with global operators such as Vodafone, Telefonica and Verizon working with network equipment makers to develop the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arqiva, which provides TV broadcast and mobile infrastructure, said the fixed wireless access network would operate in its own 28GHz band spectrum using Samsung&amp;rsquo;s 5G base stations and equipment installed in premises in central London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Over time, smarter network infrastructure and an enhanced ability to support exponential scale for connectivity will open the doors to further applications across a variety of markets such as IoT (Internet of Things), industrial applications and the full promise of autonomous vehicles,&amp;rdquo; Arqiva Chief Executive Simon Beresford-Wylie said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung has already undertaken some early tests of the technology on its campus in South Korea, and mobile operators and vendors have announced 5G trials in countries ranging from the United States to Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arqiva, which counts the Canada Pension Plan Investment Board and Macquarie as investors, is considering a stock market listing and is seeking new investors, sources said this month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>