<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/latest-technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Summer Surprise Packs Offer Up To 100 GB Of 4G Data</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-summer-surprise-packs-offer-up-to-100-gb-of-4g-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-summer-surprise-packs-offer-up-to-100-gb-of-4g-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime prepaid customers opting for Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 999 recharge pack will get 100GB of free data for 90 days under the Summer Surprise offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio has announced a &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer under which it is offering 100 GB of data as complimentary benefit under select recharge packs. Jio also extended its enrolment for paid Prime scheme by 15 days. &amp;ldquo;Jio Prime offers many attractive benefits - the absolute best data tariffs in the industry, free voice calling, access to all Jio apps, and many more periodic surprises going forward. Jio prime members will always get the very best of what Jio has to offer,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani said in a letter to Jio members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Summer Surprise scheme, Jio prepaid customers subscribing to Prime are being offered complimentary benefits under various recharge packs. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime members making their first paid recharge of Rs 303 plan (or any higher value plan) till April 15, 2017 will get three months of services on a complimentary basis. The paid tariff plan will be applied only in July, after the expiry of the complimentary offer. (Also read: Summer Surprise offer features, extra benefits)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime prepaid customers opting for Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 999 recharge pack will get 100GB of free data for 90 days under the Summer Surprise offer. After July, under the Rs 999 pack, Prime members will 60 GB of data for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, on recharges of Rs 1,999 (125 GB of data with validity of 90 days), Rs. 4,999 (350GB-180 days) and Rs. 9,999 (750GB-360 days), Prime plan members will get 100 GB data for 90 days, according to Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of recharge packs which offer 100GB of free high-speed data under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Summer Surprise offer:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-100gb-90-days_650x400_41491373824.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New ITR Form Filers: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-itr-form-1-sahaj-to-benefit-2-crore-filers-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-itr-form-1-sahaj-to-benefit-2-crore-filers-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sahaj makes quoting of the 12-digit Aadhaar number mandatory along with Permanent Account Number (PAN).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax return filing season has started. The Income Tax Department has launched e-filing facility for the assessment year 2017-18. In this regard, the tax department has also launched a simplified one-page ITR-1 form called Sahaj. This ITR Form-1 (Sahaj) can be filed by an individual having income up to Rs 50 lakh and who is receiving income from salary, one house property or other income (interest etc). The Income Tax Return Form-1 or Sahaj will replace the earlier seven-page form, making it much easier for filing returns for most taxpayers. The simplified ITR will &amp;ldquo;reduce the compliance burden to a significant extent on the individual tax payer&amp;rdquo;, the Income Tax Department said. Simultaneously, the number of ITR Forms has been reduced from the existing nine to seven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not much tinkering has been done with the contents of existing form and some redundant columns have been done away with which will simplify the filing to some extent for a vast majority of people. However, mandatory quoting of Aadhaar may cause some hardship as there will be a sudden rush for such people to apply for Aadhaar who don&amp;rsquo;t have one yet,&amp;rdquo; said Sandeep Sehgal, director-tax and regulatory at Ashok Maheshwary &amp;amp; Associates LLP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 key highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Sahaj makes quoting of the 12-digit Aadhaar number mandatory along with Permanent Account Number (PAN). While the earlier ITR form too had a column to quote Aadhaar, the government has through an amendment to the Income Tax Act made quoting it mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Cash deposited in excess of Rs 2 lakh during the November 9-December 30 period last year, if any, has to be mentioned in Sahaj.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) In the new form, the parts relating to tax computation and deductions have been rationalised and simplified for easy compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Besides personal details, an income tax filer needs to disclose only his or her income from salary or pension, one house property and other sources like interest. Thereafter, deduction claims are to be stated, followed by computation of taxable income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Instead of 20 columns of deductions in the old form, only five columns need to be filled - four columns specifically for claims in respect of Sections 80C, 80D, 80G and 80TTA, and one for other deductions to be specified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Section 80C is one of the most popular avenues for claiming income tax deductions. Under this section, a deduction of up to Rs 1.5 lakh is allowed. PPF, EPF, life insurance premium etc. qualify for deductions under this section. Section 80D refers to deduction for premium paid for medical insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Section 80G pertains to contributions made to certain relief funds and charitable institutions while 80TTA provides a deduction of Rs 10,000 on interest income from savings account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Bank details are to be filled in the next column. Details of advance tax, self-assessment tax payments and tax deducted at source (TDS) come next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The simplified tax form will benefit more than two crore taxpayers who will be eligible to file their returns through this simplified form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) The existing income tax return forms ITR-2, ITR-2A and ITR-3 have been rationalised and a single ITR-2 form has been notified in place of these three forms. Taxpayers having more than one house will have to file the ITR-2 form. Details of exempt income (income not to be included in total income) like long-term capital gains from transactions on which securities transaction tax is paid has been made mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>