<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Technology on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/latest-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latest Technology on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/latest-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Summer Surprise Packs Offer Up To 100 GB Of 4G Data</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-summer-surprise-packs-offer-up-to-100-gb-of-4g-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-summer-surprise-packs-offer-up-to-100-gb-of-4g-data/</guid>
      <description>Prime prepaid customers opting for Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 999 recharge pack will get 100GB of free data for 90 days under the Summer Surprise offer.
Reliance Jio has announced a &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer under which it is offering 100 GB of data as complimentary benefit under select recharge packs. Jio also extended its enrolment for paid Prime scheme by 15 days. &amp;ldquo;Jio Prime offers many attractive benefits - the absolute best data tariffs in the industry, free voice calling, access to all Jio apps, and many more periodic surprises going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New ITR Form Filers: 10 Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-itr-form-1-sahaj-to-benefit-2-crore-filers-10-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-itr-form-1-sahaj-to-benefit-2-crore-filers-10-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Sahaj makes quoting of the 12-digit Aadhaar number mandatory along with Permanent Account Number (PAN).
The income tax return filing season has started. The Income Tax Department has launched e-filing facility for the assessment year 2017-18. In this regard, the tax department has also launched a simplified one-page ITR-1 form called Sahaj. This ITR Form-1 (Sahaj) can be filed by an individual having income up to Rs 50 lakh and who is receiving income from salary, one house property or other income (interest etc).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>