<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>84 GB For 84 Days: New Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan Offer Out Now</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-84-gb-for-84-days-new-jio-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer-out-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-84-gb-for-84-days-new-jio-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer-out-now/</guid>
      <description>As Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Summer Surprise offer comes to an end, the disruptive telecom firm has come out with a new offer which extends the benefits of its blockbuster &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan Offer.&amp;rdquo; The plan which costs Rs. 399 promises unlimited local and STD calls to any network, free roaming and 20 per cent more data than the competition, according to reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s website. The network also added new recharge plans like a Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Mistakes While Filing ITR (Income Tax Return) And How to Avoid Them</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/common-mistakes-while-filing-itr-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/common-mistakes-while-filing-itr-and-how-to-avoid-them/</guid>
      <description>Are you always worried about filing your income tax return (ITR) the wrong way? Here are some of the most common mistakes that people make while filing ITR. By avoiding them, you will be able to file your taxes in a hassle-free manner:
 Filing the wrong ITR form  Using the wrong type of ITR is one of the most common mistakes. If you earn income from salary only, you should file your return in Form ITR 1 (Sahaj).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.
SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.
Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.
HIGHLIGHTS  Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1 The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent  The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.
HIGHLIGHTS  Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%  The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4GB Data Per Day For Rs 444</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</guid>
      <description>State-run telecom firm BSNL today increased per day data offering to 4GB at 3G speeds under a new prepaid mobile scheme priced at Rs 444 with 90 days validity.
&amp;ldquo;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) has introduced &amp;lsquo;BSNL Chaukka - 444&amp;rsquo;, a new STV, for truly unlimited data for 90 days as special promotional offer under prepaid mobile services,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.
This is the highest per day data limit being offered by any telecom operator in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM
Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio’s new plans offer 100% cashback on JioFi on exchange of old dongle, datacard, routers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio has launched a 100% cashback offer with JioFi 4G router, as the Mukesh Ambani-owned tries to attract users of dongles, datacard and wifi routers offered by rival telcos.
The company has come up with two plans where as part of the first plan, users will get a 100% exchange offer where they’ll be required to exchange their existing datacard, dongle or hotspot router at any Jio Digital store or Jio Care store and will get 4G data worth Rs 2010 against the device exchanged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation To Launch RuPay Credit Card Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India has forayed in to the credit card business and would make the commercial launch of its RuPay credit card &amp;ldquo;in a month&amp;rsquo;s time,&amp;rdquo; a top official said today.
&amp;ldquo;Maybe in a month&amp;rsquo;s time we will be able to make the commercial launch (of RuPay credit card),&amp;rdquo; NPCI Chairman M Balachandran told reporters here.
NPCI, which currently offers RuPay debit cards, has partnered with 10 banks including public sector and cooperative banks, to make the pilot launch of the &amp;ldquo;RuPay Credit Card&amp;rdquo;, Balachandran said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.
Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ATMs Are Going Dry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/atms-going-dry-ambedkar-replacing-gandhi-new-face-money/</guid>
      <description>1: The ATM expansion era is over. ATM extensions will no longer be part of future banking growth, and future ATMs may well be of the mobile kind focused only on rural cash deliveries. But even here, the growth will be limited. Standalone ATM companies may have a future, but only because banks may choose to outsource all their existing networks to them so that they can focus on growing the digital business themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.
Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI Launches Three New Mobile Apps For Voice, Data Quality Tracking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</guid>
      <description>TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring.
Aiming to protect consumer interests, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Monday launched three new mobile applications and a web portal.
TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring. The app will help mobile phone users rate their experience about voice call quality in real time and help TRAI gather customer experience data along with network data, an official TRAI statement said here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-Aadhaar as ID proof in Railways</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</guid>
      <description>After receiving several requests from passengers, Railway has agreed to accept e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class. Earlier only printed version was considered as a valid ID.
According to railway ministry, the issue regarding acceptance of e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class was being raised at various foras.
Accordingly, the matter was examined in consultation with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>