<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1,000 bank branches open Aadhaar updation centres on premises</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-branches-open-aadhaar-updation-centres-on-premises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-branches-open-aadhaar-updation-centres-on-premises/</guid>
      <description>The UIDAI today said over 1,000 bank branches of 42 private and public sector banks have opened Aadhaar enrolment and updation centres within their premises.
The Aadhaar issuing body further said it has received commitments for opening of such centres in 15,000 bank branches &amp;ldquo;at the earliest&amp;rdquo;.
&amp;ldquo;Bank Aadhaar Kendras are being established with a view to make the Aadhaar verification process of bank accounts convenient for the people as it has become mandatory under amended Prevention of Money Laundering Rules to verify bank accounts with Aadhaar by December 31, 2017,&amp;rdquo; Ajay Bhushan Pandey, CEO of UIDAI said in a statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airtel Vs Jio: Latest Recharge Offers Compared</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-vs-jio-latest-recharge-offers-compared/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-vs-jio-latest-recharge-offers-compared/</guid>
      <description>To counter a slew of data and unlimited calling offers by Reliance Jio, Bharti Airtel, India’s largest telecom operator has updated its prepaid recharges to keep customers from switching to Jio. The entry of jio last year has brought a pricing revolution in the telecom industry through its ultra-low cost data and free voice call offerings, some analysts say. However, consumers have become the ultimate beneficiary of this pricing war in the telecom industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airtel&#39;s 30 GB Bonus Data Offer: How To Avail It</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-counters-jio-with-30-gb-bonus-data-offer-how-to-avail-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-counters-jio-with-30-gb-bonus-data-offer-how-to-avail-it/</guid>
      <description>As the latest entrant in India’s telecom sector, Reliance Jio aggressively grabs market share, Bharti Airtel has fought back with attractive offers of its own. Airtel is now tempting potential postpaid customers with a new offer that gives 30 GB of free data to new postpaid customers over three months, which amounts to 10 GB of free data every month. The offer is valid on all Airtel postpaid plans apart from the Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FD Interest Rate: A Comparison Between SBI, HDFC Bank And ICICI Bank Rates</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fd-interest-rate-a-comparison-between-sbi-hdfc-bank-and-icici-bank-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fd-interest-rate-a-comparison-between-sbi-hdfc-bank-and-icici-bank-rates/</guid>
      <description>Bank fixed deposits (FDs) are one of the most popular instruments used to save money for the future. Despite falling interest rates, many people prefer FDs over other savings/investment products as they offers a secured return and easy access to liquidity in case of an emergency. Depending on the investment horizon, fixed deposits offer a wide range of choices ranging from seven days to 10 years. However, to get the best return out of your fixed deposits, you need to know the various rates offered by top lenders in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Booster Packs: Get Additional 10 GB Data After Daily Limit</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-booster-packs-get-additional-10-gb-data-after-daily-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-booster-packs-get-additional-10-gb-data-after-daily-limit/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio, the new comer in to the Indian telecom industry, offers special recharge packs, known as booster packs, which allows subscribers to get addition data at 4G speed once he/she exhausts daily limit. Some of Jio&amp;rsquo;s recharge packs come with daily usage limit or FUP limit. The most popular recharge packs of Jio - Rs 309, Rs 399 - have daily usage limit of 1 GB post which speed comes down to 128kbps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: BSNL Offers Free Calls, 28 GB Data At Rs 249, 90 GB At Rs 429</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-free-on-net-calls-28-gb-data-at-rs-249-90-gb-at-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-bsnl-offers-free-on-net-calls-28-gb-data-at-rs-249-90-gb-at-rs/</guid>
      <description>Amid intense competition among telecom companies led by Reliance Jio, BSNL (Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited) has announced a promotional special tariff voucher (STV) or recharge coupon at Rs 249 which includes voice and data benefits. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 249 recharge pack comes with a validity of 28 days, according to its website - bsnl.co.in. Under a limited-period scheme, BSNL prepaid customers recharging their mobile connection with the Rs 249 pack will get 10 GB of data per day, among other benefits, according to the BSNL website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Less On Petrol, Diesel While Paying Via BHIM, Cards</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-up-to-rs-0-49-litre-less-on-petrol-diesel-while-paying-via-bhim-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-up-to-rs-0-49-litre-less-on-petrol-diesel-while-paying-via-bhim-cards/</guid>
      <description>Fuel prices are sky-rocketing due to changes in global crude prices resulting in consumers to feel the pinch as the value of domestic fuel prices is determined by it. A daily revision in petrol and diesel rates by oil marketing companies has made the consumers feel the heat more. However, if you pay for fuel using the government&amp;rsquo;s BHIM or Bharat Interface for Money app, you can get 49 paise per litre off on petrol and 41 paise per litre discount on diesel, stated a tweet from Digital India&amp;rsquo;s official account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Account Has No Minimum Balance Charges But Offers Same Interest Rate</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance-charges-but-offers-same-interest-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance-charges-but-offers-same-interest-rate/</guid>
      <description>SBI in a Twitter post said that its Basic Savings Bank Deposit accounts offer same interest rates as its other savings bank accounts but do not charge any penalty for not maintaining monthly average balance. The Basic Savings Bank Deposit account of SBI has no monthly average balance requirement, SBI said. The state-owned lender also said that those who want to avoid paying monthly average balance non-maintenance charges, can convert their regular savings account to basic savings bank deposit account without any cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You could soon need Aadhaar for driving licence, registration of new vehicles</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-need-aadhaar-for-driving-licence-registration-of-new-vehicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-need-aadhaar-for-driving-licence-registration-of-new-vehicles/</guid>
      <description>The government is planning to link driving license with the unique identity number Aadhaar in order to curb issue of duplicate and fake licenses, union minister for electronics and IT, Ravi Shankar Prasad said on Friday. Prasad who was speaking at the Digital Haryana Summit 2017 added that he has already had a word Nitin Gadkari, minister for road transport &amp;amp; highways regarding the linkage.
&amp;ldquo;We are planning to link driving licence to Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things that are banned for you, from opening a bank account to processing of I-T returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</guid>
      <description>If you thought that filing an income tax return or opening a bank account are the only few things which require Aadhaar cards now, then think again. The fact is Aadhaar has now been made mandatory for so many things, including availing the benefits of various social and government schemes. While for some schemes it has already been made compulsory, for some others it will be made mandatory soon.
Here we are taking a look at 10 such things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Notes Ban, 18 Lakh Cases Of Income, Bank Account Mismatches Detected: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</guid>
      <description>Government authorities have detected 18 lakh cases after demonetisation where the income profiles of people do not match their account profile, the Lok Sabha was informed today. Preliminary information has been sought from such people and many have responded. Those who have not given details would be issued with notices as per procedure, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said during Question Hour.
Responding to supplementaries, he said there was an extended footprint of digitisation in the banking sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All You Need To Know About New Rs 100 Coins That Are Coming Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-100-coins-to-be-issued-to-mark-mg-ramachandrans-birth-centenary-1749334/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-100-coins-to-be-issued-to-mark-mg-ramachandrans-birth-centenary-1749334/</guid>
      <description>The Rs 100 coins will be introduced to commemorate the occasion of Dr MG Ramachandran birth centenary. This was stated in a notification, dated September 11, from the Ministry of Finance. New Rs 5 coins will also be issued to mark the birth centenary of the late AIADMK founder, the notification added. The Rs 100 coin will be 44 millimeter in diameter with a metal composition of silver (50 per cent), copper (40 per cent), nickel (5 per cent) and zinc (5 per cent).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Aadhaar linking deadlines you should not miss</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/four-aadhaar-linking-deadlines-not-miss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/four-aadhaar-linking-deadlines-not-miss/</guid>
      <description>There are certain deadlines that you need to meet related to your Aadhaar in order to avoid pain in the coming year, 2018.
Here’s the list of various deadlines set by the government regarding Aadhaar.
 Aadhaar and PAN linking deadline is now December 31, 2017 The government had earlier notified that income tax returns (ITR) filed after July 1, 2017 would be accepted only after a tax assessee linked his/her PAN with Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to link Aadhaar Card with SIM card: What you need to do in this critical task; step by step guide</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-card-sim-card-need-critical-task-step-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-card-sim-card-need-critical-task-step-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>#How to link Aadhaar Card with SIM card?
Aadhaar card is now a crucial thing to have in India, especially with the way the government has made it mandatory in several sectors and even services. Having an Aadhaar number is not only necessary for establishing your identity to avail schemes but also in financial matters like bank accounts and filing taxes. Even mobile phone service users will now have to verify using Aadhaar numbers, as the telcos, in March, had been instructed to start the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Numbers Not Linked To Aadhaar To Be Deactivated After February: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sim-cards-not-linked-to-aadhaar-to-be-deactivated-after-february-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sim-cards-not-linked-to-aadhaar-to-be-deactivated-after-february-report/</guid>
      <description>The government is moving ahead with linking Aadhaar with mobile SIM cards and all unlinked phones will be deactivated after February 2018, said informed sources. Sources told news agency IANS that linking of Aadhaar with mobile is being done as per the orders of Supreme Court passed in February this year in Lokniti foundation case and all SIM cards have to be verified with Aadhaar within a year from the date of judgement, with all unlinked phones to be deactivated after February next year, so criminals, fraudsters and terrorists cannot use the issued SIMs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>