<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7 smart tips which can help you save more &amp; become rich</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t want to become rich? However, getting wealthy isn’t that easy. It begins with determined consciousness to get wealthy. We all know that to become rich you need to spend less than what you earn. That is because the less you spend, the more you will be able to save. You should save and invest what you have into investments (assets) that appreciate over time. Apart from these, here we are taking a look at a few really easy and ‘anyone can do it’ strategies or DIY tips that can make you a crorepati:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Not Mandatory For Insurance, Says IRDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-for-insurance-says-irdai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-for-insurance-says-irdai/</guid>
      <description>Aadhar is not mandatory for the (insurance) sector but is the most simple one, IRDAI, the insurance sector regulator said.
Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (IRDAI) today said though Aadhar is not a mandatory requirement for Know Your Customer (KYC) in the insurance sector, it is the most simple form of KYC document.
&amp;ldquo;Aadhar is not mandatory for the (insurance) sector but is the most simple one. On the government level they are creating a platform for all the KYC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data hack: IIT Kharagpur graduate arrested, earns Rs 40 lakh a year at Ola</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</guid>
      <description>An IIT Kharagpur graduate, Abhinav Srivastava, who allegedly hacked Aadhaar data has been arrested by Bengaluru Police. According to investigation, Srivastava had gained access to the repository of the Unique Identification Development Authority of India’s (UIDAI) Aadhaar project through the Digital India e-hospital portal. The 31-year-old hails from Uttar Pradesh and was arrested in connection with a complaint filed by the UIDAI on July 26, according to Indian Express.
Police said the complaint against Srivastava stated that he accessed UIDAI data without authorisation between January 1 and July 26 for an app called ‘eKYC Verification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank of Baroda Follows SBI, Cuts Interest On Savings Accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-of-baroda-follows-sbi-cuts-interest-on-savings-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-of-baroda-follows-sbi-cuts-interest-on-savings-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Within days of SBI slashing interest rate on savings bank account, another PSU bank &amp;ndash; Bank of Baroda &amp;ndash; has followed suit, cutting it to 3.5 per cent on deposits of up to Rs 50 lakh.
&amp;ldquo;We wish to inform you that it has been decided to introduce a 2-tier savings bank interest rate (from) August 5&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; the bank said in a regulatory filing. Effective tomorrow, the interest rate on savings bank balance of up to Rs 50 lakh has been reduced to 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you have two PAN cards? Here&#39;s a solution</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/do-you-have-multiple-pan-cards-heres-how-to-surrender-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/do-you-have-multiple-pan-cards-heres-how-to-surrender-one/</guid>
      <description>If you have more than one PAN, whether acquired intentionally or inadvertently, you run the risk of being penalised. Following government&amp;rsquo;s mandate to link PAN with Aadhaar, and Aadhaar with bank accounts, detecting multiple PANs could become easier for the Income Tax Department once the data is collated.
As per Section 139A of Income Tax Act, 1961 a person can hold only one PAN. This section deals with the eligibility to apply for PAN, when an individual is supposed to quote it and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Extends Deadline To Get Aadhaar For Free LPG</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-extends-deadline-to-get-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-extends-deadline-to-get-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The government has extended till September-end the time by which poor women wishing to avail of free cooking gas (LPG) connections must apply for the unique 12-digit biometric identification number Aadhaar.
The government had in March this year mandated that anyone not having Aadhaar but desirous of availing free LPG connection under the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana must apply for it by May 31.
The Ministry of Petroleum and Natural Gas yesterday issued a gazettee notification extending that deadline to September 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Hike In BHIM Incentives</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-augments-hike-bhim-incentives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-augments-hike-bhim-incentives/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) and banks have requested the Finance Ministry to augment the referral bonus on transactions app Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) as it has been unsuccessful to draw users. The government is taking into consideration the request and may declare modified incentives soon.
Any user who refers BHIM app to another individual receives Rs 10 as an incentive and the user who commences utilizing the app receives Rs 25 as starting cash back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt:Aadhaar Not Mandatory For Booking Rail Tickets</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-for-booking-rail-tickets-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-for-booking-rail-tickets-government/</guid>
      <description>The Aadhaar number is not mandatory for booking rail tickets, the Centre told the Rajya Sabha today.
In a written reply in the Upper House of Parliament, Union Minister of State for Railways Rajen Gohain said as of now, his ministry had no plans to make the 12-digit unique identification number compulsory for booking rail tickets.
&amp;ldquo;At present, there is no proposal to make the Aadhaar number compulsory for booking tickets for rail journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Recruitment: Latest Jobs For Freshers To MBAs</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-recruitment-latest-jobs-for-freshers-to-mbas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-recruitment-latest-jobs-for-freshers-to-mbas/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio is recruiting more than 1,900 executives for its sales and distribution team. Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries, said on its website - jio.com - that the positions &amp;ldquo;will be responsible for sales research and planning, demand creation, sales costing and budgeting, establishing sales territories, and co-ordination of sales&amp;rdquo;. Jio is apparently looking to strengthen its team to support its expansion plans, some analysts say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.
HIGHLIGHTS  Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1 The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent  The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Balance Account </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-mahindra-bank-launches-debit-card-offer-for-zero-balance-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-mahindra-bank-launches-debit-card-offer-for-zero-balance-account/</guid>
      <description>Private sector Kotak Mahindra Bank today said it will offer debit card at a special price of Rs 99 for the first year for customers who will open account under its zero balance account scheme till September 15.
The usual annual fee for debit card procured by 811 account holders (zero balance) is Rs 299.
The name 811, inspired by November 8, 2016, decision of demonetisation, allows customers to open a zero balance account using the bank&amp;rsquo;s mobile application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4GB Data Per Day For Rs 444</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</guid>
      <description>State-run telecom firm BSNL today increased per day data offering to 4GB at 3G speeds under a new prepaid mobile scheme priced at Rs 444 with 90 days validity.
&amp;ldquo;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) has introduced &amp;lsquo;BSNL Chaukka - 444&amp;rsquo;, a new STV, for truly unlimited data for 90 days as special promotional offer under prepaid mobile services,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.
This is the highest per day data limit being offered by any telecom operator in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM
Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio’s new plans offer 100% cashback on JioFi on exchange of old dongle, datacard, routers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio has launched a 100% cashback offer with JioFi 4G router, as the Mukesh Ambani-owned tries to attract users of dongles, datacard and wifi routers offered by rival telcos.
The company has come up with two plans where as part of the first plan, users will get a 100% exchange offer where they’ll be required to exchange their existing datacard, dongle or hotspot router at any Jio Digital store or Jio Care store and will get 4G data worth Rs 2010 against the device exchanged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation To Launch RuPay Credit Card Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India has forayed in to the credit card business and would make the commercial launch of its RuPay credit card &amp;ldquo;in a month&amp;rsquo;s time,&amp;rdquo; a top official said today.
&amp;ldquo;Maybe in a month&amp;rsquo;s time we will be able to make the commercial launch (of RuPay credit card),&amp;rdquo; NPCI Chairman M Balachandran told reporters here.
NPCI, which currently offers RuPay debit cards, has partnered with 10 banks including public sector and cooperative banks, to make the pilot launch of the &amp;ldquo;RuPay Credit Card&amp;rdquo;, Balachandran said.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>