<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Tickets Delivered To Home, Cash On Delivery</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-get-train-tickets-delivered-to-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-get-train-tickets-delivered-to-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IRCTC has now introduced pay-on-delivery as one of the payment options for its customers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has offered delivery of rail tickets allowing passengers to make payment through any payment mode, including cash. Broad-basing the customer service, the Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation has now introduced pay-on-delivery service allowing passengers to book train tickets online and pay at the time of delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC through its website and mobile app has now introduced pay-on-delivery as one of the payment options for its customers, said a senior IRCTC official. Delivering tickets at the consumer&amp;rsquo;s doorstep by offering the pay-on-delivery (PoD) option will facilitate those consumers who book through travel agents to move to online medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also encourage people who book at railway reservation counters to move to online medium as there is a cost and effort to reach the reservation counters. The customer will have to do a one-time registration for availing PoD as a payment option. He or she will have to tender either Aadhaar or Pan card to avail this payment option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PoD charges shall be Rs. 90 plus sales tax for transactions up to Rs. 5,000 and Rs. 120 plus tax for transactions over Rs. 5,000. In case of refusal or cancellation before delivery, the customer will be liable to pay the cancellation and delivery charges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches. From the fifth transaction onwards, the customers will have to pay a minimum of Rs 150 per transaction (plus taxes and cess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Earlier, HDFC Bank savings account customers were offered five free transactions and the sixth transaction was charged at Rs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) HDFC Bank after December 30, 2016 reintroduced charges on cash transactions at branches after the deadline to deposit old currency notes ended. The charges were waived off after the government had announced a ban on high value currency notes on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) According to the revised norms which came into effect from March 1, from non-home branch, HDFC Bank customers can deposit/withdraw up to Rs 25,000 per day without any charge but any deposit/withdrawal from non-home branch above Rs 25,000 will attract charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess), whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) At the home branch of HDFC Bank, if the cumulative cash transactions (deposit/withdrawal) exceed Rs 2 lakh, a transaction charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess) whichever is higher will be levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For example, if a customer withdraws Rs 2 lakh from an account in four transactions and goes for another fifth transaction of Rs 50,000 from the home branch, then the customer will have to pay a charge of Rs 250. Thus, the charges apply only on the fifth transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) However, the charges for withdrawing money from automatic teller machines (ATMs) remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For senior citizens and minor accounts, the limit of Rs 25,000 per day will be applicable but the accounts will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) India&amp;rsquo;s biggest private sector bank ICICI Bank had reintroduced the cash transaction charges at bank branches from January 1, 2017. There will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while thereafter Rs 5 per Rs 1,000 would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150. The third party limit is Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Meanwhile, news agency Press Trust of India reported that another private sector lender Axis Bank has also started charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Loan Or Credit Card Loan: Which One To Go For?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a phone call and money gets credited to your account within 2-3 days. Yes, it is this simple today to get credit card loans. Though credit card loans are easier to get, they come at a higher cost than personal loans from banks. So you need to know clearly when to take a credit card loan or a personal loan. Even if the credit card company charges you the same rate of interest as that of personal loan, the cost for servicing credit card loan is higher. Along with processing fees and pre-closure charges, credit card companies also charge service tax on the interest you pay on your loan every month, which is 15 per cent currently (service tax@14%+ Swach Bharat Cess@ 0.5%+ Krishi Klyan Cess @ 0 .5%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you take a personal loan of Rs 1 lakh from a bank at 14 per cent interest for 24 months, then your first month instalment will be Rs 4,802, in which interest component will be Rs 1,166.66 and principal repayment will be Rs 3635.33. If you take the same loan on your credit card at the same interest rate, in the first month you have to pay Rs 4,976.99 which is Rs 175 more than what you pay on a bank loan. This is because of the service tax of Rs 175 on interest of Rs 1,166.66. This service tax is also applicable when you convert your purchases on credit card to equated monthly instalment (EMI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are some instances, where credit card loans are preferred over bank personal loans. If the amount you are opting for is less (less than Rs 50,000) and the tenure you want is less than 1 year, then credit card loans become more useful (even with higher cost) because banks generally do not offer personal loans below Rs 50,000 and for less than one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit cards even offer loans even for six months and for small amounts as low as Rs 10,000. If your requirement for funds is for a short term and you think you can repay it faster, then it is worth going for a credit card loan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banking on Aadhaar without bank accounts via IndiaPost payments bank can be a real game-changer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banking-aadhaar-without-bank-accounts-via-indiapost-payments-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banking-aadhaar-without-bank-accounts-via-indiapost-payments-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar-based transactions by people even without a bank account through the IndiaPost payments bank’s Aadhaar-pay model could be the real game-changer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears extremely attractive in the context of the government’s drive to promote digital transactions in a big way that Aadhaar numbers of the people—the total number has touched 112 crore already—will be good enough to pay or receive money, even without a bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what IndiaPost payments bank is striving to establish as its basic model once it starts operations in the next few months. According to its CEO A P Singh this can change the face of financial transaction in the country, especially in the rural areas where post offices can play a big role in promoting financial inclusion and handling direct benefit transfers (DBT), which is still around Rs 50,000 crore in a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way it will work is, take for example MGNREGA payment to a worker is sent to the nearest post office mentioning his/her Aadhaar number. The worker will go to the post office, complete the Aadhaar authentication process, and just take out that money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be various options with him apart from just taking cash—he/she can open an account with the IndiaPost payments bank immediately as the e-KYC process is complete with Aadhaar authentication, or just take a pre-paid card which can be used in any ATM to withdraw cash or make payments anywhere just as a debit card does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switch to normal transaction between two persons, and the same thing can be replicated through mobile wallets without bringing in any bank account. Going ahead, India Post is planning to equip the postman with biometric authentication and payment machines to remove the hassle of even going to the post offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the extensive reach of India Post throughout the country, something that has been a major bottleneck for the banks in handling transactions in rural areas and also DBT, Aadhaar-post combine can prove to be a big driver here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That India Post is targeting about 650 districts in the country in the initial stages itself with the help of those having feature phones and even those who have not, through its network, indicates that the door-to-door banking model may soon become a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, for this model to succeed, the mobile and broadband connectivity in the rural areas will also have to improve besides Aadhaar seeding, which to a certain extent is happening at a better pace now than what it was in the UPA years, even after the launch of DBT on January 1, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only about 35% people in India are having internet facility, and out of the 65,475 gram panchayats with access to the optic fibre laid under the BharatNet project, according to a report in The Indian express, less than 25% have active internet. So, even though the government, as announced in the Budget, achieves the target of taking broadband connectivity to 1.5 lakh panchayats by the end of 2017-18—it will be of help if there is a working internet available in these panchayats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Price Wars: Airtel, Vodafone, Idea Offers To Rival Jio&#39;s Dhan Dhana Dhan Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-price-wars-airtel-vodafone-idea-offers-to-rival-jios-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-price-wars-airtel-vodafone-idea-offers-to-rival-jios-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio again disrupted the voice calls and internet data tariffs after it decided to withdraw its &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. The company after withdrawing the &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; plan earlier this week launched  a new scheme called &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo;, offering &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs. 309. In response to the  &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer other telecom players like Bharti Airtel,Idea Cellular and Vodafone have also come out with special recharge plans offering their customers free voice calls and high speed 4G internet. Recent reports also suggest that Airtel and Vodafone have done away with roaming charges to counter  Jio&amp;rsquo;s free domestic roaming policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some recharge plans released in the past few days to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 399 plan:&lt;/em&gt; Under this plan, cutomers will get 1 GB of high speed 4G internet data along with 300 minutes of calling per day for Airtel to Airtel customers (1,200 minutes per week) and 3,000 minutes of local and STD calling for 70 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; In this plan customers will get 2 GB of 4G high speed internet for 28 days along with 300 minutes per day of Airtel to Airtel calling (1,200 minutes per week).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; In this plan, customers will get 1 GB of 4G internet per day along with 300 minutes of Airtel to Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for week for 70 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; Select customers can use 1GB data per day for 56 days along with unlimited and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea Rs. 351 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; Idea is offering unlimited local and STD calls and unlimited 3G/2G data per day for 4G handsets for 28 days and this recharge can be done by visiting Idea store.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Bank Account:Here Are More Ways To Transfer Your Money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-transfer-money-using-sbi-mingle-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-transfer-money-using-sbi-mingle-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India had in July 2016 launched the SBI Mingle app, allowing its customers access various banking services via social media sites Facebook and Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is offering a new facility that helps customers transfer money using their accounts on social media sites Facebook and Twitter. Users can &amp;ldquo;conveniently transfer funds&amp;rdquo; by logging on to SBI&amp;rsquo;s app &amp;lsquo;Mingle&amp;rsquo;. This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on microblogging site Twitter. SBI had in July 2016 launched the SBI Mingle app, allowing its customers access various banking services via these social media platforms. The SBI Mingle app is available on Google Play for Android mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about the SBI Mingle app:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is SBI Mingle?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Mingle is a social banking application that enables SBI customers to perform basic banking activities through the bank&amp;rsquo;s official Facebook page, the bank said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-mingle-650-400_650x287_51494382504.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The SBI Mingle app is available on Google Play for Android mobile users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to use Mingle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI customers need to register through a simple one-time process using either their account number or their ATM/Debit Card details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who can use Mingle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using SBI Mingle, SBI customers can do a host of banking services on their preferred social platform (i.e. Facebook and Twitter) at their own convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which all tasks can I perform using SBI&amp;rsquo;s Mingle app?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon completing the registration process, the SBI customers can perform a variety of tasks using the Mingle app. Some of them include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance enquiry of accounts
Obtaining a mini statement
Transfer money - within and outside SBI
Request for cheque book
Blocking of ATM Cards&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-mingle-services_650x400_61494383417.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1. Announced in a circular on the SBI website on Thursday morning, the revisions initially created confusion among customers over news that all cash withdrawals through ATM will now be charged at Rs. 25 per transaction. The bank later clarified that the Rs 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through SBI’s mobile wallet app “State Bank Buddy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an emailed statement to NDTV Profit, an SBI spokesperson clarified that a limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applied to the Basic Savings Banks deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal Saving Bank accounts will continue to get 8 free ATM transactions (5 SBI ATMs + 3 other bank ATMs) in metros &amp;amp; 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 SBI ATM + 5 Other Bank ATMs) free, the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from ATM charges, SBI also  revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers. Here are some of the other key changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh, Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; Going forward SBI said it will charge 2 rupees for every soiled note on exchange of more than 20 notes or if the total value of exchanged notes is above Rs 5,000 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs 30 plus service tax for a 10 leaf cheque book, Rs 75 with service tax for 25 leaf cheque book and Rs 150 plus service tax for a 50 leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issue of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only Rupay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At 110 Crore GB Data Traffic A Month, Jio&#39;s Offers For Its Prepaid Users</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a number of recharge options to prepaid subscribers under its paid Prime service. Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website. Jio has become the largest network globally with more than 110 crore GB of data traffic per month and 220 crore voice and video minutes a day, Reliance Industries said in a statement while reporting the group&amp;rsquo;s earnings for financial year 2016-17. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mr Ambani said in the statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All recharges under Jio Prime include free voice call and roaming benefits. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at Jio&amp;rsquo;s various data offerings under its latest recharge options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Rs 19 _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 19 recharge comes with a validity of one day and includes 200 MB of 4G, or high speed, data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 49&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits on offer under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 49 pack include 600 MB of high speed data valid for three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 96&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a validity of seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge includes 7GB of 4G data per day. 4G data comes at a daily limit of 1GB under Jio&amp;rsquo;s fair usage policy, beyond which the speed is reduced to 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 149&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 309&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Jio&amp;rsquo;s three-month benefits on first recharge begin. Subscribers making their first recharge of Rs 309 after taking up Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service will get 1GB of 3G data per day for 84 days, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 509&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimed at &amp;ldquo;daily high data users&amp;rdquo;, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 509 recharge extends the daily 4G data limit offered under the Rs 309 plan to 2GB. Data benefits on subsequent recharges will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first Rs 999 recharge, valid for 120 days, Jio users will get 120 GB of 4G data, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will come with 60 GB of high speed data valid for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s next long-term pack comes at Rs 1,999. The first recharge of this kind includes 185 GB of 4G data valid for 150 days. The 4G data on offer is reduced to 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges, Jio said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 4,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those making their first Prime recharge with the Rs 4,999 pack will get 410 GB of 4G data valid for 240 days. Subsequent recharges will offer 350 GB of such data for 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is the Rs 9,999. The first recharge will offer a total of 810 GB of 4G data valid for 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with a reduced 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 19 To Rs 9,999: What Jio Prepaid, Postpaid Users Get</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering free voice calls and roaming on all its post-paid and pre-paid plans. Also there is no charge for data used to make 4G voice calls under all its plans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. Beyond the daily 4G data limits of 1GB and 2GB per day across its prepaid recharges and postpaid plans, wherever specified, subscribers will continue to use unlimited internet at a reduced speed of 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service - prepaid and postpaid alike - include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are various plans offered by Jio, as per its website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREPAID&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for just one day, Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid offerings start from the Rs 19 recharge, which includes 200 MB of 4G data for Prime members and 100 MB for non-Prime members, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 49&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s next recharge is priced at Rs 49. Jio Prime members recharging with the Rs 49 voucher get 600 MB of high speed data over a validity of three days. The 4G data on offer under this pack is limited to 300 MB for non-Prime members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 96&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge comes with 1GB of 4G data per day. That is for Prime members. Non-Prime members get 600MB of 4G data for seven days with a recharge of Rs 96.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 149&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data valid for 28 days for Prime users and 1GB for non-Prime subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime subscribers buying their first recharge of Rs 309 will get 1GB of 4G data per day for 84 days, as per the Jio website. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first recharge of Rs 509 offers 2GB of 4G data daily, for 84 days. This is comparable with half of the daily 4G data on offer in the Rs 309 pack. Data benefits on subsequent recharges of Rs 509 will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Rs 999 recharge comes with a validity of 120 days, in which subscribers get 120 GB of 4G data. Subsequent recharges are limited to 60 GB of 4G data for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A first recharge of Rs 1,999 comes with 185 GB of 4G data and validity of 150 days. The 4G data on offer is 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 4,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those buying their first recharge after subscribing to Prime will get 410 GB of 4G data with a validity of 240 days. Users will get 350 GB of 4G data with a validity of 180 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is priced at Rs. 9,999. Those buying their first recharge of Rs 9,999 are being offered 810 GB of 4G data with a validity of 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;postpaid&#34;&gt;POSTPAID&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First cycle: Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data per day - which sums up to 90GB of 4G data - for a period of three months under this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequent cycle: Customers will get 30GB of 4G data for a period of one month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering 2GB of 4G data per day for a period of three months on the first cycle, and one month on subsequent cycles. Therefore, users get 180GB of 4G data for three months in the first cycle, and 60GB for one month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first cycle, Jio is offering 180 GB of 4G data for three months under the Rs 999 postpaid plan. Users will get 60 GB of 4G data per month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Plans To Eliminate Sale Of Petrol, Diesel Vehicles By 2030. Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-plans-to-eliminate-sale-of-petrol-diesel-vehicles-by-2030/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-plans-to-eliminate-sale-of-petrol-diesel-vehicles-by-2030/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ministry of Heavy Industries and the NITI Aayog are working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles, Power Minister Piyush Goyal said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India is looking at having an all-electric car fleet by 2030 with an express objective of lowering the fuel import bill and running cost of vehicles. &amp;ldquo;We are going to introduce electric vehicles in a very big way. We are going to make electric vehicles self-sufficient like UJALA. The idea is that by 2030, not a single petrol or diesel car should be sold in the country,&amp;rdquo; Power Minister Piyush Goyal said while addressing the CII Annual Session 2017 here on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyal is of the view that initially the government can handhold the electric vehicle industry for 2-3 years to help it stabilise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing the example of Maruti, which has logged over 30 per cent profit this time, he explained that the government had supported India&amp;rsquo;s largest car maker initially, which eventually led to development of the big automotive industry in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyal told reporters later that the Ministry of Heavy Industries and the NITI Aayog are working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles. The minister pointed to the cost factor, saying people would like to buy electric vehicle when they find it cost effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About offshore wind projects, Goyal said these are more like an R&amp;amp;D project. The minister suggested that big PSUs, including NTPC, can initially invest in such projects that will lead to development of this segment in coming years. Goyal said that in the last 3 years, India&amp;rsquo;s energy consumption has grown by about 6.5 per cent CAGR (compounded annual growth rate), more than the figure for the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, &amp;ldquo;Through UJALA, the LED distribution programme, we have already seen about 500 million LED bulbs sold in the last two years. My job is to improve India&amp;rsquo;s energy efficiency to reduce consumption wherever it is wasteful and ensure that demand is met fully.&amp;rdquo; He made a point that UDAY as not been just about financial re-engineering but financial discipline. The UDAY scheme is meant for revival of debt stressed discoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NITI Aayog is working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government said it can help the electric vehicle industry initially&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electric cars must be cost effective to be popular, Power Minister said&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also bear logo of 125th anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year &amp;ldquo;1891&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in English shall be written on the upper and lower periphery of the coin respectively. The year &amp;ldquo;1916&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in international numerals shall be written respectively on left and right top of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI said the existing coins in this denomination shall also continue to be legal tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 5 coin, the RBI said the coin&amp;rsquo;s face will bear an image depicting centre facade of Allahabad High Court Building emerging from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 1866-2016 in English numerals shall be written at the bottom of the image, the RBI said in a release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Correct Aadhaar, PAN Details Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-aadhaar-pan-details-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-aadhaar-pan-details-online/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tax department has launched facilities to correct errors in PAN, Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has urged taxpayers to link Aadhaar with PAN immediately. This will be useful for e-verification of income tax returns using OTP (one-time password) sent to their mobile registered with Aadhaar, the tax department said. In this regard, the income tax department has launched an online facility to link Aadhaar with PAN, In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided by taxpayer when compared to the actual data in Aadhaar, One Time Password (Aadhaar OTP) will be sent to the mobile registered with Aadhaar. In rare cases where Aadhaar name is completely different from name in PAN, then the linking will fail and taxpayer will be prompted to change the name in either Aadhaar or in PAN database, the tax department said. For the benefit of taxpayers, the income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IT department has launched an online facility to link Aadhaar with PAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor mismatches in Aadhaar name and PAN name can be fixed with an OTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In rare cases a user will be prompted to change name in Aadhaar or PAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website - &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; - one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/graph_650x400_51494824521.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/pan_650x400_41494824562.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;2) The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for correcting data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The income tax department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has a new link on its homepage for connecting Aadhaar with PAN of a taxpayer.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/graph_650x400_51494824644.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;4) There is no need to log in or be registered on e-filing website of the income tax department. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The link requires a person to key in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact&amp;rdquo; name as mentioned on the Aadhaar card. After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR). Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN or permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Savings Account Minimum Balance Requirement. Read Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. The minimum balance requirement for SBI customers varies depending on geographies such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural. If the minimum balance drops below a particular threshold, SBI will charge a fee from the account holder. SBI says the minimum balance in your savings bank account is the monthly average balance - the average of daily balances in the account during the month. SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holders of SBI&amp;rsquo;s savings bank account in urban areas need to maintain a monthly average balance (MAB) of Rs 3,000, Rs 2,000 in case of those in semi-urban areas and Rs 1,000 in rural areas. This was said on Thursday by SBI - which recently merged its operations with six other banks - on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting 31 crore depositors, SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For metropolitan areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Under 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For rural areas, the penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance ranges from Rs 20 to Rs 50 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI offers other types of accounts where it customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. Small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products offered SBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1. After the merger, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>