<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Lucky Grahak, Digi Dhan: Rs 1 Crore Jackpot For Person Making Rs 1,590 Digital Payment</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of the Digi Dhan scheme, three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were declared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Pranab Mukherjee picked six winners from a draw of lots under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes, aimed at promoting digital transactions in the country. &amp;ldquo;In the consumer category, three mega Prizes of Rs 1 crore, Rs 50 lakh and Rs 25 lakh went to the Consumers using Rupay Debit Cards making digital payment of less than Rs.1,000,&amp;rdquo; an official release said. Three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were also declared at the event on the final day of the 100-day scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction of Rs. 1,590 won a Central Bank of India customer a lucky draw of Rs. 1 crore under the consumer category, as part of the government&amp;rsquo;s promotional scheme to popularise digital payments. The President congratulated all the six winners - three consumers and three merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am happy today to be a part of the digital payment movement that India has embarked upon. I congratulate each one of you who has contributed in this mission to make India a less cash society,&amp;rdquo; the President said in his address on the occasion of mega draw of lots for the two schemes held at Rashtrapati Bhawan on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners will be felicitated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on April 14 at Nagpur on the occasion of Ambedkar Jayanti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his address, Mr Mukherjee asked citizens to extend their unstinted support to the mission of a less-cash India. &amp;ldquo;India has a long way to go to become a cash less society. The initiatives of the government are a good beginning and we need to sustain and nurture these with active participation from all segments of the society&amp;hellip;It is necessary to reduce cash in circulation and impart greater urgency to promoting secure digital payment methods to ensure greater transparency,&amp;rdquo; the President said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the consumer section, the second prize of Rs 50 lakh went to a Bank of Baroda customer while the third prize of Rs. 25 lakh was bagged by a customer of Punjab National Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the three customers had made the transactions using their RuPay debit cards. The names of three winners were not yet known as the draw only displayed their transaction numbers. These will be matched with card details to identify the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital transactions have gathered momentum giving a fillip to the less cash economy post demonetisation thanks to the initiatives taken by the government. NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digidhan Vyapar schemes have played a catalytic role in making it a mass movement, the statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressing that India is on the cusp of a digital revolution, Mr Mukherjee noted that more than one billion Indians have a unique identity number with a biometric identifier which is unique in its own way. &amp;ldquo;Even countries which are technologically far more advanced than India with comparatively much smaller size population do not have such a system in place. The Aadhaar card initiative is a watershed event in the development story of India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs. 1,000 notes on November 9 last year, the government took a slew of measures to promote digital payments in the country. It had launched the Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes on December 25 last year for consumers and merchants, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes are being implemented by the National Payment Corporation of India (NPCI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the scheme, daily, weekly and monthly rewards worth Rs. 256 crore have been disbursed to over 16 lakh citizens over the past 100 days for making and accepting small transactions digitally. Over the past 100 days, everyday 15,000 consumers have qualified for total prize money of Rs. 1.5 crore, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The draw has seen a positive impact from various age groups and occupations in adopting digital payments methods. We have seen a steady increase in the number of transactions made using all payment methods,&amp;rdquo; said A P Hota, MD and CEO of National Payment Corporation of India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Notes Ban, 18 Lakh Cases Of Income, Bank Account Mismatches Detected: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government authorities have detected 18 lakh cases after demonetisation where the income profiles of people do not match their account profile, the Lok Sabha was informed today. Preliminary information has been sought from such people and many have responded. Those who have not given details would be issued with notices as per procedure, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said during Question Hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to supplementaries, he said there was an extended footprint of digitisation in the banking sector. With digitisation, the risk of tampering of technology also increases. But banks are also hiring experts to develop firewalls around their system to make it increasingly difficult to breach it, Jaitley said, adding that technology has to keep pace with crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that risk assessment was a continuous process for banks who do it individually and collectively. In his written response, Jaitley said as on March 31, 2016, 29 per cent of the savings accounts of public sector banks and regional rural banks sponsored by them were inoperative or lying dormant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A variety of factors have a bearing on an account being inoperative. These may include factors like opening of a new account with change of residence or office, death of the account holder or the relative convenience of operating different accounts, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Get Time Till June 30 To Obtain PAN From Account Holders</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department has given banks three more months till June 30 to obtain permanent account number (PAN) or Form-60 from all account holders as it looks to tighten the noose around evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the notification, the Income Tax Department said that in Income-Tax Rules 114B, in the fourth proviso, &amp;ldquo;for the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;28th day of February&amp;rsquo; the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;30th day of June&amp;rsquo; shall be substituted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 114B lists various transactions for which quoting PAN is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had in January asked banks, post offices and cooperative banks to document PAN or declaration of Form 60 received from account holders and maintain all records for transactions under Rule 114B of I-T Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had said that persons who have not quoted PAN, or did not furnish Form 60 at the time of opening account, will have to provide the same by February 28. Form 60 is a declaration form filed by an individual without PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the demonetisation move effective November 9, the tax department had asked banks and post offices to report to it all deposits above Rs 2.5 lakh in savings accounts and more than Rs 12.50 lakh in current accounts made between November 10 and December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cash deposits exceeding Rs 50,000 in a single day had to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an estimated Rs 15 lakh crore in junked currency notes coming back into the banking system post demonetisation, the tax department has started analysing the bank deposit trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much You Pay For Petrol, Diesel Could Change Every Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-you-pay-for-petrol-diesel-could-change-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-you-pay-for-petrol-diesel-could-change-every-day/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;State-run oil marketing companies, which control over 90 per cent of the retail fuel market in the country, are mulling a plan that would allow daily changes in the price of petrol and diesel, Economic Times reported on Friday. State-owned Indian Oil Corporation and its two smaller peers Bharat Petroleum and Hindustan Petroleum are considering ways to roll out the plan to review petrol and diesel prices daily, executives from the firms told the daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Petrol, diesel prices depend on global oil prices and rupee rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently, petrol and diesel prices are revised on a fortnightly basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This could change into daily revision of fuel prices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state-run companies declined to immediately comment. The daily price change - also called dynamic fuel pricing - essentially means the companies will not wait for a fortnight to adjust the price of petrol and diesel in tandem with crude price as they do now. Instead, they will change the price every day based on crude price movements. This will help India move to an international standard of fuel pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This will cushion the companies from any loss they face due to currency and crude movements over a 15-day period and will make their margins more predictable,&amp;rdquo; said Dhaval Joshi, analyst with Emkay Global Financial Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move would free private players - Essar Oil and Reliance Industries - which currently follow the price set by state-owned companies, to also shift to a dynamic model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Gives 10GB Data At Rs 100 Under &#39;Data Jackpot&#39; Plan</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-gives-10gb-data-at-rs-100-under-data-jackpot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-gives-10gb-data-at-rs-100-under-data-jackpot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Idea Cellular is offering a promotional &amp;ldquo;Data Jackpot&amp;rdquo; offer for its postpaid users. Under the new Idea offer, users can get up to 10GB of data per month, for first three months, at a monthly rental of Rs 100. Idea&amp;rsquo;s plan is available via its app (My Idea app) only and customers who opt for the offer will get a minimum of 1GB per month for three months, at Rs 100 per month, up to a maximum of 10GB per month. After the three months, those who have opted for the same will get 1GB extra data per month at Rs 100 as an additional benefit. The data benefits under this limited offer may vary from circle to circle, Idea noted.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/idea-cellular-data-jackpot_650x187_81491661007.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;All the major telecom operators are offering various discounts to counter the new entrant Reliance Jio which has commenced a price war in the sector. Telecom regulator TRAI has recently asked Jio to end its &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise offer&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Vodafone India and Idea agreed to merge their operations to create the country&amp;rsquo;s largest mobile phone operator worth more than $23 billion with a 35 per cent market share. The new combined entity of Vodafone and Idea, which are India&amp;rsquo;s number 2 and 3 mobile players respectively, will overtake Bharti Airtel in a bid to tackle a raging price war in the world&amp;rsquo;s second-largest market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britain&amp;rsquo;s Vodafone Group will own 45.1 per cent of the merged entity while the Aditya Birla group, Idea&amp;rsquo;s parent company, will own 26 per cent after paying Rs 3,874 crore cash for a 4.9 per cent stake. The remaining 28.9 per cent will be held by other shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Still Get Reliance Jio&#39;s &#39;Summer Surprise Offer&#39;? Here Are The Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-you-still-get-jios-summer-surprise-offer-here-are-the-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-you-still-get-jios-summer-surprise-offer-here-are-the-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although, the offer can still be availed over the &amp;ldquo;next few days&amp;rdquo; and those who &amp;ldquo;subscribe before the discontinuation&amp;rdquo; will remain eligible for the complimentary plan,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s website stated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) asked Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio to withdraw the complimentary &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; plan as it did not fit into the &amp;ldquo;regulatory framework&amp;rdquo;. Reliance Jio has accepted the regulator&amp;rsquo;s decision and is in the process of &amp;ldquo;fully complying&amp;rdquo; with it. Jio &amp;lsquo;complimentary&amp;rsquo; offer included free data usage and calls for three months on a recharge of Rs 303 or higher. Although, the offer can still be availed over the &amp;ldquo;next few days&amp;rdquo; and those who &amp;ldquo;subscribe before the discontinuation&amp;rdquo; will remain eligible for the complimentary plan,&amp;rdquo; the company&amp;rsquo;s website stated.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/reliance-jio_650x400_61491559381.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We examined it and found that it was not in accordance with regulatory framework, so we advised them to stop it,&amp;rdquo; TRAI Chairman RS Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the regulator&amp;rsquo;s decision, Cellular Operators Association of India (COAI) said that the TRAI&amp;rsquo;s move to stop the three-month complimentary offer would reduce the deterioration in industry&amp;rsquo;s revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When the regulator establishes a level-playing-field, the market forces establish the right price points,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said, terming the withdrawal of the offer as a &amp;ldquo;relief&amp;rdquo; for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the data released by TRAI, the revenue of telecom sector from consumer services like mobile telephony and data dipped 10.5 per cent to Rs 37,284 crore in the October-December period over the previous three months. The revenue of the sector from the same set of services stood at Rs 41,681 crore in July-September last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incumbent telecom operators have blamed free services of new entrant Reliance Jio for the decline in their quarterly numbers. While Jio provided free 4G service during the period, other telecom operators struggled to compete with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31 March Last Day For Depositing Old Notes In RBI: Here&#39;s A Checklist</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-31-march-last-day-for-depositing-old-notes-in-rbi-heres-a-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-31-march-last-day-for-depositing-old-notes-in-rbi-heres-a-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the March 31 deadline looming for depositing demonetised currency, the Reserve Bank offices continued to witness long queues. There is confusion among people standing in the queues as ineligible ones are making it longer. &amp;ldquo;Several people who are ineligible queueing up at RBI counters making the queue longer,&amp;rdquo; Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal said in the Rajya Sabha. As tempers ran high outside the central bank branches, he added that &amp;ldquo;each application has to be checked at the counters for his/her absence from the country from passport stamp marks, it is taking considerable time for the counter staff.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a checklist before the opportunity ends on March 31:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Possession of more than 10 notes in junked currency after March 31 is illegal for Indian residents. Violation of this is punishable with a fine which may extend to Rs 10,000 or five times the amount of the face value of the notes, whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central bank allowed Indian residents who were abroad during November-December 2016 to exchange the scrapped notes up to March 31 but for non-resident Indians (NRIs) the deadline is June 30.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NRIs coming to India are required to come through &amp;lsquo;Red Channel&amp;rsquo; disclosing to the Customs authorities at the airport the amount of the defunct notes and secure a certificate to be tendered at RBI at the time of exchange. A one-page form has been worked out for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no monetary limit for exchange for the eligible resident Indians, but the limit for NRIs will be as per the relevant FEMA Regulations (Rs 25,000 per person).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indian citizens resident in Nepal, Bhutan, Pakistan and Bangladesh cannot avail this facility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The facility to exchange old notes is available at RBI offices in Mumbai, Delhi, Kolkata, Chennai and Nagpur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On fulfillment of the terms and conditions and the genuineness of the notes tendered, the amount will be credited to the person&amp;rsquo;s Know Your Customer (KYC) compliant bank account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case of refusal by the central bank, a person may appeal to the Central Board of the Reserve Bank within 14 days of the communication of such refusal to him. Such representations may be addressed to the Central Board, Reserve Bank of India, Secretary&amp;rsquo;s Department.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto, Health Insurance To Cost More As Regulator Okays Raise For Agents</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Car, motorcycle and health insurance will cost more from April 1 with regulator Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority (IRDAI) giving go-ahead to insurers for revision in commission for agents. The change in premium after modification will be limited to around 5 per cent of the existing rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase will be in addition to the enhanced third party motor insurance rates, which too will come into affect from April. The IRDAI (Payment of Commission or Remuneration or Reward to Insurance Agents and Insurance Intermediaries) Regulations, 2016 comes into effect from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulations, the regulator said, bring about certain revisions in commission/ remuneration rates and also introduce the reward system. These may trigger insurers to revisit the pricing of their products in so far as the costing input relating to commission or remuneration is concerned, said IRDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the change in premium due to the new regulations should be &amp;ldquo;limited to +/- 5 per cent of the existing premium rates of products/add-ons&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, insurers will have to give a certificate that there is &amp;ldquo;no detrimental change&amp;rdquo; in premium rates or any other provision of policies already sold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-based payment modes work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government is planning to utilise the Aadhaar database to give shape to a digital future and utilise it for payments, and authentication of transactions is the key to its success. While Unified Payments Interface and BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) are processes for peer-to-peer transactions using smartphones, the government is promoting Aadhaar-enabled payment systems for the non-smartphone savvy. As per sources it is planning to launch Aadhaar Pay on April 14. ET looks into the different forms of Aadhaar payment modes being developed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems?
Payments that can be done with the help of au thentication and identi fication through the Aadhaar database is referred to as the Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems (AEPS). This is the new form of pay ment that is being pro moted by the govern ment to push for digital payments instead of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the major types of Aadhaar Enabled Payments?
The first type of payment is Aadhaar Bridge Payment System which is meant for direct bene fit transfer and subsidy payments from the gov ernment to the benefi ciaries. The second is AEPS which is used at the level of the business correspondent or `bank mitras’ where bank customers can use Aadhaar to access various services like cash withdrawal, account opening and fund transfer even without going to a bank branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is Aadhaar Pay wherein merchants can accept payments through Aadhaar identification of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we need Aadhaar Enabled payments?
These forms of payments are be ing promoted by the government specifically for the under privileged sections of the society and the rural poor who are not comfortable using cards or mobile wallets for payments.Instead of a mobile phone or a plastic card, in these forms of payments, the mode of authentication becomes the Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who runs the systems?
National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is the nodal authority for all Aadhaar-enabled payments in collaboration with banks. The payment company is trying to get as many banks to seed their customers’ accounts with their Aadhaar number so that payments can flow smoothly .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do the different forms of payments work?
Aahdaar Bridge Payment (ABPS):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant for recur ring payments done by the government to its customers for various subsidies as well as direct benefit transfer. Here the beneficiary is identified through an Aadhaar number, then NPCI manages an Aadhaar Mapper where the Aadhaar number is mapped to a specific bank account and the money flows to the connected bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-enabled-payment-aeps&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Payment (AEPS):&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the customer has to approach a business correspondent (BC), use his Aadhaar number and biometrics which the BC shares with NPCI, which checks the ID with UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India) to confirm the customer’s identity . It also checks the funds in the connected account and allows the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for merchant payments where the merchant will download the merchant payments app of his bank, authenticate the customer through his biometrics and Aadhaar number and initiate a pull transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Select Tax Department Offices To Be Open Till March 31 Midnight</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/select-tax-department-offices-to-be-open-till-march-31-midnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/select-tax-department-offices-to-be-open-till-march-31-midnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The last date for making declaration under the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana, 2016 is March, 31 2017.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CBDT on Thursday issued an order that all designated offices of the Income Tax department which can accept declarations under the black money window of PMGKY will remain open till midnight of March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The last date for making declaration under the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana, 2016 is March, 31 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Therefore, in order to facilitate the filing of declarations even after the office hours on the last date, the CBDT, hereby directs that the designated offices for receiving the declarations under PMGKY shall remain open till the midnight of March 31, 2017 in all jurisdictions,&amp;rdquo; the CBDT order said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) is the policymaking body of the Income Tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A person or entity who opts for PMGKY will have to pay 49.9 per cent tax on the undisclosed income, whereas a person who does not opt for the scheme but offers his black income in his Income Tax Returns will face a tax and penalty rate of 77.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one who does not offer his stash funds under the scheme but is caught with undisclosed income in scrutiny assessment will face 83.25 per cent tax rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who do not declare their stash under the PMGKY and are raided will face 107.25 per cent tax and penalty if the undisclosed income is surrendered during the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who do not surrender such hidden income even during searches will stand to face the highest level of penalty and tax at 137.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre had come out with the PMGKY scheme after its decision to demonetise high value currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quarter of the total sum will also have to be parked in a non-interest bearing deposit for four years under the said scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scheme had commenced on December 17 last year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Prepaid Users Can Get Up To 120GB Extra Data. Here Is How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-prepaid-users-can-get-120gb-extra-data-here-is-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-prepaid-users-can-get-120gb-extra-data-here-is-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier this week, a survey conducted by Bank of America Merrill Lynch said that around 84 per cent of the current Jio members are expected to subscribe for the Prime membership.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime offer, which opened for enrolment on March 1, entitles customers to &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; benefits till March 2018. To sweeten the Prime offer, Jio is offering additional benefits for subscribers who recharge their accounts before March 31, 2017. Those who recharge before March 31, will get up to 10 GB of extra data for one recharge cycle (under different prepaid plans). For example, If subscribers opt for the Rs. 149 prepaid plan (validity 28 days) before March 31, then they will get 1 GB of free data in addition to 2 GB of data originally on offer. Similarly under the Rs. 303 plan, Jio offers 5 GB of free data along with 28 GB of data subscribers are originally entitled for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Jio customer care executive confirmed that a Prime member can lock in the above benefits till March 2018. For example, if a Prime customer recharges his account with the Rs. 499 plan 12 times before March 31, 2017, then he would be entitled to get 120GB of extra data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-prime-650_650x400_41490449016.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

Meanwhile, in the Rs. 999, Rs. 1999, Rs. 4,999 and Rs. 9,999 plans Jio is offering 10 GB of extra data per recharge cycle over and above the data originally on offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rs. 149, Rs. 303 and Rs. 499 plans of Reliance Jio have a validity of 28 days while the Rs. 999 plan offers a validity of 60 days. Meanwhile, the Rs. 1,999 and Rs. 4,999 plans have validity of 90 and 180 days respectively. The Rs. 9,999 plan of Jio comes with a validity of 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio, which started its operations in September 2016, has already crossed the 100 million subscribers mark. Earlier this week, a survey conducted by Bank of America Merrill Lynch said that around 84 per cent of the current Jio members are expected to subscribe for the Prime membership.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associate Bank Branches To Become SBI Branches From April 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branches of all five associate banks, which are merging with parent State Bank of India, will begin functioning as SBI branches from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customers, including depositors of State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore will be treated as customers of State Bank of India with effect from April 1, 2017,&amp;rdquo; the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) said in a notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officers and employees, with the exception of the board of directors and executive trustees of the associate banks, will become employees of SBI following the merger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI alone has nearly 20,000 branches, including 191 foreign offices spread across 36 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the five subsidiary banks, only SBBJ, SBM and SBT are listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the government on Monday announced that Bharatiya Mahila Bank will also be merged with SBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>