<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7 smart tips which can help you save more &amp; become rich</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t want to become rich? However, getting wealthy isn’t that easy. It begins with determined consciousness to get wealthy. We all know that to become rich you need to spend less than what you earn. That is because the less you spend, the more you will be able to save. You should save and invest what you have into investments (assets) that appreciate over time. Apart from these, here we are taking a look at a few really easy and ‘anyone can do it’ strategies or DIY tips that can make you a crorepati:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt makes Aadhaar mandatory for students</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</guid>
      <description>The move is aimed at checking the drop-out rate and ensuring quality education
The Yogi Adityanath government in Uttar Pradesh has made Aadhaar Card mandatory for students from Class 1 to 8 in government schools. The Basic Education department has been entrusted with this task involving over 1.75 crore students.
The Basic Education Minister Anupama Jaiswal said that directions have been issued in this regard. “The main aim of the government is to link their Aadhaar Card number with different welfare schemes, including mid-day meal, run by the state for the welfare of primary students,” she said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.
The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either 567678 or 56161.
It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.
Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.
DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.
HIGHLIGHTS  The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions  India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.
HIGHLIGHTS  Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1 The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent  The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Not Mandatory For Insurance, Says IRDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-for-insurance-says-irdai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-for-insurance-says-irdai/</guid>
      <description>Aadhar is not mandatory for the (insurance) sector but is the most simple one, IRDAI, the insurance sector regulator said.
Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (IRDAI) today said though Aadhar is not a mandatory requirement for Know Your Customer (KYC) in the insurance sector, it is the most simple form of KYC document.
&amp;ldquo;Aadhar is not mandatory for the (insurance) sector but is the most simple one. On the government level they are creating a platform for all the KYC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data hack: IIT Kharagpur graduate arrested, earns Rs 40 lakh a year at Ola</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</guid>
      <description>An IIT Kharagpur graduate, Abhinav Srivastava, who allegedly hacked Aadhaar data has been arrested by Bengaluru Police. According to investigation, Srivastava had gained access to the repository of the Unique Identification Development Authority of India’s (UIDAI) Aadhaar project through the Digital India e-hospital portal. The 31-year-old hails from Uttar Pradesh and was arrested in connection with a complaint filed by the UIDAI on July 26, according to Indian Express.
Police said the complaint against Srivastava stated that he accessed UIDAI data without authorisation between January 1 and July 26 for an app called ‘eKYC Verification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data leak: Now govt agencies will safeguard your personal info</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</guid>
      <description>The linking of Aadhaar — the 12-digit unique identification number for Indian residents is about to become safer as new rules put the onus on government departments and agencies to safeguard personal data or information held by them.
Departments handling the data will have to ensure that end-users are made aware of the data usage and collection and their consent is taken either in writing or electronically, according to new guidelines issued by the government for security of personal data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>