<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>9 online jobs that you can do from home</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Whether you’re looking for a respite from your 9 to 5, are unable to commute to work, are a stay at-home parent, or have some other constraint that prevents you from finding a full-time job, there’s no need to waste your earning potential.
There are plenty of opportunities available online that let you work from home. Here are a few options you can consider.
 Virtual assistantship  Entrepreneurs, professionals and small teams often need assistance with various administrative tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.
SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Allows Co-Operative Banks To Deposit Old Notes With RBI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</guid>
      <description>The relaxation comes against the backdrop of reports that many district co-operative banks did not have enough cash to disburse to farmers.
The Finance Ministry on Tuesday allowed banks, post offices and district central cooperative banks to deposit the scrapped Rs 500 and 1,000 rupee notes with the Reserve Bank of India within 30 days and exchange the value of notes deposit with the new notes.
In an official notification the Finance Ministry said, &amp;ldquo;Specified bank notes may be deposited by such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, in any office of the Reserve Bank, within a period of 30 days from the commencement of these rules, and get the exchange value thereof by credit to the account of such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, subject to the satisfaction of the Reserve Bank of the conditions specified in the said notification and the reasons for non-deposit of the specified bank notes within the period under that notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GST will impact your household budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</guid>
      <description>Goods and services tax (GST) comes into effect from 1 July. ET Wealth analyses the impact on some basic expenses in the household consumption basket.
AUTOMOBILES The price difference will be bigger for SUVs (55% to 43%) compared to small cars (30% to 29%).
Base price : Rs 4.75 lakh
Total taxes now* : Rs 1.43 lakh
Under GST : Rs 1.38 lakh
DURABLES : Refrigerators and washing machines For most white goods, there won&amp;rsquo;t be much difference in price as new rates will be close to earlier ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.
Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Announces Mega Auction Of Properties</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</guid>
      <description>The bank will auction off 150 properties,including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country.
State Bank of India (SBI) has a nnounced a sale of properties through a mega e-auction on June 23, 2017. This was said by the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank on microblogging site Twitter. The bank will auction off 150 properties, including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country, SBI said on its website. These properties were pledged as collateral for housing and business loans and were taken over by the bank under the Security and Reconstruction of Financial Assets and Enforcement of Security Interest (Sarfaesi) Act due to non-payment of pending dues by the borrowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammers are trying to get your Aadhaar details via calls, emails</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</guid>
      <description>Watch out! The scammers are out with a new set of tricks to swindle the gullible public. Curiously, the Centre’s directive to link the bank accounts with Aadhaar has apparently made these fraudsters more brazen. Their latest modus operandi is to seek details of the Aadhaar card from unsuspecting victims through phone calls and emails.
Posing as bank executives or tele-callers, they call up potential victims saying, “The bank has decided to link your Aadhaar number with debit card for better customer service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win Rupay Select Credit Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>IDBI Bank announced the launch of ‘Winnings’ Rupay Select Credit Card that offers a range of travel, shopping and dining privileges and also enables earning of rewards points on every spend. The credit card has been launched in association with National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI). This product is similar to the international credit cards offered by VISA and MasterCard.
The ‘Winnings’ RuPay Select Credit Card is a premium credit card variant and is at par with the premium Card variants of International Card networks which is Visa Signature and MasterCard World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM
Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Facility Launched To Link Aadhaar With PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.
The Income Tax Department has launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing income tax returns (ITRs) now. The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.
The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through Frotels.com for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4GB Data Per Day For Rs 444</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</guid>
      <description>State-run telecom firm BSNL today increased per day data offering to 4GB at 3G speeds under a new prepaid mobile scheme priced at Rs 444 with 90 days validity.
&amp;ldquo;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) has introduced &amp;lsquo;BSNL Chaukka - 444&amp;rsquo;, a new STV, for truly unlimited data for 90 days as special promotional offer under prepaid mobile services,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.
This is the highest per day data limit being offered by any telecom operator in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange old notes for new at a premium</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</guid>
      <description>Scrapped old notes ­ Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 ­ which were to be exchanged latest by December 20, 2016, are still there. They can be exchanged even now, but for a hefty premium.
Non-Resident Indians (NRIs), who were allowed to exchange old notes till June 30 this year, are being offered a handsome commission for exchanging these notes.
&amp;ldquo;The going rate for exchanging old notes is Rs 9 on every Rs 100, so if you want to exchange Rs 1 crore in old notes, then you would get back Rs 9 lakh in new notes,&amp;rdquo; said Pravin (name changed), who is involved in this trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation To Launch RuPay Credit Card Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India has forayed in to the credit card business and would make the commercial launch of its RuPay credit card &amp;ldquo;in a month&amp;rsquo;s time,&amp;rdquo; a top official said today.
&amp;ldquo;Maybe in a month&amp;rsquo;s time we will be able to make the commercial launch (of RuPay credit card),&amp;rdquo; NPCI Chairman M Balachandran told reporters here.
NPCI, which currently offers RuPay debit cards, has partnered with 10 banks including public sector and cooperative banks, to make the pilot launch of the &amp;ldquo;RuPay Credit Card&amp;rdquo;, Balachandran said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PM insurance schemes on June 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</guid>
      <description>Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY) were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner.
You must have heard about the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY), which were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?
SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.
 Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.
HIGHLIGHTS  The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions  India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI Launches Three New Mobile Apps For Voice, Data Quality Tracking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</guid>
      <description>TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring.
Aiming to protect consumer interests, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Monday launched three new mobile applications and a web portal.
TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring. The app will help mobile phone users rate their experience about voice call quality in real time and help TRAI gather customer experience data along with network data, an official TRAI statement said here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.
To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-Aadhaar as ID proof in Railways</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</guid>
      <description>After receiving several requests from passengers, Railway has agreed to accept e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class. Earlier only printed version was considered as a valid ID.
According to railway ministry, the issue regarding acceptance of e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class was being raised at various foras.
Accordingly, the matter was examined in consultation with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>