<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Govt:Over Rs 153cr awarded to 10lk people to promote e-payments</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-153-cr-awarded-10-lk-people-promote-e-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;check if you are winner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dev.digidhanlucky&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px;padding:4px&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/logoapp.png&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0 auto;&#34; src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on start button in Digi Dhan Lucky Yojana App.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on whether you are a Consumer or a Merchant, click on the corresponding button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box that appears next, provide the mobile phone number registered with your UPI/ USSD/ RuPay/ AEPS account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive an OTP, which you must enter in the box that appears in the middle of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Try Your Luck button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next message will show if you have won under the Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi Dhan Vyapar Yojana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been awarded over Rs 153.5 crore in the last 58 days under Niti Aayog’s schemes to promote digital payments, its CEO Amitabh Kant said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It has been 58 days since the launch of Niti Aayog’s two incentive schemes – Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana to promote digital payments and the public response has been quite encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the latest figures released by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), which has been executing the schemes, nearly 10 lakh consumers and merchants have been disbursed over Rs 153.5 crore as reward money till February 20, 2017,” Kant said at a press conference here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s think-tank said in a statement that among the 9.8 lakh winners are more than 9.2 lakh consumers and 56,000 merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners belong to diverse socio-economic backgrounds, including farmers, merchants, small entrepreneurs, professionals, housewives, students and retired persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Uttar Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh and Delhi have emerged as the top five states/Union Territories with maximum number of winners,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While majority of the winners are in the age group of 21 to 30, Niti Aayog pointed out that a significant number are also above 60 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The diversity in age of winners is from 15 to 66 years, challenging the notion that the old find it difficult to embrace technology to adopt digital payments,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government on December 25 had launched two schemes — Lucky Grahak Yojana and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojana — to boost digital transactions post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associate Bank Branches To Become SBI Branches From April 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branches of all five associate banks, which are merging with parent State Bank of India, will begin functioning as SBI branches from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customers, including depositors of State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore will be treated as customers of State Bank of India with effect from April 1, 2017,&amp;rdquo; the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) said in a notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officers and employees, with the exception of the board of directors and executive trustees of the associate banks, will become employees of SBI following the merger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI alone has nearly 20,000 branches, including 191 foreign offices spread across 36 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the five subsidiary banks, only SBBJ, SBM and SBT are listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the government on Monday announced that Bharatiya Mahila Bank will also be merged with SBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation Says No Vulnerability In BHIM App</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-says-no-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-says-no-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPCI significant downloads have been witnessed since the BHIM app was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;National Payments Corporation of India&lt;/em&gt; (NPCI) on Monday said there is no vulnerability or loopholes reported in the Bharat Interface for Money or BHIM application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI has done intensive testing, robust design of security controls and continuous monitoring of its Unified Payments Interface (UPI) infrastructure, the corporation said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The environment in which BHIM or UPI is run by NPCI is highly secure and certified with best global practices,&amp;rdquo; it said, adding that the packages have also been audited by reputed IT security firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI has put in place adequate governance mechanism for banks to report any fraud or system issues and its redressal, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, it said that since BHIM was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, significant downloads have been witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Out of the 19.16 million downloads, 5.1 million customers have been able to link their bank accounts. In many cases customers downloaded the application to see that they have not linked their mobile number to the bank account,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks are expected to reach out to all their customers by various means and ensure universal acceptance of mobile banking services at the earliest,&amp;rdquo; NPCI managing director and CEO A P Hota said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt tells RBI to work with stakeholders for PoS roll-out</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-tells-rbi-work-stakeholders-pos-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-tells-rbi-work-stakeholders-pos-roll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The govt has asked RBI to fix responsibilities for stakeholders, including PoS manufactures, UIDAI that administers the 12-digit Aadhaar number, and the NPCI to launch the process&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance ministry has asked the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to bring together all stakeholders, including banks and back-end service providers, and establish a process for the roll-out of Aadhaar-based point of sales (PoS) machines to promote cashless transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his budget speech last month, finance minister Arun Jaitley said two million Aadhaar-based PoS machines will be rolled out by September-end. Banks have flagged the lack of an established back-end infrastructure as an impediment in implementing this mandate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has now asked RBI to fix responsibilities for stakeholders, including PoS manufactures, back-end service providers, banks, and the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) that administers the 12-digit Aadhaar number, and the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) to launch the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For Aadhaar-based PoS machines to be a reality, many systems and processes have to be put in place. The biometric data captured on these machines has to be encrypted and transmitted after which Aadhaar authentication has to be done. The payment then has to be processed. For this, all the stakeholders have to be brought together by RBI and the process established,” said a senior finance ministry official, who did not wish to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time that an Aadhaar-based authentication process has been proposed. RBI, in a notification in September 2016, made it mandatory for all banks to ensure that all new card acceptance infrastructure deployed from 1 January, 2017 is enabled for processing payment transactions using Aadhaar-based biometric authentication. After banks raised concerns about a mismatch between demand and supply of such Aadhaar-enabled devices, the central bank gave banks time till end-June to deploy this infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deepak Bhutra, chief executive officer, India Transact Services Ltd, a merchant payment solutions firm, said it is possible to shift to new age biometric payment systems. “This is not technically a difficult task but rather a very expensive one. Companies will have to invest in securing these biometric readers and assembling them in the currently available PoS machines,” he said in an email. “We do see faster acceptance of the PoS machines now with the push from the government, but a major challenge would be to educate the customer to pay through Aadhaar payment method as opposed to paying via the card route,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are a few things which banks will incrementally have to follow. Firstly, banks will need to get certified with NPCI for AEPS (Aadhaar- enabled payment system) switching capability which will have to be managed or outsourced by the bank. Secondly, deployment of a merchant app with low cost peripheral, to enable Aadhaar biometric authentication is needed. Lastly, banks would need to upgrade their existing EDC (electronic draft capture) PoS or mPoS terminals to support biometric capture which may work out to be more costly and much less scalable,” Deepak Sharma, chief digital officer, Kotak Mahindra Bank, said in response to emailed questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“From a consumer perspective, the Aadhaar-based payment methodology will work even in the absence of feature phones and high-end smart phones—which addresses a significant part of the population at the bottom of the pyramid,” added Sharma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An IDFC Bank official said the target is easily achievable if new age banks adopt this route. “The bank has an ambitious roll-out plan for both Aadhaar Pay as well as micro ATMs,” the official added on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay is a service for merchants that will enable them to receive payments from customers without any physical payment instrument. The app has to be downloaded by merchants on their phones and linked to an Aadhaar biometric reader. Once the merchant has this infrastructure in place, consumers can start transacting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPI, Aadhaar Pay, Bharat QR force Paytm, Mobikwik to step up their game</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/upi-aadhaar-pay-bharat-qr-force-paytm-mobikwik-step-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/upi-aadhaar-pay-bharat-qr-force-paytm-mobikwik-step-game/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the arrival of state-sponsored e-payment services, electronic payment firms have ratcheted up their efforts to lure customers in the cashless driven market&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic payment firms got a big boost when India abolished most of the country’s banknotes last year, but rival state-sponsored e-payment services are forcing them to raise their game to hang on to their new customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until November’s move, which scrapped 86% of all notes to foil counterfeiting and the black market, more than 90% of transactions in India were in cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic payments providers such as market leaders Paytm and MobiKwik, and smaller players FreeCharge, Citrus, ItzCash and Oxigen, seized the opportunity, snapping up millions of customers and merchants caught out by the sudden shortage of cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the government is rolling out three tools to facilitate rival cashless transactions, including a United Payments Interface (UPI) app that simplifies inter-bank fund transfers, and Aadhaar Pay, a bank-linked payment service that relies on the national identity card and can be used with just a fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also promoted Bharat QR, another bank-linked service that uses machine-readable labels as the base for a simple payment system, helped by Visa and MasterCard. It requires only a smartphone and is aiming to sign up 2 million merchants by September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UPI app was downloaded more than 17 million times within two months of launch, and transaction values jumped 18 times between November and January, albeit from a low base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So e-wallet providers such as Alibaba-backed Paytm, the largest, with more than 200 million clients, are adding services to stay a step ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paytm is betting that its licence to set up a niche bank so it can pay interest on deposits—and connect its systems with the UPI network—will help, and it knows it will need extra services to make the business profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The point is that e-wallets as a standalone business will be massively risky and not viable,” said Vijay Shekhar Sharma, founder and chief executive of Paytm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;freebies&#34;&gt;Freebies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early stages of their build-up, the companies haven’t even paid lipservice to viability—giving a free service to customers and merchants, while burning through their start-up funding. Their only source of income has been commissions on phone and utility bill payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paytm’s parent company has raised $675 million from Alibaba and more from others, and says its current valuation is about $5 billion, but it has lost about $230 million over the last financial year. MobiKwik, part-owned by American Express and Sequoia Capital, has raised about $80 million and is eyeing a $1 billion valuation as it holds talks with investors for more funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both have waived fees to enable free money transfers from wallets to bank accounts. Paytm says transfers within its wallets and accounts will be free forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they have been using cash discounts and freebies to lure customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mumbai-based management teacher Christina Sundaresan says she started using Paytm when the government pulled the plug on notes, and now uses it so frequently she gets a free movie ticket each weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My laptop repairer, the vegetable vendor and the medical store are all accepting Paytm, so it works well,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she says she would consider other payment options, including UPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That will make it difficult for Paytm to withdraw the freebies, but they can’t keep burning cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t have a business that says ‘pay a 500 bill and take 250 cash back’,” said Aditya Puri, head of third-biggest Indian lender HDFC Bank, which has its own payment app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MobiKwik, which started as a simple digital wallet, is looking to partner with mainstream banks to market a host of financial services on its platform, from mutual funds to loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It aims to triple its wallets user base to 150 million by end-2017, and raise the value of transactions five times to $10 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It thinks its head start and extra services will keep it on top of the competition, and that banks, latecomers to e-payment, will struggle to match the scale of its operations and vendor network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“UPI is a solution for bank transfers. UPI is not a payments ecosystem today, as there are no merchants on UPI,” said MobiKwik chief executive Bipin Preet Singh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dhruv Chopra, managing director at the Indian unit of South African payments solutions provider Net1, which has invested in MobiKwik, is also betting the start-ups will be too nimble for the banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with a large number of small players, many will not survive, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avnish Bajaj of venture capital firm Matrix Partners, which has investments in payments companies ItzCash, Mswipe, and ride hailing firm Ola, which has its own e-wallet, agrees there will be a clearout under competitive pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s going to be a bit of consolidation in the e-wallets space in the next two years,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar payments: All you need to know about the new Aadhar Pay app</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-payments-need-know-new-aadhar-pay-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-payments-need-know-new-aadhar-pay-app/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to promote Aadhaar-based payment system, Modi government has launched a new Android app for merchants to accept payments using their biometric data or the registered data under UIDAI’s Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar-based payment system is currently being used by 1,10,000 business correspondents for disbursing cash, and is also being utilised in Common Service Centres to pay for various services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is all you need to know about the newly launched Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-the-new-app-will-work&#34;&gt;How the new app will work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After downloading the app, the user also needs to register with a valid ID. Then he/she needs to fill the required details to validate the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Merchants: After downloading the Aadhaar Pay app from Google Play Store, the user has to install a biometric scanner linked to the user’s smartphone. The user also needs to link his bank account to the phone so that the transaction can be completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Customers: Customers need their Aadhaar number which has to be linked to their bank account. They can use either a fingerprint or biometric data to complete the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages of doing a transaction through Aadhaar app is that no additional charges will be levied unlike debit and credit cards.
Also, the installing cost for a biometric scanner for Aadhaar Pay is much more less than a POS machine. A POS machine costs Rs 5,000 whereas the biometric scanner will cost around Rs 2,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;however-one-of-the-limitation-of-aadhaar-app-payments-is-that-they-can-only-take-place-if-the-internet-is-available&#34;&gt;However, one of the limitation of Aadhaar app payments is that they can only take place if the internet is available.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;meanwhile-here-are-other-related-points-about-the-newly-launched-aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Meanwhile, here are other related points about the newly launched Aadhaar Pay&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app has been jointly developed by UIDAI,NPCI and IDFC Bank. The Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is the nodal body responsible for rolling out the Aadhaar programme in the country. Transactions through the app would be made with the help of registered data under UIDAI’s          Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emphasizing upon the rural pockets of the country, UIDAI has favored “incentives” for merchants using the biometric mode for digital transactions, in line with commission given by banks to Business Correspondents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Ajay Bhushan Pandey, CEO of UIDAI told media, “If a merchant is using Aadhaar-enabled payment systems then he should be put at par with Business Correspondent and whatever facility and commission is available to the Business Correspondent, he should be paid on the same lines”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also added that incentivizing shopkeepers who adopt the biometric payment system would also “remove an extra layer” as consumers today approach banks, ATMs or business correspondents for withdrawal of money to purchase items such as ration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to an Economic Times report, the Government is mulling over an option of giving banks an incentive of up to Rs 10 for each transaction. Quoting a government official, the report stated that a suggestion to provide an incentive of 0.25% on the value of a transaction – capped at Rs 10 –     made on the biometric-based payment system Aadhaar Pay and UPI platform BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The committee of secretaries had said that if they (banks) don’t have incentives, they may not go and acquire merchants, so let them have incentives, and merchant will not bear cost and it may be borne from the financial inclusion fund,” the official told ET.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digital payment channels like mobile wallets, USSD and RuPay have seen massive uptake and rise in transactions post demonetisation on November 8. Even in case of Aadhaar-enabled payment system, the volume of transactions have jumped 2.5 times post demonetisation from 6 lakh a day before November   to 15 lakh transactions per day at present.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPF Withdrawal Rules Relaxed, Get Money In 15 Days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gpf-withdrawal-rules-relaxed-get-money-in-15-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gpf-withdrawal-rules-relaxed-get-money-in-15-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Employees can also withdraw the fund for select purposes after completing 10 years of service, as against 15 years of service earlier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In good news for about 50 lakh central government employees, the norms for withdrawal of General Provident Fund (GPF) have been relaxed which will enable them to receive payments within 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees can also withdraw the fund for select purposes after completing 10 years of service, as against 15 years of service earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GPF can be taken for education &amp;ndash; including primary, secondary and higher education, covering all streams and institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, a subscriber could withdraw GPF for beyond the high school stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some amendments have been made (in rules) from time to time to address the concerns raised by the subscribers. However, the provisions, largely remain restrictive. There is a felt need to liberalise provisions, raise limits and simplify the procedure,&amp;rdquo; the Ministry said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The provisions in the rules have been reviewed and it has now been decided to permit withdrawals from the fund by the subscriber for obligatory expenses viz. betrothal (engagement), marriage, funerals, or other ceremonies of self or family members and dependants, besides illness of self, family members or dependants, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It has been decided to permit withdrawal of up to twelve months pay or three-fourth of the amount standing at credit, whichever is less. For illness, the withdrawal may be allowed up to 90 per cent of the amount standing at credit of the subscriber. A subscriber may seek withdrawal after completion of ten years of service,&amp;rdquo; the ministry said in an order to all central government departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GPF can be withdrawn for purchase of consumer durables also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing rules do not give any time limit or sanction and payment of withdrawal amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Therefore, it has been decided to prescribe a maximum time limit of fifteen days for sanction and payment of withdrawal from the fund. In case of emergencies like illness etc., the time limit maybe restricted to seven days,&amp;rdquo; the order said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the employees also do not have to furnish any documentary proof in support of their request to withdraw from GPF except for a self-declaration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all cases of withdrawal from the fund by the subscriber, the declared head of department (HOD) is competent to sanction withdrawal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No documentary proof will be required to be furnished by the subscriber. A simple declaration form by the subscriber explaining the reasons for withdrawal would be sufficient,&amp;rdquo; the order said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, withdrawal of up to 90 per cent of balance without assigning reasons is allowed for government servants who are due for retirement on superannuation within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is proposed that this may be allowed for up to two years before superannuation, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GPF can be withdrawn for purchase of motor car, motor cycle, scooter etc. or for repayment of loan already taken for the purpose, as per new rules issued by Ministry of Personnel, Public Grievances and Pensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount will also be made available for making deposit to book a car or motor cycle, besides their extensive repair or overhauling, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The withdrawal will also be allowed for housing including building or acquiring a suitable house or ready built flat, repayment of outstanding housing loan, purchase of house site for building a house, constructing a house on a site acquired, reconstructing or making additions on a house already acquired besides renovating, additions or alterations of ancestral house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is also decided do away with the present instructions which lay down that subsequent to the sale of house for which GPF withdrawal has been availed, the amount withdrawn has to be deposited back. GPF withdrawal for housing purpose will no longer be linked with the limits prescribed under House Building Advance (HBA) rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A subscriber may be permitted to avail the facility at any time during his service,&amp;rdquo; the new rules said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Justifies Penalty For Not Keeping Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-justifies-penalty-for-not-keeping-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-justifies-penalty-for-not-keeping-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI also said it has not received any &amp;ldquo;formal communication&amp;rdquo; from the government for re-considering the penalty and it will take a call &amp;ldquo;if something comes&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facing a backlash for levying penalty on non-maintenance of minimum balance in accounts, State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, on Wednesday justified its move saying the bank needs to impose some charges to balance the &amp;ldquo;burden&amp;rdquo; of managing a large number of no-frills Jan Dhan accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank also said it has not received any &amp;ldquo;formal communication&amp;rdquo; from the government for re-considering the penalty and it will take a call &amp;ldquo;if something comes&amp;rdquo;. It also clarified the penalty would not apply to Jan Dhan accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank decided to reintroduce penalty on non-maintenance of minimum balance in accounts and also revised charges on other banking services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new charges would be applicable from April 1. The move by the state-run banking major has faced a lot of criticism, including from the opposition parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Today, we have lot of burden such as we have 11 crore financial inclusion or Jan Dhan accounts. To manage such a large number of Jan Dhan accounts, we need some charges. We have considered many factors and after analysing carefully, we have taken this step,&amp;rdquo; State Bank of India chairperson Arundhati Bhattacharya told reporters here on the sidelines of a national convention of women entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the list of revised charges of SBI, failure to maintain monthly average balance (MAB) in accounts will attract a penalty of up to Rs 100 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In metropolitan areas, there will be a charge of Rs 100 plus service tax, if the balance falls below 75 per cent of the monthly average balance of Rs 5,000. If the shortfall is 50 per cent or less of the MAB, then the bank will charge Rs 50 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The charges and monthly average balance varies according to the location of bank. It is minimum in case of rural branches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms Bhattacharya said that all the banks have minimum balance requirement for account holders and SBI as such has the lowest minimum balance requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said the penalty was there earlier also and State Bank of India was the only bank to withdraw it in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our analysis have shown that most of the account holders maintain more than Rs 5,000 on a monthly basis and so they do not have to worry about any penalty,&amp;rdquo; Ms Bhattacharya said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She clarified that the penalty on non-maintenance of minimum balance will not be applicable on Jan Dhan accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked about the government&amp;rsquo;s direction to the bank to reconsider the decision, SBI managing director (national banking) Rajnish Kumar said the bank has not received any communication on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no formal communication. We will see if something comes,&amp;rdquo; Mr Kumar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the revised charges, withdrawal of cash from ATMs will attract a charge of up to Rs 20 if the number of transactions exceeds three from other bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs in a month and Rs 10 for more than five withdrawals from State Bank of India ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, SBI will not levy any charge on withdrawals from its own ATMs if the balance exceeds Rs 25,000. In case of withdrawal by its customers from ATMs of other banks, there will be no charge if the balance exceeds Rs 1 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are charging as people go to ATMs, withdraw cash and give it to somebody who in turns deposit it into the bank. This type of transaction involves a cost which is not known to public as bankers do not levy any charge on the customers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is some cost involved in printing cash, in transportation, counting and providing security to cash. The cost is borne by the tax payers. There is a cost in installing an ATM and so we feel the charges are very reasonable,&amp;rdquo; Ms Bhattacharya said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said the customers must use alternate channels like mobile, internet to do their transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We do not see there is a requirement for an household person to withdraw cash through ATMs for more than four times. Daily cash requirement is more for people doing businesses and we want them to use mobile and internet banking to do transactions,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While addressing the convention, Ms Bhattacharya said the bank so far has given loan worth to Rs 1,60,000 crore to the MSME sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This year alone we have done more than Rs 10,000 crore. We wish to do around Rs 16,000 crore of Mudra loans by the end of this financial year,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, nearly 55 per cent of the bank&amp;rsquo;s balance sheet comprises retail segment and balance is to large segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have no problem at all if I am able to tilt that more in favour of retail. I would love to do that. Of course large segment needs support because of that you would have the airports &amp;hellip; the roads you have today, for defence you are going to set up an SME and for that you need steel, cement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So, the large sector also needs support from the bank. But that does not mean that we (banks) are not there for you (retail segment),&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches. From the fifth transaction onwards, the customers will have to pay a minimum of Rs 150 per transaction (plus taxes and cess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Earlier, HDFC Bank savings account customers were offered five free transactions and the sixth transaction was charged at Rs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) HDFC Bank after December 30, 2016 reintroduced charges on cash transactions at branches after the deadline to deposit old currency notes ended. The charges were waived off after the government had announced a ban on high value currency notes on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) According to the revised norms which came into effect from March 1, from non-home branch, HDFC Bank customers can deposit/withdraw up to Rs 25,000 per day without any charge but any deposit/withdrawal from non-home branch above Rs 25,000 will attract charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess), whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) At the home branch of HDFC Bank, if the cumulative cash transactions (deposit/withdrawal) exceed Rs 2 lakh, a transaction charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess) whichever is higher will be levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For example, if a customer withdraws Rs 2 lakh from an account in four transactions and goes for another fifth transaction of Rs 50,000 from the home branch, then the customer will have to pay a charge of Rs 250. Thus, the charges apply only on the fifth transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) However, the charges for withdrawing money from automatic teller machines (ATMs) remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For senior citizens and minor accounts, the limit of Rs 25,000 per day will be applicable but the accounts will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) India&amp;rsquo;s biggest private sector bank ICICI Bank had reintroduced the cash transaction charges at bank branches from January 1, 2017. There will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while thereafter Rs 5 per Rs 1,000 would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150. The third party limit is Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Meanwhile, news agency Press Trust of India reported that another private sector lender Axis Bank has also started charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fds-to-cash-deposits-how-tax-department-is-tracking-your-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fds-to-cash-deposits-how-tax-department-is-tracking-your-transactions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Income tax authorities have set up an e-platform through which banks and other institutions can report the transactions to them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From bank deposits to credit card bill payments to property transactions, financial institutions and other entities have to report transactions above a certain threshold to the income tax department. A January 17 notification from the tax department lists the financial transactions that have to be reported. Income tax authorities have set up an e-platform through which banks and other institutions can report the transactions to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-key-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 key things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Banks have to report cash deposits aggregating to Rs 10 lakh or more in a financial year, in one or more accounts (other than a current account and fixed deposit) of a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Fixed deposits other than renewals of a person aggregating to Rs 10 lakh or more of a person in a financial year have to be also reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Cash payments of Rs 1 lakh or more for credit card bills have to be reported. Also to be reported is payment of Rs 10 lakh or more made by any mode (including cheque or wire transfer) to settle credit card dues in a financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) The tax department also reiterated its November 2016 instruction asking banks to report all cash deposits of Rs 2.5 lakh or more made in one or more accounts of a person during November 9 to December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) For current accounts, banks have to report deposits of Rs 12.5 lakh or more during the period. After demonetisation of old 500 and 1,000 rupee notes, the government had allowed the junked currency to be deposited in bank accounts during a 50-day window ending December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Cash deposits during April 1, 2016, to November 9, 2016 in any account that are reportable should also be intimated to the tax authorities by January 31, 2017, the notification said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Companies or institutions have to report receipt from any person an amount aggregating to Rs 10 lakh or more in a financial year for acquiring bonds or debentures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) A similar limit is also set for reporting purchase of mutual funds units or buyback of shares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Purchase of foreign exchange including travellers cheque and a forex card aggregating to Rs 10 lakh will have to be reported to tax authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*10) Property registrars will have to report to tax authorities purchase or sale by any person of immovable property for an amount of Rs 30 lakh or more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing Of Rs 2000 Notes Started In August 2016, Says RTI Query</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/printing-of-rs-2000-note-started-in-august-2016-says-rti-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/printing-of-rs-2000-note-started-in-august-2016-says-rti-query/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BRBNMPL stopped printing the old Rs 500 note on October 27 while the printing of the Rs 1,000 note ceased earlier, on July 28 last year, the reply said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharatiya Reserve Bank Note Mudran Private Limited (BRBNMPL), an RBI subsidiary, started printing the Rs 2000 notes two and a half months before the November 8 demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A reply from BRBNMPL to my query under the Right To Information Act said the printing of Rs 2000 notes began on August 22, 2016, while printing of the new Rs 500 notes began on November 23, 2016,&amp;rdquo; said Chandrashekhar Gaud, resident of Neemuch district of Madhya Pradesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRBNMPL stopped printing the old Rs 500 note on October 27 while the printing of the Rs 1,000 note ceased earlier, on July 28 last year, the reply said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘what is BHIM’ to ‘what are the benefits’, here are top 5 FAQs answered</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whether India has really adopted digital or not would only be clear once data for the coming months is released, but what can be said with certainty is that there are enough avenues available if one wants to go digital.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While pre-demonetisation, the government had launched UPI and other services, post this it has rolled out BHIM and BharatQR, and is expected to launch AadhaarPay. In fact, PM Modi in Mann-ki-Baat lauded the initiative to go digital, urging the youth to teach BHIM transfers to 125 people commemorating the 125th anniversary of Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-bhim&#34;&gt;What is BHIM?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM or Bharat Interface for Money is an app available both on iOS and Playstore. Built on the UPI platform, it operates much like a wallet, allowing transfer of money via input of mobile number or virtual address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-operate-it&#34;&gt;How to operate it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to have Aadhaar linked to your bank account to use BHIM. Once that is done, BHIM asks you to set a password. And, then you can select your bank. If you don’t have m-pin, entering last 6 digits of debit card and expiry can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;are-people-using-it&#34;&gt;Are people using it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per latest data, BHIM has 17 million downloads with 7 million active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-the-benefits&#34;&gt;What are the benefits?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i. Supported by NPCI, which operates IMPS and UPI, BHIM is safe.
ii. Moreover, unlike wallet, BHIM does not require frequent recharges.
iii. It also supports QR code much like PayTM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-else-can-you-use&#34;&gt;What else can you use?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also BharatQR now, which is an interoperable QR code,i.e., if you have Visa and merchant has Mastercard you can use BharatQR to make payment, which you couldn’t do earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govt will also be launching AadhaarPay soon which will allow fingerprint-based payments. For this you would not even need your phone; if the merchant has a smartphone, he will just use a fingerprint scanner and confirm your bank to authorise payments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PM Modi:Digital Payment Can Check Black Money, Graft</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payment-can-check-black-money-graft-pm-modi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payment-can-check-black-money-graft-pm-modi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Addressing his monthly &amp;lsquo;Mann ki baat&amp;rsquo; radio programme, he said people, especially the youth, should become ambassadors of digital payment schemes rolled out by the government.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital payment can check black money and play a key role in fighting graft, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said today as he asked the youth to become an &amp;ldquo;anti-corruption cadre&amp;rdquo; as part of the &amp;ldquo;cleanliness&amp;rdquo; drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing his monthly &amp;lsquo;Mann ki baat&amp;rsquo; radio programme, he said people, especially the youth, should become ambassadors of digital payment schemes rolled out by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lead this movement. Take it further as it has a very major and prominent role in the fight against corruption and black money. To me, each and every individual involved in this mission constitutes a new anti-corruption cadre in the country. In a way you are a soldier in the cause of cleanliness and purity,&amp;rdquo; the Prime Minister said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said gradually people are &amp;ldquo;shedding their hard currency mindset&amp;rdquo; and moving towards digital currency and the youth are leading the way using their mobile phones as the new tool to make and receive payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last two months, 10 lakh people have been rewarded, over 50,000 traders have won prizes and an amount of over Rs 150 crore has been earned as prize money by people who have promoted and carried forward the digital payment campaign, PM Modi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the digital payment schemes will complete 100 days on April 14, the 126th birth anniversary of B R Amdedkar and people should help 125 people download the Bhim application on their mobile phone for digital transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referring to his favourite Swachh Bharat campaign, he said &amp;ldquo;psychological barrier&amp;rdquo; should not come in the way even while cleaning toilets. Some senior bureaucrats had recently demonstrated on how to clean a &amp;lsquo;twin pit&amp;rsquo; toilet, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They also displayed as to how convenient these new technique toilets are and that there is absolutely no inconvenience and there should be no hesitation in emptying or cleaning these toilets and even the psychological barrier should not come in the way at all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PM Modi also used the opportunity to congratulate &amp;lsquo;divyang&amp;rsquo; (physically challenged) players for defeating Pakistan in the final of the Blind T-20 World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referring to the role of women, he said be it the field of sports or space science, they lag behind in none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;Beti Bachao, Beti Padhao&amp;rsquo; programme is no longer just a government programme, but has become a campaign of societal empathy and public education, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This, I believe, is a healthy sign,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Government App To Provide Updates To Taxpayers On GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-app-to-provide-updates-to-taxpayers-on-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-app-to-provide-updates-to-taxpayers-on-gst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The app will also provide Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs) on GST and help desk/email contacts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Finance Ministry today launched a mobile app for Goods and Services Tax so as to provide updates to taxpayers on the new tax regime which is to be rolled out from July 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minister of State for Finance Santosh Gangwar said the Centre and states are in the final lap of discussions for the implementation of GST which will usher in &amp;lsquo;one-nation one-tax&amp;rsquo; regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;GST discussion is in final stages and GST will be implemented within the given time-frame,&amp;rdquo; he told reporters on the sidelines of Central Excise Day event here. The GST mobile app launched by the ministry can be downloaded for free on Android platforms. The iOS version will be made available shortly, an official statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the app, the taxpayers can readily access a host of GST information such as migration to  GST-approach and guidelines for migration, draft law-Model GST Law, IGST Law and GST Compensation Law, draft rules related to registration, returns, payment, refund and invoice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app will also provide Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs) on GST and help desk/email contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Mobile Application enables taxpayers to be well informed of the latest updates on GST. Taxpayers can also provide feedback and contact CBEC&amp;rsquo;s 24x7 help desk &amp;lsquo;CBEC Mitra&amp;rsquo; through a toll-free number or email, at the touch of a button,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indirect tax reform GST will subsume excise and service tax and will ensure uniform tax rates across the country for seamless transfer of goods and services. The government plans to implement GST from July 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>