<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.
DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.
HIGHLIGHTS  The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions  India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.
HIGHLIGHTS  Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1 The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent  The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Not Mandatory For Insurance, Says IRDAI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-for-insurance-says-irdai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-mandatory-for-insurance-says-irdai/</guid>
      <description>Aadhar is not mandatory for the (insurance) sector but is the most simple one, IRDAI, the insurance sector regulator said.
Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (IRDAI) today said though Aadhar is not a mandatory requirement for Know Your Customer (KYC) in the insurance sector, it is the most simple form of KYC document.
&amp;ldquo;Aadhar is not mandatory for the (insurance) sector but is the most simple one. On the government level they are creating a platform for all the KYC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data hack: IIT Kharagpur graduate arrested, earns Rs 40 lakh a year at Ola</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</guid>
      <description>An IIT Kharagpur graduate, Abhinav Srivastava, who allegedly hacked Aadhaar data has been arrested by Bengaluru Police. According to investigation, Srivastava had gained access to the repository of the Unique Identification Development Authority of India’s (UIDAI) Aadhaar project through the Digital India e-hospital portal. The 31-year-old hails from Uttar Pradesh and was arrested in connection with a complaint filed by the UIDAI on July 26, according to Indian Express.
Police said the complaint against Srivastava stated that he accessed UIDAI data without authorisation between January 1 and July 26 for an app called ‘eKYC Verification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data leak: Now govt agencies will safeguard your personal info</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-leak-now-govt-agencies-will-safeguard-personal-info/</guid>
      <description>The linking of Aadhaar — the 12-digit unique identification number for Indian residents is about to become safer as new rules put the onus on government departments and agencies to safeguard personal data or information held by them.
Departments handling the data will have to ensure that end-users are made aware of the data usage and collection and their consent is taken either in writing or electronically, according to new guidelines issued by the government for security of personal data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Notes Ban, 18 Lakh Cases Of Income, Bank Account Mismatches Detected: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</guid>
      <description>Government authorities have detected 18 lakh cases after demonetisation where the income profiles of people do not match their account profile, the Lok Sabha was informed today. Preliminary information has been sought from such people and many have responded. Those who have not given details would be issued with notices as per procedure, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said during Question Hour.
Responding to supplementaries, he said there was an extended footprint of digitisation in the banking sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM
Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.
To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Balance Account </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-mahindra-bank-launches-debit-card-offer-for-zero-balance-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-mahindra-bank-launches-debit-card-offer-for-zero-balance-account/</guid>
      <description>Private sector Kotak Mahindra Bank today said it will offer debit card at a special price of Rs 99 for the first year for customers who will open account under its zero balance account scheme till September 15.
The usual annual fee for debit card procured by 811 account holders (zero balance) is Rs 299.
The name 811, inspired by November 8, 2016, decision of demonetisation, allows customers to open a zero balance account using the bank&amp;rsquo;s mobile application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>