<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank. Some banks like SBI also allow customers to link their Aadhaar number to their bank account at an ATM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are different easy ways through which you can update your aadhaar number in your bank account without having to visit your bank branch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To link your Aadhaar to your bank account online:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to the internet banking service of your bank.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the &amp;ldquo;Update Aadhar Card Details&amp;rdquo; option or &amp;ldquo;Aadhaar Card Seeding&amp;rdquo; option and click on it. On clicking, you will be directed to another page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your Aadhaar card number and click on Submit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The last 2 digits of registered mobile number (non-editable) will be displayed to the customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank will communicate the status of the linking to Customer&amp;rsquo;s registered mobile number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To link your Aadhaar card to your bank account though SMS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your mobile number is registered with the Bank, then you can link your Aadhaar number to your bank account through SMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you are an SBI customer send SMS to 567676 in the following format: UID(space)Aadhaar number(space)Account number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the mobile number is not registered or in case the Aadhaar is already linked to Account, an SMS reply will be sent to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your mobile number is registered with the Bank, you will receive an SMS confirmation of the seeding request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many banks are yet to offer the option of linking Aadhaar to bank account through SMS,  so do check through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;your bank’s customer helpline if this option is available.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To link your Aadhaar card to your bank account from an ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some banks like SBI offer an option for seeding Aadhaar from an ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After swiping the ATM card and entering your PIN, Select the menu &amp;ldquo;Service – Registrations&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this menu, select Aadhaar Registration (or Inquiry as per your need)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select the Account type (Savings/Checking) after which you will be asked to enter your Aadhaar number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Facility Launched To Link Aadhaar With PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax Department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing income tax returns (ITRs) now. The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals. The link requires a person to punch in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact name as given in the Aadhaar
card&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number and email of the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It urged them to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linking without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no need to login or be registered on e-filing website (of the I-T department). This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for a permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 crore Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4GB Data Per Day For Rs 444</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;State-run telecom firm BSNL today increased per day data offering to 4GB at 3G speeds under a new prepaid mobile scheme priced at Rs 444 with 90 days validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) has introduced &amp;lsquo;BSNL Chaukka - 444&amp;rsquo;, a new STV, for truly unlimited data for 90 days as special promotional offer under prepaid mobile services,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the highest per day data limit being offered by any telecom operator in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the scheme, one gigabyte of 3G mobile data will cost less than a rupee &amp;ndash; the lowest in the sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are committed to provide affordable and efficient services to all segment of our mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL Director for consumer mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s competitors in the market are offering up to 2GB of mobile broadband per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the new STV-444 &amp;lsquo;BSNL Chaukka&amp;rsquo; of Rs 444 truly unlimited data with 4 GB data/day with validity of 90 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new offer follows BSNL&amp;rsquo;s unlimited data offer &amp;lsquo;Triple ACE&amp;rsquo; special tariff voucher of Rs 333 in which it offered customers 3 GB data per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange old notes for new at a premium</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scrapped old notes ­ Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 ­ which were to be exchanged latest by December 20, 2016, are still there. They can be exchanged even now, but for a hefty premium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-Resident Indians (NRIs), who were allowed to exchange old notes till June 30 this year, are being offered a handsome commission for exchanging these notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The going rate for exchanging old notes is Rs 9 on every Rs 100, so if you want to exchange Rs 1 crore in old notes, then you would get back Rs 9 lakh in new notes,&amp;rdquo; said Pravin (name changed), who is involved in this trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked why anyone would want to pay Rs 1 crore and get Rs 9 lakh, Pravin said, &amp;ldquo;These are people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to show the government their source of funds. It&amp;rsquo;s not about taking a hit on their current cash. Those who have not declared are the ones who feel their future source of income would also be exposed before the tax authorities,&amp;rdquo; said Pravin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that after they collect their 1 per cent commission, they pass on the old notes to NRIs. &amp;ldquo;NRIs have approached us and for a crore of old notes, we ask them to give us Rs 10 lakh in new notes. This is how the trade is going on,&amp;rdquo; said Pravin. For a crore, we get a commission of Rs 50,000 to Rs 1 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He reckons that while the RBI deadline is June 30, they will stop the trade by June 25, as it would be a huge risk to carry on after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, Thane police nabbed three people who were trying to exchange Rs 1 crore in old notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyderabad police too caught a businessman with Rs 3.48 crore old notes a couple of days back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ET spoke to others involved in the trade and they confirmed that old notes were still being ex changed and the premium was Rs 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior RBI officials confirmed that they have heard of the ex change of banned notes through illegal means, but added that it was not in their jurisdiction to keep a tab on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They are exchanging notes with NRIs and submitting absolutely foolproof documents,&amp;rdquo; said an RBI official. RBI did not respond to an email sent by ET seeking comments. On January 2, RBI said NRIs will be provided the facility to exchange banned notes at five offices ­ in Mumbai, Delhi, Chennai, Kolkata and Nagpur - till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exchange limit for NRIs as per FEMA (Foreign Exchange Management Act) regulations is Rs 25,000 per person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time, while issuing the circular, RBI had said no thirdparty tender will be accepted under the facility. On fulfilment of the terms and conditions and the genuineness of the notes tendered, admissible amount will be credited to the tenderer&amp;rsquo;s KYC (know your customer) compliant bank account, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation To Launch RuPay Credit Card Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Payments Corporation of India has forayed in to the credit card business and would make the commercial launch of its RuPay credit card &amp;ldquo;in a month&amp;rsquo;s time,&amp;rdquo; a top official said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe in a month&amp;rsquo;s time we will be able to make the commercial launch (of RuPay credit card),&amp;rdquo; NPCI Chairman M Balachandran told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI, which currently offers RuPay debit cards, has partnered with 10 banks including public sector and cooperative banks, to make the pilot launch of the &amp;ldquo;RuPay Credit Card&amp;rdquo;, Balachandran said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI had launched its debit card RuPay in April 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are all set for launching the credit card version of RuPay card. We have been undertaking more than 300 different workshops as part of the launch campaign,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving some statistics, he said compared to 775 million debit cards operating in the domestic market, there were 25 million credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RuPay credit card would be offered in four variants including a high end card that would offer insurance for upto Rs 10 lakh, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On future launches planned by the Corporation, he said NPCI would launch &amp;ldquo;tap and go&amp;rdquo; card that would be used to travel in Kochi Metro project scheduled to be inaugurated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on June 17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will simultaneously be launching a similar card for the BMTC (Bengaluru Metropolitan Transport Corporation) in Bengaluru on that day itself,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PM insurance schemes on June 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY) were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must have heard about the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY), which were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner. While the first is a life insurance scheme, the other is an accidental cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already enrolled yourself under these schemes and want the cover to continue, then the premium will be auto debited from your account on June 1. You might also have received an SMS from your bank in this respect. However, if you have still not done this and want to go for the schemes, then you can enrol for these schemes on June 1 to get their full benefit as the schemes provide coverage for one-year period from June 1 to May 31. You can go for these schemes anytime during the year, but will have to pay the same premium. So, why to delay? Why not to get enrolled from Day 1?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how these schemes work:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana is a one-year life insurance scheme, which is annually renewable. The scheme provides coverage of Rs 2 lakh for death owing to any reason and is offered to all saving bank account holders in the age group of 18 to 50 years at the annual premium of only Rs 330.
The date of commencement of insurance cover under this scheme is the date of debit of premium from the insured member’s account for joining the scheme and the insurance cover is provided up to May 31 of the subsequent year. However, the risk is not covered for new members during the first 45 days from the date of enrollment into the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover is automatically renewed on June 1 of every year by debiting the premium from the member’s bank account. In case anyone wishes to join the scheme thereafter, one can do so by paying the full year’s premium and submitting the requisite documents.
According to the information provided by the government, as on April 12, 2017, Cumulative Gross enrolment reported by banks subject to verification of eligibility, etc. was about 3.1 crore under PMJJBY. A total of 63291 claims were registered under this scheme, of which 59770 have been disbursed.
Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana is a one-year accident insurance, which can be renewed annually. Under this scheme, accidental death and full disability cover of Rs 2 lakh and partial disability cover of Rs 1 lakh is offered on account of an accident to all saving bank account holders in the age group of 18 to 70 years for a premium of Rs 12 per annum. If you subscribe for this scheme, then the premium will directly auto-debited by the bank from your account.
As on April 12, 2017, cumulative gross enrolment reported by banks subject to verification of eligibility, etc. was about 10 crore under PMSBY. A total of 12816 claims were registered under PMSBY, of which 9646 have been disbursed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh. In the present scenario where bank interest rates are on a falling trend, financial planners say that equity mutual funds are one of the best instruments to accumulate long-term savings through systematic investment plan (SIP). Gains from equity mutual funds after a year are tax-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, fund selection is one of the most difficult things to do for a retail investor as it needs lot of research. Financial planners say diversified equity funds are the best to invest through SIP for long term. Here are some funds which have generates over 20 per cent CAGR return in past 20 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Equity Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on January 1, 1995, it is one of the oldest and best performing funds in India. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.95 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 23.56 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This fund has generated a CAGR return of 23.68 per cent since its inception. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998 would have helped you accumulate a corpus of Rs. 2.12 crore by April 1, 2017 implying 17.66 times return in 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;Franklin India Prima Fund:&lt;/em&gt; It is one of the flagship fund of Franklin Templeton India. Since its inception in December 1993, it has generated a CAGR return of 21.04 per cent till now. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 2.38 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 25.11 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Vision Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on October 8, 1995, it has generated a CAGR return of 19.92 per cent till now. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998, would have become Rs. 1.46 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Top 200 Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This flagship fund of HDFC Mutual Fund has generated a CAGR return of 20.88 per cent since its inception in September 1996. If you would have started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.43 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With falling return on bank fixed deposits, equity mutual funds are witnessing increased investment from retail investors now. Equity and equity-linked schemes have seen inflows of more than Rs. 70,000 crore in last financial year according to Association of Mutual Funds in India data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI Launches Three New Mobile Apps For Voice, Data Quality Tracking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aiming to protect consumer interests, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Monday launched three new mobile applications and a web portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring. The app will help mobile phone users rate their experience about voice call quality in real time and help TRAI gather customer experience data along with network data, an official TRAI statement said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is available on Google Playstore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulator has launched new version of TRAI MySpeed App that will enable the regulator to obtain test-driven data from users in all service areas, without any action by the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These tests would be brief, very infrequent for a specific device, free to the user and anonymous. The user may also do a test and submit the results, as before,&amp;rdquo; the regulator said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also launched DND 2.0 App (Do Not Disturb) Services App that will help smartphone users to register their mobile number under DND to avoid unsolicited commercial communication/ telemarketing calls/ SMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, TRAI has also launched a new website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-Aadhaar as ID proof in Railways</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After receiving several requests from passengers, Railway has agreed to accept e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class. Earlier only printed version was considered as a valid ID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to railway ministry, the issue regarding acceptance of e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class was being raised at various foras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the matter was examined in consultation with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The authority has specified that as per Section 4(3) of Aadhaar Act, 2016, an Aadhaar number in physical or electronic form subject to authentication and other conditions, may be accepted as proof of identity of the Aadhaar number holder for any purpose,” said an order issued by railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railway has now decided that downloaded Aadhaar is a legally valid proof of identity under Section 4(3) of the Aadhaar Act along with the printed version of the card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In view of the above, it has been decided to incorporate downloaded Aadhaar (e-Aadhaar) also as prescribed proof of identity at par with printed Aahaar card in the list of prescribed proofs of identity which are valid for undertaking journey in any reserved class,” said the order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are ten recognised documents which are accepted by railways as proof of identity during journey for travellers. While printed Aadhaar was accepted but downloaded version was not considered valid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘what is BHIM’ to ‘what are the benefits’, here are top 5 FAQs answered</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whether India has really adopted digital or not would only be clear once data for the coming months is released, but what can be said with certainty is that there are enough avenues available if one wants to go digital.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While pre-demonetisation, the government had launched UPI and other services, post this it has rolled out BHIM and BharatQR, and is expected to launch AadhaarPay. In fact, PM Modi in Mann-ki-Baat lauded the initiative to go digital, urging the youth to teach BHIM transfers to 125 people commemorating the 125th anniversary of Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-bhim&#34;&gt;What is BHIM?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM or Bharat Interface for Money is an app available both on iOS and Playstore. Built on the UPI platform, it operates much like a wallet, allowing transfer of money via input of mobile number or virtual address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-operate-it&#34;&gt;How to operate it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to have Aadhaar linked to your bank account to use BHIM. Once that is done, BHIM asks you to set a password. And, then you can select your bank. If you don’t have m-pin, entering last 6 digits of debit card and expiry can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;are-people-using-it&#34;&gt;Are people using it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per latest data, BHIM has 17 million downloads with 7 million active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-the-benefits&#34;&gt;What are the benefits?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i. Supported by NPCI, which operates IMPS and UPI, BHIM is safe.
ii. Moreover, unlike wallet, BHIM does not require frequent recharges.
iii. It also supports QR code much like PayTM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-else-can-you-use&#34;&gt;What else can you use?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also BharatQR now, which is an interoperable QR code,i.e., if you have Visa and merchant has Mastercard you can use BharatQR to make payment, which you couldn’t do earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govt will also be launching AadhaarPay soon which will allow fingerprint-based payments. For this you would not even need your phone; if the merchant has a smartphone, he will just use a fingerprint scanner and confirm your bank to authorise payments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio’s new plans offer 100% cashback on JioFi on exchange of old dongle, datacard, routers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio has launched a 100% cashback offer with JioFi 4G router, as the Mukesh Ambani-owned tries to attract users of dongles, datacard and wifi routers offered by rival telcos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has come up with two plans where as part of the first plan, users will get a 100% exchange offer where they’ll be required to exchange their existing datacard, dongle or hotspot router at any Jio Digital store or Jio Care store and will get 4G data worth Rs 2010 against the device exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customers will have to pay Rs 1999 to get the JioFi router and will have to do a mandatory first recharge of Rs 408 which is Rs309 for the plan – which ensures freebies for 84 days - and Rs99 for a Jio Prime membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the customer pays Rs 1999 minus the Rs 2010 worth 4G data which translates into zero cost for the customer and the device with internet connection becomes almost free. However, the Rs 408 mandatory recharge is the additional cost which the user will have to pay in order to avail the services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the second plan, users get JioFi at Rs 1999 after a first mandatory recharge of Rs 408 (Rs309 + Rs99) but they get 4G data worth Rs 1005 which translates to the effective cost of Rs 994 (Rs1999 - Rs1005). Users need not exchange their existing data connections for this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first plan is ideal for all existing dongle users whereas the second plan is ideal for laptop users, 2G/3G phone users and tablet users, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Queries addressed to Jio for the new plans went unanswered till the press time. Reliance Retail currently has four JioFi devices running in the market namely JioFi 1 Router, JioFi 2 Router, JioFi 3 Router, JioFi 4 Dongle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the first plan, the telco is trying to capture the market of rival telcos offering dongles, datacard and wifi routers, since the exchange scheme will encourage existing dongle users to shift to Jio’s services, say experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They added that by offering free data in the second plan to the first time users or users that are willing to keep multiple connections, the telco is looking to expand the subscriber-base for its JioFi routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIL’s retail arm namely Reliance Retail sold 2.6 million LYF and JioFi devices during the last quarter and nearly 10 million units in the financial year, and is further looking to accelerate the sales with the launch of new JioFi plans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>