<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Price Wars: Airtel, Vodafone, Idea Offers To Rival Jio&#39;s Dhan Dhana Dhan Offer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-price-wars-airtel-vodafone-idea-offers-to-rival-jios-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/telecom-price-wars-airtel-vodafone-idea-offers-to-rival-jios-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio again disrupted the voice calls and internet data tariffs after it decided to withdraw its &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. The company after withdrawing the &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; plan earlier this week launched  a new scheme called &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo;, offering &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs. 309. In response to the  &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer other telecom players like Bharti Airtel,Idea Cellular and Vodafone have also come out with special recharge plans offering their customers free voice calls and high speed 4G internet. Recent reports also suggest that Airtel and Vodafone have done away with roaming charges to counter  Jio&amp;rsquo;s free domestic roaming policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some recharge plans released in the past few days to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 399 plan:&lt;/em&gt; Under this plan, cutomers will get 1 GB of high speed 4G internet data along with 300 minutes of calling per day for Airtel to Airtel customers (1,200 minutes per week) and 3,000 minutes of local and STD calling for 70 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; In this plan customers will get 2 GB of 4G high speed internet for 28 days along with 300 minutes per day of Airtel to Airtel calling (1,200 minutes per week).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; In this plan, customers will get 1 GB of 4G internet per day along with 300 minutes of Airtel to Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for week for 70 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; Select customers can use 1GB data per day for 56 days along with unlimited and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea Rs. 351 Plan:&lt;/em&gt; Idea is offering unlimited local and STD calls and unlimited 3G/2G data per day for 4G handsets for 28 days and this recharge can be done by visiting Idea store.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 30 Link bank accounts to Aadhaar : I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-bank-accounts-aadhaar-april-30-t-department/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-bank-accounts-aadhaar-april-30-t-department/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accounts opened from July 2014 to August, 2015 will have to submit know your customer (KYC) details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tax officials said that the accounts would include banks, insurance, stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account holders will also have to mention their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounts opened from July 2014 to August, 2015 will have to submit know your customer (KYC) details and their Aadhaar number to banks and financial institutions+ by April 30 and self-certify them to comply with FATCA regulations(Foreign Tax Compliance Act), the tax department said on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the account holders are unable to furnish details and provide self-certification by the new deadline, banks and financial institutions have the option ofblocking the accounts+ .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the details are furnished they can operate the accounts. The provision applies to accounts which come under the ambit of FATCA regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks and financial institutions were asked to obtain self-certification and carry out due diligence for all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015 to comply with the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act(FATCA) pact signed by India and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July 2015, India and the US signed a tax information sharing agreement under a new US law, FATCA, aimed at bolstering efforts for automatic exchange of financial information between the two nations about tax evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,” the tax department said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax officials said that the accounts would include banks, insurance, stocks. Account holders will also have to mention their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto, Health Insurance To Cost More As Regulator Okays Raise For Agents</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Car, motorcycle and health insurance will cost more from April 1 with regulator Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority (IRDAI) giving go-ahead to insurers for revision in commission for agents. The change in premium after modification will be limited to around 5 per cent of the existing rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase will be in addition to the enhanced third party motor insurance rates, which too will come into affect from April. The IRDAI (Payment of Commission or Remuneration or Reward to Insurance Agents and Insurance Intermediaries) Regulations, 2016 comes into effect from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulations, the regulator said, bring about certain revisions in commission/ remuneration rates and also introduce the reward system. These may trigger insurers to revisit the pricing of their products in so far as the costing input relating to commission or remuneration is concerned, said IRDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the change in premium due to the new regulations should be &amp;ldquo;limited to +/- 5 per cent of the existing premium rates of products/add-ons&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, insurers will have to give a certificate that there is &amp;ldquo;no detrimental change&amp;rdquo; in premium rates or any other provision of policies already sold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuts in Insurance Premiums On Larger Cars, Bikes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/irdai-cuts-insurance-premiums-on-larger-cars-bikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/irdai-cuts-insurance-premiums-on-larger-cars-bikes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As per the revised list, premium on mid-segment cars(1,000cc - 1,500 cc) has been reduced to Rs. 2,863 from Rs3,132 announced on March 28.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insurance sector regulator Irdai today reduced motor insurance premium rates in most of the segments like two-wheelers, cars and trucks by modifying the rates for 2017-18 issued three-weeks ago. The modified &amp;lsquo;premium rates for motor third party liability insurance cover&amp;rsquo; will apply retrospectively from April 1, the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (Irdai) said in an order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the premium rates for the current fiscal are higher than those of the previous year. As per the revised list, premium on mid-segment cars (1,000cc - 1,500 cc) has been reduced to Rs 2,863 from Rs 3,132 announced on March 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, premium for cars with engine capacity of more than 1,500 cc has been brought down to Rs 7,890 from earlier Rs 8,630.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no change in cars having engine capacity of less than 1,000 cc. The premium has been fixed at Rs 2,055. Similarly, premium has been brought down in case of two-wheelers with engine of 150 cc and more. Irdai further said premium rates have been reduced for most of the truck categories. The new rate, for instance, in case of &amp;lsquo;goods carrying vehicles public carriers (exceeding 40,000 kg)&amp;rsquo; has been reduced to Rs 33,024 from Rs 36,120 notified on March 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduction has been also affected for e-rickshaw and other passenger carrying vehicles. Modification in premium rates follows protest by a section of truckers against the Irdai&amp;rsquo;s move to substantially
hike insurance rates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-based payment modes work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government is planning to utilise the Aadhaar database to give shape to a digital future and utilise it for payments, and authentication of transactions is the key to its success. While Unified Payments Interface and BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) are processes for peer-to-peer transactions using smartphones, the government is promoting Aadhaar-enabled payment systems for the non-smartphone savvy. As per sources it is planning to launch Aadhaar Pay on April 14. ET looks into the different forms of Aadhaar payment modes being developed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems?
Payments that can be done with the help of au thentication and identi fication through the Aadhaar database is referred to as the Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems (AEPS). This is the new form of pay ment that is being pro moted by the govern ment to push for digital payments instead of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the major types of Aadhaar Enabled Payments?
The first type of payment is Aadhaar Bridge Payment System which is meant for direct bene fit transfer and subsidy payments from the gov ernment to the benefi ciaries. The second is AEPS which is used at the level of the business correspondent or `bank mitras’ where bank customers can use Aadhaar to access various services like cash withdrawal, account opening and fund transfer even without going to a bank branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is Aadhaar Pay wherein merchants can accept payments through Aadhaar identification of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we need Aadhaar Enabled payments?
These forms of payments are be ing promoted by the government specifically for the under privileged sections of the society and the rural poor who are not comfortable using cards or mobile wallets for payments.Instead of a mobile phone or a plastic card, in these forms of payments, the mode of authentication becomes the Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who runs the systems?
National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is the nodal authority for all Aadhaar-enabled payments in collaboration with banks. The payment company is trying to get as many banks to seed their customers’ accounts with their Aadhaar number so that payments can flow smoothly .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do the different forms of payments work?
Aahdaar Bridge Payment (ABPS):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant for recur ring payments done by the government to its customers for various subsidies as well as direct benefit transfer. Here the beneficiary is identified through an Aadhaar number, then NPCI manages an Aadhaar Mapper where the Aadhaar number is mapped to a specific bank account and the money flows to the connected bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-enabled-payment-aeps&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Payment (AEPS):&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the customer has to approach a business correspondent (BC), use his Aadhaar number and biometrics which the BC shares with NPCI, which checks the ID with UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India) to confirm the customer’s identity . It also checks the funds in the connected account and allows the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for merchant payments where the merchant will download the merchant payments app of his bank, authenticate the customer through his biometrics and Aadhaar number and initiate a pull transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs 333: BSNL Takes On Jio With New Prepaid Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnl-takes-on-jio-with-new-prepaid-offers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnl-takes-on-jio-with-new-prepaid-offers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special tariff voucher &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo;, priced at Rs. 349, comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive tariffs, BSNL has launched prepaid plans priced from Rs 333, under which it is offering 3GB of 3G data per day for up to three months. As part of its revised Rs 339 plan, BSNL is also offering 3GB of high speed data per day. &amp;ldquo;#BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new 333 &amp;amp; 339 STV&amp;rsquo;s offer there is nothing better than this!&amp;rdquo; state-run telecom company BSNL said on site Twitter. New entrant Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing has given rise to a highly competitive Indian telecom market, pushing incumbent players to revise their existing offerings to protect market share, some analysts say. &amp;ldquo;The price war in the Rs 1.5-trillion wireless telecom market will continue this fiscal year as well leaving bruised bottom lines,&amp;rdquo; Crisil&amp;rsquo;s said in a note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333 special tariff voucher, called &amp;ldquo;Triple ACE&amp;rdquo;, comes with a validity of three months and offers 3GB of 3G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-of-the-other-offerings-by-bsnl&#34;&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 339&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL users subscribing to the Rs 339 voucher will now get 3 GB of 3G data, which is high-speed data, per day, instead of 2 GB earlier. The Rs 339 plan - which comes with a validity of 28 days - includes unlimited local and STD BSNL-to-BSNL calls and 25 minutes of local and inter-circle calls made to other networks, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special tariff voucher &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo;, priced at Rs. 349, comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs. 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all four plans - &lt;em&gt;Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 395 and Rs 375&lt;/em&gt;, the internet or data speed is reduced to 80 Kbps after a subscriber exhausts the daily 3G limit, BSNL has said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60% People Facing Frequent Call Drops: Telecom Department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/facing-frequent-call-drops-telecom-department-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/facing-frequent-call-drops-telecom-department-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Out of 3.56 lakh subscribers surveyed across telecom service providers, 2.15 lakh (about 60 per cent) complained about frequent call drops.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 60 per cent people are still facing frequent call drops, with most of them experiencing problem indoors, found a survey by the Department of Telecom (DoT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of 3.56 lakh subscribers surveyed across telecom service providers, 2.15 lakh (about 60 per cent) complained about frequent call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DoT, however, made 26.97 lakh calls to subscribers of various telecom operators in the country, out of which only 3.56 lakh subscribers (about 13 per cent) participated in the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department also claimed that overall call drops have come down by 7 per cent in three months between December 2016 to March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Remaining 87 per cent subscribers, who did not participate, were either not willing or did not have problem of frequent call drops&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; the DoT said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the feedback, the DoT observed that the complaint is &amp;ldquo;mostly indoors&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback is shared with the telecom service providers (TSPs) to take corrective action in a time-bound manner and submit the action taken report (ATR) to DoT Task Force every fortnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;TSPs contact each subscriber, who has reported frequent call drops, through telephonic calls and SMS in English and local languages to collect further details required for resolution of the complaint,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On cumulative basis, since launch of Interactive Voice Response System (IVRS), telecom operators have resolved 13,631 cases related to the call drop issue and also resolved another 7,975 which were reported as frequent call drops but were found to be having other issues related to data, roaming, billing, MNP, mobile device etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of these, 1,406 cases were resolved through optimisation, rectifying hardware or power problems, through field visits etc during the fortnight March 15-31, 2017, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The call drops reported by subscribers have dropped from 64 per cent in December 2016 to 57 per cent at the end of March 2017, a drop of nearly 7 per cent in 3 months,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DoT said the government has facilitated telecom operators to identify black spots and plan new sites or infrastructure to improve their services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operators have planned 987 new sites and boosters out of which 109 have been already installed and commissioned, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At 110 Crore GB Data Traffic A Month, Jio&#39;s Offers For Its Prepaid Users</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a number of recharge options to prepaid subscribers under its paid Prime service. Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website. Jio has become the largest network globally with more than 110 crore GB of data traffic per month and 220 crore voice and video minutes a day, Reliance Industries said in a statement while reporting the group&amp;rsquo;s earnings for financial year 2016-17. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mr Ambani said in the statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All recharges under Jio Prime include free voice call and roaming benefits. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at Jio&amp;rsquo;s various data offerings under its latest recharge options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Rs 19 _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 19 recharge comes with a validity of one day and includes 200 MB of 4G, or high speed, data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 49&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits on offer under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 49 pack include 600 MB of high speed data valid for three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 96&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a validity of seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge includes 7GB of 4G data per day. 4G data comes at a daily limit of 1GB under Jio&amp;rsquo;s fair usage policy, beyond which the speed is reduced to 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 149&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 309&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Jio&amp;rsquo;s three-month benefits on first recharge begin. Subscribers making their first recharge of Rs 309 after taking up Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service will get 1GB of 3G data per day for 84 days, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 509&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimed at &amp;ldquo;daily high data users&amp;rdquo;, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 509 recharge extends the daily 4G data limit offered under the Rs 309 plan to 2GB. Data benefits on subsequent recharges will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first Rs 999 recharge, valid for 120 days, Jio users will get 120 GB of 4G data, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will come with 60 GB of high speed data valid for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s next long-term pack comes at Rs 1,999. The first recharge of this kind includes 185 GB of 4G data valid for 150 days. The 4G data on offer is reduced to 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges, Jio said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 4,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those making their first Prime recharge with the Rs 4,999 pack will get 410 GB of 4G data valid for 240 days. Subsequent recharges will offer 350 GB of such data for 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is the Rs 9,999. The first recharge will offer a total of 810 GB of 4G data valid for 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with a reduced 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar. To further incentivize Indians to make the switch to using the BHIM app for transacting business, PM Modi also launched two schemes - cash back for merchants and referral bonus for individual owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Are Some Of The Key Features Of BHIM:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BHIM, short for Bharat Interface for Money, enables its users to transfer money using their mobile phone. The app created a world record by registering 10 million downloads in just four months since its launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. For every successful referral, users can earn Rs. 10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;PM Modi declared on Friday that incentives totalling Rs. 495 crore will be given to merchants for accepting payments through BHIM and existing users for referring it to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 2 MB in size, the latest version of the app enables payments through a fingerprint scanner by authenticating biometric details of the user against the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is available in 12 languages with three new languages (Marathi, Punjabi and Assamese) added in BHIM 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, now allows users to transfer money to contacts saved on the phone. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a cap of Rs. 10,000 for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present account holders of around 30 banks can transact on BHIM 1.3. The app will add Punjab And Maharashtra Co-Operative Bank Ltd, Punjab &amp;amp; Sind Bank and Jammu and Kashmir Bank soon, according to its Google Play Store page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the United Payments Interface (UPI), BHIM users do not need to download mobile applications of multiple banks to transact with different banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the government&amp;rsquo;s move on November 8 last year to demonetise Rs. 500 and Rs. 1,000 currency notes, the number of digital payment apps have logged a nearly 23-fold increase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed by National Payments Corporation of India, BHIM aims pave the way for making payments using fingerprints or iris scanners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biometric attendance made compulsory from May 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-attendance-made-compulsory-may-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-attendance-made-compulsory-may-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporation has procured 93 machines based on ‘Aadhaar Authentication’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an important step towards streamlining the attendance of employees, Tiruchi Corporation has introduced biometric attendance for all of its officers, staff members and sanitary workers. Biometric machines have been installed at 91 offices and field units of the Corporation. Of the total 93 machines, purchased at a cost of ₹9.37 lakh, two have been kept on standby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machines have been installed at all reporting sections of sanitary workers, junior engineer offices, main office, zonal offices, lorry shed, water head works, and at the Ariyamangalam compost yard. Similarly, 11 urban primary health centres and mother and child health care units have also been brought under the new e-roster system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the machines are based on ‘Aadhaar Authentication’ (fingerprint and iris-based validation). Details of all 2,147 officers and employees of the Corporation have been synchronised with the machines along with their Aadhaar number. To enable the implementation of the e-attendance project, all employees of the Corporation were required to obtain Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The system is working well. Officers, clerical staff members and workers report on time to mark attendance. The issue of late coming has been addressed to a great extent,” said Corporation Commissioner N. Ravichandran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was Aadhaar enabled, supervisory officers can get the attendance details of employees easily. A centralised monitoring facility has also been created. Besides, the system has enabled the personnel department to maintain the attendance records of employees in a more efficient and transparent way, he pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biometric machines have been provided with the work schedule of all employees. For instance, the duty hours of employees in the main office is between 9.30 am and 5.30 pm. However, the work schedule of junior engineers, water head employees, sanitary workers varies. An employee can avail an hour’s permission thrice a month. And any late coming by an hour thrice a month, the machine will mark half a day absent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric attendance has been taken as the base for preparing the salary. While a few employees and sanitary workers have complained that machines did not recognise their thumb impression, the problem will be solved in a few days, Mr. Ravichandran said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-attendance system will be made compulsory from May 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No card? Aadhaar, fingerprints will do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance minister also sought to turbo-charge the government’s objective of maximising cashless transactions with institutional support that included waiving all duties on point-of-sale (PoS) machines and biometric readers, improving rural digital infrastructure, tax breaks, cash incentives and easier loans based on digital transactions history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring about structural reforms, a Payments Regulatory Board will be created in the Reserve Bank of India. The governor and deputy governor of RBI will be on this Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sops have been lined up too. The government has announced a ‘referral bonus scheme’ for individuals and a cashback scheme for merchants who use the Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the tax front, the Budget encourages small businesses (with turnover up to Rs 2 crore) by reducing presumptive income tax to 6% on non-cash receipts against 8% at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of digital transaction is on rural and semi-urban areas through post offices, fair price shops and banking correspondents. Petrol pumps, fertilizer depots, municipalities, block offices, road transport offices, universities, colleges, hospitals and other institutions will also be encouraged, and possibly rule-bound at some point of time, to have facilities for digital payments. “A proposal to mandate all government receipts through digital means, beyond a prescribed limit, is under consideration,” Jaitley said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small Industries Development Bank of India (SIDBI) will be encouraged to refinance credit institutions that provide unsecured loans, at reasonable interest rates, to borrowers based on their electronic payment transaction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In my opinion, initiatives like cutting excise duty on manufacturing of payment devices and a Payment Regulatory Board will further boost India’s digital economy,” said Sanjay Rishi, regional president, American Express.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Himanshu Pujara, managing director, Euronet Services India said the measures would allow people in rural areas, those “beyond the 15% data-enabled smartphone users and mobile subscribers across the country” to become a part of the digital payments ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also bear logo of 125th anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year &amp;ldquo;1891&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in English shall be written on the upper and lower periphery of the coin respectively. The year &amp;ldquo;1916&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in international numerals shall be written respectively on left and right top of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI said the existing coins in this denomination shall also continue to be legal tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 5 coin, the RBI said the coin&amp;rsquo;s face will bear an image depicting centre facade of Allahabad High Court Building emerging from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 1866-2016 in English numerals shall be written at the bottom of the image, the RBI said in a release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: How Much Fine You Have To Pay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is charging a fine on savings bank account customers not meeting the average monthly balance requirement. The amount of penalty for non-compliance with monthly average balance or MAB requirement is based on customer location - such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on Twitter while specifying various ranges according to which it will levy the charges. Charges levied for not maintaining the minimum balance depend upon how much the average balance in the account is below the agreed minimum, said SBI, which has&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. SBI also unveiled a new identity after merging its operations with six other banks recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is minimum balance requirement?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI savings bank account customers need to maintain a monthly average balance or MAB, which is the average of daily balances in the account during the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When do SBI savings bank account customers pay this charge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing to maintain the monthly balance as specified by the bank will attract a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What to do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A regular review of your account will help you to ensure the average monthly balance is maintained and avoid the minimal charges,&amp;rdquo; State Bank of India (SBI) said in another tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much fine do I need to pay?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking behemoth SBI has divided its customers into four categories: metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For metro customers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the monthly average balance of an SBI savings bank account holder comes out to be between Rs 2,500 and Rs 5,000 - a shortfall of less than 50 per cent, a charge of Rs 50 plus service tax will be levied, SBI said. For those with a shortfall of between 50 and 75 per cent (MAB from Rs 1,250 to Rs 2,500), a fee of Rs 75 plus service tax will be charged, and Rs 100 plus service tax for those keeping an average less than Rs 749 (more than 75 per cent shortfall).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-semi-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For semi-urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-rural-customers&#34;&gt;For rural customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-minimum.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The charges have been permitted by the Reserve Bank of India and are being levied by banks across the industry &amp;ldquo;and help us in providing better services to the customers&amp;rdquo;, SBI added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides savings bank accounts, SBI offers some other accounts wherein customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After its merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>