<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either &lt;em&gt;567678 or 56161.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said linking the two numbers is the key to &amp;ldquo;seamlessly avail online, a world of income tax facilities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar can also be seeded into PAN database by quoting Aadhaar in PAN application form for new PAN allotment or by quoting Aadhaar in change request form used for reprint of PAN card,&amp;rdquo; it said in the advertisement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income-Tax-department had early this month launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing I-T returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has hosted a new link on its homepage to link the two unique identities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires a person to punch in his PAN number, Aadhaar number and the exact name as given in the Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department had said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number in the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of Income-Tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the I-T department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon,Bank Account number portability</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-soon-you-may-be-able-to-port-your-bank-account-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-soon-you-may-be-able-to-port-your-bank-account-number/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;From linking Aadhaar numbers to bank accounts to the increase in digital payments, the days are not far when people can port their account numbers too. Reserve Bank of India&amp;rsquo;s (RBI) deputy governor SS Mundra on Tuesday batted for the need of account number portability and said that &amp;ldquo;the prospect of an aggrieved customer moving his/her account to another bank in the near future is very real.&amp;rdquo; He also spoke about the security issues involved in the electronic banking as the use of technology is being increasing over the recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account number portability has come within the realms of possibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SS Mundra first advocated the idea a couple of years ago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He also spoke on the security issues involved in the electronic banking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At an event organised by the Banking Codes and Standards Board of India (BCSBI) in Mumbai, Mr Mundra said, &amp;ldquo;I first advocated the idea of &amp;lsquo;account number portability&amp;rsquo; a couple of years ago. Back then the concept might have appeared somewhat abstract but with technological advancements in the field of payment system such as UPI etc. coupled with massive enrolments under Aadhaar and their linkage to individual bank accounts, it has come within the realms of possibility.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BCSBI is an independent body set up by RBI, Indian Banks Association (IBA) and scheduled commercial banks with the specific objective of ensuring that customers get fair treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the security risks involved in the online banking, he said, &amp;ldquo;There have been several incidents of theft of personal information, fraudulent use of ATMs, net banking frauds, ATM/Debit card incidents or cases of unauthorized access to bank servers. Hence, there is an immediate need for plugging all the gaps and vulnerabilities in tech-enabled service delivery.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While banks have been granted autonomy in fixing minimum average balance or for charging for premium services, it should not be used as an excuse to deny service or to drive away common man,&amp;rdquo; Mr Mundra said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank is also in the process of reiterating its guidelines to the banks for providing essential minimum relevant details in respect of various transactions in the passbook or statement, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trai Releases An App Which Lets You Rate Call Quality</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sector regulator Trai today said it will soon roll-out an app that enables subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call. The &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app would be available by the end of this month, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) chairman RS Sharma said at &amp;lsquo;Digital Broadcasting in India - Way Forward&amp;rsquo;, a seminar to commemorate the completion of 20 years of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We would like the consumers to assess the quality of calls, through &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app, which will be rolled out by this month end,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, once downloaded, the new app would give the subscribers the choice of assessing the quality of all or a portion of calls. When the call is completed, the users will be able to rate it, and the data will thereafter be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The application will pop up a window and enquire about the quality of the call. The subscriber can give it one star to five stars. There will also be assessment parameters like whether the call was indoors or outside or while travelling,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government and the regulator have refused to lower their guard on the issue of call drops, and have kept a close watch on call quality through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.
Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops. The system is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trai through its analytics portal has also rolled out initiatives that measure data speeds and maps call drops in India, which is the world&amp;rsquo;s second largest telecom market with 1.12 billion mobile subscribers.
Sharma today said that Trai also plans to &amp;ldquo;strengthen&amp;rdquo; the &amp;lsquo;Do Not Disturb&amp;rsquo; or DND service aimed at blocking pesky calls by telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already done a lot of work in this,&amp;rdquo; Sharma said, but refused to elaborate on the upcoming plans. At present, there is a framework for DND registry that allows telecom subscribers to block unwanted communication from telemarketers. Reaching out to such subscribers can result in a heavy fine for telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source familiar with the initiative said that the regulator may look at building specific intelligence features into the system such that pesky messages with certain key words could automatically generate a prompt on whether the users wishes to report the message as a spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the occasion, Communications Minister Manoj Sinha said TRAI&amp;rsquo;s regulatory framework has provided a conducive environment for the sector&amp;rsquo;s growth. It has made the sector more competitive and enhanced accessibility of services at affordable tariffs, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awareness of the some of the main challenges faced by the sector and regulatory framework of today - ranging from convergence to the persisting issue of the digital divide - is therefore necessary to be better equipped to handle these challenges in future,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Now Pay Later: IRCTC To Offer Train Tickets On Credit</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potential passengers can book a ticket and pay for it online within 14 days, IRCTC said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation or IRCTC has decided to make booking tickets a hassle-free affair by providing a &amp;lsquo;buy tickets now and pay later&amp;rsquo; service for regular travelers. Soon passengers would be able to buy tickets from the IRCTC website and pay later, an IRCTC official told Indo-Asian News Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential passengers can book a ticket five days prior to the journey with a service charge of 3.5 per cent and pay it in the next 14 days, IRCTC spokesperson Sandip Dutta said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRCTC has collaborated with a Mumbai-based firm ePayLater for adding the new service option. The ePayLater platform allows persons to log out immediately after booking tickets and make payments later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The railway agency had earlier introduced &amp;lsquo;pay on delivery&amp;rsquo; category for train tickets booked using its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be applicable for new &amp;ldquo;Buy Now Pay Later&amp;rdquo; feature, users will have fill in basic details including Aadhaar and PAN card details after which they will be able to use the feature with a One Time Password (OTP), ePayLater said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your NPS Account With Aadhaar Number</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPS subscribers have the facility to add their Aadhaar numbers online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPS or National Pension Scheme subscribers have been advised to add Aadhaar number to their accounts. Aadhaar is a 12-digit number issued by Unique Identification Authority of India or UIDAI based on the demographic and biometric information of the person. NPS subscribers can add their Aadhaar numbers online. The Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority (PFRDA), the body which manages NPS, been taking a number of measures to simplify the processes. For example, the Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority has done away with the requirement of submission of a physical application form for opening of an NPS account if done through Aadhaar verification and e-signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to add Aadhaar to your NPS account online:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Log-in to your NPS account (www.cra-nsdl.com)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Click on &amp;ldquo;Update Details&amp;rdquo; tab and then select the option &amp;ldquo;Add/Update Aadhaar Number&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Submit your Aadhaar number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Enter the OTP received from UIDAI on your registered mobile number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) After authentication through OTP, Aadhaar will be linked to your PRAN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PRAN or Permanent Retirement Account Number is a unique number allotted to NPS subscribers that remains the same for the rest of subscriber&amp;rsquo;s life)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NPS body has said that a subscriber is required to seed the Aadhaar in his or her PRAN through this process even if Aadhaar was provided earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: PFRDA has said that the name registered against your PRAN should exactly match the name as registered with &amp;ldquo;UIDAI&amp;rdquo; in Aadhaar. If the correction is required on PRAN card, then the NPS subscriber has to submit a self-attested PRAN card copy and a self-attested Aadhaar card copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For government subscribers, the Aadhaar seeding process will be completed once the request initiated by a subscriber is authorised online by his /her respective Nodal Office, PFRDA said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also bear logo of 125th anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year &amp;ldquo;1891&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in English shall be written on the upper and lower periphery of the coin respectively. The year &amp;ldquo;1916&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in international numerals shall be written respectively on left and right top of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI said the existing coins in this denomination shall also continue to be legal tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 5 coin, the RBI said the coin&amp;rsquo;s face will bear an image depicting centre facade of Allahabad High Court Building emerging from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 1866-2016 in English numerals shall be written at the bottom of the image, the RBI said in a release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches. From the fifth transaction onwards, the customers will have to pay a minimum of Rs 150 per transaction (plus taxes and cess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Earlier, HDFC Bank savings account customers were offered five free transactions and the sixth transaction was charged at Rs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) HDFC Bank after December 30, 2016 reintroduced charges on cash transactions at branches after the deadline to deposit old currency notes ended. The charges were waived off after the government had announced a ban on high value currency notes on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) According to the revised norms which came into effect from March 1, from non-home branch, HDFC Bank customers can deposit/withdraw up to Rs 25,000 per day without any charge but any deposit/withdrawal from non-home branch above Rs 25,000 will attract charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess), whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) At the home branch of HDFC Bank, if the cumulative cash transactions (deposit/withdrawal) exceed Rs 2 lakh, a transaction charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess) whichever is higher will be levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For example, if a customer withdraws Rs 2 lakh from an account in four transactions and goes for another fifth transaction of Rs 50,000 from the home branch, then the customer will have to pay a charge of Rs 250. Thus, the charges apply only on the fifth transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) However, the charges for withdrawing money from automatic teller machines (ATMs) remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For senior citizens and minor accounts, the limit of Rs 25,000 per day will be applicable but the accounts will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) India&amp;rsquo;s biggest private sector bank ICICI Bank had reintroduced the cash transaction charges at bank branches from January 1, 2017. There will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while thereafter Rs 5 per Rs 1,000 would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150. The third party limit is Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Meanwhile, news agency Press Trust of India reported that another private sector lender Axis Bank has also started charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp scam alert! how to be safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-be-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-be-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A WhatsApp scam is going viral all around the world where users could be tricked into paying a fake subscription fee. WhatsApp users are being targeted by a fake message which falsely claims their current &amp;lsquo;subscription&amp;rsquo; has expired.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A WhatsApp scam is going viral all around the world where users could be tricked into paying a fake subscription fee. WhatsApp users are being targeted by a fake message which falsely claims their current ‘subscription’ has expired. It encourages the users to tap on a weird link. While WhatsApp is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a hugely popular messaging app with more than a billion global users, it also is a prime target for malware and scammers. The new malicious link has been telling WhatsApp users that their ‘subscription has expired’. This message is being circulated all around WhatsApp. Additionally, the message asks its users for a verification of their accounts. It also asks the users to buy a lifetime subscription for 0.99 British pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that WhatsApp is a free messaging service, and it does not charge its users at all. There was a time, long back, when it used to charge a small annual amount from its users, but now it does not. The link which is going viral is essentially a scam and you should refrain from clicking on it. If you click on the malicious link, it might give access of your personal data including your bank details to hackers. The fake WhatsApp message reads as: “Your subscription has expired. To verify your account and purchase a lifetime subscription for just 0.99 GBP simply tap on this link.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, several users have taken to Twitter where they are warning others about the new scam. You have been advised to delete the message immediately, if you get it, and also block the sender. In order to block a contact which is not saved to your device, open the WhatsApp conversation and click on ‘Block’. Users may also report the user under ‘Spam’ category. In case you received the fake message from one of your contacts, you can block them too, by clicking on the menu button present on the WhatsApp home screen. Just select Settings, Go to Account, Go to Privacy, Select ‘Blocked contacts’. Then add that contact to your Blocked list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users who have already clicked on the link can safeguard themselves by running an antivirus software on their smartphones to make sure they are not infected with malware.
There have been many such instances where hackers have made use of WhatsApp to circulate dangerous links. Earlier, a spam message was circulated on the messaging app, where it invited users to a WhatsApp Gold version, an invite-only club with special features where they could be able to meet movie stars. There have been cases where links were circulated inviting users to download video-calling. These messages also claimed that PM Narendra Modi wanted to give everyone in India, ‘Rs 500 balance’ free for their mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory for Joining a Company</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government has made the biometric authentication using Aadhaar mandatory after facing several scenarios of fake identity theft—including becoming a director on a board of the company or for issuing its returns by company secretaries and chartered accountants—for Companies Act-related transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the sources, the Ministry Of Corporate Affairs has encountered several instances where people have established a Director Identification Number or have been chosen as directors on boards of the company without their consent, a necessity for connecting a board, as their signatures were copied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, in the near future, anyone looking for a Director Identification Number will have to authenticate using biometric devices and fill up the online form that can soon be connected to PCs. In the same way, anyone chosen by the banks or government and financial institutions on boards of the company will have to provide biometric authentication. A parallel setup for company secretaries and CAs is also being operated out, confirmed the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A squad from Infosys has been assigned with placing in the new machine that will be introduced in stages, initiating with the allocation of Director Identification Number. Progressively over a period of couple of years, it will be extended to involve all work related to MCA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be exclusions for non-residents and others, who are not qualified to get Aadhaar such as those people whose iris or fingerprints are not able to capture. MCA considers that the projected system does not encounter any issues since the recent order of the Supreme Court on Aadhaar as the system was destined for authentication. According to sources, the Supreme court had itself recommended that mobile connections be confirmed using Aadhaar and tax department as well as the banks have also been permitted to use the distinctive identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2017, the income tax department has also made Aadhaar compulsory for issuing permanent account numbers since it targets individuals using numerous PANs, which is not legal, to avoid from taxes. Though this move was disapproved, the government thinks that employment of UID can aid in enhancing compliance across various sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>