<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 19 To Rs 9,999: What Jio Prepaid, Postpaid Users Get</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering free voice calls and roaming on all its post-paid and pre-paid plans. Also there is no charge for data used to make 4G voice calls under all its plans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. Beyond the daily 4G data limits of 1GB and 2GB per day across its prepaid recharges and postpaid plans, wherever specified, subscribers will continue to use unlimited internet at a reduced speed of 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service - prepaid and postpaid alike - include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are various plans offered by Jio, as per its website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREPAID&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for just one day, Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid offerings start from the Rs 19 recharge, which includes 200 MB of 4G data for Prime members and 100 MB for non-Prime members, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 49&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s next recharge is priced at Rs 49. Jio Prime members recharging with the Rs 49 voucher get 600 MB of high speed data over a validity of three days. The 4G data on offer under this pack is limited to 300 MB for non-Prime members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 96&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge comes with 1GB of 4G data per day. That is for Prime members. Non-Prime members get 600MB of 4G data for seven days with a recharge of Rs 96.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 149&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data valid for 28 days for Prime users and 1GB for non-Prime subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime subscribers buying their first recharge of Rs 309 will get 1GB of 4G data per day for 84 days, as per the Jio website. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first recharge of Rs 509 offers 2GB of 4G data daily, for 84 days. This is comparable with half of the daily 4G data on offer in the Rs 309 pack. Data benefits on subsequent recharges of Rs 509 will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Rs 999 recharge comes with a validity of 120 days, in which subscribers get 120 GB of 4G data. Subsequent recharges are limited to 60 GB of 4G data for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A first recharge of Rs 1,999 comes with 185 GB of 4G data and validity of 150 days. The 4G data on offer is 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 4,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those buying their first recharge after subscribing to Prime will get 410 GB of 4G data with a validity of 240 days. Users will get 350 GB of 4G data with a validity of 180 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is priced at Rs. 9,999. Those buying their first recharge of Rs 9,999 are being offered 810 GB of 4G data with a validity of 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;postpaid&#34;&gt;POSTPAID&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First cycle: Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data per day - which sums up to 90GB of 4G data - for a period of three months under this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequent cycle: Customers will get 30GB of 4G data for a period of one month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering 2GB of 4G data per day for a period of three months on the first cycle, and one month on subsequent cycles. Therefore, users get 180GB of 4G data for three months in the first cycle, and 60GB for one month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first cycle, Jio is offering 180 GB of 4G data for three months under the Rs 999 postpaid plan. Users will get 60 GB of 4G data per month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs. 200,&amp;rdquo; he added. Developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI), the Aadhaar-linked BHIM mobile app is based on the Unified Payment Interface (UPI). In December last year, PM Modi had launched the app for facilitating electronic payments by consumers. In March, the government launched Aadhaar Pay, a new Android-based smartphone app. The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting PM Modi NITI Aayog tweeted that &amp;ldquo;just by helping more people use BHIM app, India will receive cashback and referral Bonus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to earn the referral bonus:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;referral bonus scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is for individuals, is meant to get more people on the BHIM platform and asking them to do transactions with others using BHIM or by referring new users on it. The bonus will be paid to both the existing and new users of BHIM. The referral will only be considered successful after three unique successful financial transactions by the new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three unique successful transactions with a minimum limit of Rs. 50 to any three unique users (either to customers or to merchants), the existing and the new user will be notified about the bonus amount via notification in BHIM app. The existing user will get Rs. 10 per successful referral, while the new user will get Rs. 25 for downloading and transacting from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the &amp;lsquo;cashback scheme&amp;rsquo;, which is only for merchants, users can earn up to &lt;em&gt;Rs. 300 per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs. 333: BSNL&#39;s New Plan To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 333, Rs. 339, Rs. 349 and Rs. 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL or Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited has announced three new data plans priced from Rs 333, the latest offering from the telecom operator seen as aimed at Jio&amp;rsquo;s Dhan Dhana Dhan plans. BSNL is offering up to 270 GB of 3G mobile data along with unlimited voice calls for a period of 90 days. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs 333 includes 3 GB per day of unlimited data, beyond which the speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps, the operator said. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing is causing intense competition in Indian telecom industry, forcing incumbent operators to offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attractive mobile data and unlimited voice calls plans, according to analysts. BSNL has also revised its existing Rs 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of data per day, instead of 2 GB earlier, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s revised Rs 339 pack, valid for 28 days, also includes unlimited local and inter-circle BSNL-to-BSNL calls. Calls to other networks are allowed with a limit of 25 minutes per day, beyond which BSNL customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 349 and Rs 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL had earlier launched yearly packs starting from Rs 1,498 and going up to Rs 4,498, which include 18 GB and 80 GB of data for 365 days, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Savings Account Minimum Balance Requirement. Read Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-savings-account-minimum-balance-requirement-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. The minimum balance requirement for SBI customers varies depending on geographies such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural. If the minimum balance drops below a particular threshold, SBI will charge a fee from the account holder. SBI says the minimum balance in your savings bank account is the monthly average balance - the average of daily balances in the account during the month. SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holders of SBI&amp;rsquo;s savings bank account in urban areas need to maintain a monthly average balance (MAB) of Rs 3,000, Rs 2,000 in case of those in semi-urban areas and Rs 1,000 in rural areas. This was said on Thursday by SBI - which recently merged its operations with six other banks - on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting 31 crore depositors, SBI will charge a fee ranging from Rs 50 to Rs 100 plus service tax in case of non-compliance with minimum balance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For metropolitan areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Under 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50 plus service tax&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For rural areas, the penalty for non-maintenance of minimum balance ranges from Rs 20 to Rs 50 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI offers other types of accounts where it customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. Small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products offered SBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore, besides Bharatiya Mahila Bank (BMB), became part of SBI with effect from April 1. After the merger, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1,500 रुपये का 4G फीचर फोन जल्द बन सकता है हकीकत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4G फीचर फोन या बेसिक मोबाइल फोन, जिसकी कीमत 1,500 रुपये हो, जल्द ही हकीकत बन सकता है। चाइनीज मोबाइल चिप मेकर स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस ने कहा है कि वह मौजूदा लेवल्स से शुरुआती कीमत कम से कम आधा करने पर काम कर रही है। एक डिवेलपमेंट एक्सपर्ट ने कहा कि यह कई कन्ज्यूमर को स्मार्टफोन की ओर शिफ्टिंग से रोक सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस के कंट्री हेड नीरज शर्मा ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, ‘हम एक ऐसी टेक्नॉलजी पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो कि 1,500 रुपये के 4G फीचर फोन को व्यावहारिक बनाती है। हमने अपने पार्टनर्स के लिए कॉन्सेप्ट प्रमोशन पहले ही शुरू कर दिया है।’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लावा और माइक्रोमैक्स जैसी घरेलू मोबाइल फोन कंपनियों के 4G फीचर फोन की कीमतें करीब 3,000 रुपये से शुरू होती हैं। कॉर्बन के अलावा, यह दोनों हैंडसेट मेकर कंपनियां आगे ऐसे फोन की कीमतें घटाना चाहती हैं। इस मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले इंडस्ट्री एग्जिक्यूटिव्स के मुताबिक, रिलायंस जियो इंफोकॉम भी अपनी सहयोगी रिटेल फर्म के जरिए किफायती 4G VoLTE फीचर फोन लाने की योजना बना रही है, इस फोन की कीमत 1,500 रुपये से कम हो सकती है। शंघाई बेस्ड स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस बेसबैंड चिप सेगमेंट में सधी ग्रोथ हासिल कर रही है और यह मीडियाटेक, क्वॉलकॉम जैसे मोबाइल चिप मेकर्स के साथ मुकाबला कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चिपसेट, किसी भी मोबाइल हैंडसेट का एक अहम हिस्सा है और डिवाइस की कीमत में इसकी बड़ी हिस्सेदारी होती है। स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस की रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज के साथ दो साल पुरानी पार्टनरशिप है और इसने RIL के अफोर्डेबल LYF फ्लेम 5 स्मार्टफोन को तैयार किया है। कंपनी ने लावा M1 4G फीचर फोन को भी पावर्ड किया है, जिसकी कीमत 3,599 रुपये है। कंपनी का कहना है कि उसे टेक्नॉलजी ईजाद करने और डिवाइसेज को मार्केट तक पहुंचाने में करीब छह महीने लगते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फाइनेंशल सर्विसेज फर्म जेपी मॉर्गन ने अपनी एक हालिया रिपोर्ट में कहा है कि 2017 में 4G कैपेबिलिटी वाले फीचर फोन पॉपुलर होंगे। इन्हें उम्मीद से कहीं ज्यादा तेजी से आने वाले 4G नेटवर्क से मजबूती मिलेगी। शर्मा ने कहा कि यह देखना काफी रोचक होगा कि ऐसे समय में जबकि मार्केट का झुकाव डेटा प्ले की तरफ है और वॉयस सेगमेंट स्थिर हो गया है, तब ऑपरेटर्स अपनी स्ट्रैटिजी को कैसे पुख्ता बनाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, ‘पिछले छह महीने में मार्केट पूरी तरह से 3G से 4G में शिफ्ट हो गया है और दमदार टेक्नॉलजी के बीच वेंडर्स को अपनी मार्केट स्ट्रैटेजी को दुरुस्त करना होगा।’ उन्होंने कहा कि अडिशनल वैल्यू ऑफर करने वाले LTE फीचर फोन को और आकर्षक तरीके में पैक्ड किया जाना चाहिए। साथ ही उन्हें बढ़ते डेटा मार्केट के हिसाब से टियर-III लोकेशंस और रूरल एरिया में बेचा जाना चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also bear logo of 125th anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year &amp;ldquo;1891&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in English shall be written on the upper and lower periphery of the coin respectively. The year &amp;ldquo;1916&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in international numerals shall be written respectively on left and right top of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI said the existing coins in this denomination shall also continue to be legal tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 5 coin, the RBI said the coin&amp;rsquo;s face will bear an image depicting centre facade of Allahabad High Court Building emerging from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 1866-2016 in English numerals shall be written at the bottom of the image, the RBI said in a release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aims To Implement Fully Paperless Travel Soon!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/set-replace-boarding-pass-air-travel-govt-aims-implement-fully-paperless-air-travel-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/set-replace-boarding-pass-air-travel-govt-aims-implement-fully-paperless-air-travel-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In few months time, this shall be the new scenario for air travellers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Step 1: Show your mobile and Aadhaar card for getting entry into airport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Step 2: Show your Aadhaar Card, instead of Boarding Pass, and get pass through Security check&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Step 3: Experience paperless air travel: Digi Yatra&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govt. of India has now decided to extend the scope of Aadhaar Card, and introduce it in Air Travel as well. Under the new premise of ‘Digi Yatra’, translated into Digital Travel, all you would need is your mobile phone to travel anywhere in the country, using air-mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logically, Civil Aviation Minister Jayant Sinha explained: “Your payment is digital, your boarding and security interactions are digital… That is the digi yatra concept we are working on,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questioning the very need for paper anywhere in the journey, the Minister explained: “.. You would be able to book your car to the airport, get to the airport, get a digital boarding pass, board your aircraft, take a car way back and do all of that just with your mobile phone..”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficulty, as the Minister informed, lies in forming a uniform platform, wherein an Aadhaar Card would be enough to ensure air travel without any paper. For instance, Govt. is working on how to make all airlines follow the concepts of Aadhaar based boarding pass, and how to incorporate Airport into the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, it is still not clear, whether Aadhaar would be now compulsory for air travel or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govt. to Supreme Court: PAN will not be invalidated retrospectively for not linking with Aadhaar
Meanwhile, Govt. has informed the Supreme Court that PAN card would not be cancelled retrospectively, in case it is not linked with Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney general Mukul Rohatgi, while representing Govt. in Supreme Court regarding a case challenging the mandatory status of Aadhaar Card said, “It will be invalid from 1 July 2017 and not from when you had applied for a PAN number,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior advocate Arvind Datar, who is representing the petitioners, challenged Govt. by stating: “Aadhaar linkage is only for an individual assessee and not for companies, firms etc. The consequences of non-compliance are draconian,”, adding, “Aadhaar is a right that a citizen is entitled to. There is no duty cast upon him to obtain one,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Supreme Court had directly questioned Govt., when they asked why Aadhaar has been made as a mandatory requirement when the Apex Court has already passed the order to make it an optional requirement. Very soon, Supreme Court will announce its verdict on Govt. decision to make Aadhaar mandatory for filing Income Tax returns and for linking it with PAN Card.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At 110 Crore GB Data Traffic A Month, Jio&#39;s Offers For Its Prepaid Users</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a number of recharge options to prepaid subscribers under its paid Prime service. Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website. Jio has become the largest network globally with more than 110 crore GB of data traffic per month and 220 crore voice and video minutes a day, Reliance Industries said in a statement while reporting the group&amp;rsquo;s earnings for financial year 2016-17. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mr Ambani said in the statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All recharges under Jio Prime include free voice call and roaming benefits. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at Jio&amp;rsquo;s various data offerings under its latest recharge options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Rs 19 _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 19 recharge comes with a validity of one day and includes 200 MB of 4G, or high speed, data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 49&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits on offer under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 49 pack include 600 MB of high speed data valid for three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 96&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a validity of seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge includes 7GB of 4G data per day. 4G data comes at a daily limit of 1GB under Jio&amp;rsquo;s fair usage policy, beyond which the speed is reduced to 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 149&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 309&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Jio&amp;rsquo;s three-month benefits on first recharge begin. Subscribers making their first recharge of Rs 309 after taking up Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service will get 1GB of 3G data per day for 84 days, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 509&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimed at &amp;ldquo;daily high data users&amp;rdquo;, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 509 recharge extends the daily 4G data limit offered under the Rs 309 plan to 2GB. Data benefits on subsequent recharges will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first Rs 999 recharge, valid for 120 days, Jio users will get 120 GB of 4G data, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will come with 60 GB of high speed data valid for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s next long-term pack comes at Rs 1,999. The first recharge of this kind includes 185 GB of 4G data valid for 150 days. The 4G data on offer is reduced to 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges, Jio said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 4,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those making their first Prime recharge with the Rs 4,999 pack will get 410 GB of 4G data valid for 240 days. Subsequent recharges will offer 350 GB of such data for 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is the Rs 9,999. The first recharge will offer a total of 810 GB of 4G data valid for 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with a reduced 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Plans To Eliminate Sale Of Petrol, Diesel Vehicles By 2030. Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-plans-to-eliminate-sale-of-petrol-diesel-vehicles-by-2030/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-plans-to-eliminate-sale-of-petrol-diesel-vehicles-by-2030/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ministry of Heavy Industries and the NITI Aayog are working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles, Power Minister Piyush Goyal said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India is looking at having an all-electric car fleet by 2030 with an express objective of lowering the fuel import bill and running cost of vehicles. &amp;ldquo;We are going to introduce electric vehicles in a very big way. We are going to make electric vehicles self-sufficient like UJALA. The idea is that by 2030, not a single petrol or diesel car should be sold in the country,&amp;rdquo; Power Minister Piyush Goyal said while addressing the CII Annual Session 2017 here on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyal is of the view that initially the government can handhold the electric vehicle industry for 2-3 years to help it stabilise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing the example of Maruti, which has logged over 30 per cent profit this time, he explained that the government had supported India&amp;rsquo;s largest car maker initially, which eventually led to development of the big automotive industry in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyal told reporters later that the Ministry of Heavy Industries and the NITI Aayog are working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles. The minister pointed to the cost factor, saying people would like to buy electric vehicle when they find it cost effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About offshore wind projects, Goyal said these are more like an R&amp;amp;D project. The minister suggested that big PSUs, including NTPC, can initially invest in such projects that will lead to development of this segment in coming years. Goyal said that in the last 3 years, India&amp;rsquo;s energy consumption has grown by about 6.5 per cent CAGR (compounded annual growth rate), more than the figure for the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, &amp;ldquo;Through UJALA, the LED distribution programme, we have already seen about 500 million LED bulbs sold in the last two years. My job is to improve India&amp;rsquo;s energy efficiency to reduce consumption wherever it is wasteful and ensure that demand is met fully.&amp;rdquo; He made a point that UDAY as not been just about financial re-engineering but financial discipline. The UDAY scheme is meant for revival of debt stressed discoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NITI Aayog is working on a policy for promotion of electric vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government said it can help the electric vehicle industry initially&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electric cars must be cost effective to be popular, Power Minister said&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Rs 50,000 On Your Provident Fund Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-deposits-to-earn-rs-50-000-more-under-new-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/provident-fund-deposits-to-earn-rs-50-000-more-under-new-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund body EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation&amp;rsquo;s (EPFO) apex decision making body, the Central Board of Trustees (CBT), has recommended a minimum sum assured of Rs 2.5 lakh in the event of death of a subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The CBT has recommended amending the Employees&amp;rsquo; Deposit Linked Insurance Scheme (EDLI) to provide for minimum benefit of Rs 2.5 lakh and loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at a meeting held yesterday,&amp;rdquo; a senior official said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The suggested benefits will be available to members after government approval. Initially, these will be provided for two years on a pilot basis and will be reviewed thereafter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the proposal, loyalty-cum-life benefit will be provided to all those members on retirement at 58 or 60 years who have contributed to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability. In these cases, the members who have contributed to the EDLI scheme for less than 20 years will be eligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those members whose average basic wages are up to Rs 5,000 will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of Rs 30,000. Similarly, the members with wages of Rs 5,001-10,000 Will be eligible for Rs 40,000 benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those members getting more than Rs 10,000 monthly wage will be eligible for Rs 50,000 loyalty-cum-life benefit under the proposed scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board has recommended such benefits in view of a huge EDLI corpus of Rs 18,119 crore following addition of interest that accrued on investment of this fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, the dependants of the deceased get a sum assured of up to Rs 6 lakh. There is no provision of minimum insurance and any benefit for surviving members or in cases of permanent disability under the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya launched Aadhaar Seeding Application after the meeting. The EPFO has developed this application with support of Common Service Centres (CSCs) and C-DAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CSCs are ICT-enabled front-end service delivery points at the village level for delivery of government and private services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With implementation of the seeding application, a PF member or pensioner can now walk into any of the field offices of EPFO or CSC outlets with UAN and Aadhaar and seed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPFO enrolled 49,39,929 workers during January-March 2017. It had launched a special enrolment scheme to cover leftout formal sector workers from January 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Developments On Your Provident Fund (PF) Money You Should Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-aadhaar-to-loyalty-scheme-5-developments-from-epfo-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-aadhaar-to-loyalty-scheme-5-developments-from-epfo-this-month/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From interest rate for 2016-17 to Aadhaar to a new loyalty scheme, there has been a lot of news coming from EPFO or Employees Provident Fund Organisation that manages your provident fund money. EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number to April 30, 2017 for its over four crore members. The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier. EPFO has also extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-the-other-developments&#34;&gt;Here are the other developments:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers will get loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more. The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided. The benefits will be available for EPFO subscribers after approval from the government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;EPFO&amp;rsquo;s apex decision-making body the Central Board of Trustees (CBT) has recommended a minimum sum assured of Rs 2.5 lakh in the event of death of a subscriber. At present, the dependants of the deceased get a sum assured of up to Rs 6 lakh. There is no provision of minimum insurance and any benefit for surviving members or in cases of permanent disability under the scheme. The benefits will be available for EPFO subscribers after approval from the government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 4 crore subscribers of EPFO will get 8.65 per cent interest on provident fund deposits for 2016-17, as decided by the organisation&amp;rsquo;s trustees in December, Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya has said. The comments follow reports suggesting that the Finance Ministry is nudging the Labour Ministry to lower the EPF interest rate by up to 50 basis points. &amp;ldquo;It is not like that. The CBT (EPFO trustees) had decided to give 8.65 per cent. Our ministry keeps on discussing with Finance Ministry. We would have surplus of Rs 158 crore on providing 8.65 per cent,&amp;rdquo; Mr Dattatreya said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The board of retirement fund body EPFO deferred the proposal to raise investment in stock market to 15 per cent of its investible deposits from current 10 per cent. &amp;ldquo;It was proposed to increase investments in the Exchanges Traded Funds to 15 per cent. But trade unions representatives opposed it,&amp;rdquo; an EPFO trustee said after the meeting. The EPFO has invested Rs 18,069 crore in exchange trade funds (ETFs) till February 18, 2017 and yielded a return of 18.13 per cent on these investments. Earlier, Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya had indicated that the EPFO will increase its investment in ETFs in the backdrop of good returns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly four crore members of retirement fund body EPFO will soon be able to settle their claims like EPF withdrawal through mobile application UMANG. &amp;ldquo;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) is developing online claims settlement process by receiving application online,&amp;rdquo; Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya said in a written reply to the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>