<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4GB Data Per Day For Rs 444</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-introduces-chaukka-plan-offers-4gb-data-per-day/</guid>
      <description>State-run telecom firm BSNL today increased per day data offering to 4GB at 3G speeds under a new prepaid mobile scheme priced at Rs 444 with 90 days validity.
&amp;ldquo;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) has introduced &amp;lsquo;BSNL Chaukka - 444&amp;rsquo;, a new STV, for truly unlimited data for 90 days as special promotional offer under prepaid mobile services,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.
This is the highest per day data limit being offered by any telecom operator in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange old notes for new at a premium</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exchange-old-notes-for-new-at-a-premium/</guid>
      <description>Scrapped old notes ­ Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 ­ which were to be exchanged latest by December 20, 2016, are still there. They can be exchanged even now, but for a hefty premium.
Non-Resident Indians (NRIs), who were allowed to exchange old notes till June 30 this year, are being offered a handsome commission for exchanging these notes.
&amp;ldquo;The going rate for exchanging old notes is Rs 9 on every Rs 100, so if you want to exchange Rs 1 crore in old notes, then you would get back Rs 9 lakh in new notes,&amp;rdquo; said Pravin (name changed), who is involved in this trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation To Launch RuPay Credit Card Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-to-launch-rupay-credit-card-soon/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India has forayed in to the credit card business and would make the commercial launch of its RuPay credit card &amp;ldquo;in a month&amp;rsquo;s time,&amp;rdquo; a top official said today.
&amp;ldquo;Maybe in a month&amp;rsquo;s time we will be able to make the commercial launch (of RuPay credit card),&amp;rdquo; NPCI Chairman M Balachandran told reporters here.
NPCI, which currently offers RuPay debit cards, has partnered with 10 banks including public sector and cooperative banks, to make the pilot launch of the &amp;ldquo;RuPay Credit Card&amp;rdquo;, Balachandran said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PM insurance schemes on June 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pms-insurance-schemes-on-june-1/</guid>
      <description>Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY) were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner.
You must have heard about the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) and the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana (PMSBY), which were launched by Prime Minister Modi in May 2015 to provide affordable universal access to essential social security protection in a convenient manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?
SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.
 Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.
HIGHLIGHTS  The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions  India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI Launches Three New Mobile Apps For Voice, Data Quality Tracking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</guid>
      <description>TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring.
Aiming to protect consumer interests, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Monday launched three new mobile applications and a web portal.
TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring. The app will help mobile phone users rate their experience about voice call quality in real time and help TRAI gather customer experience data along with network data, an official TRAI statement said here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.
To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-Aadhaar as ID proof in Railways</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/railways-accept-e-aadhaar-id-proof/</guid>
      <description>After receiving several requests from passengers, Railway has agreed to accept e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class. Earlier only printed version was considered as a valid ID.
According to railway ministry, the issue regarding acceptance of e-Aadhaar as one of the prescribed proof of identity for undertaking journey in any reserved class was being raised at various foras.
Accordingly, the matter was examined in consultation with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar based lic policies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-launches-two-aadhaar-based-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-launches-two-aadhaar-based-policies/</guid>
      <description>Life insurance behemoth LIC has introduced two endowment assurance plans for individuals having Aadhaar card.
While the _Aadhaar Shila _is a plan exclusively designed for women, the other scheme Aadhaar Stambh is meant for men. Absolute amount assured on death under Aadhaar Stambh is 100%, whereas for Aadhaar Shila it is 110% of basic sum assured.
These plans offer a combination of protection and savings and provide a lump-sum amount at the time of maturity for the surviving policyholder and financial support for the family in case of death of the policyholder, a Corporation statement said today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.
SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Allows Co-Operative Banks To Deposit Old Notes With RBI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</guid>
      <description>The relaxation comes against the backdrop of reports that many district co-operative banks did not have enough cash to disburse to farmers.
The Finance Ministry on Tuesday allowed banks, post offices and district central cooperative banks to deposit the scrapped Rs 500 and 1,000 rupee notes with the Reserve Bank of India within 30 days and exchange the value of notes deposit with the new notes.
In an official notification the Finance Ministry said, &amp;ldquo;Specified bank notes may be deposited by such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, in any office of the Reserve Bank, within a period of 30 days from the commencement of these rules, and get the exchange value thereof by credit to the account of such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, subject to the satisfaction of the Reserve Bank of the conditions specified in the said notification and the reasons for non-deposit of the specified bank notes within the period under that notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GST will impact your household budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</guid>
      <description>Goods and services tax (GST) comes into effect from 1 July. ET Wealth analyses the impact on some basic expenses in the household consumption basket.
AUTOMOBILES The price difference will be bigger for SUVs (55% to 43%) compared to small cars (30% to 29%).
Base price : Rs 4.75 lakh
Total taxes now* : Rs 1.43 lakh
Under GST : Rs 1.38 lakh
DURABLES : Refrigerators and washing machines For most white goods, there won&amp;rsquo;t be much difference in price as new rates will be close to earlier ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.
The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either 567678 or 56161.
It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine online jobs that you can do from home</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Whether you’re looking for a respite from your 9 to 5, are unable to commute to work, are a stay at-home parent, or have some other constraint that prevents you from finding a full-time job, there’s no need to waste your earning potential.
There are plenty of opportunities available online that let you work from home. Here are a few options you can consider.
 Virtual assistantship  Entrepreneurs, professionals and small teams often need assistance with various administrative tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Announces Mega Auction Of Properties</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</guid>
      <description>The bank will auction off 150 properties,including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country.
State Bank of India (SBI) has a nnounced a sale of properties through a mega e-auction on June 23, 2017. This was said by the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank on microblogging site Twitter. The bank will auction off 150 properties, including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country, SBI said on its website. These properties were pledged as collateral for housing and business loans and were taken over by the bank under the Security and Reconstruction of Financial Assets and Enforcement of Security Interest (Sarfaesi) Act due to non-payment of pending dues by the borrowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammers are trying to get your Aadhaar details via calls, emails</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</guid>
      <description>Watch out! The scammers are out with a new set of tricks to swindle the gullible public. Curiously, the Centre’s directive to link the bank accounts with Aadhaar has apparently made these fraudsters more brazen. Their latest modus operandi is to seek details of the Aadhaar card from unsuspecting victims through phone calls and emails.
Posing as bank executives or tele-callers, they call up potential victims saying, “The bank has decided to link your Aadhaar number with debit card for better customer service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win Rupay Select Credit Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>IDBI Bank announced the launch of ‘Winnings’ Rupay Select Credit Card that offers a range of travel, shopping and dining privileges and also enables earning of rewards points on every spend. The credit card has been launched in association with National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI). This product is similar to the international credit cards offered by VISA and MasterCard.
The ‘Winnings’ RuPay Select Credit Card is a premium credit card variant and is at par with the premium Card variants of International Card networks which is Visa Signature and MasterCard World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.
HIGHLIGHTS  Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change
 Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%
  The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.
Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.
Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘what is BHIM’ to ‘what are the benefits’, here are top 5 FAQs answered</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</guid>
      <description>Whether India has really adopted digital or not would only be clear once data for the coming months is released, but what can be said with certainty is that there are enough avenues available if one wants to go digital.
While pre-demonetisation, the government had launched UPI and other services, post this it has rolled out BHIM and BharatQR, and is expected to launch AadhaarPay. In fact, PM Modi in Mann-ki-Baat lauded the initiative to go digital, urging the youth to teach BHIM transfers to 125 people commemorating the 125th anniversary of Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM
Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Facility Launched To Link Aadhaar With PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.
The Income Tax Department has launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing income tax returns (ITRs) now. The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.
The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through Frotels.com for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio’s new plans offer 100% cashback on JioFi on exchange of old dongle, datacard, routers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio has launched a 100% cashback offer with JioFi 4G router, as the Mukesh Ambani-owned tries to attract users of dongles, datacard and wifi routers offered by rival telcos.
The company has come up with two plans where as part of the first plan, users will get a 100% exchange offer where they’ll be required to exchange their existing datacard, dongle or hotspot router at any Jio Digital store or Jio Care store and will get 4G data worth Rs 2010 against the device exchanged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.
Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon,Bank Account number portability</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-soon-you-may-be-able-to-port-your-bank-account-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-soon-you-may-be-able-to-port-your-bank-account-number/</guid>
      <description>From linking Aadhaar numbers to bank accounts to the increase in digital payments, the days are not far when people can port their account numbers too. Reserve Bank of India&amp;rsquo;s (RBI) deputy governor SS Mundra on Tuesday batted for the need of account number portability and said that &amp;ldquo;the prospect of an aggrieved customer moving his/her account to another bank in the near future is very real.&amp;rdquo; He also spoke about the security issues involved in the electronic banking as the use of technology is being increasing over the recent years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trai Releases An App Which Lets You Rate Call Quality</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</guid>
      <description>The sector regulator Trai today said it will soon roll-out an app that enables subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call. The &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app would be available by the end of this month, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) chairman RS Sharma said at &amp;lsquo;Digital Broadcasting in India - Way Forward&amp;rsquo;, a seminar to commemorate the completion of 20 years of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s formation.
&amp;ldquo;We would like the consumers to assess the quality of calls, through &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app, which will be rolled out by this month end,&amp;rdquo; he said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Now Pay Later: IRCTC To Offer Train Tickets On Credit</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/book-now-pay-later-irctc-to-offer-train-tickets-on-credit/</guid>
      <description>Potential passengers can book a ticket and pay for it online within 14 days, IRCTC said.
Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation or IRCTC has decided to make booking tickets a hassle-free affair by providing a &amp;lsquo;buy tickets now and pay later&amp;rsquo; service for regular travelers. Soon passengers would be able to buy tickets from the IRCTC website and pay later, an IRCTC official told Indo-Asian News Service.
Potential passengers can book a ticket five days prior to the journey with a service charge of 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.
Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.
&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your NPS Account With Aadhaar Number</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-nps-account-with-aadhaar-number/</guid>
      <description>NPS subscribers have the facility to add their Aadhaar numbers online.
NPS or National Pension Scheme subscribers have been advised to add Aadhaar number to their accounts. Aadhaar is a 12-digit number issued by Unique Identification Authority of India or UIDAI based on the demographic and biometric information of the person. NPS subscribers can add their Aadhaar numbers online. The Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority (PFRDA), the body which manages NPS, been taking a number of measures to simplify the processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.
The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.
The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.
On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.
India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.
Here are 10 things to know: 1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp scam alert! how to be safe</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-be-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-be-safe/</guid>
      <description>A WhatsApp scam is going viral all around the world where users could be tricked into paying a fake subscription fee. WhatsApp users are being targeted by a fake message which falsely claims their current &amp;lsquo;subscription&amp;rsquo; has expired.
A WhatsApp scam is going viral all around the world where users could be tricked into paying a fake subscription fee. WhatsApp users are being targeted by a fake message which falsely claims their current ‘subscription’ has expired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory for Joining a Company</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</guid>
      <description>The government has made the biometric authentication using Aadhaar mandatory after facing several scenarios of fake identity theft—including becoming a director on a board of the company or for issuing its returns by company secretaries and chartered accountants—for Companies Act-related transactions.
As per the sources, the Ministry Of Corporate Affairs has encountered several instances where people have established a Director Identification Number or have been chosen as directors on boards of the company without their consent, a necessity for connecting a board, as their signatures were copied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.
Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt makes Aadhaar mandatory for students</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</guid>
      <description>The move is aimed at checking the drop-out rate and ensuring quality education
The Yogi Adityanath government in Uttar Pradesh has made Aadhaar Card mandatory for students from Class 1 to 8 in government schools. The Basic Education department has been entrusted with this task involving over 1.75 crore students.
The Basic Education Minister Anupama Jaiswal said that directions have been issued in this regard. “The main aim of the government is to link their Aadhaar Card number with different welfare schemes, including mid-day meal, run by the state for the welfare of primary students,” she said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCO Bank Says RBI Begins Corrective Action Over High Bad Loans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uco-bank-says-rbi-begins-corrective-action-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uco-bank-says-rbi-begins-corrective-action-over/</guid>
      <description>Under RBI rules, prompt corrective action is triggered if a bank&amp;rsquo;s net NPL ratio crosses 6 percent.
The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has initiated &amp;ldquo;prompt corrective action&amp;rdquo; for state-run UCO Bank over its high bad loans and negative return on assets, UCO said on Friday.
UCO, in a filing to the stock exchanges, said the action &amp;ldquo;will not have any material impact&amp;rdquo; on its performance, but did not give details of the corrective action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>