<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Banking on Aadhaar without bank accounts via IndiaPost payments bank can be a real game-changer</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banking-aadhaar-without-bank-accounts-via-indiapost-payments-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banking-aadhaar-without-bank-accounts-via-indiapost-payments-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aadhaar-based transactions by people even without a bank account through the IndiaPost payments bank’s Aadhaar-pay model could be the real game-changer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears extremely attractive in the context of the government’s drive to promote digital transactions in a big way that Aadhaar numbers of the people—the total number has touched 112 crore already—will be good enough to pay or receive money, even without a bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what IndiaPost payments bank is striving to establish as its basic model once it starts operations in the next few months. According to its CEO A P Singh this can change the face of financial transaction in the country, especially in the rural areas where post offices can play a big role in promoting financial inclusion and handling direct benefit transfers (DBT), which is still around Rs 50,000 crore in a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way it will work is, take for example MGNREGA payment to a worker is sent to the nearest post office mentioning his/her Aadhaar number. The worker will go to the post office, complete the Aadhaar authentication process, and just take out that money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be various options with him apart from just taking cash—he/she can open an account with the IndiaPost payments bank immediately as the e-KYC process is complete with Aadhaar authentication, or just take a pre-paid card which can be used in any ATM to withdraw cash or make payments anywhere just as a debit card does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switch to normal transaction between two persons, and the same thing can be replicated through mobile wallets without bringing in any bank account. Going ahead, India Post is planning to equip the postman with biometric authentication and payment machines to remove the hassle of even going to the post offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the extensive reach of India Post throughout the country, something that has been a major bottleneck for the banks in handling transactions in rural areas and also DBT, Aadhaar-post combine can prove to be a big driver here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That India Post is targeting about 650 districts in the country in the initial stages itself with the help of those having feature phones and even those who have not, through its network, indicates that the door-to-door banking model may soon become a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, for this model to succeed, the mobile and broadband connectivity in the rural areas will also have to improve besides Aadhaar seeding, which to a certain extent is happening at a better pace now than what it was in the UPA years, even after the launch of DBT on January 1, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only about 35% people in India are having internet facility, and out of the 65,475 gram panchayats with access to the optic fibre laid under the BharatNet project, according to a report in The Indian express, less than 25% have active internet. So, even though the government, as announced in the Budget, achieves the target of taking broadband connectivity to 1.5 lakh panchayats by the end of 2017-18—it will be of help if there is a working internet available in these panchayats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Tops 4G Download Speed Chart in April: Telecom Regulator</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-tops-4g-download-speed-chart-in-april-says-telecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-tops-4g-download-speed-chart-in-april-says-telecom/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio logged a download speed of 19.12 mbps during April, even bettering its own performance of 18.48 mbps demonstrated in the previous month, telecom regulator TRAI said in its report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio recorded all-time high download speed of 19.12 MB per second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telecom regulator TRAI collects download speed on a real-time basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio overtook its own performance of 18.48 mbps in previous month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio topped the chart in 4G network speed for the month of April with an all-time high download speed of 19.12 megabit per second, according to the latest report by telecom regulator TRAI (Telecom Regulatory Authority of India). The regulator collects and computes data download speed with the help of its MySpeed application on a real-time basis. Theoretically, a user can download one Bollywood movie in about five minutes at 16 mbps speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the pole position among other operators, Reliance Jio logged a download speed of 19.12 mbps during April, even bettering its own performance of 18.48 mbps demonstrated in the previous month, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, April was the fourth consecutive month for RJio to lead the 4G network speed chart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During April, the download speed on Idea Cellular network stood at 13.70 mbps and Vodafone network at 13.38 mbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone India and Idea Cellular have announced merger of their operations to create the country&amp;rsquo;s largest mobile phone operator worth more than $23 billion with a 35 per cent market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the monthly trend on TRAI&amp;rsquo;s portal, Bharti Airtel logged average download speed of 10.15 mbps in April.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Pension Scheme (NPS) Or Public Provident Fund (PPF): Which One To Pick?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-national-pension-scheme-nps-or-public-provident-fund-ppf-which-one-to-pick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-national-pension-scheme-nps-or-public-provident-fund-ppf-which-one-to-pick/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although EPF is an option for salaried employees only, PPF is for all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public Provident Fund (PPF) and Provident Fund (PF) take centre stage whenever savings for retirement come to mind for most of us. Although EPF or Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund is for salaried employees only, PPF is for all. People have been investing in PPF - which provides secured return over the long term - for ages. However, the National Pension Scheme or NPS has been gaining lot of attention as a retirement savings product after the government provided additional tax deduction of Rs. 50,000 in Budget 2015-16. Under NPS, there are two types of accounts: Tier I and Tier II. While the Tier I account is non-withdrawable till the age of 60 except in specific situations, the Tier II account is a voluntary savings account. Subscribers to Tier II accounts can withdraw the money whenever they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the key differences between NPS and PPF:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-invest&#34;&gt;Who can invest?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PPF account can be opened by any Indian resident. One can also open a PPF account in the name of his or her minor children and can avail tax benefit on the contribution. However, an NPS account can be opened by Indian citizens above 18 years and less than 60 years of age. Non-resident Indians (NRIs) can also open an NPS account, but they cannot open a PPF account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;maturity&#34;&gt;Maturity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PPF account matures in 15 years. One can also extend this term after 15 years by a block of five years with or without making further contribution. However, in case of NPS, the maturity tenure is not fixed. You can contribute to the NPS account till the age of 60 years with an option to extend the investment to the age of 70 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;investment-limit&#34;&gt;Investment limit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One has to contribute a minimum Rs 500 to a PPF account annually with the maximum amount capped at Rs 1,50,000. A maximum 12 contributions per year are allowed in PPF accounts. However, in case of NPS, the minimum contribution required is Rs 6,000. There is no limit on contribution as long as it does not exceed 10 per cent of your salary, or 10 per cent of your gross total income in case of self-employed. But tax benefit will be available only on Rs 1.5 lakh under Section 80CCD(1) of the Income Tax Act, and an additional Rs 50,000 will be available under Section 80CCD(2) - a total tax benefit of up to Rs 2 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premature withdrawal/partial withdrawal: In case of PPF, partial withdrawals are allowed from the seventh year onwards with some limitation. One can also avail loan against his or her PPF account during the third and sixth financial years of opening the account with certain limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of NPS, after 10 years, subscribers become eligible for early, partial withdrawal under specific circumstance like children&amp;rsquo;s higher education or marriage, construction or purchase of house and treatment of critical illness (for self, spouse, children or dependant parents). But if you want to exit before retirement, you must use at least 80 per cent of the accumulated corpus to buy an annuity from a life insurance company including LIC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;investment-option&#34;&gt;Investment option&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of PPF, you do not have any discretion in deciding where to invest your money. However, in NPS, you can choose from a mix of three funds - equity funds, government securities fund and fixed income instruments other that government securities. A subscriber is allowed to invest up to 75 per cent in the equity fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;returns&#34;&gt;Returns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For PPF subscribers, interest rate is announced every quarter by the government. In case of NPS, returns are market-linked. &amp;ldquo;In our view, the potential of returns in a market-related investment like NPS is higher than of a guaranteed return instrument like PPF/PF. This is due to two reasons, one is the choice of equity exposure in NPS and secondly the component of professional fund management,&amp;rdquo; Manog Nagpal, CEO of Outlook Asia Capital, told NDTV Profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Mr Nagpal added: &amp;ldquo;PPF continues to be an attractive investment in itself, for those looking at zero volatility and a guarantee (in return). On a risk-adjusted basis, PPF returns though will be lower, will not be subject to the vagaries of the market.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tax-treatment&#34;&gt;Tax Treatment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PPF enjoys an EEE or &amp;lsquo;exempt, exempt, exempt&amp;rsquo; status, where the amount you contribute (up to Rs 1.5 lakh), the return you get and the maturity amount, all are tax exempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, NPS comes under an EET or &amp;lsquo;exempt, exempt, tax&amp;rsquo; tax structure. This means that contributions to NPS and the growth in corpus are not taxed but the lump sum withdrawn is partially taxed. Lump sum withdrawals above 40 per cent of the maturity amount are taxable in NPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;annuity&#34;&gt;Annuity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At maturity, you have to mandatorily purchase an annuity for at least 40 per cent of the accumulated wealth in case of NPS. But in case of a maturity amount less than Rs 2 lakh, you have the option of complete withdrawal. However, in case of PPF, you are not required to buy any annuity at the time of maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason NPS is purely a retirement savings scheme. You cannot use NPS for other purposes like children&amp;rsquo;s education, daughter&amp;rsquo;s marriage etc., which you can do with PPF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are certain limitations in NPS, it scores over PPF as a retirement savings scheme on various grounds, say financial planners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Home Loan At 8.35% Interest Rate: Five Things To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-home-loan-at-8-35-interest-rate-5-things-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-home-loan-at-8-35-interest-rate-5-things-to-know/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In line with the government&amp;rsquo;s push on affordable housing, State Bank of India or SBI is offering an interest rate of 8.35 per cent on home loans up to Rs 30 lakh. Eligible borrowers of home loans from SBI, which last month cut its home loan interest rates to the lowest rate in the market, can also avail an interest subsidy up to Rs. 2.67 lakh under the &amp;lsquo;Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana&amp;rsquo;, a government scheme aimed at providing subsidised housing loans to the low and middle income groups. Also, customers of other banks can also transfer their existing home loans to SBI at &amp;ldquo;no processing fee charges!&amp;rdquo; according to an advertisement by SBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five things to know on SBI&amp;rsquo;s affordable home loans scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The revised rates are effective on new home loans from May 9, 2017. The rates are:
Two year fixed interest rate home loans up to Rs 30 lakh:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For salaried:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borrower type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Effective rate of interest&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women  | 8.35%
Other  | 8.40%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For non-salaried:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borrower type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Effective rate of interest&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Women&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8.50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Others&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8.55%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;affordable-housing-push&#34;&gt;Affordable housing push&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;With a drop in interest rates and significant interest subsidy benefits offered by the Government of India, the affordable housing segment is poised for a major leap forward in the near future, with projects specially designed for the middle and lower income segments,&amp;rdquo; SBI said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home loan borrowers buying their first home are eligible for subsidy on interest repayments under the Pradhan Mantri Awas scheme, which is a credit-linked subsidy scheme run by the government. National Housing Bank or NHB has come up with operational guidelines for availing subsidy under Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana (Urban) for middle-income groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI is offering home loan takeovers without any processing fee till June 30, 2017. This facility is applicable on home loans from scheduled commercial bank, private and foreign banks and housing finance companies (HFCs) registered with the National Housing Bank (NHB), among others, SBI said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also launched a mobile app - SBI Loans - that enables customers to check loan eligibility and apply for home loans online. The SBI Loans app is available on both Android and iPhone platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI Launches Three New Mobile Apps For Voice, Data Quality Tracking</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-launches-three-new-mobile-apps-for-voice-data-quality-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aiming to protect consumer interests, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Monday launched three new mobile applications and a web portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRAI MyCall App is an Android application for crowd sourced voice call quality monitoring. The app will help mobile phone users rate their experience about voice call quality in real time and help TRAI gather customer experience data along with network data, an official TRAI statement said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is available on Google Playstore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulator has launched new version of TRAI MySpeed App that will enable the regulator to obtain test-driven data from users in all service areas, without any action by the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These tests would be brief, very infrequent for a specific device, free to the user and anonymous. The user may also do a test and submit the results, as before,&amp;rdquo; the regulator said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also launched DND 2.0 App (Do Not Disturb) Services App that will help smartphone users to register their mobile number under DND to avoid unsolicited commercial communication/ telemarketing calls/ SMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, TRAI has also launched a new website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Counter Jio, Airtel, Vodafone Launch New Plans. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/to-counter-jio-airtel-vodafone-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/to-counter-jio-airtel-vodafone-launch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As new comer Jio, the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, continues to offer discounted tariffs under its &amp;ldquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer in a bid to attract more customers, top two telecom players - Airtel and Vodafone - have launched data-oriented prepaid plans and offers to restrict their existing customers to switch to Reliance Jio. From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-of-the-recharge-plans-offered-by-airtel-and-vodafone-to-counter-jio-s-offers&#34;&gt;Here are some of the recharge plans offered by Airtel and Vodafone to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-399-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs 399 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs 399 recharge pack, Airtel is offering 1GB of 4G data per day along with free voice calls to any network for 70 days. However, there are some limitations on voice calls. You can do 300 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to Airtel (1200 minutes in a week) and for other networks, 3,000 minutes of free local and STD calls for 70 days. If you exhaust the free minutes, Rs 0.10 per minute will be charged.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bharti-airtel_650x400_61492413333.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-345-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel is offering 2GB of data per day at 4G speed for 28 days under its new Rs 345 recharge pack. Also, now there is no restriction with regard to the timing of data consumption. Under the earlier Rs 345 recharge pack, users were restricted to use only 500 MB of data daily from 6 am till midnight , and the remaining 500 MB between 12 am and 6 am. Along with the above data, users will also get free voice calls to Airtel and other networks as it is in the Rs 399 pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-244-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs 244 recharge, users will get 1 GB of 4G data per day for 70 days without any restriction on usage timing. But this pack offers free calls on Airtel networks only (300 minutes of daily Airtel-to-Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for a week for 70 days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above three recharge packs of Airtel have become active from April 15, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;vodafone-rs-352-recharge&#34;&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week. If you cross the call limit, a fee of 30 paise per minute will be charged for every call. This offer is not available for every Vodafone users. You can check if the offer is available for you by dialing *121# from your Vodafone number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JioFiber, Reliance Jio Broadband, In These Cities</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/preview-offer-of-jiofiber-reliance-jio-broadband/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/preview-offer-of-jiofiber-reliance-jio-broadband/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid and postpaid offerings have led to further competition in Indian telecom sector since the launch of its paid &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; services.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services being launched in some areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JioFiber Preview Offer being tested in select Mumbai areas, among others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm provides telecom services under brand Jio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid heightened competition in the telecom sector due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, the market is abuzz about Jio&amp;rsquo;s broadband services - JioFiber. Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services - called &amp;ldquo;JioFiber&amp;rdquo; - are being launched in some parts of cities like Mumbai, Delhi and Vadodara. This was said on Twitter by Jio&amp;rsquo;s official customer support- Jio Care. Jio, whose prepaid and postpaid offerings have led to further competition in Indian telecom sector since the launch of its paid &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; services, is testing a &amp;ldquo;JioFiber Preview Offer&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;select areas of Mumbai, Delhi-NCR, Ahmedabad, Jamnagar, Surat and Vadodara&amp;rdquo;, Jio Care said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care also said the company&amp;rsquo;s network is in the process of being rolled out to other cities. Jio Care was responding to a query posted by an individual on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, is a provider of telecom services under brand Jio. &amp;ldquo;The Company continues to make progress on the roll-out of its Fibre to the Home (FTTH) business offering with beta trials initiated in a few locations. It would expand the scope of the beta trials over the next few months,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Industries said recently while announcing earnings for the financial year ended March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, Reliance Jio has not revealed more details about the JioFiber broadband or its fiber-to-the-home (FTTH) service - which was mentioned by Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani while launching Jio operations in September last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While announcing the launch of pan-India digital services with its &amp;ldquo;Welcome Offer&amp;rdquo; in September last year, Jio had said: &amp;ldquo;In addition to fixed and wireless broadband connectivity offering superior voice and data services on an all-IP network, Jio will also offer end-to-end solutions that address the entire value chain across various digital services in key domains such as education, healthcare, security, communication, financial services, government-citizen interfaces and entertainment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care team did not name any other cities where the JioFiber Preview Offer was being tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some analysts say Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing has intensified competition in the Indian telecom sector, forcing existing players to come up with lower tariffs. Reliance Jio is likely to gain market share from existing telecom operators, ratings agency India Ratings and Research said earlier this month, while revising its outlook on India&amp;rsquo;s telecom services sector outlook from &amp;lsquo;stable&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;negative&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service, which came into effect from April 1, include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio has said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 150 Bank Charge on Cash Transactions Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-150-bank-charge-on-cash-transactions-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s leading private sector lender HDFC Bank has raised charges on cash transactions at bank branches, effective from March 1. An HDFC Bank official said that the charges on cash transactions at branches are being raised with an objective to promote digital payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-10-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Savings and salary account customers of HDFC Bank will now have four free cash transactions (which include both cash deposit and withdrawal) per month over the counter at bank branches. From the fifth transaction onwards, the customers will have to pay a minimum of Rs 150 per transaction (plus taxes and cess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Earlier, HDFC Bank savings account customers were offered five free transactions and the sixth transaction was charged at Rs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) HDFC Bank after December 30, 2016 reintroduced charges on cash transactions at branches after the deadline to deposit old currency notes ended. The charges were waived off after the government had announced a ban on high value currency notes on November 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) According to the revised norms which came into effect from March 1, from non-home branch, HDFC Bank customers can deposit/withdraw up to Rs 25,000 per day without any charge but any deposit/withdrawal from non-home branch above Rs 25,000 will attract charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess), whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) At the home branch of HDFC Bank, if the cumulative cash transactions (deposit/withdrawal) exceed Rs 2 lakh, a transaction charge of Rs 5 per thousand or Rs 150 (plus taxes and cess) whichever is higher will be levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) For example, if a customer withdraws Rs 2 lakh from an account in four transactions and goes for another fifth transaction of Rs 50,000 from the home branch, then the customer will have to pay a charge of Rs 250. Thus, the charges apply only on the fifth transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) However, the charges for withdrawing money from automatic teller machines (ATMs) remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For senior citizens and minor accounts, the limit of Rs 25,000 per day will be applicable but the accounts will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) India&amp;rsquo;s biggest private sector bank ICICI Bank had reintroduced the cash transaction charges at bank branches from January 1, 2017. There will be no charge for first four transactions a month at branches in home city while thereafter Rs 5 per Rs 1,000 would be charged thereafter subject to a minimum of Rs 150. The third party limit is Rs 50,000 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Meanwhile, news agency Press Trust of India reported that another private sector lender Axis Bank has also started charging a minimum amount of Rs 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1,000 Each Month For 20 Years Is Now Rs. 26,00,000 In This Fund</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DSP BlackRock Equity Fund recently completed 20 years of its existence. The fund (dividend option) has delivered 20.65 per cent compound annual growth rate since its inception, outperforming the 13 per cent return of Nifty50 index by a huge margin, says its website. The objective of DSP BlackRock Equity Fund is to seek to generate long-term capital appreciation, from a portfolio that is substantially constituted of equity securities and equity related securities of issuers domiciled in India. DSP BlackRock Equity Fund benchmarks itself against NIFTY 500 index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you consider the NIFTY 500, DSP BlackRock Equity Fund has also outperformed this index by a big margin. NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you had invested Rs 1,000 in the fund each month since its inception? Now you would be sitting on a corpus of nearly Rs 26 lakh as compared to your invested amount of Rs 2.41 lakh crore. If you had invested Rs 4,000 each month, it would have been over a crore now. Returns for investments in dividend plans of schemes are calculated after assuming that the net dividend payouts post statutory taxes &amp;amp; levies, are re-invested back in the scheme. As of March 31, 2017, the fund had assets worth Rs 2,310 crore under management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the country&amp;rsquo;s mutual fund industry managed an asset base of over Rs 18 lakh crore. Mutual funds are investment vehicles made up of a pool of funds collected from a large number of investors. The funds are invested in stocks, bonds and money market instruments, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inflows into domestic equity mutual funds have helped Sensex and Nifty rise to record levels. According to estimates domestic investors are pouring in Rs 4,000 crore every month into equity mutual funds through systematic investment route. Systematic Investment Plans or SIPs are fixed amounts invested at regular intervals in a financial instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New Charges On ATM, Other Transactions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-s-new-charges-on-atm-other-transactions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATM transactions from SBIs mobile app &amp;ldquo;Bank Buddy&amp;rdquo; will attract a Rs. 25 charge per transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cash transactions are capped at Rs 2 lakh with effective from April 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government is monitoring all large cash and suspicious transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any breach of the rule will attract a penalty of 100 per cent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country’s largest lender State Bank of India has revised service charges on ATM withdrawal for users of its mobile app “SBI Bank Buddy,” and various other cash transactions, effective June 1. SBI has clarified that the Rs. 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through its mobile wallet app. SBI’s app Bank Buddy is a new facility that enables withdrawal of cash through ATMs using the bank&amp;rsquo;s mobile wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal saving bank accounts in a month will continue to get eight free ATM transactions (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks) in metros and 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 at SBI ATMs + 3 at ATMs of other banks), the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applies to the Basic Savings Banks Deposit Accounts, SBI further said. SBI’s basic savings account is a limited-services bank account aimed at poorer sections of society to encourage them to start saving without any burden of charges or fees. This type of bank account comes with an ATM-cum-debit free of cost and no annual maintenance charges. A basic savings bank deposit account holder is not eligible to open any other savings bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has also revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective June 1. Here are some of the other key changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS or Immediate Payment Service will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh; Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh; and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; If a customer wishes to exchange of more than 20 soiled notes or if the total value of soiled notes is above Rs. 5,000, SBI said it will charge Rs. 2 plus service charge for every soiled note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customer with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs. 30 plus service tax for a 10-leaf cheque book, Rs. 75 with service tax for 25-leaf cheque book and Rs. 150 plus service tax for a 50-leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issuance of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only RuPay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs. 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs. 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>देशों पर साइबर अटैक: चपेट में ये देसी कंपनियां एवं सरकारी संस्थान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;दुनियाभर के 99 देशों पर हुए साइबर अटैक की चपेट में देश की कई कंपनियां भी आ गईं। रैनसमवेअर वानाक्राइ से प्रभावित हुईं कंपनियों में दो दक्षिण भारतीय बैंक, दिल्ली की दो मैन्युफैक्चरिंग कंपनियां, बहुराष्ट्रीय कंपनी (एमएनसी) की एक मैन्युफैक्चरिंग यूनिट, मुंबई की एक दिग्गज कंपनी और एक एफएमसीजी कंपनी के मुख्यालय शामिल हैं। इनके अलावा, आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के 100 से ज्यादा कंप्यूटर भी इस भयावह हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुरक्षा विशेषज्ञों का मानना है कि इस हमले से हुआ नुकसान और ज्यादा हो सकता है और प्रभावित कंपनियों की तादाद बढ़ सकती है। चूंकि यह हमला वीकेंड में (शुक्रवार को) हुआ है, इसलिए नुकसान का सही-सही आकलन सोमवार को ही किया जा सकता है जब सारे पर्सनल कंप्यूटर्स स्टार्ट किए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EY इंडिया में पाटर्नर (फ्रॉड इन्वेस्टिगेशन ऐंड डिस्प्यूट सर्विसेज) मुकुल श्रीवास्तव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;भारतीय कंपनियां हालिया हमले की चपेट में आई हैं। पिछले एक साल में रैनसमवेअर के मामले बहुत बढ़ गए हैं। अब साइबर क्रिमिनल्स बेहद टेक सेवी हो चुके हैं और हरेक रैनसमवेअर की अपनी यूनीक एन्क्रिप्टिंग मशीनें हैं। ये हमले लगातार बाधा पहुंचाने और फिरौती वसूलने के मकसद से हो रहे हैं। इसलिए संगठनों को ऐसे खतरों का सामना करने के लिए गंभीर उपाय करने होंगे। हम साइबरक्राइम और रैनसमवेअर के खिलाफ समाधान प्रक्रिया में कई देसी एवं वैश्विक कंपनियों के साथ काम कर रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जाल में ऐसे फंसाते हैं हैकर्स, रहें सावधान&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;शुक्रवार को मैलवेअर बड़ी तेजी से फैल गया और दुनियाभर की कंपनियों एवं सरकारी संगठनों में कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए। दरअसल, रैनसमवेअर के डाउनलोड होते ही सभी कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए और उनमें पड़े डेटा एन्क्रिप्ट कर लिए गए। हमलावर ने इन डेटा को रीस्टोर करने के लिए फिरौती की मांग की।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनियां ऐसे हमलों से निपटने के लिए देश के जिन साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर कर रही हैं, उनके मुताबिक ऐसे कई मामले सामने आए हैं जब भारतीय कंपनियों ने अपने प्रभावित कंप्यूटरों को दुबारा ऐक्सेस करने के एवज में फिरौती दी। यूके की नैशनल हेल्थ सर्विसेज (एनएसएस) जैसे वैश्विक संस्थान और रेनॉ, फेडेक्स एवं टेलिफोनिका जैसी कंपनियों ने हमले से प्रभावित होने की जानकारी दी, लेकिन देश की एक भी कंपनी ने नहीं बताया कि उनके कंप्यूटर हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के कंप्यूटरों पर साइबर हमले, फिरौती मांग रहे हैकर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक्सपर्ट्स का कहना है कि शुक्रवार को फैलाया गया मैलवेअर अमेरिका की नैशनल सिक्यॉरिटी एजेंसी का वही इटरनलब्लू टूल है जिसे अप्रैल महीने में द शैडो ब्रॉकर्स नाम के हैकर ग्रुप ने चुरा लिया था। दिग्गज साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी कंपनी अवास्ट ने कहा कि उसने रैनसमवेअर और इसके विभिन्न रूपों के 75,000 मामले देखे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी एक्सपर्ट ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इस हमला कुछ अलग है। इससे कोई एक बार इन्फेक्ट हो गया तो हो गया। इसे हटाने के लिए तीन से चार घंटे लगेंगे और पीसी रीबूट करना पड़ेगा। हालांकि, इसमें कोई नुकसान या कोई डेटा खत्म नहीं होता।&amp;rsquo; साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स के मुताबिक, भारतीय कंपनियों पर रैनसमवेअर अटैक्स के मामले में एक सिलिसला सा जुड़ रहा है। पिछले तीन महीनों में 25 से 30 ऐसे मामले सामने आ चुके हैं जब कंपनियां मैलवेअर का शिकार हुई हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 GB Free Data: Vodafone&#39;s Latest Offer In Response To Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September, incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Vodafone is also currently offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone is giving &lt;em&gt;9 GB data&lt;/em&gt; free to customers in a special scheme, its latest offer to counter Reliance Jio which has come up with aggressive tariff plans. &amp;ldquo;Thank you for making us a 200 million strong family! As a token of appreciation, we are happy to delight you with free data on your Vodafone mobile,&amp;rdquo; Vodafone said. A Vodafone customer care executive said the 9 GB free data offer has been made to select customers. The 9 GB free data will be applicable &lt;em&gt;at 3 GB/month&lt;/em&gt; for three billing cycles. Vodafone said this 9GB offer is in addition to &amp;ldquo;existing data quota on your plan/pack at no extra cost&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September,&lt;/em&gt; incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Currently, Vodafone is also offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New entrant Reliance Jio has kept the pressure on other operators to cut tariffs and make special offers to customers. Jio&amp;rsquo;s current &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans offer &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs. 309.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Vodafone said that it will offer free incoming calls during international roaming on its network in 45 countries at a daily rental of Rs. 500 along with all international and local outgoing calls for Rs. 1 a minute. In the countries where Vodafone operates, the customer will get 1 megabyte of mobile internet for Rs. 1 which implies 1 GB of data will cost them Rs. 1,024. &amp;ldquo;Keeping in mind the requirements of international travelers, Vodafone had recently introduced the i-RoamFREE proposition offering free incoming calls, Re 1 for all international and local outgoing calls and data at Re 1 per MB in over 45 countries on a daily basis,&amp;rdquo; Vodafone said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price war for data subscribers has dented the bottom lines of wireless telecom service providers, yet none of them is likely to pull a punch, Crisil said in a report. If anything, competition will only heat up further given that market leadership is all-crucial to the business, it said. The proposed merger between Idea and Vodafone - which marks the biggest consolidation in the Indian telecom sector - is also part of this quest to strengthen market position, alongside lowering investment needs and costs, Crisil added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile number will be deactivated if not linked with Aadhaar card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mobile-number-will-deactivated-not-linked-aadhaar-card-heres-can-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mobile-number-will-deactivated-not-linked-aadhaar-card-heres-can-link/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government had in March 2017, had announced that Aadhaar-based e-KYC (know your customer) will be made mandatory for mobile phone connections. The department of telecommunications (DoT) had then ordered all mobile operators to verify the details of the existing customers by using their unique Aadhaar identity number and biometric details by early 2018. Aadhaar-based e-KYC will also be made compulsory for customers who have to get new SIM cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Airtel and Idea have begun the process of completing this verification. The two service providers are sending messages to their customers to initiate the KYC process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A message in Airtel store reads: “Link your Aadhaar card to your number now to stay active! As per the Government of India, this is mandatory to enjoy continued services”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To save yourself from getting your services discontinued, here is your guide to link your Aadhaar card with your mobile phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to link the phone number to your Aadhaar card?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• As soon as you receive the SMS, go to the nearby store of your operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Take your Aadhaar card along and give the details there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• After this, you will receive a 4 digit verification code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Once the code is confirmed, fingerprint verification will be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Within 24 hours, you will get another message for “Final verify”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Reply to that message with “Y”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• You will get an SMS that your number is linked to the Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;clear-your-doubts-with-these-answers&#34;&gt;Clear your doubts with these answers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do I need to pay any charges?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is free and you need to get it done through an operator’s store only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can I do online registration?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, don’t go behind any online registration sites, as they are fake. The process is manual and as of now, only offline registration facility is available. Telecom operators haven’t started online registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s the last date?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last date is 6th of February 2018. Do it as soon as possible as it is rightly said, “Sooner the better”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can the Aadhaar card be linked to multiple SIM cards?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you can link it. However, a limit has been set for maximum connections. You need to find it out from your operator store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions mentioned above and get your card linked as soon as possible. It is better to be safe than sorry; following the rule at the earliest will not only benefit you, but will also ensure that you don’t face any issues later on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>