<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines To Link Aadhaar With PAN, Mobile Number, Bank Account: A Checklist</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/four-deadlines-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan-mobile-number-sim-banks-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/four-deadlines-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan-mobile-number-sim-banks-details-here/</guid>
      <description>Quoting of Aadhaar number - the 12-digit number given on the Aadhaar card - has been made mandatory for many essentials. These range from filing of income tax returns (ITR) to applying for a PAN or permanent account number to using a mobile phone connection. The government is moving ahead with linking Aadhaar with mobile SIM cards, according to a report by news agency Indo-Asian News Service (IANS). All mobile phone numbers or SIMs not linked with Aadhaar will be deactivated after February 2018, the agency said citing informed sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio: Not Rs 1500, you will have to spend at least Rs 4500 to get a refund:Jio Phone terms &amp; conditions</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-terms-conditions-not-rs-1500-you-will-have-to-spend-at-least-rs-4500-to-get-a-refund/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-terms-conditions-not-rs-1500-you-will-have-to-spend-at-least-rs-4500-to-get-a-refund/</guid>
      <description>Jio Phone costs Rs 1500 which the company said will be refunded after a period of 3 years. Here&amp;rsquo;s why you will have to pay at least Rs 4,500.
Reliance Jio Phone has finally started getting delivered and if you are staying in a rural area chances are you will get it first. The Jio Phone costs Rs 1500 which the company said will be refunded after a period of 3 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF Money Transfer Becomes Easier. Here Is The New Rule</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-money-transfer-becomes-easier-here-is-the-new-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pf-money-transfer-becomes-easier-here-is-the-new-rule/</guid>
      <description>Retirement fund body EPFO&amp;rsquo;s subscribers are no longer required to file separate EPF transfer claims using Form-13 after changing jobs as it will now be done automatically.
Now, at the time of joining new employer, the employees&amp;rsquo; can give details of their previous EPF account in new composite F-11 form to give declaration about their details, a senior official said.
Once the old EPF account details are provided in F-11 form, the funds will be automatically transferred by the EPFO to new EPF account, the official added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Basic Savings Account: No Minimum Balance Charges And Other Benefits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-basic-savings-account-no-minimum-balance-charges-and-other-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-basic-savings-account-no-minimum-balance-charges-and-other-benefits/</guid>
      <description>Normal savings account holders, who want to avoid paying minimum balance non-maintaining charges, can convert their account to basic savings bank deposit accounts without any fee, SBI said.
India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI has clarified that charges for non-maintenance of monthly average balance does not apply to all its bank accounts. In a Twitter post, SBI said that basic savings bank deposit accounts are exempted from maintaining monthly average balance. Out of the 40 crore savings bank accounts that SBI has, 13 crore accounts fall under exempted category, the state-owned lender said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI&#39;s New Rule On Minimum Account Balance, Charges Explained In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-new-rule-on-minimum-account-balance-charges-explained-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-new-rule-on-minimum-account-balance-charges-explained-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>SBI (State Bank of India), the biggest lender in the country, brings cheers for the 42 crore customers holding savings accounts in the bank by reducing its monthly average balance (MAB) requirements and charges for non-compliance. That means customers not maintaining sufficient balance in SBI savings bank accounts will now pay lower charges. In a press release, SBI said it has reduced the MAB requirement for metro cities and slashed charges for non-maintenance by up to 50 per cent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammers are trying to get your Aadhaar details via calls, emails</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</guid>
      <description>Watch out! The scammers are out with a new set of tricks to swindle the gullible public. Curiously, the Centre’s directive to link the bank accounts with Aadhaar has apparently made these fraudsters more brazen. Their latest modus operandi is to seek details of the Aadhaar card from unsuspecting victims through phone calls and emails.
Posing as bank executives or tele-callers, they call up potential victims saying, “The bank has decided to link your Aadhaar number with debit card for better customer service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using BHIM App Can Earn You Referral Bonus, Cashback</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-can-earn-you-referral-bonus-cashback/</guid>
      <description>The BHIM-Aadhaar app will pave the way for making digital payments by using the Aadhaar platform.
To push digital payments further, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has announced &amp;lsquo;cashback&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;referral bonus&amp;rsquo; schemes for using BHIM - Bharat Interface for Money - app. PM Modi said for every person you introduce to the BHIM app, you will get a cashback of Rs. 10. &amp;ldquo;If you refer 20 people a day, you can earn Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-facility to link Aadhaar with PAN launched</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</guid>
      <description>I-T Department asks people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.
The Income Tax Department has launched an e-facility to link Aadhaar with Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing IT returns now.
The department’s e-filing website https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in has created the link on its homepage.
The link requires the PAN, the Aadhaar number and the “exact name as given in the Aadhaar card”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things that are banned for you, from opening a bank account to processing of I-T returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</guid>
      <description>If you thought that filing an income tax return or opening a bank account are the only few things which require Aadhaar cards now, then think again. The fact is Aadhaar has now been made mandatory for so many things, including availing the benefits of various social and government schemes. While for some schemes it has already been made compulsory, for some others it will be made mandatory soon.
Here we are taking a look at 10 such things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>508 Km In 3 Hours: India&#39;s First Bullet Train Project In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/508-km-in-3-hours-india-s-first-bullet-train-project-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/508-km-in-3-hours-india-s-first-bullet-train-project-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his Japanese counterpart Shinzo Abe laid the foundation stone for India’s first bullet train project in Ahmedabad on Thursday. The bullet train project touted to revolutionize railways technology in the country. The first line which will connect Ahmedabad to Mumbai can cover the 508 km distance in as little as two hours, the government said. The project will be executed as a joint venture between the Indian Railways and Japanese firm Shinkansen Technology at an estimated cost of Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 smart tips which can help you save more &amp; become rich</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t want to become rich? However, getting wealthy isn’t that easy. It begins with determined consciousness to get wealthy. We all know that to become rich you need to spend less than what you earn. That is because the less you spend, the more you will be able to save. You should save and invest what you have into investments (assets) that appreciate over time. Apart from these, here we are taking a look at a few really easy and ‘anyone can do it’ strategies or DIY tips that can make you a crorepati:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data hack: IIT Kharagpur graduate arrested, earns Rs 40 lakh a year at Ola</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</guid>
      <description>An IIT Kharagpur graduate, Abhinav Srivastava, who allegedly hacked Aadhaar data has been arrested by Bengaluru Police. According to investigation, Srivastava had gained access to the repository of the Unique Identification Development Authority of India’s (UIDAI) Aadhaar project through the Digital India e-hospital portal. The 31-year-old hails from Uttar Pradesh and was arrested in connection with a complaint filed by the UIDAI on July 26, according to Indian Express.
Police said the complaint against Srivastava stated that he accessed UIDAI data without authorisation between January 1 and July 26 for an app called ‘eKYC Verification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Less On Petrol, Diesel While Paying Via BHIM, Cards</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-up-to-rs-0-49-litre-less-on-petrol-diesel-while-paying-via-bhim-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-up-to-rs-0-49-litre-less-on-petrol-diesel-while-paying-via-bhim-cards/</guid>
      <description>Fuel prices are sky-rocketing due to changes in global crude prices resulting in consumers to feel the pinch as the value of domestic fuel prices is determined by it. A daily revision in petrol and diesel rates by oil marketing companies has made the consumers feel the heat more. However, if you pay for fuel using the government&amp;rsquo;s BHIM or Bharat Interface for Money app, you can get 49 paise per litre off on petrol and 41 paise per litre discount on diesel, stated a tweet from Digital India&amp;rsquo;s official account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only 5 Free ATM Transactions From October, Punjab National Bank Says</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</guid>
      <description>PNB customers will have to shell out money beginning October if they carry out more than five transactions a month from the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs. At present, account holders of the country&amp;rsquo;s second largest public sector bank can make any number of transactions in a month, financial or non-financial, at the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs without attracting any charge.
&amp;ldquo;The number of free transactions and the charges beyond these free transactions for PNB customers on PNB ATMs have been revised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>link your SBI account to Aadhaar via ATMs and SMS: Here’s how to do it in easy steps</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-link-aadhaar-card-online-via-atm-sms-state-bank-of-india-heres-how-to-do-it-in-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-link-aadhaar-card-online-via-atm-sms-state-bank-of-india-heres-how-to-do-it-in-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Are you a State Bank of India customer and want to link your Aadhaar number to your SBI account? Or have got a message from the bank to do so? Here’s some good news for you. SBI allows its customers to link their bank accounts to their Aadhaar number in various ways, including their ATM channel and through SMS. You can also get it done by visiting any of their branches or through Internet banking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1,000 bank branches open Aadhaar updation centres on premises</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-branches-open-aadhaar-updation-centres-on-premises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-branches-open-aadhaar-updation-centres-on-premises/</guid>
      <description>The UIDAI today said over 1,000 bank branches of 42 private and public sector banks have opened Aadhaar enrolment and updation centres within their premises.
The Aadhaar issuing body further said it has received commitments for opening of such centres in 15,000 bank branches &amp;ldquo;at the earliest&amp;rdquo;.
&amp;ldquo;Bank Aadhaar Kendras are being established with a view to make the Aadhaar verification process of bank accounts convenient for the people as it has become mandatory under amended Prevention of Money Laundering Rules to verify bank accounts with Aadhaar by December 31, 2017,&amp;rdquo; Ajay Bhushan Pandey, CEO of UIDAI said in a statement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>