<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1,500 रुपये का 4G फीचर फोन जल्द बन सकता है हकीकत</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-could-soon-buy-a-4g-feature-phone-at-just-rs-1500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4G फीचर फोन या बेसिक मोबाइल फोन, जिसकी कीमत 1,500 रुपये हो, जल्द ही हकीकत बन सकता है। चाइनीज मोबाइल चिप मेकर स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस ने कहा है कि वह मौजूदा लेवल्स से शुरुआती कीमत कम से कम आधा करने पर काम कर रही है। एक डिवेलपमेंट एक्सपर्ट ने कहा कि यह कई कन्ज्यूमर को स्मार्टफोन की ओर शिफ्टिंग से रोक सकता है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस के कंट्री हेड नीरज शर्मा ने इकनॉमिक टाइम्स को बताया, ‘हम एक ऐसी टेक्नॉलजी पर काम कर रहे हैं, जो कि 1,500 रुपये के 4G फीचर फोन को व्यावहारिक बनाती है। हमने अपने पार्टनर्स के लिए कॉन्सेप्ट प्रमोशन पहले ही शुरू कर दिया है।’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लावा और माइक्रोमैक्स जैसी घरेलू मोबाइल फोन कंपनियों के 4G फीचर फोन की कीमतें करीब 3,000 रुपये से शुरू होती हैं। कॉर्बन के अलावा, यह दोनों हैंडसेट मेकर कंपनियां आगे ऐसे फोन की कीमतें घटाना चाहती हैं। इस मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले इंडस्ट्री एग्जिक्यूटिव्स के मुताबिक, रिलायंस जियो इंफोकॉम भी अपनी सहयोगी रिटेल फर्म के जरिए किफायती 4G VoLTE फीचर फोन लाने की योजना बना रही है, इस फोन की कीमत 1,500 रुपये से कम हो सकती है। शंघाई बेस्ड स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस बेसबैंड चिप सेगमेंट में सधी ग्रोथ हासिल कर रही है और यह मीडियाटेक, क्वॉलकॉम जैसे मोबाइल चिप मेकर्स के साथ मुकाबला कर रही है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चिपसेट, किसी भी मोबाइल हैंडसेट का एक अहम हिस्सा है और डिवाइस की कीमत में इसकी बड़ी हिस्सेदारी होती है। स्प्रेडट्रम कम्यूनिकेशंस की रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज के साथ दो साल पुरानी पार्टनरशिप है और इसने RIL के अफोर्डेबल LYF फ्लेम 5 स्मार्टफोन को तैयार किया है। कंपनी ने लावा M1 4G फीचर फोन को भी पावर्ड किया है, जिसकी कीमत 3,599 रुपये है। कंपनी का कहना है कि उसे टेक्नॉलजी ईजाद करने और डिवाइसेज को मार्केट तक पहुंचाने में करीब छह महीने लगते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फाइनेंशल सर्विसेज फर्म जेपी मॉर्गन ने अपनी एक हालिया रिपोर्ट में कहा है कि 2017 में 4G कैपेबिलिटी वाले फीचर फोन पॉपुलर होंगे। इन्हें उम्मीद से कहीं ज्यादा तेजी से आने वाले 4G नेटवर्क से मजबूती मिलेगी। शर्मा ने कहा कि यह देखना काफी रोचक होगा कि ऐसे समय में जबकि मार्केट का झुकाव डेटा प्ले की तरफ है और वॉयस सेगमेंट स्थिर हो गया है, तब ऑपरेटर्स अपनी स्ट्रैटिजी को कैसे पुख्ता बनाते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा, ‘पिछले छह महीने में मार्केट पूरी तरह से 3G से 4G में शिफ्ट हो गया है और दमदार टेक्नॉलजी के बीच वेंडर्स को अपनी मार्केट स्ट्रैटेजी को दुरुस्त करना होगा।’ उन्होंने कहा कि अडिशनल वैल्यू ऑफर करने वाले LTE फीचर फोन को और आकर्षक तरीके में पैक्ड किया जाना चाहिए। साथ ही उन्हें बढ़ते डेटा मार्केट के हिसाब से टियर-III लोकेशंस और रूरल एरिया में बेचा जाना चाहिए।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Correct Aadhaar, PAN Details Online</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-aadhaar-pan-details-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-correct-aadhaar-pan-details-online/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tax department has launched facilities to correct errors in PAN, Aadhaar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The income tax department has urged taxpayers to link Aadhaar with PAN immediately. This will be useful for e-verification of income tax returns using OTP (one-time password) sent to their mobile registered with Aadhaar, the tax department said. In this regard, the income tax department has launched an online facility to link Aadhaar with PAN, In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided by taxpayer when compared to the actual data in Aadhaar, One Time Password (Aadhaar OTP) will be sent to the mobile registered with Aadhaar. In rare cases where Aadhaar name is completely different from name in PAN, then the linking will fail and taxpayer will be prompted to change the name in either Aadhaar or in PAN database, the tax department said. For the benefit of taxpayers, the income tax department has launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IT department has launched an online facility to link Aadhaar with PAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor mismatches in Aadhaar name and PAN name can be fixed with an OTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In rare cases a user will be prompted to change name in Aadhaar or PAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department has also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website - &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; - one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/graph_650x400_51494824521.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/pan_650x400_41494824562.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;2) The second hyperlink is for individuals who want to update Aadhaar details by logging into &amp;lsquo;Aadhaar Self Service Update Portal&amp;rsquo; using the unique identity number. The individual can then upload scanned documents as proof for correcting data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The income tax department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has a new link on its homepage for connecting Aadhaar with PAN of a taxpayer.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/graph_650x400_51494824644.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;4) There is no need to log in or be registered on e-filing website of the income tax department. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The link requires a person to key in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact&amp;rdquo; name as mentioned on the Aadhaar card. After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR). Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN or permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trai Releases An App Which Lets You Rate Call Quality</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sector regulator Trai today said it will soon roll-out an app that enables subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call. The &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app would be available by the end of this month, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) chairman RS Sharma said at &amp;lsquo;Digital Broadcasting in India - Way Forward&amp;rsquo;, a seminar to commemorate the completion of 20 years of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We would like the consumers to assess the quality of calls, through &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app, which will be rolled out by this month end,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, once downloaded, the new app would give the subscribers the choice of assessing the quality of all or a portion of calls. When the call is completed, the users will be able to rate it, and the data will thereafter be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The application will pop up a window and enquire about the quality of the call. The subscriber can give it one star to five stars. There will also be assessment parameters like whether the call was indoors or outside or while travelling,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government and the regulator have refused to lower their guard on the issue of call drops, and have kept a close watch on call quality through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.
Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops. The system is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trai through its analytics portal has also rolled out initiatives that measure data speeds and maps call drops in India, which is the world&amp;rsquo;s second largest telecom market with 1.12 billion mobile subscribers.
Sharma today said that Trai also plans to &amp;ldquo;strengthen&amp;rdquo; the &amp;lsquo;Do Not Disturb&amp;rsquo; or DND service aimed at blocking pesky calls by telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already done a lot of work in this,&amp;rdquo; Sharma said, but refused to elaborate on the upcoming plans. At present, there is a framework for DND registry that allows telecom subscribers to block unwanted communication from telemarketers. Reaching out to such subscribers can result in a heavy fine for telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source familiar with the initiative said that the regulator may look at building specific intelligence features into the system such that pesky messages with certain key words could automatically generate a prompt on whether the users wishes to report the message as a spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the occasion, Communications Minister Manoj Sinha said TRAI&amp;rsquo;s regulatory framework has provided a conducive environment for the sector&amp;rsquo;s growth. It has made the sector more competitive and enhanced accessibility of services at affordable tariffs, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awareness of the some of the main challenges faced by the sector and regulatory framework of today - ranging from convergence to the persisting issue of the digital divide - is therefore necessary to be better equipped to handle these challenges in future,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-facility to link Aadhaar with PAN launched</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I-T Department asks people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched an e-facility to link Aadhaar with Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing IT returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department’s e-filing website &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; has created the link on its homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires the PAN, the Aadhaar number and the “exact name as given in the Aadhaar card”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After verification from the UIDAI [Unique Identification Authority of India], the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in the Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP [one time password] will be required,” the department said in an advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OTP would be sent on the registered mobile number and email of an individual, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department urged people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no need to login or be registered on the e-filing website. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of the Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a 10-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>99 देशों पर साइबर अटैक: चपेट में ये देसी कंपनियां एवं सरकारी संस्थान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;दुनियाभर के 99 देशों पर हुए साइबर अटैक की चपेट में देश की कई कंपनियां भी आ गईं। रैनसमवेअर वानाक्राइ से प्रभावित हुईं कंपनियों में दो दक्षिण भारतीय बैंक, दिल्ली की दो मैन्युफैक्चरिंग कंपनियां, बहुराष्ट्रीय कंपनी (एमएनसी) की एक मैन्युफैक्चरिंग यूनिट, मुंबई की एक दिग्गज कंपनी और एक एफएमसीजी कंपनी के मुख्यालय शामिल हैं। इनके अलावा, आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के 100 से ज्यादा कंप्यूटर भी इस भयावह हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुरक्षा विशेषज्ञों का मानना है कि इस हमले से हुआ नुकसान और ज्यादा हो सकता है और प्रभावित कंपनियों की तादाद बढ़ सकती है। चूंकि यह हमला वीकेंड में (शुक्रवार को) हुआ है, इसलिए नुकसान का सही-सही आकलन सोमवार को ही किया जा सकता है जब सारे पर्सनल कंप्यूटर्स स्टार्ट किए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EY इंडिया में पाटर्नर (फ्रॉड इन्वेस्टिगेशन ऐंड डिस्प्यूट सर्विसेज) मुकुल श्रीवास्तव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;भारतीय कंपनियां हालिया हमले की चपेट में आई हैं। पिछले एक साल में रैनसमवेअर के मामले बहुत बढ़ गए हैं। अब साइबर क्रिमिनल्स बेहद टेक सेवी हो चुके हैं और हरेक रैनसमवेअर की अपनी यूनीक एन्क्रिप्टिंग मशीनें हैं। ये हमले लगातार बाधा पहुंचाने और फिरौती वसूलने के मकसद से हो रहे हैं। इसलिए संगठनों को ऐसे खतरों का सामना करने के लिए गंभीर उपाय करने होंगे। हम साइबरक्राइम और रैनसमवेअर के खिलाफ समाधान प्रक्रिया में कई देसी एवं वैश्विक कंपनियों के साथ काम कर रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जाल में ऐसे फंसाते हैं हैकर्स, रहें सावधान&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;शुक्रवार को मैलवेअर बड़ी तेजी से फैल गया और दुनियाभर की कंपनियों एवं सरकारी संगठनों में कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए। दरअसल, रैनसमवेअर के डाउनलोड होते ही सभी कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए और उनमें पड़े डेटा एन्क्रिप्ट कर लिए गए। हमलावर ने इन डेटा को रीस्टोर करने के लिए फिरौती की मांग की।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनियां ऐसे हमलों से निपटने के लिए देश के जिन साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर कर रही हैं, उनके मुताबिक ऐसे कई मामले सामने आए हैं जब भारतीय कंपनियों ने अपने प्रभावित कंप्यूटरों को दुबारा ऐक्सेस करने के एवज में फिरौती दी। यूके की नैशनल हेल्थ सर्विसेज (एनएसएस) जैसे वैश्विक संस्थान और रेनॉ, फेडेक्स एवं टेलिफोनिका जैसी कंपनियों ने हमले से प्रभावित होने की जानकारी दी, लेकिन देश की एक भी कंपनी ने नहीं बताया कि उनके कंप्यूटर हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के कंप्यूटरों पर साइबर हमले, फिरौती मांग रहे हैकर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक्सपर्ट्स का कहना है कि शुक्रवार को फैलाया गया मैलवेअर अमेरिका की नैशनल सिक्यॉरिटी एजेंसी का वही इटरनलब्लू टूल है जिसे अप्रैल महीने में द शैडो ब्रॉकर्स नाम के हैकर ग्रुप ने चुरा लिया था। दिग्गज साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी कंपनी अवास्ट ने कहा कि उसने रैनसमवेअर और इसके विभिन्न रूपों के 75,000 मामले देखे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी एक्सपर्ट ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इस हमला कुछ अलग है। इससे कोई एक बार इन्फेक्ट हो गया तो हो गया। इसे हटाने के लिए तीन से चार घंटे लगेंगे और पीसी रीबूट करना पड़ेगा। हालांकि, इसमें कोई नुकसान या कोई डेटा खत्म नहीं होता।&amp;rsquo; साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स के मुताबिक, भारतीय कंपनियों पर रैनसमवेअर अटैक्स के मामले में एक सिलिसला सा जुड़ रहा है। पिछले तीन महीनों में 25 से 30 ऐसे मामले सामने आ चुके हैं जब कंपनियां मैलवेअर का शिकार हुई हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBSE affiliated schools to be made Aadhaar centres</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to ensure that all students have unique identification number to be enrolled, the Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) recently directed all its affiliated schools to set up Aadhaar enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To implement this, the board has collaborated with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) to collect demographic and biometric data of residents directly or through enrolment agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-on-the-report&#34;&gt;More on the report:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, schools are free to decide whether or not to set up the centres&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if a school wishes to set up an Aadhaar centre, then they can do so by signing a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with either the Board or UIDAI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, the board has asked schools to procure equipment for the purpose as per the UIDAI check list&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reasons-behind-this-step&#34;&gt;Reasons behind this step:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As reported, this move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-cbse-said-in-its-notice&#34;&gt;Here’s what CBSE said in its notice:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools shall set up enrolment centres to facilitate their bonafide students, teachers, staff and their family members to to enrol for Aadhar and make any updation or corrections,” it said in a communication to schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Equipment such as computer, printer, biometric devices and other such things will have to be procured by the school themselves and should be as per the UIDAI specifications,” as reported in a recent PTI report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to encourage students to enroll themselves, the schools will not be charging any fees for the Aadhaar enrolment; but CBSE will pay them Rs 30 for every enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the February 2017 data of the board, there are 18,546 CBSE affiliated schools in India and 210 schools in 25 foreign countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, the schools will also be required to adhere to all code of conducts applicable to other enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1,000 Each Month For 20 Years Is Now Rs. 26,00,000 In This Fund</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DSP BlackRock Equity Fund recently completed 20 years of its existence. The fund (dividend option) has delivered 20.65 per cent compound annual growth rate since its inception, outperforming the 13 per cent return of Nifty50 index by a huge margin, says its website. The objective of DSP BlackRock Equity Fund is to seek to generate long-term capital appreciation, from a portfolio that is substantially constituted of equity securities and equity related securities of issuers domiciled in India. DSP BlackRock Equity Fund benchmarks itself against NIFTY 500 index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you consider the NIFTY 500, DSP BlackRock Equity Fund has also outperformed this index by a big margin. NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you had invested Rs 1,000 in the fund each month since its inception? Now you would be sitting on a corpus of nearly Rs 26 lakh as compared to your invested amount of Rs 2.41 lakh crore. If you had invested Rs 4,000 each month, it would have been over a crore now. Returns for investments in dividend plans of schemes are calculated after assuming that the net dividend payouts post statutory taxes &amp;amp; levies, are re-invested back in the scheme. As of March 31, 2017, the fund had assets worth Rs 2,310 crore under management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the country&amp;rsquo;s mutual fund industry managed an asset base of over Rs 18 lakh crore. Mutual funds are investment vehicles made up of a pool of funds collected from a large number of investors. The funds are invested in stocks, bonds and money market instruments, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inflows into domestic equity mutual funds have helped Sensex and Nifty rise to record levels. According to estimates domestic investors are pouring in Rs 4,000 crore every month into equity mutual funds through systematic investment route. Systematic Investment Plans or SIPs are fixed amounts invested at regular intervals in a financial instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Hiring For Marketing Department. Check Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-hiring-for-marketing-department-check-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-hiring-for-marketing-department-check-details/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For SBI&amp;rsquo;s recruitment, the online registration of application and payment of fees which commenced on May 12 will end on May 25.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, State Bank of India (SBI) is inviting recruitment applications for its marketing department. SBI is asking to hire one person each for five different posts which are: Senior Vice President (Brand/Media/Research), Vice President (Marketing Communications), Vice President (Digital Marketing), Vice President (Media Strategy and Operations) and Senior Manager (Digital Marketing). These specialists in the marketing field will be hired on a contract basis. The online registration of application and payment of fees which commenced on May 12 will end on May 25. The last date for receipt of print out of the application along with enclosures is May 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contract, which is for a period of three years, will be renewable at the discretion of the bank. The contract can be terminated at one month&amp;rsquo;s notice on either side or on payment/surrender of one month&amp;rsquo;s compensation amount. While applying for the post, the applicant should ensure that he/she fulfils the eligibility and other norms and that the particulars furnished by him/her are correct in all respects. Also, candidates are required to have a valid email ID which should be kept active during the recruitment exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-the-selection-procedure&#34;&gt;What is the selection procedure?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The selection procedure of candidates will be based on short listing (qualification, experience and overall suitability) and personal interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;application-fee&#34;&gt;Application fee:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application fee (non-refundable) is of Rs 600 and the payment needs to be done online. Application fee once paid will not be refunded nor can it be adjusted for any other examination or selection in future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UDAN Funding: Government Brings Down Levy To Rs 5,000</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/udan-funding-government-brings-down-levy-to-rs-5-000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/udan-funding-government-brings-down-levy-to-rs-5-000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) &amp;ndash; the Civil Aviation Ministry is collecting a levy of up to Rs 8,500 per departure from airlines operating in major domestic routes, including Mumbai and Delhi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has decided to reduce the regional air connectivity levy charged from airlines flying on major routes to a uniform rate of Rs 5,000 per flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fund the ambitious regional connectivity scheme &amp;ndash; UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) &amp;ndash; the Civil Aviation Ministry is collecting a levy of up to Rs 8,500 per departure from airlines operating in major domestic routes, including Mumbai and Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a senior official, the ministry has decided to bring down the levy amount to a uniform rate of Rs 5,000 per flight on major routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move comes at a time when the government is looking to &amp;ldquo;refine&amp;rdquo; the present norms for UDAN ahead of the second round of bidding which is likely in three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With at least half of the seats in UDAN flights offered at subsidised fares, the participating carriers would be provided a certain amount of Viability Gap Funding (VGF) &amp;ndash; an amount shared between the Centre and the states concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The levy is being collected towards the VGF. The Federation of Indian Airlines (FIA) has already challenged the collection of levy from carriers for the RCS fund in the court. Jet Airways, IndiGo, SpiceJet and GoAir are members of the FIA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry started collecting the levy from December 1, 2016. Airports Authority of India (AAI) is the nodal agency for UDAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about local carriers moving court against the levy, AAI Chairman Guruprasad Mohapatra recently told PTI that he hoped that the issue would be resolved soon even as he asserted that the scheme would not suffer due to court case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The scheme will not be affected by virtue of this dispute&amp;hellip;These are all government of India schemes and they don&amp;rsquo;t suffer on account of some court cases. They are sovereign commitments,&amp;rdquo; he had said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, UDAN scheme commenced with the first flight starting from Shimla to the national capital. In the first round of UDAN bidding, five airlines won bids to operate on 128 routes connecting 70 airports of which 31 are un-served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;(Before) the second round of bidding, we will further refine (the scheme) after extensive stakeholder consultations,&amp;rdquo; Mohapatra had said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पेट्रोल पंप मालिकों ने वापस लिया संडे को छुट्टी का प्रस्ताव</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-took-back-the-proposal-of-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-took-back-the-proposal-of-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;देशभर के पेट्रोल पंप मालिकों ने 14 मई से रविवार के प्रस्तावित साप्ताहिक अवकाश और 15 मई से एक शिफ्ट में पंपों के संचालन का फैसला शनिवार को वापस ले लिया। एक आधिकारिक बयान जारी कर यह जानकारी दी गई।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फेडरेशन ऑफ ऑल महाराष्ट्र पेट्रोल डीलर्स असोसिएशन (एफएएमपीईडीए) के अध्यक्ष उदय लोध ने कहा कि तेल विपणन कंपनियों (ओमसी) द्वारा बुधवार को बुलाई गई समीक्षा बैठक में अगली सूचना तक प्रस्तावित विरोध प्रदर्शन को स्थगित करने का फैसला लिया गया। एफएएमपीईडी सहित भारत के पेट्रोल डीलर्स के गुट (सीआईपीडी) ने महाराष्ट्र, कर्नाटक, केरल, तमिलनाडु, पुडुचेरी, आंध्र प्रदेश, तेलंगाना और हरियाणा में &amp;lsquo;कॉस्ट कटिंग मॉड्यूल&amp;rsquo; लांच करने की योजना बनाई है। लोध ने कहा कि प्रस्तावित कदम से महाराष्ट्र में ही 4,500 पेट्रोल पंप प्रभावित होते, जिनमें मुंबई में ही 225 पेट्रोल पंप हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एफएएमपीईडीए यह प्रस्तावित अवकाश सीआईपीडी के आह्वान पर ओमसी से की गई मांगों के समर्थन में शुरू करने जा रही थी। सीआईपीडी काफी समय से ओएमसी से डीलर्स मार्जिन बढ़ाने सहित कई मांगें कर रही है। लोध ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमें पिछले साल नवंबर में तेल कंपनियों से हुए समझौते पर चर्चा करने के लिए अगले बुधवार को बुलाया गया है इसलिए तब तक हमने विरोध प्रदर्शन को स्थगित करने का फैसला किया है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा कि पेट्रोल पंपों को इस समय काफी कम मार्जिन मिल रहा है। उन्नत किस्म का सीसा रहित पेट्रोल और डीजल बहुत तेजी से वाष्पित होता है, जिससे काफी घाटा सहना पड़ता है। लोध ने कहा कि इसके अलावा भी कई मुद्दे हैं, हर पेट्रोल पंप पर कर्मचारियों को न्यूनतम वेतन देना संभव नहीं है। पेट्रोल पंपों द्वारा रविवार को अवकाश करने और शेष दिन एक शिफ्ट में पंप का संचालन करने के फैसले से महाराष्ट्र में ही करीब एक लाख कामगार प्रभावित होते, जो अमूमन रोज दो शिफ्ट में काम करते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>