<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 19 To Rs 9,999: What Jio Prepaid, Postpaid Users Get</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-19-to-rs-9999-what-jio-prepaid-postpaid-users-get/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio is offering free voice calls and roaming on all its post-paid and pre-paid plans. Also there is no charge for data used to make 4G voice calls under all its plans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. Beyond the daily 4G data limits of 1GB and 2GB per day across its prepaid recharges and postpaid plans, wherever specified, subscribers will continue to use unlimited internet at a reduced speed of 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service - prepaid and postpaid alike - include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are various plans offered by Jio, as per its website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREPAID&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for just one day, Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid offerings start from the Rs 19 recharge, which includes 200 MB of 4G data for Prime members and 100 MB for non-Prime members, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 49&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s next recharge is priced at Rs 49. Jio Prime members recharging with the Rs 49 voucher get 600 MB of high speed data over a validity of three days. The 4G data on offer under this pack is limited to 300 MB for non-Prime members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 96&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valid for seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge comes with 1GB of 4G data per day. That is for Prime members. Non-Prime members get 600MB of 4G data for seven days with a recharge of Rs 96.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 149&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data valid for 28 days for Prime users and 1GB for non-Prime subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime subscribers buying their first recharge of Rs 309 will get 1GB of 4G data per day for 84 days, as per the Jio website. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first recharge of Rs 509 offers 2GB of 4G data daily, for 84 days. This is comparable with half of the daily 4G data on offer in the Rs 309 pack. Data benefits on subsequent recharges of Rs 509 will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Rs 999 recharge comes with a validity of 120 days, in which subscribers get 120 GB of 4G data. Subsequent recharges are limited to 60 GB of 4G data for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A first recharge of Rs 1,999 comes with 185 GB of 4G data and validity of 150 days. The 4G data on offer is 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 4,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those buying their first recharge after subscribing to Prime will get 410 GB of 4G data with a validity of 240 days. Users will get 350 GB of 4G data with a validity of 180 days on subsequent recharges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is priced at Rs. 9,999. Those buying their first recharge of Rs 9,999 are being offered 810 GB of 4G data with a validity of 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;postpaid&#34;&gt;POSTPAID&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 309&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First cycle: Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data per day - which sums up to 90GB of 4G data - for a period of three months under this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequent cycle: Customers will get 30GB of 4G data for a period of one month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 509&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering 2GB of 4G data per day for a period of three months on the first cycle, and one month on subsequent cycles. Therefore, users get 180GB of 4G data for three months in the first cycle, and 60GB for one month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs 999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first cycle, Jio is offering 180 GB of 4G data for three months under the Rs 999 postpaid plan. Users will get 60 GB of 4G data per month on subsequent cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian ISRAELI-ORIGIN GUNS: INDIA WILL SOON START MAKING THESE FIVE DEADLY GUNS</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arming-india-india-will-soon-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arming-india-india-will-soon-start/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;From India&amp;rsquo;s first private small arms manufacturing unit based at Malanpur, M.P., India, and Israel will manufacture lethal Israeli guns for the Indian armed forces and the world. This has been made possible through a joint venture between Indian defence conglomerate, Punj Lloyd, and Israel Weapon Industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As clearly stated by Army Chief General Bipin Rawat there is a need to invest more in the military, in view of emerging security threats. And these are the guns that will add to the capabilities of the armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/FmkUwDRSdI8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;tavor&#34;&gt;Tavor&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Besides the Israel Defence Forces, it is being used across the world, including by the US and the Special Forces of the Indian Army, Navy and IAF. This weapon was also used during the surgical strikes in POK. The Special Frontier Force (SFF), a covert special operations unit, created with the help of the CIA post the 1962 India-China war, is also using them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bullpup-configuration&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Bullpup Configuration&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bullpup configuration&amp;rdquo; makes it compact, perfect for counter-terrorist operations in built up areas such as J&amp;amp;K.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves gun&amp;rsquo;s accuracy and reduces weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable at all firing positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrosion resistant metal parts. Easily maintainable in adverse battle conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses 5.56mm cartridges, as adopted by NATO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The capacity of 30 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Punj Lloyd pitching it as a replacement for INSAS rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;negev-light-machine-gun&#34;&gt;Negev Light Machine Gun&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Negev_NG7_Light_Machine_Gun.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A robust light machine gun with powerful target acquisition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopted by the Israeli Defence Forces in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also has a semi-automatic mode to provide accurate, controlled fire in close quarter battle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic mode for maximum firepower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mountable&#34;&gt;Mountable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negev cartridges are placed in the gun from a belt, which can contain up to 200 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses 5.56 mm and 7.65 mm cartridges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has different variants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Known to be a reliable weapon under extreme conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important feature: Can be mounted on inside helicopters, over vehicles and naval vessels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gun being used by the Indian armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;galil-sniper&#34;&gt;Galil Sniper&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Galil_Sniper_Rifle.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can hit targets up to 1 km away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even at this range will fire accurately at targets, which are small and mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With this weapon, combat units gain efficiency in firing at long range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The semi-automatic feature ensures it is stable while firing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7.65mm calibre and has a capacity of 10 to 25 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foldable bipod makes it suitable for user&amp;rsquo;s needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;raw-s-aim&#34;&gt;RAW&amp;rsquo;s Aim&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galil sniper being used by the covert RAW unit, Special Frontier Force, and Indian Army.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Army has been searching for sniper rifles for infantry units and Special Forces to replace the Russian Dragunov sniper rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Army&amp;rsquo;s aim is to get the new sniper rifle with greater range, accuracy, and firepower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian Navy&amp;rsquo;s MARCOS also using the rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galil is a family of small arms named after its designer, Yisrael Galil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;world-manufacturing-hub&#34;&gt;World Manufacturing Hub&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/IWI_Punj_Lloyd_Small_Arms_Plant.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Picture of the inauguration of the small arms plant at Malanpur by Madhya Pradesh Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mark Shachar, V.P. Business Development, S K Group, explained the plant will be a hub of manufacturing the weapons for the Indian armed forces and will also export them. &amp;ldquo;We will also make the plant a centre of maintenance for these guns for India and abroad,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Facility Launched To Link Aadhaar With PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax Department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing income tax returns (ITRs) now. The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals. The link requires a person to punch in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact name as given in the Aadhaar
card&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number and email of the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It urged them to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linking without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no need to login or be registered on e-filing website (of the I-T department). This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for a permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 crore Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The biggest privacy risk is your smartphone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-privacy-risk-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biggest-privacy-risk-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Former UIDAI chairman Nandan Nilekani dispels privacy concerns surrounding Aadhaar and bats for biometric data protection and privacy laws in India&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks and months have witnessed a steady stream of negative news surrounding Aadhaar, the government’s unique identity number programme, with wide-ranging concerns being raised on the security of the system and the potential leakage of Aadhaar numbers by government departments. The government also received flak for making Aadhaar mandatory for filing income tax returns. Then there are issues with the technology itself—the Aadhaar biometric authentication failure rate in the rural job guarantee scheme was as high as 36% in Telangana, as reported by Mint in April.
In an interview, Infosys co-founder and former Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) chairman Nandan Nilekani, the creator of Aadhaar, dispelled most of the concerns surrounding Aadhaar, especially around the security of the system, but conceded that there are areas where it can improve, while calling for the creation of a data-protection and privacy law. Edited excerpts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How big a problem is the current situation with the lack of a privacy law?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very clear that India needs a very modern privacy and data-protection law. And I’ve been saying this far longer than most people. Sometime in May of 2010, I wrote to Prime Minister Manmohan Singh that we should have a privacy law. And I followed that up. I asked Rahul Matthan (partner at Trilegal and a Mint columnist) and he helped. He worked with the department of administrative reforms and came out with a draft law and subsequently there was a committee under Justice A.P. Shah, and one of my colleagues (at UIDAI) Ashok Pal Singh was a member of that committee. They contributed to the framing of the principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue I have with the current narrative is, why should Aadhaar be singled out as a reason for the law? The biggest privacy risk that you have is your smartphone. A billion people will have smartphones as we go forward, their conversations will be recorded, their messages will be read, their location can be identified with the GPS or the triangulation of the towers on a real-time basis. So, for 24 hours a day, you know where a person is. Using all the accelerometers and gyrometers on the phone, you can actually make out if someone is drunk or not. The kind of intrusion of privacy that the smartphone does is order of magnitudes higher. Aadhaar is a sporadic thing—it is episodic, for instance, when I go and open an account, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second big privacy risk that we have are CCTV cameras—there doesn’t seem to be a law on these things. Every mall, every retailer, every ATM, every bus-stand, every railway station, every airport, every hotel has a CCTV camera. And now, we have CCTV combined with face recognition technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, we have the Internet companies and data collection. Indians are essentially giving data to companies that are essentially unaccountable to Indian law and that data is often shared with foreign governments as we have seen, time and again. There is more risk of Indians sharing data with foreign governments, than their own government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there are drones, or the Internet of Things, with sensors everywhere collecting data on you. So, when you look at it, there is a data tsunami that is coming due to a variety of things—(it has) nothing to do with Aadhaar as such. Given that, we should have a data-protection and privacy law which is an umbrella law, which looks at all these phenomena and certainly Aadhaar and the use of Aadhaar should be part of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s perfectly fine—but people are acting as if Aadhaar is the only reason why we should have a privacy law. That’s where I have a problem. We have a far bigger risk today from a cell-phone than Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why are we witnessing such reluctance from the government in terms of creating this legal framework around Aadhaar?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to have an internal champion in the system who will take it forward. It cuts across everything. There are a lot of stakeholder interests inside the government—so, it requires someone to champion it and lead it. In any case, we need a very modern data-protection law—data generation has become so huge now; all the current constructs of data laws were designed 10-15 years ago. If you look at the work happening in Europe with the generalized data protection regulations which come into effect next year, it was actually designed pre-big data. So, how do we design it (a privacy law) so that it operates in this massive data which is coming out of sensors, phones, etc? We need to rethink the entire concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These (current) laws were designed for a different era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Concerns have been raised around how Aadhaar is facilitating the creation of an Orwellian sort of surveillance state…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, this is another attempt to criticize and (create) this notion that Aadhaar is an instrument of mass surveillance. It’s complete nonsense. Your smartphone is a much better tool for the government to do surveillance than Aadhaar. Because Aadhaar by nature is episodic. I open a bank account once in a while. I buy a SIM card once in a while. If I use it for payments, I’ll use for low-value payments; I’ll use other means of authentication. So, it’s not really surveillance. By definition, a surveillance system is collecting data about you. The Aadhaar system does not collect data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s no limit to the amount of data the system can collect on individuals…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the Aadhaar system is concerned, what enters the system is very limited information and when you do an Aadhaar authentication, the Aadhaar authentication does not even know for what purpose that authentication has happened. It has been deliberately designed like that. Suppose I use it to do a financial transaction in a bank, the bank knows the financial transaction, but the Aadhaar system does not know. It’s deliberately designed like that. Real surveillance happens when data is accumulated which is what is happening in many organizations and that data is a black box. Nobody knows what’s happening with that data. And on top of that, you have black-box algorithms operating, which is what is happening. We have no idea what algorithms are being used today to feed you news or whatever. That is where the risks are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What happens in the event of a data breach? Unlike a credit card, one cannot block the Aadhaar card.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the Aadhaar system is extremely well-designed. It’s not an online system that is exposed to the Internet. When the enrolment happens, the packet is encrypted at source and sent, so that there can’t be a man-in-the-middle attack. And when the authentication happens, that is also encrypted—not compared to the original data, but to a digital minutiae. The point is that the system is very, very secure. So, if the objection is to centralization, then you should not have clouds. Clouds are also centralized. Everything today is centralized—otherwise, let’s all go back to pen and paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s a realization that we have this extraordinary transformation in governance platform—so, there is the willingness to use this platform to achieve more”- Nandan Nilekani
The point is that on Aadhaar authentication, a number of things are happening that make it even more secure because UIDAI has over the past couple of years come out with an architecture that is called registered devices. And registered devices have level-zero and level-one. Level-zero is software-based and level-one is hardware-based. Increasingly what is happening is that biometrics is now becoming common to every phone. When you’re using your phone, you’re giving your biometric to some company. For example, if you look at the latest Samsung Galaxy 8, it has something called Fort Knox—it’s a secure zone. So, secure hardware zones are now going to be standard in most of these—and this is military-grade security. So, in hardware-based registered devices, the biometric authentication details are captured and encrypted there itself. So that makes it even better and more secure. And the government or the Reserve Bank of India can say that all payment transactions should be only on level-one registered devices. So, it’s a continuous game of making things more and more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s also a perception of a general lack of transparency in terms of sharing concrete data from the UIDAI on how the system has done more good than harm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, every RTI (request under the Right to Information law) has been responded to. But I think the Aadhaar authentication with registered devices, especially with hardware-registered devices, will make it even more safe. The Aadhaar law limits what organizations can do when they do an eKYC (electronic Know Your Customer, a process of verifying the identity of customers) with the Aadhaar number. That law has to be rigorously enforced. The Aadhaar law is a very good law—in fact, the Aadhaar law has more privacy kind of details than most laws have. But I agree we need an overall data-protection and privacy law which covers everything, including foreign companies collecting data in India, including drones, Internet of Things, people reading your emails, smartphones, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But doesn’t the system need to be held accountable in the event of a breach of data? That doesn’t seem to be happening—for instance, a lot of things are being done in the name of national security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everywhere in the world national security exceptions are there. Everywhere in the world, the tension is between privacy and security because the security guys feel that if there is a criminal action, they should get access. Now, most countries do provide under national security, the ability to access very specific information—which is provided for in the Aadhaar law… I think instead of attacking Aadhaar which is a negative activity, everyone should get together and get the (privacy) law passed, which is a positive activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Given the developments of the past few weeks and months, is the Aadhaar law in need of an overhaul? Does the legal framework around Aadhaar need to be re-examined to ensure that the scope of the program is not abused?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aadhaar law which was passed in 2016 governs the UIDAI’s authority, which as I said has better privacy protection than any other law that I can think of and it has a lot of checks and balances. That’s one part. Then there’s the use of Aadhaar which is done by other laws. For example, in the Finance Bill, they say Aadhaar should be mandatory for PAN (permanent account number) Card. That’s got nothing to do with Aadhaar, that’s a legal provision in another law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are broadly four purposes to the use of Aadhaar: first, the feature of Aadhaar, which is unique only to Aadhaar and no other system, is that it gives a unique ID across a billion people—you can be sure that somebody does not have more than one ID; second, Aadhaar is used to do direct benefit transfer by sending money to the Aadhaar number which in turn is linked to a bank where your account is; third, Aadhaar is as an online authentication system; and the fourth use of Aadhaar is as an electronic KYC where I give permission to the Aadhaar system to release my name and address to the bank and I get an instant bank account or an instant SIM card. So, four very different uses of one platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first use has a used case in both benefits as well as documents. In benefits, you want to eliminate ghosts and duplicates. You want to make sure there are no fake pensioners, etc. We’ve already seen the value of the savings that the government has got. The government has said that the savings is somewhere around Rs49,000 crore. The total investment in Aadhaar is around Rs8,000-9,000 crore. The impact is there to be seen….a variation of the duplicate problem is in documents. India has 250 million PAN (cards). And only 40 million Indians are paying taxes. Why should there be 250 million PAN (cards) and only 40 million taxpayers? Many people have taken PAN for ID proof. But even when you discount the people who have PAN for ID, there are still many duplicate PAN (cards). The reason is that there are people who want to evade taxes. But having the Aadhaar number de-duplicate PAN numbers you’re actually making sure that a guy has only one PAN number and that will help in eliminating tax evasion, so that’s a good social purpose. Similarly, the mobile phone using Aadhaar-eKYC actually came out of a Supreme Court decision. Now, in the old days, you used to submit a copy of your passport or an ID proof, to get a SIM card. Now, that’s even more unsafe—because that fellow now has all your data. Secondly, 10 other people will get a SIM using your details—you don’t know. Even though we have a billion phones, we have about 600 million unique users, is my estimate. And even in that, how many of them have given a genuine ID to get a phone? I don’t know. The same story is playing out with driving licences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is still concern around all this data being centralized…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, the data is not in one system—that’s the whole point. The data is in respective systems. The Aadhaar number is in the PAN database. The PAN number is not in the Aadhaar database… that’s the point. The Aadhaar database does not have any data. This is a conscious design choice, which is why to say that the system is for surveillance makes no sense. The nature of surveillance requires you to collect data. This does not collect data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But then why is Aadhaar become all-pervasive? Why is Aadhaar being made mandatory for everyone?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, there’s a realization that we have this extraordinary transformation in governance platform—so, there is the willingness to use this platform to achieve more. All the goals that we’ve identified are all the things that improve governance: making sure there’s one PAN card reduces tax evasion; making sure that a person has done a proper KYC reduces criminality and terrorism; making sure that a person has only one driver’s licence makes it easier to enforce the rules of the road, which makes it safer for you and me to travel on the roads… So everything that has been done is being done to ensure that it enhances the quality of governance. Now if the concern is of privacy, I’ve made my position clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Instead of attacking Aadhaar, which is a negative activity, everyone should get together and get the (privacy) law passed, which is a positive activity.”- Nandan Nilekani
In everything in life, there’s always a trade-off between privacy and convenience. There’s no absolute privacy, there’s no absolute convenience. In our view, the benefits of the Aadhaar system to individuals and society far outweigh the inconvenience or the risk. Everything in life is a risk. You always see how you balance these out. But the benefits here are so huge, it’s worth anything—and obviously the obligation of the Aadhaar system is to ensure that things are done properly and nobody is denied benefits. As technology evolves, you make things better and safer. Within seven years of its launch, the Aadhaar system has made a remarkable leap in terms of its security and privacy and it will keep improving. Technology does not come through immaculate conception. It has to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speaking of evolution, what are some of things that still need to be fixed in the system?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, I agree we need a privacy law, covering everything. Secondly, we need to implement (the concept of) registered devices as soon as possible. The first launch is by June… Also, the Aadhaar law already provides that anyone who uses the Aadhaar number cannot display the number or publish it, so that enforcement has to happen. We have to make sure that any user of this, whether it’s the government or the private sector, follows the law of (for?) the protection of the Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protection of numbers and preventing leakages have been a massive issue…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know the government has sent a notice to everyone. If somebody has done it, they ought not to have done it—there’s a law for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even with these kind of checks and balances, why are so many concerns being raised on the security of the system?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very safe. Security is an ongoing thing. You have to keep improving and getting better. You have to keep doing that and I’m sure the guys (at UIDAI) are aware of that. The methods followed here, the architecture, the encryption, the use of HSM (hardware security module)—all these are way above what we’ve seen anywhere. You saw what happened with debit cards in India—there the breach happened and wasn’t noticed for months. In the Aadhaar system, we’ve caught these guys within 24 hours. The point is, as I said, technology will keep getting better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Several experts on security have pointed out flaws in the system and said Aadhaar can be breached. There’s also a general sense that the UIDAI is being reluctant to invite people to help improve security or point out flaws.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to know which government system has been as open as UIDAI has. The kind of documentation that we have put out right from day 1, design documentation, architecture documentation, standards, etc—it’s incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something is built at scale, there will be points of view on that. And if there are any gaps, they have to be addressed. That’s how we move forward. But when it’s a motivated campaign where the agenda is something else, then you have to deal with it differently. I’m all for learning and reforming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>45GB Free Data On Amazon Exclusive Smartphones:Vodafone Offers </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-45gb-free-data-on-amazon-exclusive-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-45gb-free-data-on-amazon-exclusive-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the purchase of 1GB or above 4G data pack, users will get 9GB additional free 4G data for five recharges with maximum validity of five months from Vodafone, Amazon stated on its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major telecom players in India, Vodafone is offering 45GB of free data on the purchase of Amazon exclusive 4G smartphones. For the purchase of 1GB or above 4G data pack, users will get 9GB additional free 4G data for five recharges with maximum validity of five months from Vodafone, e-commerce firm Amazon stated on its website. The offer is only available on select smartphones. To avail the offer from Vodafone, one must purchase the Amazon exclusive handset till June 30. According to the website, the offer was started on May 11. (Click here to see the full list of smartphones which are applicable under the offer)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the smartphones included under the offer are Samsung On5 Pro, OnePlus 3T, Honor 6X and Moto G Play (4th Gen), among others. This free data offer cannot be cumulated with any other special discounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-how-users-can-avail-the-vodafone-offer&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how users can avail the Vodafone offer:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Insert Vodafone SIM in the new Amazon exclusive handset. You will get an activation message saying &amp;ldquo;You are eligible for Vodafone Amazon Buy 1GB or above pack and Get 9 GB for 5 Recharges with maximum validity of 5 months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For prepaid connections, recharge with 1GB or above pack, 9GB free data will get credited automatically. The 9GB free data is valid for 28 days only and a user can avail the offer up to five times or five months, whatever comes first. No special recharges and prices are applicable to get the free 9GB data offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For postpaid connections, user need to have 1GB or above rental plan, then 9GB free data will get attached within 48 hours. The 9GB Offer is valid for five billing cycles with a condition that the user has 1 GB or higher pack throughout the promotional period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea Cellular is also providing a similar offer in collaboration with Flipkart. It has announced 4G data offer with no daily limit and unlimited voice calling. Users purchasing a new 4G-enabled smartphone through Flipkart can avail up to 30GB of 4G data per month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBSE affiliated schools to be made Aadhaar centres</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to ensure that all students have unique identification number to be enrolled, the Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) recently directed all its affiliated schools to set up Aadhaar enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To implement this, the board has collaborated with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) to collect demographic and biometric data of residents directly or through enrolment agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-on-the-report&#34;&gt;More on the report:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, schools are free to decide whether or not to set up the centres&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if a school wishes to set up an Aadhaar centre, then they can do so by signing a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with either the Board or UIDAI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, the board has asked schools to procure equipment for the purpose as per the UIDAI check list&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reasons-behind-this-step&#34;&gt;Reasons behind this step:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As reported, this move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-cbse-said-in-its-notice&#34;&gt;Here’s what CBSE said in its notice:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools shall set up enrolment centres to facilitate their bonafide students, teachers, staff and their family members to to enrol for Aadhar and make any updation or corrections,” it said in a communication to schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Equipment such as computer, printer, biometric devices and other such things will have to be procured by the school themselves and should be as per the UIDAI specifications,” as reported in a recent PTI report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to encourage students to enroll themselves, the schools will not be charging any fees for the Aadhaar enrolment; but CBSE will pay them Rs 30 for every enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the February 2017 data of the board, there are 18,546 CBSE affiliated schools in India and 210 schools in 25 foreign countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, the schools will also be required to adhere to all code of conducts applicable to other enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: Aircel Offers 1 GB Of 3G Data At Rs. 76</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-aircel-offers-1-gb-of-3g-data-at-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-aircel-offers-1-gb-of-3g-data-at-rs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aircel is also offering full talk time or FTT benefits on a recharge of Rs. 86. It is also offering 100MB of data with the download of its Aircel App.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is offering its customers 1GB of 3G data at a price of Rs. 76 on its mobile app. Aircel, which last month announced free incoming calls on national roaming on its network across the country, is also offering additional 100MB of free data on recharges above Rs. 50, the telecom company said in a press release on Wednesday. &amp;ldquo;Tapping the increasing trend of customers choosing to recharge their phones online or through apps, Aircel&amp;hellip;has launched special Data and Calling packs on its mobile application,&amp;rdquo; the press release by Aircel noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1gb-rs-76&#34;&gt;1GB @ Rs. 76&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel&amp;rsquo;s 1GB of 3G data on offer in a recharge of Rs. 76 will come with a validity of 10 days, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The exciting offers are designed keeping the customer demands at the forefront and giving them best value offers with Aircel,&amp;rdquo; the company said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aircel has always worked to delight its customers and present them with value for money offers. Through apps, we know our customers, their plans, usage, and the services they are interested in, and hence have curated these products basis the trends observed,&amp;rdquo; Aircel chief marketing officer Anupam Vasudev said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some analysts say the aggressive pricing by Reliance Jio has led to high competition in the Indian telecom industry, forcing existing players to come up with lower tariffs and lucrative schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full talk time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is also offering full talk time or FTT benefits on a recharge of Rs. 86. It is also offering 100MB of data with the download of its Aircel App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel&amp;rsquo;s app - Aircel App-Recharge &amp;amp; BillPay - is available on Google Play (for Android users) and App Store (for iPhone users).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app successfully caters to the growing customer base and increasing data consumption, offering benefits like data loan and main balance recharge options which are industry&amp;rsquo;s first features on the app, Aircel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen great success in the past with such products and we feel that these App exclusive products will suit the convenience of our customers and assist them to stay seamlessly connected,&amp;rdquo; Mr Vasudev added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is a pan-India operator with 3G spectrum in 13 circles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs. 333: BSNL&#39;s New Plan To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 333, Rs. 339, Rs. 349 and Rs. 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL or Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited has announced three new data plans priced from Rs 333, the latest offering from the telecom operator seen as aimed at Jio&amp;rsquo;s Dhan Dhana Dhan plans. BSNL is offering up to 270 GB of 3G mobile data along with unlimited voice calls for a period of 90 days. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs 333 includes 3 GB per day of unlimited data, beyond which the speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps, the operator said. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing is causing intense competition in Indian telecom industry, forcing incumbent operators to offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attractive mobile data and unlimited voice calls plans, according to analysts. BSNL has also revised its existing Rs 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of data per day, instead of 2 GB earlier, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s revised Rs 339 pack, valid for 28 days, also includes unlimited local and inter-circle BSNL-to-BSNL calls. Calls to other networks are allowed with a limit of 25 minutes per day, beyond which BSNL customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 349 and Rs 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL had earlier launched yearly packs starting from Rs 1,498 and going up to Rs 4,498, which include 18 GB and 80 GB of data for 365 days, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>