<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs 333: BSNL Takes On Jio With New Prepaid Offers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnl-takes-on-jio-with-new-prepaid-offers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnl-takes-on-jio-with-new-prepaid-offers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special tariff voucher &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo;, priced at Rs. 349, comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive tariffs, BSNL has launched prepaid plans priced from Rs 333, under which it is offering 3GB of 3G data per day for up to three months. As part of its revised Rs 339 plan, BSNL is also offering 3GB of high speed data per day. &amp;ldquo;#BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new 333 &amp;amp; 339 STV&amp;rsquo;s offer there is nothing better than this!&amp;rdquo; state-run telecom company BSNL said on site Twitter. New entrant Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing has given rise to a highly competitive Indian telecom market, pushing incumbent players to revise their existing offerings to protect market share, some analysts say. &amp;ldquo;The price war in the Rs 1.5-trillion wireless telecom market will continue this fiscal year as well leaving bruised bottom lines,&amp;rdquo; Crisil&amp;rsquo;s said in a note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333 special tariff voucher, called &amp;ldquo;Triple ACE&amp;rdquo;, comes with a validity of three months and offers 3GB of 3G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-of-the-other-offerings-by-bsnl&#34;&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 339&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL users subscribing to the Rs 339 voucher will now get 3 GB of 3G data, which is high-speed data, per day, instead of 2 GB earlier. The Rs 339 plan - which comes with a validity of 28 days - includes unlimited local and STD BSNL-to-BSNL calls and 25 minutes of local and inter-circle calls made to other networks, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s special tariff voucher &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo;, priced at Rs. 349, comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs. 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all four plans - &lt;em&gt;Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 395 and Rs 375&lt;/em&gt;, the internet or data speed is reduced to 80 Kbps after a subscriber exhausts the daily 3G limit, BSNL has said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60% People Facing Frequent Call Drops: Telecom Department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/facing-frequent-call-drops-telecom-department-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/facing-frequent-call-drops-telecom-department-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Out of 3.56 lakh subscribers surveyed across telecom service providers, 2.15 lakh (about 60 per cent) complained about frequent call drops.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 60 per cent people are still facing frequent call drops, with most of them experiencing problem indoors, found a survey by the Department of Telecom (DoT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of 3.56 lakh subscribers surveyed across telecom service providers, 2.15 lakh (about 60 per cent) complained about frequent call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DoT, however, made 26.97 lakh calls to subscribers of various telecom operators in the country, out of which only 3.56 lakh subscribers (about 13 per cent) participated in the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department also claimed that overall call drops have come down by 7 per cent in three months between December 2016 to March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Remaining 87 per cent subscribers, who did not participate, were either not willing or did not have problem of frequent call drops&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; the DoT said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the feedback, the DoT observed that the complaint is &amp;ldquo;mostly indoors&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback is shared with the telecom service providers (TSPs) to take corrective action in a time-bound manner and submit the action taken report (ATR) to DoT Task Force every fortnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;TSPs contact each subscriber, who has reported frequent call drops, through telephonic calls and SMS in English and local languages to collect further details required for resolution of the complaint,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On cumulative basis, since launch of Interactive Voice Response System (IVRS), telecom operators have resolved 13,631 cases related to the call drop issue and also resolved another 7,975 which were reported as frequent call drops but were found to be having other issues related to data, roaming, billing, MNP, mobile device etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of these, 1,406 cases were resolved through optimisation, rectifying hardware or power problems, through field visits etc during the fortnight March 15-31, 2017, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The call drops reported by subscribers have dropped from 64 per cent in December 2016 to 57 per cent at the end of March 2017, a drop of nearly 7 per cent in 3 months,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DoT said the government has facilitated telecom operators to identify black spots and plan new sites or infrastructure to improve their services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operators have planned 987 new sites and boosters out of which 109 have been already installed and commissioned, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At 110 Crore GB Data Traffic A Month, Jio&#39;s Offers For Its Prepaid Users</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-110-crore-gb-data-traffic-a-month-jios-offers-for-its-prepaid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries, is offering a number of recharge options to prepaid subscribers under its paid Prime service. Jio Prime subscribers now have recharge options starting from Rs 19 going all the way up to Rs 9,999, according to its website. Jio has become the largest network globally with more than 110 crore GB of data traffic per month and 220 crore voice and video minutes a day, Reliance Industries said in a statement while reporting the group&amp;rsquo;s earnings for financial year 2016-17. &amp;ldquo;Jio is witnessing the largest migration from free to paid services in history. Jio is committed to provide its customers the highest quality and the world&amp;rsquo;s most affordable data and voice services,&amp;rdquo; Mr Ambani said in the statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All recharges under Jio Prime include free voice call and roaming benefits. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at Jio&amp;rsquo;s various data offerings under its latest recharge options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Rs 19 _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 19 recharge comes with a validity of one day and includes 200 MB of 4G, or high speed, data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 49&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits on offer under Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 49 pack include 600 MB of high speed data valid for three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 96&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a validity of seven days, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 96 recharge includes 7GB of 4G data per day. 4G data comes at a daily limit of 1GB under Jio&amp;rsquo;s fair usage policy, beyond which the speed is reduced to 128 Kbps, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 149&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 recharge pack includes 2GB of 4G data per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 309&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Jio&amp;rsquo;s three-month benefits on first recharge begin. Subscribers making their first recharge of Rs 309 after taking up Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service will get 1GB of 3G data per day for 84 days, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will offer the same quantity of daily 4G data for 28 days, instead of 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 509&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimed at &amp;ldquo;daily high data users&amp;rdquo;, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 509 recharge extends the daily 4G data limit offered under the Rs 309 plan to 2GB. Data benefits on subsequent recharges will be limited to 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first Rs 999 recharge, valid for 120 days, Jio users will get 120 GB of 4G data, among other benefits. Subsequent recharges will come with 60 GB of high speed data valid for 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 1,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s next long-term pack comes at Rs 1,999. The first recharge of this kind includes 185 GB of 4G data valid for 150 days. The 4G data on offer is reduced to 125 GB for 90 days on subsequent recharges, Jio said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 4,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those making their first Prime recharge with the Rs 4,999 pack will get 410 GB of 4G data valid for 240 days. Subsequent recharges will offer 350 GB of such data for 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 9,999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only pack which offers 4G data spanning beyond a year on first recharge is the Rs 9,999. The first recharge will offer a total of 810 GB of 4G data valid for 420 days. Subsequent recharges will come with a reduced 4G data of 750 GB valid for 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar. To further incentivize Indians to make the switch to using the BHIM app for transacting business, PM Modi also launched two schemes - cash back for merchants and referral bonus for individual owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Are Some Of The Key Features Of BHIM:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BHIM, short for Bharat Interface for Money, enables its users to transfer money using their mobile phone. The app created a world record by registering 10 million downloads in just four months since its launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. For every successful referral, users can earn Rs. 10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;PM Modi declared on Friday that incentives totalling Rs. 495 crore will be given to merchants for accepting payments through BHIM and existing users for referring it to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 2 MB in size, the latest version of the app enables payments through a fingerprint scanner by authenticating biometric details of the user against the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is available in 12 languages with three new languages (Marathi, Punjabi and Assamese) added in BHIM 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, now allows users to transfer money to contacts saved on the phone. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a cap of Rs. 10,000 for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present account holders of around 30 banks can transact on BHIM 1.3. The app will add Punjab And Maharashtra Co-Operative Bank Ltd, Punjab &amp;amp; Sind Bank and Jammu and Kashmir Bank soon, according to its Google Play Store page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the United Payments Interface (UPI), BHIM users do not need to download mobile applications of multiple banks to transact with different banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the government&amp;rsquo;s move on November 8 last year to demonetise Rs. 500 and Rs. 1,000 currency notes, the number of digital payment apps have logged a nearly 23-fold increase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed by National Payments Corporation of India, BHIM aims pave the way for making payments using fingerprints or iris scanners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biometric attendance made compulsory from May 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-attendance-made-compulsory-may-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-attendance-made-compulsory-may-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporation has procured 93 machines based on ‘Aadhaar Authentication’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an important step towards streamlining the attendance of employees, Tiruchi Corporation has introduced biometric attendance for all of its officers, staff members and sanitary workers. Biometric machines have been installed at 91 offices and field units of the Corporation. Of the total 93 machines, purchased at a cost of ₹9.37 lakh, two have been kept on standby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machines have been installed at all reporting sections of sanitary workers, junior engineer offices, main office, zonal offices, lorry shed, water head works, and at the Ariyamangalam compost yard. Similarly, 11 urban primary health centres and mother and child health care units have also been brought under the new e-roster system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the machines are based on ‘Aadhaar Authentication’ (fingerprint and iris-based validation). Details of all 2,147 officers and employees of the Corporation have been synchronised with the machines along with their Aadhaar number. To enable the implementation of the e-attendance project, all employees of the Corporation were required to obtain Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The system is working well. Officers, clerical staff members and workers report on time to mark attendance. The issue of late coming has been addressed to a great extent,” said Corporation Commissioner N. Ravichandran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was Aadhaar enabled, supervisory officers can get the attendance details of employees easily. A centralised monitoring facility has also been created. Besides, the system has enabled the personnel department to maintain the attendance records of employees in a more efficient and transparent way, he pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biometric machines have been provided with the work schedule of all employees. For instance, the duty hours of employees in the main office is between 9.30 am and 5.30 pm. However, the work schedule of junior engineers, water head employees, sanitary workers varies. An employee can avail an hour’s permission thrice a month. And any late coming by an hour thrice a month, the machine will mark half a day absent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biometric attendance has been taken as the base for preparing the salary. While a few employees and sanitary workers have complained that machines did not recognise their thumb impression, the problem will be solved in a few days, Mr. Ravichandran said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-attendance system will be made compulsory from May 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link bank accounts to Aadhaar by April 30: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-bank-accounts-aadhaar-april-30-t-department/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-bank-accounts-aadhaar-april-30-t-department/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accounts opened from July 2014 to August, 2015 will have to submit know your customer (KYC) details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tax officials said that the accounts would include banks, insurance, stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account holders will also have to mention their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounts opened from July 2014 to August, 2015 will have to submit know your customer (KYC) details and their Aadhaar number to banks and financial institutions+ by April 30 and self-certify them to comply with FATCA regulations(Foreign Tax Compliance Act), the tax department said on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the account holders are unable to furnish details and provide self-certification by the new deadline, banks and financial institutions have the option ofblocking the accounts+ .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the details are furnished they can operate the accounts. The provision applies to accounts which come under the ambit of FATCA regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks and financial institutions were asked to obtain self-certification and carry out due diligence for all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014 to August 31, 2015 to comply with the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act(FATCA) pact signed by India and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July 2015, India and the US signed a tax information sharing agreement under a new US law, FATCA, aimed at bolstering efforts for automatic exchange of financial information between the two nations about tax evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,” the tax department said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax officials said that the accounts would include banks, insurance, stocks. Account holders will also have to mention their Aadhaar numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No card? Aadhaar, fingerprints will do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance minister also sought to turbo-charge the government’s objective of maximising cashless transactions with institutional support that included waiving all duties on point-of-sale (PoS) machines and biometric readers, improving rural digital infrastructure, tax breaks, cash incentives and easier loans based on digital transactions history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring about structural reforms, a Payments Regulatory Board will be created in the Reserve Bank of India. The governor and deputy governor of RBI will be on this Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sops have been lined up too. The government has announced a ‘referral bonus scheme’ for individuals and a cashback scheme for merchants who use the Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the tax front, the Budget encourages small businesses (with turnover up to Rs 2 crore) by reducing presumptive income tax to 6% on non-cash receipts against 8% at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of digital transaction is on rural and semi-urban areas through post offices, fair price shops and banking correspondents. Petrol pumps, fertilizer depots, municipalities, block offices, road transport offices, universities, colleges, hospitals and other institutions will also be encouraged, and possibly rule-bound at some point of time, to have facilities for digital payments. “A proposal to mandate all government receipts through digital means, beyond a prescribed limit, is under consideration,” Jaitley said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small Industries Development Bank of India (SIDBI) will be encouraged to refinance credit institutions that provide unsecured loans, at reasonable interest rates, to borrowers based on their electronic payment transaction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In my opinion, initiatives like cutting excise duty on manufacturing of payment devices and a Payment Regulatory Board will further boost India’s digital economy,” said Sanjay Rishi, regional president, American Express.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Himanshu Pujara, managing director, Euronet Services India said the measures would allow people in rural areas, those “beyond the 15% data-enabled smartphone users and mobile subscribers across the country” to become a part of the digital payments ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI To Issue New Rs 5, 10 Coins</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-to-issue-new-rs-5-10-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank will soon put into circulation new Rs 10 coins that have been minted to commemorate 125th year of National Archives of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank will also put into circulation new Rs 5 coins to celebrate 150th anniversary of Allahabad High Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 10 coin, the RBI said that on the reverse of the coin, there will be an image of National Archives Building in the centre with inscription &amp;lsquo;125 YEARS&amp;rsquo; below the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also bear logo of 125th anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year &amp;ldquo;1891&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in English shall be written on the upper and lower periphery of the coin respectively. The year &amp;ldquo;1916&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;2016&amp;rdquo; in international numerals shall be written respectively on left and right top of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RBI said the existing coins in this denomination shall also continue to be legal tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the design of new Rs 5 coin, the RBI said the coin&amp;rsquo;s face will bear an image depicting centre facade of Allahabad High Court Building emerging from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year 1866-2016 in English numerals shall be written at the bottom of the image, the RBI said in a release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: How Much Fine You Have To Pay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is charging a fine on savings bank account customers not meeting the average monthly balance requirement. The amount of penalty for non-compliance with monthly average balance or MAB requirement is based on customer location - such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on Twitter while specifying various ranges according to which it will levy the charges. Charges levied for not maintaining the minimum balance depend upon how much the average balance in the account is below the agreed minimum, said SBI, which has&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. SBI also unveiled a new identity after merging its operations with six other banks recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is minimum balance requirement?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI savings bank account customers need to maintain a monthly average balance or MAB, which is the average of daily balances in the account during the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When do SBI savings bank account customers pay this charge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing to maintain the monthly balance as specified by the bank will attract a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What to do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A regular review of your account will help you to ensure the average monthly balance is maintained and avoid the minimal charges,&amp;rdquo; State Bank of India (SBI) said in another tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much fine do I need to pay?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking behemoth SBI has divided its customers into four categories: metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For metro customers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the monthly average balance of an SBI savings bank account holder comes out to be between Rs 2,500 and Rs 5,000 - a shortfall of less than 50 per cent, a charge of Rs 50 plus service tax will be levied, SBI said. For those with a shortfall of between 50 and 75 per cent (MAB from Rs 1,250 to Rs 2,500), a fee of Rs 75 plus service tax will be charged, and Rs 100 plus service tax for those keeping an average less than Rs 749 (more than 75 per cent shortfall).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-semi-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For semi-urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-rural-customers&#34;&gt;For rural customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-minimum.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The charges have been permitted by the Reserve Bank of India and are being levied by banks across the industry &amp;ldquo;and help us in providing better services to the customers&amp;rdquo;, SBI added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides savings bank accounts, SBI offers some other accounts wherein customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After its merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your PAN card could become invalid from July 1: Here&#39;s why</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/invalid-pancard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/invalid-pancard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of applications submitted for correction of names in Permanent Account Number (PAN) cards have seen a significant jump in recent weeks. This is because the government has set a deadline of July 1, 2017, to link one&amp;rsquo;s PAN with his/her Aadhaar number. But people who do not have a consistent style of spelling their names are facing problems in linking their PAN cards with Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kamala Radhakrishnan, Vice President (Business Development) at CAMS, empanelled by the National Securities Depository Ltd (NSDL) for PAN applications, says, &amp;ldquo;We understand there is a significant increase in requests for correction of names in PAN cards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way out for such people is to either correct the details in their PAN cards or get the changes done in their Aadhaar cards. You can also apply for it online by uploading the requisite documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amit Maheshwari, Partner at Ashok Maheshwary &amp;amp; Associates LLP, says, &amp;ldquo;If the details in PAN are incorrect, the person is advised to submit a PAN correction form at the designated centres of NSDL with necessary evidences. Similarly, if the details in Aadhaar are to be corrected, the person should visit the designated centres with necessary evidences to get it rectified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-Resident Indians (NRIs), however, are exempted from quoting Aadhaar numbers while filing income-tax returns back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not link your PAN card with the Aadhaar card within the stipulated time, it may lead to invalidation of your PAN card. If that happens, you will not be able to file your return this year as quoting both PAN and Aadhaar numbers has been made mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar is a 12-digit number code, issued by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI). It is used to establish a person&amp;rsquo;s identity on the basis of demographic and biometric information. The Permanent Account Number or PAN is a 10-digit alphanumeric number issued by the Income-Tax Department for tracking your financial transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the latest data available, there are more than 24.37 crore PAN registered in the country while Aadhaar cards have been issued to 113 crore people. However, only 2.87 crore individuals filed income-tax returns in the assessment year 2012-2013, out of which 1.62 crore did not pay any tax, leaving the number of taxpayers at just one per cent of the country&amp;rsquo;s total population. Due to such a low number of tax payers in the country, the government intends to catch tax evaders with the linkage of PAN cards with Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12,000 cows in BJP-ruled Jharkhand get Aadhaar-like ID tags with details of horn, tail</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/12000-cows-bjp-ruled-jharkhand-get-aadhaar-like-id-tags-details-horn-tail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/12000-cows-bjp-ruled-jharkhand-get-aadhaar-like-id-tags-details-horn-tail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over 18 lakh cattle will be given Aadhaar-like UID numbers in a year that will prevent their illegal transportation and help improve their health and milk yield, officials said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jharkhand has tagged over 12,000 cows with Aadhaar-like 12-digit unique identification (UID) number to prevent illegal transportation of cattle, improve their milk yield and monitor their health, officials said, amid a nationwide debate on cow vigilantism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre told the Supreme Court on Monday that it will soon approve tamper-proof identity tags for all cattle in the country that will document a range of data, including a unique number and the type of their horn and tail, as part of efforts to prevent illegal transportation of cattle and livestock to Bangladesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jharkhand State Implement Agency for Cattle and Buffalo (JSIACB), a wing of the government of India, has been working on a pilot project to tag its cattle with Aadhaar-like details in eight districts — Ranchi, Hazaribagh, Dhanbad, Bokaro, Jamshedpur, Deoghar, Giridih and Lohardaga — much before the Centre’s proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pilot project is being carried under the Centre’s INAPH (information network for animal productivity and health) scheme for the last one year in Jharkhand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The information will be uploaded on the master data within a week,” INAPH’s Jharkhand nodal in-charge KK Tiwary said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/hindustan-number-ranchi-punching-aadhar-government-officials_c91e35c0-2988-11e7-b189-41b029cdb6ad.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Government officials punch the tag of the UID number on a cow in Ranchi. (HT Photo)
Tiwary said each animal has been tagged with 12-digit UID numbers, which is fixed around its ears, with records of identification details such as age, breed, sex, lactation, height, body, colour, horn type, tail switch, special mark and others. In Jharkhand, there is around 42 lakh head of cattle, and 70% of them are cows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Centre has recently directed us to extend the programme to all 24 districts and tag at least 18 lakh cattle in a year,” Tiwary said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSIACB chief executive officer Dr Govind Prasad said tracking of the breeding programme is one of the aims of the project. He said the unique ID would also help Society for Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, constituted in each district of Jharkhand, to monitor and check illegal trade of cattle in their respective districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to check illegal trade of cattle and their slaughtering, the Jharkhand government issued an order on March 27 for the closure of all illegal slaughterhouses across the state. The state administration has closed more than 1,000 illegal slaughterhouses so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jharkhand is one of the few states in the country where the Prevention of Cow Slaughter Act, 2005, is in place. The act imposes a penalty of Rs 5,000 and imprisonment of up to 5 years or both for offenders. However, despite the law, cow slaughter continues unabated in the several illegal slaughter houses across many districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prasad said after compilation of the information to the database, details of each animal could be accessed anywhere and anytime. “The animal details could also be tracked through smartphones,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on cow protection, especially by vigilante groups, has risen since the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP)-led government under Prime Minister Narendra Modi took power at the Centre 3 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been a string of cow-related violence but many state governments, particularly those ruled by the BJP, have defended the action on the grounds that the animal is considered holy by many Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Fixed Deposit Rates Lowest In Many Years. What Are Your Options?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fixed-deposit-rates-are-at-multi-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-fixed-deposit-rates-are-at-multi-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the interest rates on bank fixed deposits are at multi-year lows. For example, State Bank of India is offering interest rate between 5.50 per cent and 6.90 per cent across different maturities on retail deposits (below Rs 1 crore), according to its website. Though the Reserve Bank of India has held its repo rate steady for some time, the 175-basis-point cut in its key lending rate since January 2015 has led to a broad decline in overall interest rate in the financial system. And the surge in deposits after demonetisation has forced banks to bring down interest rates on fixed deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;With bank fixed deposits at around 7 per cent and offering a post-tax return of 5-7 per cent depending on one&amp;rsquo;s tax slab, clearly for people in higher tax slab this will only help them match inflation and be at best a value protector,&amp;rdquo; says Manoj Nagpal, CEO, Outlook Asia Capital. But conservative investors should maintain their asset allocation based on their risk profile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some newer private banks offer higher rates, Mr Nagpal added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given that most asset classes that replace debt like gold, real estate etc have also not been giving returns in the short term, equity seems to be emerging as the only alternative. However investors should not over-allocate to equities just in the chase of higher returns. If being safe is the objective, then one should surely remember that equities are volatile by nature,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says small savings schemes like 5-year NSC (National Savings Certificates) offer a superior alternative for investors though with a slightly longer lock-in and could also be considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For senior citizens, Mr Nagpal recommends the Senior Citizen Savings Scheme and the to-be-launched Varishtha Pension Bima Yojana from LIC. The Varishtha Pension Bima Yojana 2017 is a pension scheme for senior citizens, which was earlier approved by the Union Cabinet. The Varishtha Pension Bima scheme 2017, which will be implemented through Life Insurance Corporation of India (LIC), assures pension based on a guaranteed rate of return of 8 per cent for 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among debt mutual funds, Mr Nagpal suggests accrual funds with a high quality of underlying portfolio for conservative investors. Given that the Reserve Bank of India has once again cautioned on the higher risks to inflation, conservative investors should reduce allocation to long duration debt funds, he added. Accrual funds mainly focus on earning interest income from the coupon offered by underlying bonds while debt funds based on duration try to gain from the upward or downward movement of interest rate in the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidya Bala, head of mutual fund research at Fundsindia.com, also says conservative investors should &amp;ldquo;actively considerer income accrual funds in mutual funds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If investors have a shorter time frame, Ms Bala suggests short-term and ultra short-term debt funds. &amp;ldquo;If they need regular income, they can use systematic withdrawal from short-term debt funds,&amp;rdquo; she adds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Besides generating superior returns, debt funds are more tax efficient&amp;rdquo; than bank fixed deposits, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Vodafone To Airtel To BSNL, Operators Launch New Plans To Take On Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-drags-data-pricing-to-rock-bottom-with-new-prepaid-offers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bsnl-drags-data-pricing-to-rock-bottom-with-new-prepaid-offers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under its Rs. 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With tariff war intensifying in Indian telecom sector after Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s low cost data plans under its Summer Surprise and Dhan Dhana Dhan offers, prices of mobile data from other incumbent telecom players like Bharti Airtel, Vodafone, Idea Cellular and BSNL have fallen by nearly 60 per cent. According to domestic research house Crisil, the telecom player which will be able to retain maximum average revenue per user (ARPU) will win the ongoing tariff war and be able to sustain. In a bid to retain existing customers, incumbent telecom players like Airtel, Vodafone, Idea and BSNL are pricing their plans in such a way that they retain maximum of their existing subscribers and also maintain their ARPU. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at various plans launched by incumbent telecom players:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, Reliance Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data per day till end of June on a recharge of Rs 309. Those who recharge with the Rs 509 pack will get 2GB of 4G data every day. Under both the Rs 309 and Rs 509 plans, subscribers will also get free calls, free roaming and 100 SMSs per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs 399 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs. 399 recharge pack, Airtel is offering 1GB of 4G data per day along with free voice calls to any network for 70 days. However, there are some limitations on voice calls. You can make 300 minutes of Airtel-to-Airtel calls per day (1,200 minutes in a week) and for other networks, 3,000 minutes of free local and STD calls for 70 days. If you exhaust the free minutes, Rs 0.10 per minute will be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs 345 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel is offering 2GB of data per day at 4G speed for 28 days under its new Rs 345 recharge pack. Also, now there is no restriction with regard to the timing of data consumption. Under the earlier Rs. 345 recharge pack, users were restricted to use only 500 MB of data daily from 6 am till midnight , and the remaining 500 MB between 12 am and 6 am. Along with the above data, users will also get free voice calls to Airtel and other networks as it is in the Rs. 399 pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs. 244 recharge, users will get 1 GB of 4G data per day for 70 days without any restriction on usage timing. But this pack offers free calls on Airtel networks only (300 minutes of daily Airtel-to-Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for a week for 70 days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 recharge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs. 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week. If you cross the call limit, a fee of 30 paise per minute will be charged for every call. This offer is not available for every Vodafone users. You can check if the offer is available for you by dialing *121# from your Vodafone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL Rs. 333 plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs. 333 offers 3 GB of 3G data per day for 90 days. After you exhaust the daily data limit of 3GB data, speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL Rs. 349 plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs. 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and offers 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs. 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL Rs. 395 plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Nehle Pe Dehla&amp;rsquo; plan priced at Rs 395 provides 2GB daily data at 3G speed for 71 days. The Rs. 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BSNL Rs. 339 plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL has also revised its existing Rs. 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of 3G data per day, instead of 2 GB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>