<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar based lic policies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-launches-two-aadhaar-based-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-launches-two-aadhaar-based-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life insurance behemoth LIC has introduced two endowment assurance plans for individuals having Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the _Aadhaar Shila _is a plan exclusively designed for women, the other scheme &lt;em&gt;Aadhaar Stambh&lt;/em&gt; is meant for men. Absolute amount assured on death under Aadhaar Stambh is 100%, whereas for Aadhaar Shila it is 110% of basic sum assured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These plans offer a combination of protection and savings and provide a lump-sum amount at the time of maturity for the surviving policyholder and financial support for the family in case of death of the policyholder, a Corporation statement said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maturity benefit under both the plans will be the sum assured with loyalty additions if any, it added. Total basic sum assured under all policies issued to an individual under this plan shall not exceed Rs 3 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This plan is available to standard healthy lives from age 8-55 years, without any medical examination. The maximum age of maturity is 70 years and the terms available are from 10 to 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of death during first five years, the sum assured on death shall be payable. However, in case of death after completion of five policy years but before the date of maturity, the sum assured on death and loyalty addition, if any, shall be payable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sum assured on death is defined as the highest of 10 times of annualised premium or the absolute amount assured to be paid on death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebate on tabular premium at 2% for year mode and 1% on half-yearly mode is available while quarterly, monthly (through NACH), salary deductions are other modes available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An optional benefit of accident benefit rider is available by payment of additional premium. Loyalty addition is payable on certain conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, these plans also take care of liquidity needs through auto cover as well as loan facility. PTI KD BEN NRB&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Bills, Insurance Premiums To Get Costlier Under GST</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/credit-card-bills-insurance-premiums-to-get-costlier-under-gst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Credit card providers, banks and insurers have started alerting their customers to pay higher tax post implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1. Customers currently pay 15 per cent service tax for such services. Starting from July 1, 2017 the GST will replace all indirect taxes like service tax and VAT. Financial services and telecom have been put in the 18 per cent GST slab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Card has sent SMS to its customers alerting about the higher incidence of tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Important: The Government of India proposes to implement the GST which is likely to be effective from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the existing service tax rate of 15 per cent shall be replaced by a GST rate of 18 per cent,&amp;rdquo; the SMS sent by SBI Card read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks like Standard Chartered and HDFC are also sending messages related to GST to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICICI Prudential Life Insurance, in email messages to its customers, said premium payable on term policy and fund management charges on a Unit Linked Insurance Policy will attract 18 per cent GST post implementation of the new indirect tax regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These products currently attract 15 per cent service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GST will be levied at the rate of 2.25 per cent on premium payment for endowment policy. Currently, customers pay 1.88 per cent service tax on endowment policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parliament&amp;rsquo;s historic Central Hall will host a midnight function on June 30 to launch the nation&amp;rsquo;s biggest tax reform GST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Pranab Mukherjee, who had piloted the first Constitutional Amendment Bill to bring in GST in 2011 when he was finance minister in the previous UPA regime, will share the dais with Prime Minister Narendra Modi on the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Allows Co-Operative Banks To Deposit Old Notes With RBI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-allows-co-operative-banks-to-deposit-old-notes-with-rbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The relaxation comes against the backdrop of reports that many district co-operative banks did not have enough cash to disburse to farmers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Finance Ministry on Tuesday allowed banks, post offices and district central cooperative banks to deposit the scrapped Rs 500 and 1,000 rupee notes with the Reserve Bank of India within 30 days and exchange the value of notes deposit with the new notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an official notification the Finance Ministry said, &amp;ldquo;Specified bank notes may be deposited by such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, in any office of the Reserve Bank, within a period of 30 days from the commencement of these rules, and get the exchange value thereof by credit to the account of such Bank, Post Office or District Central Cooperative Bank, as the case may be, subject to the satisfaction of the Reserve Bank of the conditions specified in the said notification and the reasons for non-deposit of the specified bank notes within the period under that notification.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relaxation comes against the backdrop of reports that many district co-operative banks did not have enough cash to disburse to farmers, particularly in Maharashtra. The reason, the banks say, is that nearly six months after demonetisation, they still have crores of cash in old currency, which the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) is refusing to accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nashik&amp;rsquo;s District Central Cooperative Bank told NDTV they still have a stockpile of Rs 340 crore in old 500 and 1,000 notes.  Unless this money is converted to new, payments will be hard to make, said Narendra Darade, Chairman of Nashik&amp;rsquo;s DCCB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demonetisation of high value currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 announced on November 8, 2016 led to scrapping of over Rs 15 lakh crore from the system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GST will impact your household budget</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-impact-your-household-budget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Goods and services tax (GST) comes into effect from 1 July. ET Wealth analyses the impact on some basic expenses in the household consumption basket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AUTOMOBILES
The price difference will be bigger for SUVs (55% to 43%) compared to small cars (30% to 29%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 4.75 lakh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 1.43 lakh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 1.38 lakh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DURABLES : Refrigerators and washing machines
For most white goods, there won&amp;rsquo;t be much difference in price as new rates will be close to earlier ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 20,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 5,300&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 5,600&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIFE INSURANCE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While premium of term plans and non-life policies are taxed, only charges (mortality and AMC charges, etc) in other life policies attract GST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 15,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 2,250&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 2,700&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD ORNAMENTS : Making charges Rs 10,000
The yellow metal will become dearer as there will be 3% GST on gold and 5% on making charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 60,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 1,800&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HOTEL STAY
If you settle for a room that costs less than Rs 1,000, there will be no GST to pay. Then it rises progressively. Anything above Rs 5,000 will attract 28%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 7,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 1,400&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 1,960&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REFINED COOKING OIL
Hair oil prices will stay high due to 18% GST. But coconut oil being refined cooking oil, will be taxed at 5%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 200&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AIR TRAVEL : Economy
Taxation gap between economy and business class has increased with GST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 5,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 300&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 250&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRAIN TRAVEL : AC coaches
While those travelling by local trains or in sleeper class are not affected, first-class and AC compartment travellers will pay more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 3,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 131&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 150&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TELECOM : 2 phones + 1 DTH bills
Since these services will not get much input credit, you have to bear the burden of hiked rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 2,500&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 375&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 450&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EATING OUT : For a family of 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A non-AC eatery will only charge 12% GST. However, eating at a restaurant in a 5-star hotel will mean shelling out 28% in GST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 270&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 360&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APPAREL : Readymade
Due to industry pressure, GST on garments priced below Rs 1,000 has been brought down from 12% to 5%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 130&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 240&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ENTERTAINMENT : Cinema for a family of 4
Reduction in GST for tickets up to Rs 100 will benefit single screen cinemas in small towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base price : Rs 1,200&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total taxes now* : Rs 360&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GST : Rs 336&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This includes excise, sales tax, VAT, entertainment tax, luxury tax, etc; Average tax considered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_These are exempt from GST _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All unprocessed cereals like rice, wheat, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All unprocessed milk, vegetables, meat, fish, etc&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Train travel by local and sleeper class&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Education&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Healthcare (but not medicines)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hotels, lodges with room rent less than Rs 1,000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kid’s colouring /drawing books&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bindis, sindoor, bangles, etc&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either &lt;em&gt;567678 or 56161.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said linking the two numbers is the key to &amp;ldquo;seamlessly avail online, a world of income tax facilities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aadhaar can also be seeded into PAN database by quoting Aadhaar in PAN application form for new PAN allotment or by quoting Aadhaar in change request form used for reprint of PAN card,&amp;rdquo; it said in the advertisement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income-Tax-department had early this month launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing I-T returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has hosted a new link on its homepage to link the two unique identities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires a person to punch in his PAN number, Aadhaar number and the exact name as given in the Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department had said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number in the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of Income-Tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the I-T department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine online jobs that you can do from home</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/online-jobs-that-you-can-do-from-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re looking for a respite from your 9 to 5, are unable to commute to work, are a stay at-home parent, or have some other constraint that prevents you from finding a full-time job, there’s no need to waste your earning potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of opportunities available online that let you work from home. Here are a few options you can consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual assistantship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs, professionals and small teams often need assistance with various administrative tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These could include scheduling meetings, getting in touch with clients and investors, following up on orders, creating business documents like PowerPoint presentations and Excel sheets, managing blogs and websites, etc. Virtual assistants (VAs) work remotely with such clients, managing the aspects of their business or practice that they are too busy to handle themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming a VA can entail some degree of training or briefing, depending on your qualifications. However, if you have good communication skills and are capable of using applications like MS Office, you can just sign up on sites such as Elance. com and Zirtual.com and start looking for work as a VA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Rs 500-Rs 4,000 per hour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are bilingual or trilingual, this might be the opportunity for you. While being fluent in English and one or two Indian languages might serve you well enough, taking a language course can add significantly to your earning potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty of international businesses, scholars and authors would be willing to enlist your services for their translation needs if you can prove your proficiency. To start earning, enlist on a popular freelancing site like Fiverr.com or Upwork.com, listing the languages you are proficient in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Rs 1-Rs 5 per word. It can go up to Rs 10 for some languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, blog monetisation has gained momentum. To monetise your blog, you can sign up for Google Adsense, which will allot you ads to place on your blog. After this, it’s a waiting game to see if your account is approved. If it is, you can continue to receive ad placements and earn a steady, if not large, income from it. Adsense pays on the basis of clicks and views the ads receive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can take up affiliate marketing (promoting another seller’s products on your blog) or product sales through your blog to turn it into a moneymaking venture. If your blog already attracts a significant amount of traffic, you could choose to enlist blog sponsors, which includes selling ad space on your blog to merchants, which offers a more stable source of income over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Ads can pay Rs 2,000-15,000 a month for a 2”x2” space, depending on your niche and readership. Adsense earnings vary widely depending on the blogger’s reach and popularity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling your products online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you have a penchant for crafts or are particularly good at choosing fabrics and creating ensembles, there is probably a market for you products. Once you decide on what you want to sell, create an inventory by buying the products wholesale, or producing a good number of them to keep up with orders, and then set the prices you want to sell them at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sell these items, you can register on the website of any popular online seller, from Amazon and eBay to smaller portals like indiebazaar.com. These portals charge a small fee for hosting your products. Once you receive an order, package your products and keep it ready for the logistics partner of the chosen portal to pick it up and deliver it. You will receive the payment in five to seven days after a given order is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Earnings vary according to products and pricing. After the portal’s small fee is deducted, the rest of the revenue is yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making youtube videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTube is both popular and easily accessible. If you’re not camera shy or are good with a video camera, it might be the right platform for you. Choose a category or subject that you want to make videos on and get started, but make sure it’s a topic that’ll interest a lot of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything from cooking shows to political debates can find many takers on YouTube. You don’t even need to have professional equipment or a proper set-up to record videos—a mid-range smartphone will suffice. You have to create a YouTube channel, which works on a similar model as a blog—as you make your channel popular and the number of subscribers grows, so will your earning potential. From brand endorsements to event coverage, YouTube offers many earning opportunities once you gain popularity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Rs 200-300 per 1,000 views. Ads pay according to engagement and clicks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have some understanding of coding and web design? Then you can easily work from home as a web developer. Even if you are a novice who is interested in the job, you can find dozens of easy online tutorials that can help you get started. Web development is usually outsourced by companies, and is therefore an area where finding work should be easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, keep in mind that there are plenty of freelance web developers out there who can give you a run for your money. It’s important to find your niche, build a good reputation and keep your pricing reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Depending on the client and job, a single project can fetch you anywhere between Rs 20,000 and Rs 1 lakh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular avenues when it comes to freelance work is that of content writing. There is always an enormous demand for well-researched and wellwritten web content, and recruiters are constantly on the lookout for professionals who can create fresh content that attracts attention and traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a good grasp of grammar, an engaging writing style and are interested in researching diverse topics and writing about them, this is the job for you. Set up a Paypal account before you start working, since most clients would prefer to make payments through it. Once you have an account, you can sign up on freelance work websites like Fiverr.com, Upwork.com, Freelancer.com, Elance.com and Worknhire.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Beginners earn Rs 8,000-Rs 10,000 per month. Experienced content writers can earn Rs 20,000-Rs 25,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this line of work is seriously threatened by automation, there are still plenty of data entry jobs available in India. It is one the simplest jobs you can do online, and requires no special skills. You just have to have a computer, and Internet connection, fast typing skills, and the ability to pay attention to details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most freelancing websites list these jobs, and you can sign up on any of them to start working. The client provides printed or scanned sheets of data that needs to be entered into a digital format. This simple task can fetch you a steady income while working from home on a flexible schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Rs 300 to Rs 1,500 per hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online tutoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already have some tutoring experience or are an expert in a particular subject, you can earn by tutoring people online. Sign up on websites like MyPrivateTutor.com, BharatTutors.com, tutorindia.net as an online tutor, create a profile listing the subjects or classes you want to teach, how much experience you have, what your qualifications are, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your details are checked and approved, you will have to take an online test or give a telephonic interview in order to be selected. If academic tutoring is not your cup of tea, portals like Udemy let you have your own virtual classroom for anything that can be taught, from cooking to yoga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential earnings : Beginners can make around Rs 200 per hour, which can increase to Rs 500 as you gain experience and expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Announces Mega Auction Of Properties</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-mega-auction-of-properties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The bank will auction off 150 properties,including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India (SBI) has a nnounced a sale of properties through a mega e-auction on June 23, 2017. This was said by the country&amp;rsquo;s largest bank on microblogging site Twitter. The bank will auction off 150 properties, including residential, commercial and agricultural land across the country, SBI said on its website. These properties were pledged as collateral for housing and business loans and were taken over by the bank under the Security and Reconstruction of Financial Assets and Enforcement of Security Interest (Sarfaesi) Act due to non-payment of pending dues by the borrowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A list of the properties going for sale are given on the auction portal www.bankeauctions.com/sbi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the requirements to participate in SBI&amp;rsquo;s e-auction:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EMD for the particular property as mentioned in the e-Auction notice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KYC documents - to be submitted to the concerned branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valid digital signature: Bidders may approach e-auctioneers or any other authorised agency to obtain digital signature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login Id and Password will be sent to the email id of the bidders by e-auctioneers after the deposit of EMD and submission of KYC documents to the concerned branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bidders to login and bid during the auction hours on the date of e-Auction as per auction rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month lowered interest rate on home loans. SBI is offering an interest rate of 8.35 per cent on home loans up to Rs. 30 lakh. The move by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI is in line with the government&amp;rsquo;s push on affordable housing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eligible borrowers of home loans from State Bank of India can also avail an interest subsidy up to Rs. 2.67 lakh under the &amp;lsquo;Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana&amp;rsquo;, a government scheme aimed at providing subsidised housing loans to the low and middle income groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers of other banks can also transfer their existing home loans to SBI without any processing fee, SBI said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammers are trying to get your Aadhaar details via calls, emails</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/scammers-trying-get-aadhaar-details-via-calls-emails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch out! The scammers are out with a new set of tricks to swindle the gullible public. Curiously, the Centre’s directive to link the bank accounts with Aadhaar has apparently made these fraudsters more brazen. Their latest modus operandi is to seek details of the Aadhaar card from unsuspecting victims through phone calls and emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posing as bank executives or tele-callers, they call up potential victims saying, “The bank has decided to link your Aadhaar number with debit card for better customer service. For this we need your Aadhaar number and other details.” A similar call was received by a city-based businessman recently. To gain the victims’ trust, fraudsters even tell the common 12-digit code on the debit card, which will be unique to each bank, and then ask them to disclose the remaining four digits, unique to each customer. Along with the last four digits, they secure the card verification value (CVV) number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, they will place orders to generate a one-time password (OTP)on the customers’ mobile phone. Convinced the OTP is for Aaadhar linkage, customers share the password for linking the Aadhaar cards with debit or credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Express spoke to Kiran Kumar, a business analyst, who was contacted by a fraud recently. “I was quite aware of this type of fraud. So I waited till the executive asked me to share the OTP. But I refused to do so and instead warned him of police action. However, several people remain unaware of this and they normally share the number as the Centre had instructed the public to link the Aadhaar card with PAN. It’s high time people should be made aware of this new age fraud,” said Kumar. The police said the fraudsters’ primary targets are people from Kerala as many people here are unaware of this type of fraud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also said the fraudsters were operating from Bihar, Uttar Pradesh and New Delhi. Incidentally, none of the accused has been booked by the police till date. The police suspect the involvement of an international crime syndicate. IG Manoj Abraham, who is the nodal officer of Cyberdome, a unit of Kerala Police to prevent cyber crimes, told Express the fraudulent activities can be reduced to a great extent once Aadhaar linkage is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As the new system will provide an authentication to the customer, the fraudsters can never dupe the people anymore. Here, there will be a biometric verification which helps to reduce the possibility of money being siphoned from accounts. However, the fraudsters will continue to target those who remain ignorant. This can be avoided only through awareness programmes,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win Rupay Select Credit Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idbi-bank-launches-winnings-rupay-select-credit-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IDBI Bank announced the launch of ‘Winnings’ Rupay Select Credit Card that offers a range of travel, shopping and dining privileges and also enables earning of rewards points on every spend. The credit card has been launched in association with National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI). This product is similar to the international credit cards offered by VISA and MasterCard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘Winnings’ RuPay Select Credit Card is a premium credit card variant and is at par with the premium Card variants of International Card networks which is Visa Signature and MasterCard World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ‘Winnings’ RuPay Select Credit Card comes with several privileges and paybacks which are listed below:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Welcome Benefits. (Cash back, delight points, Gift vouchers, discounts)
 Complimentary Domestic &amp;amp; International Lounge Program
 Earn Cash back time after time (Utility bill payments, Eateries and Restaurants, Mobile Wallet, fuel surcharge, )
 Free movie tickets (Buy one Get one on 2nd and 4th Weekends)
 &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; Concierge Services
 Comprehensive Insurance Cover up to Rs. 10 lakhs
 Double delight points on Birthday Month etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the current thrust on digital payments and the broader aim of a less-cash society, IDBI Bank has launched the ‘Winnings’ RuPay Select Credit Card. The major benefits of this Credit Card are high levels of acceptance and the strength of the RuPay brand – all of which will contribute to an enhanced product experience.
IDBI Bank has currently four variants of Credit Cards viz. ‘Royale’ Signature Credit Card, ‘Aspire’ Platinum Credit Card, ‘Euphoria’ World Credit Card and ‘Imperium’ Secured Platinum Credit Card.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh. In the present scenario where bank interest rates are on a falling trend, financial planners say that equity mutual funds are one of the best instruments to accumulate long-term savings through systematic investment plan (SIP). Gains from equity mutual funds after a year are tax-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, fund selection is one of the most difficult things to do for a retail investor as it needs lot of research. Financial planners say diversified equity funds are the best to invest through SIP for long term. Here are some funds which have generates over 20 per cent CAGR return in past 20 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Equity Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on January 1, 1995, it is one of the oldest and best performing funds in India. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.95 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 23.56 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This fund has generated a CAGR return of 23.68 per cent since its inception. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998 would have helped you accumulate a corpus of Rs. 2.12 crore by April 1, 2017 implying 17.66 times return in 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;Franklin India Prima Fund:&lt;/em&gt; It is one of the flagship fund of Franklin Templeton India. Since its inception in December 1993, it has generated a CAGR return of 21.04 per cent till now. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 2.38 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 25.11 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Vision Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on October 8, 1995, it has generated a CAGR return of 19.92 per cent till now. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998, would have become Rs. 1.46 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Top 200 Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This flagship fund of HDFC Mutual Fund has generated a CAGR return of 20.88 per cent since its inception in September 1996. If you would have started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.43 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With falling return on bank fixed deposits, equity mutual funds are witnessing increased investment from retail investors now. Equity and equity-linked schemes have seen inflows of more than Rs. 70,000 crore in last financial year according to Association of Mutual Funds in India data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘what is BHIM’ to ‘what are the benefits’, here are top 5 FAQs answered</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-payments-bhim-benefits-top-5-faqs-answered/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whether India has really adopted digital or not would only be clear once data for the coming months is released, but what can be said with certainty is that there are enough avenues available if one wants to go digital.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While pre-demonetisation, the government had launched UPI and other services, post this it has rolled out BHIM and BharatQR, and is expected to launch AadhaarPay. In fact, PM Modi in Mann-ki-Baat lauded the initiative to go digital, urging the youth to teach BHIM transfers to 125 people commemorating the 125th anniversary of Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-bhim&#34;&gt;What is BHIM?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM or Bharat Interface for Money is an app available both on iOS and Playstore. Built on the UPI platform, it operates much like a wallet, allowing transfer of money via input of mobile number or virtual address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-operate-it&#34;&gt;How to operate it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to have Aadhaar linked to your bank account to use BHIM. Once that is done, BHIM asks you to set a password. And, then you can select your bank. If you don’t have m-pin, entering last 6 digits of debit card and expiry can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;are-people-using-it&#34;&gt;Are people using it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per latest data, BHIM has 17 million downloads with 7 million active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-the-benefits&#34;&gt;What are the benefits?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i. Supported by NPCI, which operates IMPS and UPI, BHIM is safe.
ii. Moreover, unlike wallet, BHIM does not require frequent recharges.
iii. It also supports QR code much like PayTM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-else-can-you-use&#34;&gt;What else can you use?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also BharatQR now, which is an interoperable QR code,i.e., if you have Visa and merchant has Mastercard you can use BharatQR to make payment, which you couldn’t do earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govt will also be launching AadhaarPay soon which will allow fingerprint-based payments. For this you would not even need your phone; if the merchant has a smartphone, he will just use a fingerprint scanner and confirm your bank to authorise payments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Aadhaar To Your Bank Account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-aadhaar-to-your-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can link your Aadhaar to your bank account online, through SMS or from an ATM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar is slowly becoming an important detail to conduct any financial transaction. From filing income tax returns to availing government schemes and benefits, the Indian Government is slowly making submission of Aadhaar Card mandatory for a lot of procedures. Known as Aadhaar seeding , many banks have added an option to add Aadhaar details online or through SMS in a particular format to a specific number provided by the bank. Some banks like SBI also allow customers to link their Aadhaar number to their bank account at an ATM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are different easy ways through which you can update your aadhaar number in your bank account without having to visit your bank branch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To link your Aadhaar to your bank account online:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to the internet banking service of your bank.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the &amp;ldquo;Update Aadhar Card Details&amp;rdquo; option or &amp;ldquo;Aadhaar Card Seeding&amp;rdquo; option and click on it. On clicking, you will be directed to another page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your Aadhaar card number and click on Submit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The last 2 digits of registered mobile number (non-editable) will be displayed to the customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank will communicate the status of the linking to Customer&amp;rsquo;s registered mobile number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To link your Aadhaar card to your bank account though SMS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your mobile number is registered with the Bank, then you can link your Aadhaar number to your bank account through SMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you are an SBI customer send SMS to 567676 in the following format: UID(space)Aadhaar number(space)Account number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the mobile number is not registered or in case the Aadhaar is already linked to Account, an SMS reply will be sent to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your mobile number is registered with the Bank, you will receive an SMS confirmation of the seeding request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many banks are yet to offer the option of linking Aadhaar to bank account through SMS,  so do check through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;your bank’s customer helpline if this option is available.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To link your Aadhaar card to your bank account from an ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some banks like SBI offer an option for seeding Aadhaar from an ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After swiping the ATM card and entering your PIN, Select the menu &amp;ldquo;Service – Registrations&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this menu, select Aadhaar Registration (or Inquiry as per your need)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select the Account type (Savings/Checking) after which you will be asked to enter your Aadhaar number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Facility Launched To Link Aadhaar With PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax Department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing income tax returns (ITRs) now. The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals. The link requires a person to punch in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact name as given in the Aadhaar
card&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number and email of the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It urged them to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linking without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no need to login or be registered on e-filing website (of the I-T department). This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for a permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 crore Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>