<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>70 GB 4G Data At Rs 244, Rs 399: Airtel&#39;s New Plans To Counter Jio &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-gb-4g-data-at-rs-244-rs-399-airtels-new-plans-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-gb-4g-data-at-rs-244-rs-399-airtels-new-plans-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After withdrawing the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, Jio has come up with Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plans offering unlimited data, SMS and voice calling for three months.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bharti-airtel-650_650x400_81492158840.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With the tariff war getting brutal in the telecom space, India&amp;rsquo;s biggest operator Airtel has come up with aggressive new prepaid plans to counter Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s latest &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer. Under Rs 244 plan, Airtel is offering unlimited local and STD calls on Airtel network and 1 GB/day for 70 days. Under the Rs 399 plan, Airtel is offering free local and STD calls on any network as well as 1 GB/day data for 70 days. Under the Rs 345 plan, Airtel is offering unlimited call and 2GB data/day for 28 days. A check on Airtel&amp;rsquo;s website showed these new plans are available for subscription on prepaid numbers through online payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After withdrawing the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, Jio has come up with Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plans offering unlimited data, SMS and voice calling for three months. Starting Rs 309, &amp;lsquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plan offers 1 GB data per day for a period of 84 days. Also, with a recharge of Rs 509, users will get 2 GB data per day for 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry into the telecom space has led to a drop in tariffs as the competition gets intense. The revenue of telecom sector from consumer services like mobile telephony and data dipped 10.5 per cent to Rs 37,284 crore in the October-December period over the previous three months, according to regulator Trai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aggressive offerings from telecom operators have led higher data usage. Two out of three consumers in India want to switch to a new phone within the next 12 months, a report by Counterpoint Research said. &amp;ldquo;As per the survey, two in three users plan to upgrade to a new mobile phone in the next 12 months. This is a departure from an average of 24-30 months to under 20 months upgrade cycle,&amp;rdquo; the report said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8.65% Interest On Your Provident Fund Deposits To Be Credited Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/interest-on-your-provident-fund-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/interest-on-your-provident-fund-deposits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Retirement fund body EPFO has also proposed a loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs. 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four crore subscribers of Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) will soon receive interest for 2016-17 on their deposits. Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya on Thursday said the finance ministry has agreed to a rate of interest of 8.65 per cent. &amp;ldquo;Now, the communication will come. The formal discussions are over,&amp;rdquo; the minister said. He also said: &amp;ldquo;We will immediately issue the notification and credit the rate of interest to over four crore subscribers.&amp;rdquo; The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation had earlier approved the 8.65 per cent rate on employee provident fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO has also proposed a loyalty-cum-life benefit of up to Rs. 50,000 at the time of retirement for contributing to the scheme for 20 years or more. The benefit will also be provided in case of permanent disability even if the members have contributed for less than 20 years, the EPFO board has decided. The benefits will be available for EPFO subscribers after approval from the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Central Board of Trustees (CBT), which is the EPFO&amp;rsquo;s apex decision-making body, has also recommended a minimum sum assured of Rs. 2.5 lakh in the event of death of a subscriber. At present, the dependants of the deceased get a sum assured of up to Rs. 6 lakh. There is no provision of minimum insurance and any benefit for surviving members or in cases of permanent disability under the scheme. The benefits will be available for EPFO subscribers after approval from the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly four crore members of retirement fund body EPFO will soon be able to settle their claims like EPF withdrawal through mobile application UMANG. &amp;ldquo;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) is developing online claims settlement process by receiving application online,&amp;rdquo; Labour Minister Bandaru Dattatreya had said in a written reply to the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Declaration To Your Employer: The Changes You Should Be Aware Of</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-declaration-to-your-employer-the-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/income-tax-declaration-to-your-employer-the-changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the beginning of every fiscal year, employees are asked for details like their investment in ELSS, insurance policies, house rent, home loan, education loan etc. by their employer to arrive at the annual tax liability of an employee.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of every fiscal year, employees are asked for details like their investment in ELSS (Equity Linked Savings Schemes), insurance policies, house rent, home loan, education loan etc. by their employer to arrive at the annual tax liability of an employee. This annual exercise also helps you do tax planning for the year. Based on the declaration, your employer calculates TDS or tax deducted at source. The employer will deduct tax from salary and deposit it with the tax authorities. Starting April 1, 2017, some income tax laws have changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are changes in tax laws you should be aware before submitting tax declaration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh has been halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore). However, those with taxable income of above Rs 50 lakh get the benefit of marginal relief. The concept of marginal relief is designed to provide some relief in levy of surcharge to a taxpayer where the total taxable income marginally exceeds Rs. 50 lakh or Rs. 1 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme, which has been scrapped this year. This tax-saving scheme was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties, other than self-occupied. For properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But from this year, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Individuals are required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for house rent payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term capital gains has been reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold after two years of buying. If a property is sold before two years, the profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Along with the reduction in the holding period to two years, the base year for calculating indexation of cost has also been changed. The base year has been shifted from 1981 to 2001.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000. The government has also made it compulsory for people to quote their Aadhaar details in their tax returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Under the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana (Urban) for middle-income groups, home loan borrowers buying their first home are eligible for subsidy on interest repayments. Home loans sanctioned or applications are under consideration since January 1, 2017, are eligible for interest subsidy under the Credit Linked Subsidy Scheme for Middle Income Groups. The beneficiary earlier should not have own a house in his/her name.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio At Top Spot In 4G Download Speed In March, Says Telecom Regulator&#39;s Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-at-top-spot-in-4g-download-speed-in-march-says-telecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-at-top-spot-in-4g-download-speed-in-march-says-telecom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Average download speed on Reliance Jio network was 16.48 megabit per second (mbps) in March against 8.33 mbps on Idea Cellular.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New telecom operator Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s average download speed at 16.48 mbps was almost double of its rivals Idea Cellular and Bharti Airtel&amp;rsquo;s in March, a report by telecom regulator Trai has showed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average download speed on Reliance Jio network was 16.48 megabit per second (mbps) in March against 8.33 mbps on Idea Cellular&amp;rsquo;s and 7.66 mbps on Bharti Airtel&amp;rsquo;s network, the monthly report by Trai showed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theoretically, a user can download one Bollywood movie in about 5 minutes at 16 mbps speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone registered average download speed of 5.66 mbps, Reliance Communications 2.64 mbps, Tata Docomo 2.52 mbps, state run BSNL 2.26 mbps and Aircel 2.01 mbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trai collects and computes data download speed with the help of its MySpeed application on real-time basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a survey on mobile network speed covering two metros of Delhi and Mumbai, and two states of Karnataka and Tamil Nadu by a private firm Open Signal has claimed that Bharti Airtel had the fastest network with average 4G download speed of 11.5 mbps while Reliance Jio was fourth with 3.92 mbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey claimed to have collected information from 1.3 billion datapoints covering 93,464 users during the period between December 2016 and February 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The findings reveal that Airtel didn&amp;rsquo;t just win OpenSignal&amp;rsquo;s 4G speed award, it wound up on top of 3G and overall rankings as well. OpenSignal measured Airtel&amp;rsquo;s average LTE download speed at 11.5 mbps, which was 3 mbps faster than the results measured on its nearest rivals Vodafone and Idea,&amp;rdquo; OpenSignal said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new survey has come amid ongoing tussle between Airtel and Reliance Jio over claims of India&amp;rsquo;s fastest mobile network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio has challenged Airtel&amp;rsquo;s advertisement campaign&lt;/em&gt; in which the telecom major claimed to be &amp;ldquo;officially&amp;rdquo; fastest network in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Advertising Standards Council of India (ASCI) found the ad claiming Airtel to be &amp;ldquo;officially&amp;rdquo; fastest network as misleading and asked the company to modify or withdraw the commercial by April 11 to which the company complied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel has filed appeal before ASCI for review of the decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Signal report said that Vodafone was at the second spot with average 4G download speed of 8.59 mbps followed by Idea Cellular with 8.34 mbps and Jio on 4th spot with 3.92 mbps speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report ranks Jio on top for widest availability of 4G network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;OpenSignal&amp;rsquo;s testers on Jio&amp;rsquo;s network were able to find a 4G signal 91.6 per cent of the time, an exceptional availability measurement by any global standard. In comparison, no other Indian operator scored higher than 60 per cent in its 4G availability tests,&amp;rdquo; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PM Modi To Launch Udan Air Connectivity Scheme From Shimla</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pm-modi-to-launch-udan-air-connectivity-scheme-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pm-modi-to-launch-udan-air-connectivity-scheme-from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr Sinha disclosed this at the 11th edition of the Mindmine Summit organised by the Mindmine Institute, an independent think-tank set up by Hero Enterprise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Union Minister Jayant Sinha on Thursday said Prime Minister Narendra Modi will launch the government&amp;rsquo;s air regional connectivity scheme - UDAN - on April 27. Mr Sinha disclosed this at the 11th edition of the Mindmine Summit organised by the Mindmine Institute, an independent think-tank set up by Hero Enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The aviation industry in India is a sunrise sector. We are working towards UDAN or &amp;lsquo;Ude Desh ka har Nagarik&amp;rsquo;, building efficient regional air connectivity, between the metros and the tier 3 and 4 cities like Shimla, Gorakhpur, Kanpur,&amp;rdquo; Mr Sinha said while addressing a session on &amp;lsquo;India in 2017: More Roadbumps or Achhe Din?&amp;rsquo; at the summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;PM, Shri Modi will launch UDAN on 27th April and we will add 33 new airports across the small Indian cities in one year. This will be achieved with a subsidy of only Rs. 205 crore.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PM Modi is expected to launch the scheme at Jubbarhatti, located on the outskirts of Shimla on April 27.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana: From Zero Balance To Latest Details In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pradhan-mantri-jan-dhan-yojana-from-zero-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pradhan-mantri-jan-dhan-yojana-from-zero-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government&amp;rsquo;s financial inclusion scheme PMJDY or &amp;lsquo;Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana&amp;rsquo; offers easy access to banking services. The Jan-Dhan Yojana was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on August 28, 2014. As on April 5, 2017, 28.23 crore accounts have been opened. This was stated in a tweet by the Finance Ministry on Twitter. A bank account under PMJDY can be opened by visiting any bank branch or business correspondent outlet, or &amp;ldquo;Bank Mitr&amp;rdquo;, and used thereafter for various social security schemes. The Jan Dhan tally, the ministry added, has reached Rs 63,971 crore in deposits and 22.14 crore Rupay cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana seeks to ensure access to financial services - banking/savings and deposit accounts, remittance, credit, insurance and pension - in an affordable manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jan Dhan accounts are opened with zero balance. For those who want to get a cheque book will have to fulfil the minimum balance criteria of the respective bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who want to open an account under the PMJDY scheme will need a few documents. Those who don&amp;rsquo;t have all the documents can open Small Accounts with banks, the Reserve Bank of India has said. Small Accounts - valid normally for a period of twelve months - have certain limits related to aggregate credits, aggregate withdrawals and balance. (Know more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Basic Savings Bank Deposit Account or BSBDA, as per the RBI, includes services such as deposit and withdrawal of cash at bank branch as well as ATMs and receipt/credit of money through electronic payment channels or by means of collection/deposit of cheques. (Also read: At SBI, no need to maintain minimum balance in these accounts)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits being offered under the Jan Dhan accounts include interest on deposits, accidental insurance cover (Rs 1 lakh) and life cover (Rs. 30,000) subject to fulfilment of eligibility. They also provide access to pension and insurance products&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rate applicable for Saving Bank Accounts (presently at 4 per cent in most of the banks) will be admissible to accounts opened under PMJDY scheme, as per the State Bank of India website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, a Jan Dhan account can also be used to receive Direct Benefit Transfer - under which the government transfers subsidies directly to the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overdraft facility will be permitted after satisfactory operation for six months. An overdraft up to Rs 5000 is offered by the government in only one account per household &amp;ldquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rupay Debit Card, a domestic debit card introduced by National Payment Corporation of India, is accepted at all ATMs (for cash withdrawal) and at most of the PoS or point-of-sale machines in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government aims to achieve a comprehensive financial inclusion by August 14, 2018 in two phases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School kids to lend Aadhaar details during re-admission</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/school-kids-lend-aadhaar-details-re-admission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/school-kids-lend-aadhaar-details-re-admission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on directives from the central government, the directorate of education(DoE) has asked schools under its purview to record the Aadhaar card numbers of its students. Director of education G P Bhat said that the idea was to “arrest any duplication of benefits of central government schemes extended to students”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“School children receive benefit from several central government schemes like midday meals, free raincoats and notebooks, incentives to girl students, etc,” Bhat said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DoE has issued a circular to schools asking them to inform students of the need to submit their Aadhaar card numbers when declaring the annual results for the current academic year, so that students bring with them the necessary details while seeking readmission in the higher class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move, aimed at ‘improving efficiency and transparency’, comes following a push from the central government to link the Aadhaar number with subsidy schemes related to school education. The department of school education and literacy (DSEL), under the human resource development ministry, has decided to give a window until June 30 to those who do not have an Aadhaar card yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Notes Ban, 18 Lakh Cases Of Income, Bank Account Mismatches Detected: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government authorities have detected 18 lakh cases after demonetisation where the income profiles of people do not match their account profile, the Lok Sabha was informed today. Preliminary information has been sought from such people and many have responded. Those who have not given details would be issued with notices as per procedure, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said during Question Hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to supplementaries, he said there was an extended footprint of digitisation in the banking sector. With digitisation, the risk of tampering of technology also increases. But banks are also hiring experts to develop firewalls around their system to make it increasingly difficult to breach it, Jaitley said, adding that technology has to keep pace with crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that risk assessment was a continuous process for banks who do it individually and collectively. In his written response, Jaitley said as on March 31, 2016, 29 per cent of the savings accounts of public sector banks and regional rural banks sponsored by them were inoperative or lying dormant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A variety of factors have a bearing on an account being inoperative. These may include factors like opening of a new account with change of residence or office, death of the account holder or the relative convenience of operating different accounts, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Counter Jio, Airtel, Vodafone Launch New Plans. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/to-counter-jio-airtel-vodafone-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/to-counter-jio-airtel-vodafone-launch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As new comer Jio, the telecom arm of conglomerate Reliance Industries, continues to offer discounted tariffs under its &amp;ldquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; offer in a bid to attract more customers, top two telecom players - Airtel and Vodafone - have launched data-oriented prepaid plans and offers to restrict their existing customers to switch to Reliance Jio. From Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 244 plan to Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s Rs 352 recharge pack, the incumbent telecom operators are aiming to retain their existing customers based on their individual usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-of-the-recharge-plans-offered-by-airtel-and-vodafone-to-counter-jio-s-offers&#34;&gt;Here are some of the recharge plans offered by Airtel and Vodafone to counter Jio&amp;rsquo;s offers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-399-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs 399 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs 399 recharge pack, Airtel is offering 1GB of 4G data per day along with free voice calls to any network for 70 days. However, there are some limitations on voice calls. You can do 300 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to Airtel (1200 minutes in a week) and for other networks, 3,000 minutes of free local and STD calls for 70 days. If you exhaust the free minutes, Rs 0.10 per minute will be charged.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bharti-airtel_650x400_61492413333.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-345-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs. 345 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel is offering 2GB of data per day at 4G speed for 28 days under its new Rs 345 recharge pack. Also, now there is no restriction with regard to the timing of data consumption. Under the earlier Rs 345 recharge pack, users were restricted to use only 500 MB of data daily from 6 am till midnight , and the remaining 500 MB between 12 am and 6 am. Along with the above data, users will also get free voice calls to Airtel and other networks as it is in the Rs 399 pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;airtel-rs-244-recharge&#34;&gt;Airtel Rs. 244 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Rs 244 recharge, users will get 1 GB of 4G data per day for 70 days without any restriction on usage timing. But this pack offers free calls on Airtel networks only (300 minutes of daily Airtel-to-Airtel calling and 1,200 minutes for a week for 70 days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above three recharge packs of Airtel have become active from April 15, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;vodafone-rs-352-recharge&#34;&gt;Vodafone Rs. 352 recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under its Rs 352 recharge pack, Vodafone offers 1GB of data per day for 56 days along with unlimited local and STD calls with a capping of 300 minutes in a day and 1,200 minutes in a week. If you cross the call limit, a fee of 30 paise per minute will be charged for every call. This offer is not available for every Vodafone users. You can check if the offer is available for you by dialing *121# from your Vodafone number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At SBI, You Don&#39;t Need To Maintain Minimum Balance In These Accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India is offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has said it is exempting its customers holding certain account types from maintenance of average monthly balance. Such accounts include small savings bank accounts, basic savings bank accounts and Jan Dhan accounts, or the accounts opened under the government&amp;rsquo;s financial inclusion scheme Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana or PMJDY. This was said in a tweet by SBI, which recently adopted a new brand identity after merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank. SBI had earlier decided to increase the minimum balance required for maintaining savings accounts from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, State Bank of India is also offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.
Account holders of the following types of accounts are exempt from requiring to maintain an average monthly balance: pic.twitter.com/61U8QNu7xR
— State Bank of India (@TheOfficialSBI) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement was increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros. In case of non-compliance, savings bank account holders will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs. 100 (in metro cities), as per the bank&amp;rsquo;s website. (Read more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other features SBI offers under these accounts, according to its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-savings-bank-account&#34;&gt;Small savings bank account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account has a maximum balance limit of Rs 50,000 and offers a rate of interest applicable to savings bank accounts. Account holders get an ATM-cum-Debit card, issued free of cost and without any annual maintenance charge, as per the SBI website. All credits in a financial year should not aggregate to more than Rs 1 lakh and Rs 10,000 in case of withdrawals and transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-savings-account&#34;&gt;Basic savings account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s basic savings account has no minimum balance or maximum balance limits. Holders of this account type &amp;ldquo;will not be eligible to open any other Savings Bank Account&amp;rdquo; at the bank. Such an account - in case the customer already holds one - will have to be closed within 30 days of opening the basic savings bank deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;corporate-salary-package&#34;&gt;Corporate salary package&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s salary account under corporate salary package offers many benefits to the employer and the employee alike. This account type reduces employer&amp;rsquo;s paperwork and salary administration cost. Employees get free internet banking and mobile banking services, among other features, as per the SBI website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>