<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, you can pay by hour for your hotel stay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/you-can-pay-by-hour-for-your/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of hotels charging for the whole day is beginning to change with some hospitality chains now offering stays for shorter durations at a fraction of the per-day cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move primarily benefits pilgrims and other travellers who break their journey for a few hours en route to their destination. For instance, booking a hotel through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frotels.com/&#34;&gt;Frotels.com&lt;/a&gt; for a two-hour package at Hotel Imperial Palace at Andheri in Mumbai works out to be Rs 630, as opposed to Rs 2,637 per room night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budget accommodations and branded hotels are foraying into the shorter stay segment for their properties near airports, railway stations or in pilgrim towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel chain Lemon Tree started the initiative early this year. &amp;ldquo;We decided to adopt this strategy because in most of our business hotels, 60% to 70% of departures happen early morning and likewise arrivals happen in the evening,&amp;rdquo; said Devinder Kumar, general manager, Revenue Management and eCommerce, Lemon Tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catering exclusively to shorter stays, FreshUp, a hospitality startup, is setting up an accommodation in Tirupathi with hourly rates. &amp;ldquo;We have bunker beds, meeting rooms and relaxation lounges suited for guests who would just like to freshen up for a couple of hours or more. We have 2 or 3 hour packages per person for about Rs 299,&amp;rdquo; said Vinil Reddy, founder, FreshUp. The company has set up a centre in Hyderabad and is looking to start facilities in Bengaluru, Chennai and Rameshwaram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookings mostly happen through websites such as 6-hourly, Frotels, Mistay, 9to5.com, which serve as aggregators of the branded hotels and budget accommodations offering booking by the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are vacant rooms available during the day hours (10 am - 2 pm) which we strategically vend through our website for better inventory management,&amp;rdquo; said Kumar of Lemontree. The company has witnessed a 100% increase in the number of bookings in the last three months since it have started offering this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel aggregators see the trend picking up in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with Oyo Rooms accepting check-ins at 6 am and now hotels are warming up to the concept of using their inventory judiciously. With this option, budget hotels can use the same inventory twice over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It works out economical for the customer as well as they would otherwise end up paying for the whole day or stay at an airport lounge or waiting rooms of the railway stations,&amp;rdquo; said Akshay Chhugani, head of product marketing with Ixigo, a travel and hospitality aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-facility to link Aadhaar with PAN launched</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I-T Department asks people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched an e-facility to link Aadhaar with Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing IT returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department’s e-filing website &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; has created the link on its homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires the PAN, the Aadhaar number and the “exact name as given in the Aadhaar card”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After verification from the UIDAI [Unique Identification Authority of India], the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in the Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP [one time password] will be required,” the department said in an advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OTP would be sent on the registered mobile number and email of an individual, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department urged people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no need to login or be registered on the e-filing website. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of the Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a 10-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>99 देशों पर साइबर अटैक: चपेट में ये देसी कंपनियां एवं सरकारी संस्थान</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-companies-and-government-institutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;दुनियाभर के 99 देशों पर हुए साइबर अटैक की चपेट में देश की कई कंपनियां भी आ गईं। रैनसमवेअर वानाक्राइ से प्रभावित हुईं कंपनियों में दो दक्षिण भारतीय बैंक, दिल्ली की दो मैन्युफैक्चरिंग कंपनियां, बहुराष्ट्रीय कंपनी (एमएनसी) की एक मैन्युफैक्चरिंग यूनिट, मुंबई की एक दिग्गज कंपनी और एक एफएमसीजी कंपनी के मुख्यालय शामिल हैं। इनके अलावा, आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के 100 से ज्यादा कंप्यूटर भी इस भयावह हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुरक्षा विशेषज्ञों का मानना है कि इस हमले से हुआ नुकसान और ज्यादा हो सकता है और प्रभावित कंपनियों की तादाद बढ़ सकती है। चूंकि यह हमला वीकेंड में (शुक्रवार को) हुआ है, इसलिए नुकसान का सही-सही आकलन सोमवार को ही किया जा सकता है जब सारे पर्सनल कंप्यूटर्स स्टार्ट किए जाएंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EY इंडिया में पाटर्नर (फ्रॉड इन्वेस्टिगेशन ऐंड डिस्प्यूट सर्विसेज) मुकुल श्रीवास्तव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;भारतीय कंपनियां हालिया हमले की चपेट में आई हैं। पिछले एक साल में रैनसमवेअर के मामले बहुत बढ़ गए हैं। अब साइबर क्रिमिनल्स बेहद टेक सेवी हो चुके हैं और हरेक रैनसमवेअर की अपनी यूनीक एन्क्रिप्टिंग मशीनें हैं। ये हमले लगातार बाधा पहुंचाने और फिरौती वसूलने के मकसद से हो रहे हैं। इसलिए संगठनों को ऐसे खतरों का सामना करने के लिए गंभीर उपाय करने होंगे। हम साइबरक्राइम और रैनसमवेअर के खिलाफ समाधान प्रक्रिया में कई देसी एवं वैश्विक कंपनियों के साथ काम कर रहे हैं।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जाल में ऐसे फंसाते हैं हैकर्स, रहें सावधान&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;शुक्रवार को मैलवेअर बड़ी तेजी से फैल गया और दुनियाभर की कंपनियों एवं सरकारी संगठनों में कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए। दरअसल, रैनसमवेअर के डाउनलोड होते ही सभी कंप्यूटर लॉक हो गए और उनमें पड़े डेटा एन्क्रिप्ट कर लिए गए। हमलावर ने इन डेटा को रीस्टोर करने के लिए फिरौती की मांग की।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कंपनियां ऐसे हमलों से निपटने के लिए देश के जिन साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स को हायर कर रही हैं, उनके मुताबिक ऐसे कई मामले सामने आए हैं जब भारतीय कंपनियों ने अपने प्रभावित कंप्यूटरों को दुबारा ऐक्सेस करने के एवज में फिरौती दी। यूके की नैशनल हेल्थ सर्विसेज (एनएसएस) जैसे वैश्विक संस्थान और रेनॉ, फेडेक्स एवं टेलिफोनिका जैसी कंपनियों ने हमले से प्रभावित होने की जानकारी दी, लेकिन देश की एक भी कंपनी ने नहीं बताया कि उनके कंप्यूटर हमले के शिकार हुए हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आंध्र प्रदेश पुलिस के कंप्यूटरों पर साइबर हमले, फिरौती मांग रहे हैकर&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक्सपर्ट्स का कहना है कि शुक्रवार को फैलाया गया मैलवेअर अमेरिका की नैशनल सिक्यॉरिटी एजेंसी का वही इटरनलब्लू टूल है जिसे अप्रैल महीने में द शैडो ब्रॉकर्स नाम के हैकर ग्रुप ने चुरा लिया था। दिग्गज साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी कंपनी अवास्ट ने कहा कि उसने रैनसमवेअर और इसके विभिन्न रूपों के 75,000 मामले देखे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एक साइबर सिक्यॉरिटी एक्सपर्ट ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इस हमला कुछ अलग है। इससे कोई एक बार इन्फेक्ट हो गया तो हो गया। इसे हटाने के लिए तीन से चार घंटे लगेंगे और पीसी रीबूट करना पड़ेगा। हालांकि, इसमें कोई नुकसान या कोई डेटा खत्म नहीं होता।&amp;rsquo; साइबर एक्सपर्ट्स के मुताबिक, भारतीय कंपनियों पर रैनसमवेअर अटैक्स के मामले में एक सिलिसला सा जुड़ रहा है। पिछले तीन महीनों में 25 से 30 ऐसे मामले सामने आ चुके हैं जब कंपनियां मैलवेअर का शिकार हुई हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBSE affiliated schools to be made Aadhaar centres</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to ensure that all students have unique identification number to be enrolled, the Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) recently directed all its affiliated schools to set up Aadhaar enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To implement this, the board has collaborated with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) to collect demographic and biometric data of residents directly or through enrolment agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-on-the-report&#34;&gt;More on the report:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, schools are free to decide whether or not to set up the centres&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if a school wishes to set up an Aadhaar centre, then they can do so by signing a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with either the Board or UIDAI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, the board has asked schools to procure equipment for the purpose as per the UIDAI check list&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reasons-behind-this-step&#34;&gt;Reasons behind this step:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As reported, this move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-cbse-said-in-its-notice&#34;&gt;Here’s what CBSE said in its notice:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools shall set up enrolment centres to facilitate their bonafide students, teachers, staff and their family members to to enrol for Aadhar and make any updation or corrections,” it said in a communication to schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Equipment such as computer, printer, biometric devices and other such things will have to be procured by the school themselves and should be as per the UIDAI specifications,” as reported in a recent PTI report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to encourage students to enroll themselves, the schools will not be charging any fees for the Aadhaar enrolment; but CBSE will pay them Rs 30 for every enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the February 2017 data of the board, there are 18,546 CBSE affiliated schools in India and 210 schools in 25 foreign countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, the schools will also be required to adhere to all code of conducts applicable to other enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1,000 Each Month For 20 Years Is Now Rs. 26,00,000 In This Fund</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/dsp-blackrock-equity-fund-completes-20-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DSP BlackRock Equity Fund recently completed 20 years of its existence. The fund (dividend option) has delivered 20.65 per cent compound annual growth rate since its inception, outperforming the 13 per cent return of Nifty50 index by a huge margin, says its website. The objective of DSP BlackRock Equity Fund is to seek to generate long-term capital appreciation, from a portfolio that is substantially constituted of equity securities and equity related securities of issuers domiciled in India. DSP BlackRock Equity Fund benchmarks itself against NIFTY 500 index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you consider the NIFTY 500, DSP BlackRock Equity Fund has also outperformed this index by a big margin. NIFTY 500 has delivered a return of 14.4 per cent during the past 20 years as compared to the fund&amp;rsquo;s 20.65 per cent return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you had invested Rs 1,000 in the fund each month since its inception? Now you would be sitting on a corpus of nearly Rs 26 lakh as compared to your invested amount of Rs 2.41 lakh crore. If you had invested Rs 4,000 each month, it would have been over a crore now. Returns for investments in dividend plans of schemes are calculated after assuming that the net dividend payouts post statutory taxes &amp;amp; levies, are re-invested back in the scheme. As of March 31, 2017, the fund had assets worth Rs 2,310 crore under management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the country&amp;rsquo;s mutual fund industry managed an asset base of over Rs 18 lakh crore. Mutual funds are investment vehicles made up of a pool of funds collected from a large number of investors. The funds are invested in stocks, bonds and money market instruments, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inflows into domestic equity mutual funds have helped Sensex and Nifty rise to record levels. According to estimates domestic investors are pouring in Rs 4,000 crore every month into equity mutual funds through systematic investment route. Systematic Investment Plans or SIPs are fixed amounts invested at regular intervals in a financial instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Hiring For Marketing Department. Check Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-hiring-for-marketing-department-check-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-hiring-for-marketing-department-check-details/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For SBI&amp;rsquo;s recruitment, the online registration of application and payment of fees which commenced on May 12 will end on May 25.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, State Bank of India (SBI) is inviting recruitment applications for its marketing department. SBI is asking to hire one person each for five different posts which are: Senior Vice President (Brand/Media/Research), Vice President (Marketing Communications), Vice President (Digital Marketing), Vice President (Media Strategy and Operations) and Senior Manager (Digital Marketing). These specialists in the marketing field will be hired on a contract basis. The online registration of application and payment of fees which commenced on May 12 will end on May 25. The last date for receipt of print out of the application along with enclosures is May 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contract, which is for a period of three years, will be renewable at the discretion of the bank. The contract can be terminated at one month&amp;rsquo;s notice on either side or on payment/surrender of one month&amp;rsquo;s compensation amount. While applying for the post, the applicant should ensure that he/she fulfils the eligibility and other norms and that the particulars furnished by him/her are correct in all respects. Also, candidates are required to have a valid email ID which should be kept active during the recruitment exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-the-selection-procedure&#34;&gt;What is the selection procedure?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The selection procedure of candidates will be based on short listing (qualification, experience and overall suitability) and personal interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;application-fee&#34;&gt;Application fee:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application fee (non-refundable) is of Rs 600 and the payment needs to be done online. Application fee once paid will not be refunded nor can it be adjusted for any other examination or selection in future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UDAN Funding: Government Brings Down Levy To Rs 5,000</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/udan-funding-government-brings-down-levy-to-rs-5-000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/udan-funding-government-brings-down-levy-to-rs-5-000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) &amp;ndash; the Civil Aviation Ministry is collecting a levy of up to Rs 8,500 per departure from airlines operating in major domestic routes, including Mumbai and Delhi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has decided to reduce the regional air connectivity levy charged from airlines flying on major routes to a uniform rate of Rs 5,000 per flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fund the ambitious regional connectivity scheme &amp;ndash; UDAN (Ude Desh ka Aam Naagrik) &amp;ndash; the Civil Aviation Ministry is collecting a levy of up to Rs 8,500 per departure from airlines operating in major domestic routes, including Mumbai and Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a senior official, the ministry has decided to bring down the levy amount to a uniform rate of Rs 5,000 per flight on major routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move comes at a time when the government is looking to &amp;ldquo;refine&amp;rdquo; the present norms for UDAN ahead of the second round of bidding which is likely in three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With at least half of the seats in UDAN flights offered at subsidised fares, the participating carriers would be provided a certain amount of Viability Gap Funding (VGF) &amp;ndash; an amount shared between the Centre and the states concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The levy is being collected towards the VGF. The Federation of Indian Airlines (FIA) has already challenged the collection of levy from carriers for the RCS fund in the court. Jet Airways, IndiGo, SpiceJet and GoAir are members of the FIA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry started collecting the levy from December 1, 2016. Airports Authority of India (AAI) is the nodal agency for UDAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about local carriers moving court against the levy, AAI Chairman Guruprasad Mohapatra recently told PTI that he hoped that the issue would be resolved soon even as he asserted that the scheme would not suffer due to court case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The scheme will not be affected by virtue of this dispute&amp;hellip;These are all government of India schemes and they don&amp;rsquo;t suffer on account of some court cases. They are sovereign commitments,&amp;rdquo; he had said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, UDAN scheme commenced with the first flight starting from Shimla to the national capital. In the first round of UDAN bidding, five airlines won bids to operate on 128 routes connecting 70 airports of which 31 are un-served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;(Before) the second round of bidding, we will further refine (the scheme) after extensive stakeholder consultations,&amp;rdquo; Mohapatra had said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पेट्रोल पंप मालिकों ने वापस लिया संडे को छुट्टी का प्रस्ताव</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-took-back-the-proposal-of-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-took-back-the-proposal-of-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;देशभर के पेट्रोल पंप मालिकों ने 14 मई से रविवार के प्रस्तावित साप्ताहिक अवकाश और 15 मई से एक शिफ्ट में पंपों के संचालन का फैसला शनिवार को वापस ले लिया। एक आधिकारिक बयान जारी कर यह जानकारी दी गई।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फेडरेशन ऑफ ऑल महाराष्ट्र पेट्रोल डीलर्स असोसिएशन (एफएएमपीईडीए) के अध्यक्ष उदय लोध ने कहा कि तेल विपणन कंपनियों (ओमसी) द्वारा बुधवार को बुलाई गई समीक्षा बैठक में अगली सूचना तक प्रस्तावित विरोध प्रदर्शन को स्थगित करने का फैसला लिया गया। एफएएमपीईडी सहित भारत के पेट्रोल डीलर्स के गुट (सीआईपीडी) ने महाराष्ट्र, कर्नाटक, केरल, तमिलनाडु, पुडुचेरी, आंध्र प्रदेश, तेलंगाना और हरियाणा में &amp;lsquo;कॉस्ट कटिंग मॉड्यूल&amp;rsquo; लांच करने की योजना बनाई है। लोध ने कहा कि प्रस्तावित कदम से महाराष्ट्र में ही 4,500 पेट्रोल पंप प्रभावित होते, जिनमें मुंबई में ही 225 पेट्रोल पंप हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एफएएमपीईडीए यह प्रस्तावित अवकाश सीआईपीडी के आह्वान पर ओमसी से की गई मांगों के समर्थन में शुरू करने जा रही थी। सीआईपीडी काफी समय से ओएमसी से डीलर्स मार्जिन बढ़ाने सहित कई मांगें कर रही है। लोध ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हमें पिछले साल नवंबर में तेल कंपनियों से हुए समझौते पर चर्चा करने के लिए अगले बुधवार को बुलाया गया है इसलिए तब तक हमने विरोध प्रदर्शन को स्थगित करने का फैसला किया है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्होंने कहा कि पेट्रोल पंपों को इस समय काफी कम मार्जिन मिल रहा है। उन्नत किस्म का सीसा रहित पेट्रोल और डीजल बहुत तेजी से वाष्पित होता है, जिससे काफी घाटा सहना पड़ता है। लोध ने कहा कि इसके अलावा भी कई मुद्दे हैं, हर पेट्रोल पंप पर कर्मचारियों को न्यूनतम वेतन देना संभव नहीं है। पेट्रोल पंपों द्वारा रविवार को अवकाश करने और शेष दिन एक शिफ्ट में पंप का संचालन करने के फैसले से महाराष्ट्र में ही करीब एक लाख कामगार प्रभावित होते, जो अमूमन रोज दो शिफ्ट में काम करते हैं।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Plans To Open Jan Aushadhi Stores At 1,000 Railway Stations</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-plans-to-open-jan-aushadhi-stores-at-1-000-railway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-plans-to-open-jan-aushadhi-stores-at-1-000-railway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plans are also on to open such outlets at bus stands in different states with an aim to take the network to small towns and villages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plans are afoot to open Jan Aushadhi stores at around 1,000 major railway stations across India as part of drive to make quality medicines available at low cost to the public, the government said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plans are also on to open such outlets at bus stands in different states with an aim to take the network to small towns and villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chemicals and Fertilisers Minister Ananth Kumar said efforts are being made to ensure prescription of generic medicines by doctors for the benefit of patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am going to speak to Railways Minister Suresh Prahbu in the coming days to open Jan Aushadhi stores (JAS) in 1,000 main railway stations in the country,&amp;rdquo; Kumar told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said that in order to make affordable medicines to poor people in smaller towns and villages, his ministry is looking at setting up JAS at bus stops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am going to write to the state chief ministers and later speak to them to open JAS wherever there is a bus stand,&amp;rdquo; the minister added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said under the BJP-led government, the number of JAS has been increased to over 1,320 from 88 set up during the previous UPA regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of this year, we will have at least 3,000 JAS across India. The turnover of JAS will also touch Rs 60 crore, up from Rs 3 crore,&amp;rdquo; Kumar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure that good quality medicines are available at JAS, the minister said only those companies which comply with WHO certified good manufacturing practices will be eligible for supplies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Out of 10,000 pharmaceutical companies in India, only 1,400 are WHO GMP certified and only they will be able to participate in tender process,&amp;rdquo; Kumar added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is also encouraging the youth to participate in opening of JAS, he said, adding that already 30,000 applications have been received which are under process for approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The aim is to take JAS to every block level of the country,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides expanding the JAS network, the minister said, the government has also expanded the basket of medicines available in the stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Today 23 therapeutic areas are covered with 500 medicines and 150 health supplements in JAS,&amp;rdquo; Kumar said, adding that the focus is on drugs for major diseases such as heart ailments, diabetes, respiratory problems, HIV and blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about making prescription of generic medicines by doctors mandatory, he said the Medical Council of India has already issued a circular to doctors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the health ministry has also asked central government hospitals to make prescription of generic drugs mandatory. All the state governments have also been sent advisories regarding the same, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On whether the government is bringing a legal framework for compulsory prescription of generic medicines, Kumar said at present the Drugs &amp;amp; Cosmetics Act prevents pharmacies to give equivalent of generic medicine and whatever is prescribe has to be given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A substitute cannot be given therefore we are going to bring in amendments in the Drugs &amp;amp; Cosmetics Act,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister said however that the government has no intention of banning branded drugs in the country saying there is also a need to encourage drug development and make business of pharmaceutical firms viable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Otherwise, we will become what we have in bulk drugs where we are a net importer, that too from only one source (China),&amp;rdquo; Kumar said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian ISRAELI-ORIGIN GUNS: INDIA WILL SOON START MAKING THESE FIVE DEADLY GUNS</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arming-india-india-will-soon-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arming-india-india-will-soon-start/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;From India&amp;rsquo;s first private small arms manufacturing unit based at Malanpur, M.P., India, and Israel will manufacture lethal Israeli guns for the Indian armed forces and the world. This has been made possible through a joint venture between Indian defence conglomerate, Punj Lloyd, and Israel Weapon Industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As clearly stated by Army Chief General Bipin Rawat there is a need to invest more in the military, in view of emerging security threats. And these are the guns that will add to the capabilities of the armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/FmkUwDRSdI8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;tavor&#34;&gt;Tavor&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Besides the Israel Defence Forces, it is being used across the world, including by the US and the Special Forces of the Indian Army, Navy and IAF. This weapon was also used during the surgical strikes in POK. The Special Frontier Force (SFF), a covert special operations unit, created with the help of the CIA post the 1962 India-China war, is also using them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bullpup-configuration&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Bullpup Configuration&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bullpup configuration&amp;rdquo; makes it compact, perfect for counter-terrorist operations in built up areas such as J&amp;amp;K.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves gun&amp;rsquo;s accuracy and reduces weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable at all firing positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrosion resistant metal parts. Easily maintainable in adverse battle conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses 5.56mm cartridges, as adopted by NATO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The capacity of 30 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Punj Lloyd pitching it as a replacement for INSAS rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;negev-light-machine-gun&#34;&gt;Negev Light Machine Gun&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Negev_NG7_Light_Machine_Gun.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A robust light machine gun with powerful target acquisition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopted by the Israeli Defence Forces in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also has a semi-automatic mode to provide accurate, controlled fire in close quarter battle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic mode for maximum firepower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mountable&#34;&gt;Mountable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negev cartridges are placed in the gun from a belt, which can contain up to 200 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses 5.56 mm and 7.65 mm cartridges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has different variants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Known to be a reliable weapon under extreme conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important feature: Can be mounted on inside helicopters, over vehicles and naval vessels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gun being used by the Indian armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;galil-sniper&#34;&gt;Galil Sniper&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Galil_Sniper_Rifle.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can hit targets up to 1 km away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even at this range will fire accurately at targets, which are small and mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With this weapon, combat units gain efficiency in firing at long range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The semi-automatic feature ensures it is stable while firing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7.65mm calibre and has a capacity of 10 to 25 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foldable bipod makes it suitable for user&amp;rsquo;s needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;raw-s-aim&#34;&gt;RAW&amp;rsquo;s Aim&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galil sniper being used by the covert RAW unit, Special Frontier Force, and Indian Army.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Army has been searching for sniper rifles for infantry units and Special Forces to replace the Russian Dragunov sniper rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Army&amp;rsquo;s aim is to get the new sniper rifle with greater range, accuracy, and firepower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian Navy&amp;rsquo;s MARCOS also using the rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galil is a family of small arms named after its designer, Yisrael Galil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;world-manufacturing-hub&#34;&gt;World Manufacturing Hub&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/IWI_Punj_Lloyd_Small_Arms_Plant.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Picture of the inauguration of the small arms plant at Malanpur by Madhya Pradesh Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mark Shachar, V.P. Business Development, S K Group, explained the plant will be a hub of manufacturing the weapons for the Indian armed forces and will also export them. &amp;ldquo;We will also make the plant a centre of maintenance for these guns for India and abroad,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JioFiber, Reliance Jio Broadband, In These Cities</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/preview-offer-of-jiofiber-reliance-jio-broadband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/preview-offer-of-jiofiber-reliance-jio-broadband/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid and postpaid offerings have led to further competition in Indian telecom sector since the launch of its paid &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; services.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services being launched in some areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JioFiber Preview Offer being tested in select Mumbai areas, among others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm provides telecom services under brand Jio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid heightened competition in the telecom sector due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, the market is abuzz about Jio&amp;rsquo;s broadband services - JioFiber. Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services - called &amp;ldquo;JioFiber&amp;rdquo; - are being launched in some parts of cities like Mumbai, Delhi and Vadodara. This was said on Twitter by Jio&amp;rsquo;s official customer support- Jio Care. Jio, whose prepaid and postpaid offerings have led to further competition in Indian telecom sector since the launch of its paid &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; services, is testing a &amp;ldquo;JioFiber Preview Offer&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;select areas of Mumbai, Delhi-NCR, Ahmedabad, Jamnagar, Surat and Vadodara&amp;rdquo;, Jio Care said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care also said the company&amp;rsquo;s network is in the process of being rolled out to other cities. Jio Care was responding to a query posted by an individual on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, is a provider of telecom services under brand Jio. &amp;ldquo;The Company continues to make progress on the roll-out of its Fibre to the Home (FTTH) business offering with beta trials initiated in a few locations. It would expand the scope of the beta trials over the next few months,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Industries said recently while announcing earnings for the financial year ended March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, Reliance Jio has not revealed more details about the JioFiber broadband or its fiber-to-the-home (FTTH) service - which was mentioned by Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani while launching Jio operations in September last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While announcing the launch of pan-India digital services with its &amp;ldquo;Welcome Offer&amp;rdquo; in September last year, Jio had said: &amp;ldquo;In addition to fixed and wireless broadband connectivity offering superior voice and data services on an all-IP network, Jio will also offer end-to-end solutions that address the entire value chain across various digital services in key domains such as education, healthcare, security, communication, financial services, government-citizen interfaces and entertainment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care team did not name any other cities where the JioFiber Preview Offer was being tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some analysts say Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing has intensified competition in the Indian telecom sector, forcing existing players to come up with lower tariffs. Reliance Jio is likely to gain market share from existing telecom operators, ratings agency India Ratings and Research said earlier this month, while revising its outlook on India&amp;rsquo;s telecom services sector outlook from &amp;lsquo;stable&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;negative&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service, which came into effect from April 1, include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio has said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>