<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Plans To Open Jan Aushadhi Stores At 1,000 Railway Stations</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-plans-to-open-jan-aushadhi-stores-at-1-000-railway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-plans-to-open-jan-aushadhi-stores-at-1-000-railway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plans are also on to open such outlets at bus stands in different states with an aim to take the network to small towns and villages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plans are afoot to open Jan Aushadhi stores at around 1,000 major railway stations across India as part of drive to make quality medicines available at low cost to the public, the government said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plans are also on to open such outlets at bus stands in different states with an aim to take the network to small towns and villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chemicals and Fertilisers Minister Ananth Kumar said efforts are being made to ensure prescription of generic medicines by doctors for the benefit of patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am going to speak to Railways Minister Suresh Prahbu in the coming days to open Jan Aushadhi stores (JAS) in 1,000 main railway stations in the country,&amp;rdquo; Kumar told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further said that in order to make affordable medicines to poor people in smaller towns and villages, his ministry is looking at setting up JAS at bus stops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am going to write to the state chief ministers and later speak to them to open JAS wherever there is a bus stand,&amp;rdquo; the minister added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said under the BJP-led government, the number of JAS has been increased to over 1,320 from 88 set up during the previous UPA regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of this year, we will have at least 3,000 JAS across India. The turnover of JAS will also touch Rs 60 crore, up from Rs 3 crore,&amp;rdquo; Kumar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure that good quality medicines are available at JAS, the minister said only those companies which comply with WHO certified good manufacturing practices will be eligible for supplies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Out of 10,000 pharmaceutical companies in India, only 1,400 are WHO GMP certified and only they will be able to participate in tender process,&amp;rdquo; Kumar added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is also encouraging the youth to participate in opening of JAS, he said, adding that already 30,000 applications have been received which are under process for approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The aim is to take JAS to every block level of the country,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides expanding the JAS network, the minister said, the government has also expanded the basket of medicines available in the stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Today 23 therapeutic areas are covered with 500 medicines and 150 health supplements in JAS,&amp;rdquo; Kumar said, adding that the focus is on drugs for major diseases such as heart ailments, diabetes, respiratory problems, HIV and blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about making prescription of generic medicines by doctors mandatory, he said the Medical Council of India has already issued a circular to doctors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the health ministry has also asked central government hospitals to make prescription of generic drugs mandatory. All the state governments have also been sent advisories regarding the same, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On whether the government is bringing a legal framework for compulsory prescription of generic medicines, Kumar said at present the Drugs &amp;amp; Cosmetics Act prevents pharmacies to give equivalent of generic medicine and whatever is prescribe has to be given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A substitute cannot be given therefore we are going to bring in amendments in the Drugs &amp;amp; Cosmetics Act,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister said however that the government has no intention of banning branded drugs in the country saying there is also a need to encourage drug development and make business of pharmaceutical firms viable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Otherwise, we will become what we have in bulk drugs where we are a net importer, that too from only one source (China),&amp;rdquo; Kumar said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian ISRAELI-ORIGIN GUNS: INDIA WILL SOON START MAKING THESE FIVE DEADLY GUNS</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arming-india-india-will-soon-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/arming-india-india-will-soon-start/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;From India&amp;rsquo;s first private small arms manufacturing unit based at Malanpur, M.P., India, and Israel will manufacture lethal Israeli guns for the Indian armed forces and the world. This has been made possible through a joint venture between Indian defence conglomerate, Punj Lloyd, and Israel Weapon Industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As clearly stated by Army Chief General Bipin Rawat there is a need to invest more in the military, in view of emerging security threats. And these are the guns that will add to the capabilities of the armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/FmkUwDRSdI8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;tavor&#34;&gt;Tavor&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Besides the Israel Defence Forces, it is being used across the world, including by the US and the Special Forces of the Indian Army, Navy and IAF. This weapon was also used during the surgical strikes in POK. The Special Frontier Force (SFF), a covert special operations unit, created with the help of the CIA post the 1962 India-China war, is also using them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bullpup-configuration&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Bullpup Configuration&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bullpup configuration&amp;rdquo; makes it compact, perfect for counter-terrorist operations in built up areas such as J&amp;amp;K.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves gun&amp;rsquo;s accuracy and reduces weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable at all firing positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrosion resistant metal parts. Easily maintainable in adverse battle conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses 5.56mm cartridges, as adopted by NATO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The capacity of 30 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Punj Lloyd pitching it as a replacement for INSAS rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;negev-light-machine-gun&#34;&gt;Negev Light Machine Gun&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Negev_NG7_Light_Machine_Gun.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A robust light machine gun with powerful target acquisition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopted by the Israeli Defence Forces in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also has a semi-automatic mode to provide accurate, controlled fire in close quarter battle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic mode for maximum firepower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mountable&#34;&gt;Mountable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negev cartridges are placed in the gun from a belt, which can contain up to 200 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses 5.56 mm and 7.65 mm cartridges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has different variants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Known to be a reliable weapon under extreme conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important feature: Can be mounted on inside helicopters, over vehicles and naval vessels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gun being used by the Indian armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;galil-sniper&#34;&gt;Galil Sniper&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Galil_Sniper_Rifle.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can hit targets up to 1 km away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even at this range will fire accurately at targets, which are small and mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With this weapon, combat units gain efficiency in firing at long range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The semi-automatic feature ensures it is stable while firing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7.65mm calibre and has a capacity of 10 to 25 rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foldable bipod makes it suitable for user&amp;rsquo;s needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;raw-s-aim&#34;&gt;RAW&amp;rsquo;s Aim&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galil sniper being used by the covert RAW unit, Special Frontier Force, and Indian Army.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Army has been searching for sniper rifles for infantry units and Special Forces to replace the Russian Dragunov sniper rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Army&amp;rsquo;s aim is to get the new sniper rifle with greater range, accuracy, and firepower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian Navy&amp;rsquo;s MARCOS also using the rifle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galil is a family of small arms named after its designer, Yisrael Galil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;world-manufacturing-hub&#34;&gt;World Manufacturing Hub&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/IWI_Punj_Lloyd_Small_Arms_Plant.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Picture of the inauguration of the small arms plant at Malanpur by Madhya Pradesh Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mark Shachar, V.P. Business Development, S K Group, explained the plant will be a hub of manufacturing the weapons for the Indian armed forces and will also export them. &amp;ldquo;We will also make the plant a centre of maintenance for these guns for India and abroad,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JioFiber, Reliance Jio Broadband, In These Cities</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/preview-offer-of-jiofiber-reliance-jio-broadband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/preview-offer-of-jiofiber-reliance-jio-broadband/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s prepaid and postpaid offerings have led to further competition in Indian telecom sector since the launch of its paid &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; services.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services being launched in some areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JioFiber Preview Offer being tested in select Mumbai areas, among others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm provides telecom services under brand Jio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid heightened competition in the telecom sector due to aggressive voice call and data pricing by new entrant Reliance Jio, the market is abuzz about Jio&amp;rsquo;s broadband services - JioFiber. Jio&amp;rsquo;s upcoming broadband services - called &amp;ldquo;JioFiber&amp;rdquo; - are being launched in some parts of cities like Mumbai, Delhi and Vadodara. This was said on Twitter by Jio&amp;rsquo;s official customer support- Jio Care. Jio, whose prepaid and postpaid offerings have led to further competition in Indian telecom sector since the launch of its paid &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; services, is testing a &amp;ldquo;JioFiber Preview Offer&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;select areas of Mumbai, Delhi-NCR, Ahmedabad, Jamnagar, Surat and Vadodara&amp;rdquo;, Jio Care said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care also said the company&amp;rsquo;s network is in the process of being rolled out to other cities. Jio Care was responding to a query posted by an individual on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, is a provider of telecom services under brand Jio. &amp;ldquo;The Company continues to make progress on the roll-out of its Fibre to the Home (FTTH) business offering with beta trials initiated in a few locations. It would expand the scope of the beta trials over the next few months,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Industries said recently while announcing earnings for the financial year ended March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, Reliance Jio has not revealed more details about the JioFiber broadband or its fiber-to-the-home (FTTH) service - which was mentioned by Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani while launching Jio operations in September last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While announcing the launch of pan-India digital services with its &amp;ldquo;Welcome Offer&amp;rdquo; in September last year, Jio had said: &amp;ldquo;In addition to fixed and wireless broadband connectivity offering superior voice and data services on an all-IP network, Jio will also offer end-to-end solutions that address the entire value chain across various digital services in key domains such as education, healthcare, security, communication, financial services, government-citizen interfaces and entertainment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s customer care team did not name any other cities where the JioFiber Preview Offer was being tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some analysts say Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing has intensified competition in the Indian telecom sector, forcing existing players to come up with lower tariffs. Reliance Jio is likely to gain market share from existing telecom operators, ratings agency India Ratings and Research said earlier this month, while revising its outlook on India&amp;rsquo;s telecom services sector outlook from &amp;lsquo;stable&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;negative&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options and plans to give benefits of hundreds of GBs of 4G data to its prepaid and postpaid subscribers. All schemes under Jio&amp;rsquo;s paid Prime service, which came into effect from April 1, include free voice call and roaming benefits. &amp;ldquo;Voice is truly free - no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls,&amp;rdquo; Jio has said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 5,000 Per Month For 20 Years. And They Became Crorepatis</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-5-000-per-month-for-20-years-and-they-became-crorepatis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years. Total corpus accumulated: Over Rs. 1 crore. And also tax free. Although, it seems unbelievable, it is a fact that some equity funds have generated over 20 per cent CAGR return over a period of last 20 years and have helped investors accumulate a wealth of over Rs. 1 crore by investing just Rs. 5,000 per month for 20 years or on a total investment of just Rs. 12 lakh. In the present scenario where bank interest rates are on a falling trend, financial planners say that equity mutual funds are one of the best instruments to accumulate long-term savings through systematic investment plan (SIP). Gains from equity mutual funds after a year are tax-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, fund selection is one of the most difficult things to do for a retail investor as it needs lot of research. Financial planners say diversified equity funds are the best to invest through SIP for long term. Here are some funds which have generates over 20 per cent CAGR return in past 20 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Equity Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on January 1, 1995, it is one of the oldest and best performing funds in India. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.95 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 23.56 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Growth Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This fund has generated a CAGR return of 23.68 per cent since its inception. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998 would have helped you accumulate a corpus of Rs. 2.12 crore by April 1, 2017 implying 17.66 times return in 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;Franklin India Prima Fund:&lt;/em&gt; It is one of the flagship fund of Franklin Templeton India. Since its inception in December 1993, it has generated a CAGR return of 21.04 per cent till now. If you had started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 2.38 crore by April 1, 2017, which means a CAGR return of 25.11 per cent over 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;em&gt;Reliance Vision Fund:&lt;/em&gt; Launched on October 8, 1995, it has generated a CAGR return of 19.92 per cent till now. Your Rs. 5,000 SIP in this fund, started on April 1, 1998, would have become Rs. 1.46 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;em&gt;HDFC Top 200 Fund:&lt;/em&gt; This flagship fund of HDFC Mutual Fund has generated a CAGR return of 20.88 per cent since its inception in September 1996. If you would have started an SIP of Rs. 5,000 in this fund on April 1, 1998, your investment would have grown to Rs. 1.43 crore by April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With falling return on bank fixed deposits, equity mutual funds are witnessing increased investment from retail investors now. Equity and equity-linked schemes have seen inflows of more than Rs. 70,000 crore in last financial year according to Association of Mutual Funds in India data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Bank Account:Here Are More Ways To Transfer Your Money</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-transfer-money-using-sbi-mingle-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-transfer-money-using-sbi-mingle-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India had in July 2016 launched the SBI Mingle app, allowing its customers access various banking services via social media sites Facebook and Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is offering a new facility that helps customers transfer money using their accounts on social media sites Facebook and Twitter. Users can &amp;ldquo;conveniently transfer funds&amp;rdquo; by logging on to SBI&amp;rsquo;s app &amp;lsquo;Mingle&amp;rsquo;. This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on microblogging site Twitter. SBI had in July 2016 launched the SBI Mingle app, allowing its customers access various banking services via these social media platforms. The SBI Mingle app is available on Google Play for Android mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are few other things to know about the SBI Mingle app:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is SBI Mingle?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Mingle is a social banking application that enables SBI customers to perform basic banking activities through the bank&amp;rsquo;s official Facebook page, the bank said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-mingle-650-400_650x287_51494382504.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The SBI Mingle app is available on Google Play for Android mobile users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to use Mingle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI customers need to register through a simple one-time process using either their account number or their ATM/Debit Card details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who can use Mingle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using SBI Mingle, SBI customers can do a host of banking services on their preferred social platform (i.e. Facebook and Twitter) at their own convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which all tasks can I perform using SBI&amp;rsquo;s Mingle app?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon completing the registration process, the SBI customers can perform a variety of tasks using the Mingle app. Some of them include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance enquiry of accounts
Obtaining a mini statement
Transfer money - within and outside SBI
Request for cheque book
Blocking of ATM Cards&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-mingle-services_650x400_61494383417.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI New ATM, Cash Transactions Service Charges. All You Need To Know</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-new-atm-cash-transactions-service-charges-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SBI clarified on new charges on ATM and cash transactions to be effective from June 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new rules initially created confusion over ATM charges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s Buddy app will charge Rs 25 on cash withdrawal through ATM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBI also revised service charges on various cash transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India’s largest lender State Bank of India, revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers, effective from June 1. Announced in a circular on the SBI website on Thursday morning, the revisions initially created confusion among customers over news that all cash withdrawals through ATM will now be charged at Rs. 25 per transaction. The bank later clarified that the Rs 25 charge will be levied only on withdrawing money from an ATM through SBI’s mobile wallet app “State Bank Buddy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an emailed statement to NDTV Profit, an SBI spokesperson clarified that a limit of four ATM withdrawals per month only applied to the Basic Savings Banks deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All normal Saving Bank accounts will continue to get 8 free ATM transactions (5 SBI ATMs + 3 other bank ATMs) in metros &amp;amp; 10 free transactions in non-metros (5 SBI ATM + 5 Other Bank ATMs) free, the clarification added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from ATM charges, SBI also  revised service charges on various cash transactions for its customers. Here are some of the other key changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Transfers:&lt;/em&gt; Online fund transfer through IMPS will now be charged Rs. 5 plus service tax for amounts of up to Rs. 1 lakh, Rs. 15 plus service tax for above Rs. 1 lakh and up to Rs. 2 lakh and Rs. 25 plus service tax for above Rs. 2 lakh and up to Rs. 5 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exchange of Soiled Notes:&lt;/em&gt; Going forward SBI said it will charge 2 rupees for every soiled note on exchange of more than 20 notes or if the total value of exchanged notes is above Rs 5,000 plus service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cheque Books:&lt;/em&gt; From June 1, a customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will have to pay Rs 30 plus service tax for a 10 leaf cheque book, Rs 75 with service tax for 25 leaf cheque book and Rs 150 plus service tax for a 50 leaf cheque book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charges on ATM Cards:&lt;/em&gt; SBI said that issue of new debit cards will be charged from June 1 and only Rupay classic card will be issued for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cash Withdrawals:&lt;/em&gt; Customers with a Basic Savings Bank Deposit will get four free withdrawals (including ATM) in a month, after which withdrawals will be charged at Rs 50 plus service tax at an SBI branch and at Rs 20 plus service tax at other bank ATMS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCO Bank Says RBI Begins Corrective Action Over High Bad Loans</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uco-bank-says-rbi-begins-corrective-action-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uco-bank-says-rbi-begins-corrective-action-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under RBI rules, prompt corrective action is triggered if a bank&amp;rsquo;s net NPL ratio crosses 6 percent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has initiated &amp;ldquo;prompt corrective action&amp;rdquo; for state-run UCO Bank over its high bad loans and negative return on assets, UCO said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UCO, in a filing to the stock exchanges, said the action &amp;ldquo;will not have any material impact&amp;rdquo; on its performance, but did not give details of the corrective action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the second state-run lender to come under the curbs of the Reserve Bank of India after the regulator revised the so-called prompt corrective action framework last month, tightening thresholds around bad loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier on Friday, UCO Bank reported a narrowing of its quarterly loss and bad-loan ratio. It had net non-performing loans (NPLs) of 8.94 percent at the end of March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under RBI rules, prompt corrective action is triggered if a bank&amp;rsquo;s net NPL ratio crosses 6 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDBI Bank, another state-run lender, said on Tuesday it was facing corrective action by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysts say more lenders could come under central bank curbs as regulators strive to clean up bad loans of $150 billion in the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-facility to link Aadhaar with PAN launched</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/e-facility-link-aadhaar-pan-launched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I-T Department asks people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched an e-facility to link Aadhaar with Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing IT returns now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department’s e-filing website &lt;a href=&#34;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; has created the link on its homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link requires the PAN, the Aadhaar number and the “exact name as given in the Aadhaar card”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After verification from the UIDAI [Unique Identification Authority of India], the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in the Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP [one time password] will be required,” the department said in an advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OTP would be sent on the registered mobile number and email of an individual, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department urged people to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linkage without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no need to login or be registered on the e-filing website. This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of the Aadhaar application form for filing income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for PAN with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a 10-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory for Joining a Company</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-joining-companys-board/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government has made the biometric authentication using Aadhaar mandatory after facing several scenarios of fake identity theft—including becoming a director on a board of the company or for issuing its returns by company secretaries and chartered accountants—for Companies Act-related transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the sources, the Ministry Of Corporate Affairs has encountered several instances where people have established a Director Identification Number or have been chosen as directors on boards of the company without their consent, a necessity for connecting a board, as their signatures were copied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, in the near future, anyone looking for a Director Identification Number will have to authenticate using biometric devices and fill up the online form that can soon be connected to PCs. In the same way, anyone chosen by the banks or government and financial institutions on boards of the company will have to provide biometric authentication. A parallel setup for company secretaries and CAs is also being operated out, confirmed the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A squad from Infosys has been assigned with placing in the new machine that will be introduced in stages, initiating with the allocation of Director Identification Number. Progressively over a period of couple of years, it will be extended to involve all work related to MCA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be exclusions for non-residents and others, who are not qualified to get Aadhaar such as those people whose iris or fingerprints are not able to capture. MCA considers that the projected system does not encounter any issues since the recent order of the Supreme Court on Aadhaar as the system was destined for authentication. According to sources, the Supreme court had itself recommended that mobile connections be confirmed using Aadhaar and tax department as well as the banks have also been permitted to use the distinctive identification number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2017, the income tax department has also made Aadhaar compulsory for issuing permanent account numbers since it targets individuals using numerous PANs, which is not legal, to avoid from taxes. Though this move was disapproved, the government thinks that employment of UID can aid in enhancing compliance across various sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India is building a biometric database for 1.3 billion people — and enrollment is mandatory</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-building-biometric-database-1-3-billion-people-enrollment-mandatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-building-biometric-database-1-3-billion-people-enrollment-mandatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inside the buzzing enrollment agency, young professionals wearing slim-fitting jeans and lanyards around their necks tapped away at keyboards and fiddled with fingerprint scanning devices as they helped build the biggest and most ambitious biometric database ever conceived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into the office stepped Vimal Gawde, an impoverished 75-year-old widow dressed in a floral print sari. She had come to secure her ticket to India’s digital future — to enroll in the identity program, called Aadhaar, or “foundation,” that aims to record the fingerprints and irises of all 1.3 billion Indian residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 9 out of 10 Indians have registered, each assigned a unique 12-digit number that serves as a digital identity that can be verified with the scan of a thumb or an eye. But Gawde came to the enrollment office less out of excitement than desperation: If she didn’t get a number, she worried that she wouldn’t be able to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designed as a showcase of India’s technological prowess — offering identity proof to the poor and reducing waste in welfare programs — Aadhaar’s grand promises have been muddied by controversy as the government makes enrollment mandatory for a growing number of essential services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indians now need an Aadhaar number to pay taxes, collect pensions and obtain certain welfare benefits. The rapid expansion of a program that was originally described as voluntary has sparked criticism that India is vacuuming up citizens’ personal information with few privacy safeguards and creating hardship for the very people the initiative was supposed to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many Indians living in poverty, Gawde uses a ration card to purchase her monthly allotment of subsidized rice and cooking gas. But the shopkeeper told her that starting next month, he would sell to her only if she produced an Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had visited the enrollment agency three times but had yet to be approved, for reasons she did not understand. (Enrollment agents would not comment on individual cases.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching into her canvas bag, Gawde pulled out the familiar panoply of documents — ration card, voter card, electricity bill, income tax ID — that Indians use to navigate a dizzying bureaucracy. Aadhaar, she was told, would supplant all these papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she had to get the number first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m nervous,” Gawde said outside the enrollment office on a sweltering morning. “I first applied three years ago and submitted all my documents, but didn’t follow up. Now that it’s becoming compulsory, I’m doing everything I can to get it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who had criticized Aadhaar as a “political gimmick” before he took office, has embraced the futuristic idea of an all-in-one digital identity. His party pushed through a law last year that paved the way for a dramatic expansion of Aadhaar, allowing government entities and private businesses wide latitude to access the database, which collects not just people’s names and birth dates but also phone numbers, email addresses and other information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, as more private companies use the database, it could become difficult to open a bank account, get a new cellphone number or buy plane or train tickets without being enrolled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supporters say the program, which has cost about $1 billion to implement, will save multiples of that by curbing tax evasion and ensuring that welfare subsidies are not stolen by middlemen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aadhaar was always meant to be an instrument of inclusion,” Nandan Nilekani, a tech billionaire and the program’s first chairman, said in an interview. “I’m really happy that the current government is completely endorsing Aadhaar and using it for a wide variety of services that will transform governance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nilekani calls Aadhaar “hugely empowering” for the poor, but not long ago even he argued that enrollment should remain optional so that no Indians were prevented from accessing essential services. India’s Supreme Court agreed, ruling in 2015 that the government could not require Aadhaar for any benefit to which a person was otherwise entitled, as long as they could prove their identity by some other means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet the court has stayed silent as Aadhaar creeps into every facet of Indian life, even for children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 12-year-old girl named Saiba is a case in point. After the girl’s grandmother passed away in their family’s ancestral village in northern India, Saiba’s mother moved her and her four siblings to a crowded neighborhood on the rough fringes of New Delhi, near a car parts market thick with the smell of grease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Saiba’s mother, Rani, went to the local school in April to register her for the sixth grade, administrators turned her down, saying every student must have an Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to get a number, a child usually needs a birth certificate — and like one-quarter of children born in this country, Saiba and her siblings did not have them because their village did not routinely register births.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting with her mother in the cramped offices of the local advocacy group Pardarshita, above a noisy street lined with vegetable sellers, the girl puffed her round cheeks in an expression of helplessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know anything about this,” said Saiba, who, like many Indians, has only one name. “I just want to go to school.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rakesh Thakur, a board member of Pardarshita, is trying to obtain Aadhaar numbers fordozens of children barred from Delhi schools. He called the policy “a clear violation” by the municipal government of both the Supreme Court order and India’s Right to Education Act, which guarantees every child younger than 14 free schooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Twitter account called “Rethink Aadhaar” logs new instances almost daily of Indians who have suffered because scanners couldn’t read their fingerprints or because of errors in the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jawhar, a forested zone about 60 miles north of Mumbai, administrators have told local tribal communities that they will soon use Aadhaar to distribute welfare rations and school lunches. But the area lies outside cellphone range, leading residents to wonder how scanners will connect to the Internet to verify their identities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The idea of Aadhaar and the technology may be good, but do we have the infrastructure to make it mandatory?” said Vivek Pandit, a former lawmaker who runs a nonprofit group in the area. “The law is city-centric, and it would only lead to the social exclusion of rural India.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month lawyers opposing Aadhaar argued before the Supreme Court that the government could not force Indians to share their biometric data. Atty. Gen. Mukul Rohatgi countered that Indians had no constitutional right to privacy and could not claim an “absolute right” over their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without privacy protections, activists worry that as Aadhaar numbers are linked to more and more services, intelligence agencies could use the database to more easily track Indians’ calls, travels and purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s become very clear that this is not a project about the poor,” said Usha Ramanathan, a lawyer and anti-Aadhaar activist. “The government’s ambitions have gotten greater over time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, the Center for Internet and Society, a New Delhi think tank, reported that federal and state agencies had published up to 135 million Aadhaar numbers — some including sensitive information such as a person’s caste and religion, or details of pension payments — on unsecured websites accessible through just a few clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s become very clear that this is not a project about the poor.— Usha Ramanathan, a lawyer and anti-Aadhaar activist
Pranesh Prakash, the center’s policy director, said that when Indian authorities can’t even keep Aadhaar numbers private, as the law requires, it suggests the entire database is vulnerable — particularly after sensitive information involving 22 million Americans was exposed when federal databases were hacked in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When these kinds of leaks are happening, it’s rather foolhardy to maintain a database of 1.2 billion people’s biometrics, because once this gets breached, it becomes completely unusable,” Prakash said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If your PIN number or password leaks, you can change it. You can’t change your fingerprints.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Praveen Chakravarty, a former investment banker who worked with Nilekani to launch Aadhaar, believes the lack of safeguards undermines the project’s ideals of efficiency and empowerment. He said many Indians were right to worry that Modi’s government, which has cracked down on political activists and nonprofit groups it opposes, could use Aadhaar to snoop on citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe Aadhaar didn’t need to be this big,” Chakravarty said, adding that the government could simply have worked to fix inefficiencies in individual welfare programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People could ask, ‘Did we need this at all?’” he said. “It’s a good question.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Gawde, the widow, Aadhaar remained an idea of the future. She left the enrollment agency that day empty-handed, told by a young employee that her number had not been assigned. But she retained hope that the new ID would make life easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are just poor people,” she said. “We have to trust what the government tells us.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Facility Launched To Link Aadhaar With PAN</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-facility-launched-to-link-aadhaar-with-pan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Income Tax Department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department has launched a new e-facility to link a person&amp;rsquo;s Aadhaar with the Permanent Account Number (PAN), a mandatory procedure for filing income tax returns (ITRs) now. The department&amp;rsquo;s e-filing website - incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in - has created a new link on its homepage making it &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; to link the two unique identities of individuals. The link requires a person to punch in his or her PAN number, Aadhaar number and the &amp;ldquo;exact name as given in the Aadhaar
card&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After verification from the UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India), the linking will be confirmed. In case of any minor mismatch in Aadhaar name provided, Aadhaar OTP (one time password) will be required,&amp;rdquo; the department said in its advisory to taxpayers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTP will be sent on the registered mobile number and email of the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It urged them to ensure that the date of birth and gender in PAN and Aadhaar are exactly the same, to ensure linking without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no need to login or be registered on e-filing website (of the I-T department). This facility can be used by anyone to link their Aadhaar with PAN,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, under the Finance Act 2017, has made it mandatory for taxpayers to quote Aadhaar or enrolment ID of Aadhaar application form for filing of income tax returns (ITR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Aadhaar has been made mandatory for applying for a permanent account number with effect from July 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department, till now, has linked over 1.18 crore Aadhaar with its PAN database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Aadhaar is issued by the UIDAI to a resident of India, PAN is a ten-digit alphanumeric number issued in the form of a laminated card by the IT department to any person, firm or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio’s new plans offer 100% cashback on JioFi on exchange of old dongle, datacard, routers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jios-new-plans-offer-100-cashback-on-jiofi-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio has launched a 100% cashback offer with JioFi 4G router, as the Mukesh Ambani-owned tries to attract users of dongles, datacard and wifi routers offered by rival telcos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has come up with two plans where as part of the first plan, users will get a 100% exchange offer where they’ll be required to exchange their existing datacard, dongle or hotspot router at any Jio Digital store or Jio Care store and will get 4G data worth Rs 2010 against the device exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customers will have to pay Rs 1999 to get the JioFi router and will have to do a mandatory first recharge of Rs 408 which is Rs309 for the plan – which ensures freebies for 84 days - and Rs99 for a Jio Prime membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the customer pays Rs 1999 minus the Rs 2010 worth 4G data which translates into zero cost for the customer and the device with internet connection becomes almost free. However, the Rs 408 mandatory recharge is the additional cost which the user will have to pay in order to avail the services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the second plan, users get JioFi at Rs 1999 after a first mandatory recharge of Rs 408 (Rs309 + Rs99) but they get 4G data worth Rs 1005 which translates to the effective cost of Rs 994 (Rs1999 - Rs1005). Users need not exchange their existing data connections for this plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first plan is ideal for all existing dongle users whereas the second plan is ideal for laptop users, 2G/3G phone users and tablet users, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Queries addressed to Jio for the new plans went unanswered till the press time. Reliance Retail currently has four JioFi devices running in the market namely JioFi 1 Router, JioFi 2 Router, JioFi 3 Router, JioFi 4 Dongle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the first plan, the telco is trying to capture the market of rival telcos offering dongles, datacard and wifi routers, since the exchange scheme will encourage existing dongle users to shift to Jio’s services, say experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They added that by offering free data in the second plan to the first time users or users that are willing to keep multiple connections, the telco is looking to expand the subscriber-base for its JioFi routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIL’s retail arm namely Reliance Retail sold 2.6 million LYF and JioFi devices during the last quarter and nearly 10 million units in the financial year, and is further looking to accelerate the sales with the launch of new JioFi plans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 899:Last Day To Book IndiGo&#39;s All-Inclusive Tickets </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/last-day-to-book-indigos-all-inclusive-tickets-starting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/last-day-to-book-indigos-all-inclusive-tickets-starting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*Bookings under IndiGo&amp;rsquo;s this offer - valid for travel between June 1 and August 31, this year - can be made till May 11, the airline said.
*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo is offering discounted all-inclusive fares starting from Rs 899 on select one-way flights under a promotional scheme. Bookings under IndiGo&amp;rsquo;s this offer - valid for travel between June 1 and August 31, this year - can be made till May 11, 2017, the Gurgaon-based airline said on its website. &amp;ldquo;With fares starting as low as Rs 899 there&amp;rsquo;s no reason not to get out of town,&amp;rdquo; IndiGo, which recently announced it will operate 18 new additional flights starting June, further said. &amp;ldquo;With fares starting as low as Rs 899 there&amp;rsquo;s no reason not to get out of town,&amp;rdquo; IndiGo said, adding that the offer is valid on bookings made 20 days prior to travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Rs 899 fare is being offered on the Bagdogra-Guwahati route, other routes covered under this IndiGo scheme include Chennai-Bengaluru (starting from Rs 999), Chennai-Coimbatore (Rs. 1,099), Chennai-Visakhapatnam (Rs. 1,099), Delhi-Jaipur (Rs. 1,099), Goa-Bengaluru (Rs. 1,099) and Delhi-Dehradun Rs. (1,299).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A search on the IndiGo portal showed that tickets for a one-way flight from Bagdogra to Guwahati in the last week of August were available at Rs 899:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo is the country&amp;rsquo;s largest passenger airline with a market share of 39.9 per cent as of March 2017. It currently operates flights connecting to 46 destinations - 39 domestic and 7 international. IndiGo has a fleet size of 133 including 20 new generation A320neos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IndiGo last month said it will operate 18 new additional flights starting June, as part of its summer schedule. The airline said it will add these flights to the existing routes, including Bengaluru-Delhi and Bengaluru-Hyderabad. It will operate its 15th flight between Bengaluru and Delhi (to and fro), and 10th additional flight between Bengaluru and Hyderabad and Kolkata and Bengaluru (to and fro).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new flights, IndiGo aims to provide increased frequencies on the routes and offer greater travel options to the customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian aviation sector has been witnessing double-digit growth in passenger traffic over the past few months. Many airlines operating in the Indian market have offered discounted tariffs and attractive schemes to counter rising competition, some analysts say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also read: How to know when flight prices drop)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s domestic air passenger traffic rose 14.91 per cent in March to 90.45 lakh, according to data from aviation regulator DGCA (Directorate General of Civil Aviation) showed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airlines such as Air India, Jet Airways and AirAsia have in the recent passed offered discounted air fares.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>