<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>After Jio&#39;s &#39;Summer Surprise&#39; Comes &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; Offer: Features, Price And More</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-summer-surprise-comes-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer-features-price-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-summer-surprise-comes-dhan-dhana-dhan-offer-features-price-and-more/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio makes India the highest quality, most affordable data market in the world so that every Indian can do Datagiri,&amp;rdquo; Jio said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has announced a new scheme called &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo;, offering &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs 309. &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; from Reliance Jio Infocomm - the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led conglomerate Reliance Industries - comes days after of the new entrant deciding to withdraw its &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. &amp;ldquo;In order to smoothen the migration from free to paid services, Jio has implemented simple, affordable and regulatory compliant plans in customer interest,&amp;rdquo; Jio said in a release on the Dhan Dhana Dhan scheme. Like its earlier &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; offer, &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; recharges will further boost Jio&amp;rsquo;s already strong customer retention under Prime as well as attract new customers to its fold, say analysts. (Also read: &amp;lsquo;Your first recharge an auspicious moment for Jio&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio in a statement on Tuesday said it has fully withdrawn its Summer Surprise offer &amp;ldquo;following the advice of Telecom Regulatory Authority of India&amp;rdquo;. For members of its Prime services, Jio announced new &amp;ldquo;all unlimited&amp;rdquo; plans &amp;ldquo;aimed at encouraging Jio subscribers to live the Digital Life without restrictions - Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to get &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; benefits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an existing Jio customer but have not bought your first Jio recharge so far, you &amp;ldquo;need to do so by 15 April 2017 to avoid degradation and/or discontinuation of services&amp;rdquo;. Those unable to subscribe to Prime until now can &amp;ldquo;continue to do so by paying Rs. 408 or Rs. 608 (Jio Prime + recharge price) to avail these benefits&amp;rdquo;, according to Jio.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-benefits-650_650x400_51491977379.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;dhan-dhana-dhan-plans&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 309:&lt;/em&gt; Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;all unlimited&amp;rdquo; plan priced at Rs 309 includes 1GB of 4G data, which is high speed internet, per day. Under Dhan Dhana Dhan offer - which is limited to one recharge only - Prime members will get 84 GB for 84 days, as per Jio&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 509:&lt;/em&gt; The Rs 509 plan &amp;ldquo;for daily high data users&amp;rdquo; includes 168 GB of high speed data (2GB per day at 4G speed) for 84 days on the first recharge.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-rs-309-rs-509_650x400_81491977322.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;em&gt;Rs 309 and Rs 509 plans&lt;/em&gt; include unlimited calling and unlimited SMS. Consumers will get 28 GB of 4G data (1GB per day) and 56 GB of data (2GB per day) for 28 days on subsequent recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509, respectively, as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;datagiri&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Datagiri&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jio makes India the highest quality, most affordable data market in the world so that every Indian can do Datagiri,&amp;rdquo; the Jio release noted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At SBI, You Don&#39;t Need To Maintain Minimum Balance In These Accounts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/at-sbi-you-dont-need-to-maintain-minimum-balance-in-these-accounts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Bank of India is offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Bank of India or SBI has said it is exempting its customers holding certain account types from maintenance of average monthly balance. Such accounts include small savings bank accounts, basic savings bank accounts and Jan Dhan accounts, or the accounts opened under the government&amp;rsquo;s financial inclusion scheme Pradhan Mantri Jan-Dhan Yojana or PMJDY. This was said in a tweet by SBI, which recently adopted a new brand identity after merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank. SBI had earlier decided to increase the minimum balance required for maintaining savings accounts from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, State Bank of India is also offering corporate salary accounts without the requirement to maintain minimum monthly balance.
Account holders of the following types of accounts are exempt from requiring to maintain an average monthly balance: pic.twitter.com/61U8QNu7xR
— State Bank of India (@TheOfficialSBI) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement was increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros. In case of non-compliance, savings bank account holders will invite a penalty ranging from Rs 20 (in rural branches) to Rs. 100 (in metro cities), as per the bank&amp;rsquo;s website. (Read more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other features SBI offers under these accounts, according to its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-savings-bank-account&#34;&gt;Small savings bank account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account has a maximum balance limit of Rs 50,000 and offers a rate of interest applicable to savings bank accounts. Account holders get an ATM-cum-Debit card, issued free of cost and without any annual maintenance charge, as per the SBI website. All credits in a financial year should not aggregate to more than Rs 1 lakh and Rs 10,000 in case of withdrawals and transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-savings-account&#34;&gt;Basic savings account&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s basic savings account has no minimum balance or maximum balance limits. Holders of this account type &amp;ldquo;will not be eligible to open any other Savings Bank Account&amp;rdquo; at the bank. Such an account - in case the customer already holds one - will have to be closed within 30 days of opening the basic savings bank deposit account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;corporate-salary-package&#34;&gt;Corporate salary package&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI&amp;rsquo;s salary account under corporate salary package offers many benefits to the employer and the employee alike. This account type reduces employer&amp;rsquo;s paperwork and salary administration cost. Employees get free internet banking and mobile banking services, among other features, as per the SBI website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Oil To Revise Petrol, Diesel Prices Daily In 5 Cities From May 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-cities-first-petrol-diesel-price-will-change-daily-from-next-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-cities-first-petrol-diesel-price-will-change-daily-from-next-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A pilot for daily revision of petrol and diesel price will be first implemented in Puducherry, Vizag in Andhra Pradesh, Udaipur in Rajasthan, Jamshedpur in Jharkhand and Chandigarh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come May 1, petrol and diesel prices will change every day in sync with international rates, much like what happens in most advanced markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-owned fuel retailers Indian Oil Corp (IOC), Bharat Petroleum Corp Ltd (BPCL) and Hindustan Petroleum Corp Ltd (HPCL), which own over 95 per cent of nearly 58,000 petrol pumps in the country, will launch a pilot for daily price revision in five select cities from May 1 and gradually extend it to all over the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ultimately, we will be driving towards market linked rates on a daily basis at all pumps across the country,&amp;rdquo; IOC Chairman B Ashok told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pilot for daily revision of petrol and diesel price will be first implemented in Puducherry, Vizag in Andhra Pradesh, Udaipur in Rajasthan, Jamshedpur in Jharkhand and Chandigarh, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State fuel retailers currently revise rates on 1st and 16th of every month based on average international price of the fuel in the preceding fortnight and currency exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of using fortnightly average, pump rates will reflect daily movement in international oil prices and rupee-US dollar fluctuations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is technically possible to change rates daily but we have to first do a pilot. Once pilot is done and its implications studied, we will extend it to other parts of the country,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ashok said the pilot is to be &amp;ldquo;launched within one month&amp;rdquo; and did not give a specific date, industry sources said the pilot is planned to be launched on May 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily price change will remove the big leaps in rates that need to be effected at the end of the fortnight and consumer will be more aligned to market dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While petrol price was freed from government control in June 2010, diesel rates were deregulated in October 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, oil companies have freedom to revise rates but often they have been guided by political considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rates differ by only a few paise between pumps of the three state fuel retailers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unbranded petrol at IOC pumps in Delhi costs Rs 66.29 per litre, while the same at BPCL pumps in the city is priced at Rs 66.37 a litre. HPCL pumps sell for Rs 66.48 per litre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unbranded diesel at IOC pumps in Delhi costs Rs 55.61, Rs 55.66 at BPCL outlets and Rs 55.69 a litre at HPCL pumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With daily changes, which are unlikely to more than few paise per litre, the political pressures for not revising rates particularly when they are to be hiked will go, sources said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petrol price was last revised downward by Rs 3.77 a litre on April and diesel rates were cut by Rs 2.91. This was the first revision in two-and-half-months as oil firms did not change prices during assembly elections in five states, including Uttar Pradesh and Punjab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ashok said prices of petrol and diesel in a particular market (city or town) will be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By and large, in a particular market it should be same. Though, there might be marginal difference from pump to pump,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Impact: Vodafone Offers Free 4GB Data On SIM Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-vodafone-offers-free-4gb-data-on-sim-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-impact-vodafone-offers-free-4gb-data-on-sim-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Vodafone 4G SIMs are available at all Vodafone Stores, Vodafone Mini Stores or multi brand outlets located across Mumbai,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone is offering 4GB data free on upgradation to Vodafone Supernet 4G. Vodafone users in Mumbai who upgrade to a 4G SIM card (with 4G handsets) can avail the free data. &amp;ldquo;Vodafone 4G SIMs are available at all Vodafone Stores, Vodafone Mini Stores or multi brand outlets located across Mumbai,&amp;rdquo; the company said in a statement. The new offer comes a day after the new entrant in telecom sector, Reliance Jio, announced its &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer. Jio has started a price war among the operators by offering various discounts, free data and unlimited voice calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the new 4G SIM, Vodafone prepaid users get 4GB data free for a duration of 10 days. While for postpaid customers, the offer can be availed till their next billing date. &amp;ldquo;The free data shall be added to the customer&amp;rsquo;s data balance on upgrading to a 4G SIM,&amp;rdquo; the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the development, Pushpinder Singh Gujral, business head-Mumbai, Vodafone India, said, &amp;ldquo;Vodafone is proud to be the preferred telecom services provider to over 9 million customers in Mumbai. We are offering 4GB data free for our customers to experience the benefits of our Data Strong Network and enjoy unparalleled mobile internet services.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can switch to the new 4G SIM:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walk in to any nearest outlet and get your 4G SIM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To activate the 4G SIM card, use your existing Vodafone number to SMS &amp;lsquo;SIMEX &lt;your 20 digit new 4G SIM card number&gt;&amp;rsquo; to 55199 (this number will be available on the new SIM card/jacket given to you)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will receive a response SMS from 55199 with partial SIM number entered&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Send the last 6 digits of the new SIM number to 55199 within 2 hours of receiving the SMS mentioned in the above step&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you receive a success SMS, your 4G SIM will be activated within 20 minutes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replace your old SIM in the handset with the new 4G SIM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case customers face any issues with the SIM upgrade process, they can call 199 or seek assistance from the staff at any Vodafone retail store, the company&amp;rsquo;s statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance Jio Ahead In Network Coverage But Trails In 4G Speeds: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-ahead-in-network-coverage-but-trails-in-4g-speeds-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jio-ahead-in-network-coverage-but-trails-in-4g-speeds-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliance Jio carries 90 per cent plus of all data traffic in the country currently while its network capacity share is closer to 35 per cent, the report said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio network coverage is significantly ahead of the other operators but the newcomer trails Airtel in 4G speeds given the high load on its network during the free offer period, says a report by Credit Suisse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our conclusion is that Jio&amp;rsquo;s network coverage is significantly ahead of the other operators. Jio has good coverage in 80 per cent plus of cities surveyed, compared to less than 30 per cent for the others. The difference is even more stark when compared only with 4G networks of incumbents (sub-15 per cent of cities),&amp;rdquo; the latest report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the newcomer did not fare as well when it came to speeds - the survey concluded that Airtel offered the best 4G speeds, while Jio was &amp;ldquo;probably bogged down by load&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We also studied the network speed results across all these locations. Airtel 4G offers the best download speeds in general (12Mbps plus). Jio, Vodafone and Idea are close to each other (7-8Mbps). We suspect Jio&amp;rsquo;s speeds are impacted by the high load on the network in the free offer period,&amp;rdquo; Credit Suisse said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio carries 90 per cent plus of all data traffic in the country currently while its network capacity share is closer to 35 per cent, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competitive pressure is expected to sustain, the report said adding that significant pressure on fundamentals will continue in coming quarters from Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already started seeing the impact of Jio on the incumbents&amp;rsquo; numbers (Bharti 3Q). Our study here shows Jio has built a significant lead in terms of network coverage, and the incumbents have a fair amount of catch up to do (especially on 4G). Importantly, going by recently announced enhanced capex plans, the company continues to invest,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study covers over 30 Indian cities that represent a &amp;ldquo;significant chunk of current data demand and revenues&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting Aadhaar To April 30 For EPFO Extends</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-extends-deadline-for-submitting-aadhaar-to-april-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/epfo-extends-deadline-for-submitting-aadhaar-to-april-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retirement fund body EPFO has extended the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number to April 30, 2017 for its over four crore members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) had set March 31, 2017 as the deadline for submitting Aadhaar number earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO has also extended the deadline for submitting digital life certificates for its over 50 lakh pensioners till April 30 to link pension accounts with Aadhaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have extended the deadline for submission of Aadhaar by subscribers to April 30, 2017. Besides, pensioners can also submit their life certificates till April 30,&amp;rdquo; EPFO&amp;rsquo;s Central Provident Fund Commissioner V P Joy told PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO had extended the deadline several times in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also done away with the system of accepting life certificate manually through banks. Pensioners are required to provide life certificates digitally either through their mobile phones or at common service centres or bank branches providing such facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest EPFO order provides that if a pensioner is not able to submit the life certificate in digital format, then the same can be submitted in physical form with valid reasons for not submitting it digitally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also says that a pensioner would cease to receive payments from May if life certificate is not submitted by April 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Lucky Grahak, Digi Dhan: Rs 1 Crore Jackpot For Person Making Rs 1,590 Digital Payment</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of the Digi Dhan scheme, three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were declared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Pranab Mukherjee picked six winners from a draw of lots under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes, aimed at promoting digital transactions in the country. &amp;ldquo;In the consumer category, three mega Prizes of Rs 1 crore, Rs 50 lakh and Rs 25 lakh went to the Consumers using Rupay Debit Cards making digital payment of less than Rs.1,000,&amp;rdquo; an official release said. Three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were also declared at the event on the final day of the 100-day scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction of Rs. 1,590 won a Central Bank of India customer a lucky draw of Rs. 1 crore under the consumer category, as part of the government&amp;rsquo;s promotional scheme to popularise digital payments. The President congratulated all the six winners - three consumers and three merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am happy today to be a part of the digital payment movement that India has embarked upon. I congratulate each one of you who has contributed in this mission to make India a less cash society,&amp;rdquo; the President said in his address on the occasion of mega draw of lots for the two schemes held at Rashtrapati Bhawan on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners will be felicitated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on April 14 at Nagpur on the occasion of Ambedkar Jayanti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his address, Mr Mukherjee asked citizens to extend their unstinted support to the mission of a less-cash India. &amp;ldquo;India has a long way to go to become a cash less society. The initiatives of the government are a good beginning and we need to sustain and nurture these with active participation from all segments of the society&amp;hellip;It is necessary to reduce cash in circulation and impart greater urgency to promoting secure digital payment methods to ensure greater transparency,&amp;rdquo; the President said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the consumer section, the second prize of Rs 50 lakh went to a Bank of Baroda customer while the third prize of Rs. 25 lakh was bagged by a customer of Punjab National Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the three customers had made the transactions using their RuPay debit cards. The names of three winners were not yet known as the draw only displayed their transaction numbers. These will be matched with card details to identify the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital transactions have gathered momentum giving a fillip to the less cash economy post demonetisation thanks to the initiatives taken by the government. NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digidhan Vyapar schemes have played a catalytic role in making it a mass movement, the statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressing that India is on the cusp of a digital revolution, Mr Mukherjee noted that more than one billion Indians have a unique identity number with a biometric identifier which is unique in its own way. &amp;ldquo;Even countries which are technologically far more advanced than India with comparatively much smaller size population do not have such a system in place. The Aadhaar card initiative is a watershed event in the development story of India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs. 1,000 notes on November 9 last year, the government took a slew of measures to promote digital payments in the country. It had launched the Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes on December 25 last year for consumers and merchants, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes are being implemented by the National Payment Corporation of India (NPCI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the scheme, daily, weekly and monthly rewards worth Rs. 256 crore have been disbursed to over 16 lakh citizens over the past 100 days for making and accepting small transactions digitally. Over the past 100 days, everyday 15,000 consumers have qualified for total prize money of Rs. 1.5 crore, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The draw has seen a positive impact from various age groups and occupations in adopting digital payments methods. We have seen a steady increase in the number of transactions made using all payment methods,&amp;rdquo; said A P Hota, MD and CEO of National Payment Corporation of India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Accounts To Be Blocked If Not Self-Certified By April 30. What To Do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions, without which the accounts would be blocked, the income tax department said. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Account holders are informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till 30.4.2017,A/Cs would be blocked : pic.twitter.com/YICvRHqfPm
— Income Tax India (@IncomeTaxIndia) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Investors are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed, the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014-August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016, extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The financial institutions were advised to continue to work on completing the required due diligence, including obtaining self-certifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them. (With agency inputs)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, You Can Get A PAN Or TAN Within A Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax department today said it has issued Permanent Account Number (PAN) within a day to 19,704 newly incorporated companies till March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Applicant would be benefited by having a digitally signed E-PAN card which they can submit as proof of identity to other agency electronically directly or by storing in the Digital Locker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; CBDT, the apex policy making body of the Income Tax department, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said that newly incorporated companies have also been issued Tax Deduction Account Number (TAN) simultaneously with PAN as the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) has tied up with the Ministry of Corporate Affairs (MCA) under which companies can submit a common application form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicant companies submit a common application form SPICe (INC 32) on MCA portal and once the data of incorporation is sent to CBDT by the MCA, PAN and TAN are issued immediately without any further intervention of the applicant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Certificate of Incorporation (COI) of newly incorporated companies includes the PAN in addition to the Corporate Identity Number (CIN). TAN is also allotted simultaneously and communicated to the company,&amp;rdquo; the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till March 31, 2017, 19,704 newly incorporated companies were allotted PAN in this manner. During March 2017, of the 10,894 newly incorporated companies, PAN was allotted within 4 hours in 95.63 per cent cases and within one day in all cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, TAN was allotted to all such companies within 4 hrs in 94.7 per cent cases and within 1 day in 99.73 per cent cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;CBDT&amp;rsquo;s initiative in starting of a business is expected to significantly improve the ranking of India in the Ease of Doing Business Study conducted by World Bank by reducing the number of processes of registration before various authorities under law, reducing the time taken for allotment of the registration number (CIN, PAN, TAN) and making the entire registration process for new companies much simpler,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petrol Pumps Threaten Sundays Off, 9-To-6 On Other Days</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-threaten-sundays-off-9-to-6-on-other-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/petrol-pumps-threaten-sundays-off-9-to-6-on-other-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Petrol pump owners across the country have threatened to shut down filling stations on Sundays unless their demands for higher margins are met. They have also said that filling stations will operate from 9 am to 6 pm to cut costs, unless the government intervenes. Ravi Shinde, general secretary of Consortium of Indian Petroleum Dealers, told NDTV Profit that pump owners have decided to observe Sunday offs from May 14 while from May 15, &lt;em&gt;dealers will operate from 9 am to 6 pm.&lt;/em&gt; Consortium of Indian Petroleum Dealers, an all-India organisation, represents over 50,000 petrol pump dealers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Shinde also said the petrol dealers association will observe May 10 as a &amp;ldquo;No Purchase Day&amp;rdquo; to press for their demands. &amp;ldquo;Not much of disruption is expected, but it will be an indication for oil companies to take note that dealers are on war path,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elaborating on pump owners&amp;rsquo; demands, Mr Shinde said oil marketing companies &amp;ldquo;have not honoured their written commitment of giving dealer margins in line with Apurva Chandra committee report&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the committee&amp;rsquo;s calculations, dealers should be getting Rs 3,333 per kilolitre on petrol and Rs 2,126 per kilolitre on diesel, he said, referring to dealers&amp;rsquo; margins. &amp;ldquo;We are currently getting Rs 2,570 and Rs 1,620 for petrol and diesel respectively,&amp;rdquo; he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petrol pump owners had in January threatened to stop accepting card payments over levy on digital payments, forcing the government to intervene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuel consumption in India grew at a slower rate of 5 per cent in the last fiscal year, which ended on March 31, 2017, as diesel demand cooled down. The world&amp;rsquo;s third largest oil consumer saw demand for fuel and petroleum products rise to 194.2 million tonnes in 2016-17, up from 184.6 MT in the previous fiscal year, data from Petroleum Planning and Analysis Cell (PPAC) of the Oil Ministry showed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 309 Jio&#39;s Plan, Offers &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39; </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-next-move-offers-dhan-dhana-dhan-plan-starting-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jios-next-move-offers-dhan-dhana-dhan-plan-starting-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier with a recharge of Rs 309, subscribers used to get 28GB data for 28 days, but under the Dhan Dhana Dhan offer, they will now get 84GB data for 84 days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After withdrawing the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, Reliance Jio came up with another plan offering unlimited data, SMS and voice calling for three months. Starting Rs 309, &amp;lsquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plan offers 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days. Earlier with a recharge of Rs 303, subscribers used to get 28GB data for 28 days, but under the ‘Dhan Dhana Dhan’ offer, they will now get 84GB data for 84 days. Also, with a recharge of Rs 509, users will get 2GB data per day for 84 days instead of 56GB data for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few days back, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) had asked Jio to withdraw the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer as the regulator observed that the plan did not fit into the &amp;ldquo;regulatory framework&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio also tweeted the details of the plan and said, &amp;ldquo;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to live the #JioDhanDhanaDhan life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/msid-58130455,width-400,resizemode-4,-10-.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Jio &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer is limited to only one recharge and is not available along with &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, the website stated. These plans are only for Jio Prime users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for Jio non-Prime members the offer is valid but at a higher price. For 1GB data per day for 84 days will cost Rs 408 (Rs 309 + Rs 99). And, for 2GB data per day for a period of 84 days, customers will have to shell out Rs 608 (Rs 509 + Rs 99).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot from the company&amp;rsquo;s website:
reliance jio
Jio recently clocked 72 million paid users and extended its one-time Rs 99 payment membership programme Prime till April 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entry of Reliance Jio has created a stir in the telecom market with every operator offering various discounts on prepaid and postpaid plans in an effort to keep up with the new entrant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Notes Ban, 18 Lakh Cases Of Income, Bank Account Mismatches Detected: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/after-notes-ban-18-lakh-cases-of-income-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government authorities have detected 18 lakh cases after demonetisation where the income profiles of people do not match their account profile, the Lok Sabha was informed today. Preliminary information has been sought from such people and many have responded. Those who have not given details would be issued with notices as per procedure, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said during Question Hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to supplementaries, he said there was an extended footprint of digitisation in the banking sector. With digitisation, the risk of tampering of technology also increases. But banks are also hiring experts to develop firewalls around their system to make it increasingly difficult to breach it, Jaitley said, adding that technology has to keep pace with crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that risk assessment was a continuous process for banks who do it individually and collectively. In his written response, Jaitley said as on March 31, 2016, 29 per cent of the savings accounts of public sector banks and regional rural banks sponsored by them were inoperative or lying dormant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A variety of factors have a bearing on an account being inoperative. These may include factors like opening of a new account with change of residence or office, death of the account holder or the relative convenience of operating different accounts, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Get Time Till June 30 To Obtain PAN From Account Holders</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department has given banks three more months till June 30 to obtain permanent account number (PAN) or Form-60 from all account holders as it looks to tighten the noose around evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the notification, the Income Tax Department said that in Income-Tax Rules 114B, in the fourth proviso, &amp;ldquo;for the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;28th day of February&amp;rsquo; the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;30th day of June&amp;rsquo; shall be substituted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 114B lists various transactions for which quoting PAN is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had in January asked banks, post offices and cooperative banks to document PAN or declaration of Form 60 received from account holders and maintain all records for transactions under Rule 114B of I-T Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had said that persons who have not quoted PAN, or did not furnish Form 60 at the time of opening account, will have to provide the same by February 28. Form 60 is a declaration form filed by an individual without PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the demonetisation move effective November 9, the tax department had asked banks and post offices to report to it all deposits above Rs 2.5 lakh in savings accounts and more than Rs 12.50 lakh in current accounts made between November 10 and December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cash deposits exceeding Rs 50,000 in a single day had to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an estimated Rs 15 lakh crore in junked currency notes coming back into the banking system post demonetisation, the tax department has started analysing the bank deposit trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>