<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>45GB Free Data On Amazon Exclusive Smartphones:Vodafone Offers </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-45gb-free-data-on-amazon-exclusive-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-offers-45gb-free-data-on-amazon-exclusive-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the purchase of 1GB or above 4G data pack, users will get 9GB additional free 4G data for five recharges with maximum validity of five months from Vodafone, Amazon stated on its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major telecom players in India, Vodafone is offering 45GB of free data on the purchase of Amazon exclusive 4G smartphones. For the purchase of 1GB or above 4G data pack, users will get 9GB additional free 4G data for five recharges with maximum validity of five months from Vodafone, e-commerce firm Amazon stated on its website. The offer is only available on select smartphones. To avail the offer from Vodafone, one must purchase the Amazon exclusive handset till June 30. According to the website, the offer was started on May 11. (Click here to see the full list of smartphones which are applicable under the offer)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the smartphones included under the offer are Samsung On5 Pro, OnePlus 3T, Honor 6X and Moto G Play (4th Gen), among others. This free data offer cannot be cumulated with any other special discounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-how-users-can-avail-the-vodafone-offer&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how users can avail the Vodafone offer:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Insert Vodafone SIM in the new Amazon exclusive handset. You will get an activation message saying &amp;ldquo;You are eligible for Vodafone Amazon Buy 1GB or above pack and Get 9 GB for 5 Recharges with maximum validity of 5 months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For prepaid connections, recharge with 1GB or above pack, 9GB free data will get credited automatically. The 9GB free data is valid for 28 days only and a user can avail the offer up to five times or five months, whatever comes first. No special recharges and prices are applicable to get the free 9GB data offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For postpaid connections, user need to have 1GB or above rental plan, then 9GB free data will get attached within 48 hours. The 9GB Offer is valid for five billing cycles with a condition that the user has 1 GB or higher pack throughout the promotional period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea Cellular is also providing a similar offer in collaboration with Flipkart. It has announced 4G data offer with no daily limit and unlimited voice calling. Users purchasing a new 4G-enabled smartphone through Flipkart can avail up to 30GB of 4G data per month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBSE affiliated schools to be made Aadhaar centres</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/cbse-affiliated-schools-made-aadhaar-centres/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to ensure that all students have unique identification number to be enrolled, the Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) recently directed all its affiliated schools to set up Aadhaar enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To implement this, the board has collaborated with Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) to collect demographic and biometric data of residents directly or through enrolment agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-on-the-report&#34;&gt;More on the report:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, schools are free to decide whether or not to set up the centres&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if a school wishes to set up an Aadhaar centre, then they can do so by signing a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with either the Board or UIDAI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, the board has asked schools to procure equipment for the purpose as per the UIDAI check list&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reasons-behind-this-step&#34;&gt;Reasons behind this step:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As reported, this move comes against the backdrop of the Central government mandating Aadhaar card for several benefits in educational institutions, including mid-day meal schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-cbse-said-in-its-notice&#34;&gt;Here’s what CBSE said in its notice:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schools shall set up enrolment centres to facilitate their bonafide students, teachers, staff and their family members to to enrol for Aadhar and make any updation or corrections,” it said in a communication to schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Equipment such as computer, printer, biometric devices and other such things will have to be procured by the school themselves and should be as per the UIDAI specifications,” as reported in a recent PTI report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to encourage students to enroll themselves, the schools will not be charging any fees for the Aadhaar enrolment; but CBSE will pay them Rs 30 for every enrolment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the February 2017 data of the board, there are 18,546 CBSE affiliated schools in India and 210 schools in 25 foreign countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, the schools will also be required to adhere to all code of conducts applicable to other enrolment centres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free 360GB 4G Data, Calls For 1 Year With Micromax Canvas 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/airtel-offers-free-360gb-4g-data-calls-for-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day from Airtel to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom major Bharti Airtel will offer one year free 4G service along with unlimited calling within its network to buyers of Micromax Canvas 2 smartphone that was been launched on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Micromax Canvas 2 will come with one year of unlimited Airtel to Airtel calling, unlimited data at no extra cost for both existing and new Airtel customers,&amp;rdquo; Shubhajit Sen, Chief Marketing Officer, Micromax told reporters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax on Thursday launched its dual SIM 4G VoLTE smartphone Canvas 2 for Rs 11,999 to foray in the device segment priced between Rs 10,000-15,000 a unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the pact, Airtel will offer 1GB of 4G data every day and thereafter the speed will get reduced, Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers purchasing Canvas 2 device will also get 400 minutes of calling per day to any network in India for one year with weekly limit of 1,500 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We saw huge queues in front of the Reliance (Jio) stores when they launched 3 months free offer. For 1 year, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what would be the response. After that three-month offer has become norm but for 1 year no one has seen the response,&amp;rdquo; Micromax Informatics co-founder, Rahul Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company started shipping Canvas 2 from today for sale on retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By the end of next week, it will be available across 40 -60 per cent of our market in the country. This is first phone in India with Corning Gorilla Glass 5. We will be disappointed if at least 1 million Canvas 2 are not shipped till Diwali season,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax Canvas 2 will be sold only through offline retail channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will run on Android Nougat. It comes with MediaTek quad core chipset, 3,050 mAh battery promising talk time of up to 11 hours, 3GB RAM, 16 GB internal storage and 64 GB expandable memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We will sell this phone offline only because offline buyers are looking for something more. With this phone, we are offering them 1 Year of screen replacement and 30 day smartphone replacement,&amp;rdquo; Sen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromax has plans to launch around 15 smartphones within one year with focus on consumers buying smartphones in the range of Rs 10,000-15,000, Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Effect: Aircel Offers 1 GB Of 3G Data At Rs. 76</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-aircel-offers-1-gb-of-3g-data-at-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-effect-aircel-offers-1-gb-of-3g-data-at-rs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aircel is also offering full talk time or FTT benefits on a recharge of Rs. 86. It is also offering 100MB of data with the download of its Aircel App.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is offering its customers 1GB of 3G data at a price of Rs. 76 on its mobile app. Aircel, which last month announced free incoming calls on national roaming on its network across the country, is also offering additional 100MB of free data on recharges above Rs. 50, the telecom company said in a press release on Wednesday. &amp;ldquo;Tapping the increasing trend of customers choosing to recharge their phones online or through apps, Aircel&amp;hellip;has launched special Data and Calling packs on its mobile application,&amp;rdquo; the press release by Aircel noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1gb-rs-76&#34;&gt;1GB @ Rs. 76&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel&amp;rsquo;s 1GB of 3G data on offer in a recharge of Rs. 76 will come with a validity of 10 days, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The exciting offers are designed keeping the customer demands at the forefront and giving them best value offers with Aircel,&amp;rdquo; the company said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aircel has always worked to delight its customers and present them with value for money offers. Through apps, we know our customers, their plans, usage, and the services they are interested in, and hence have curated these products basis the trends observed,&amp;rdquo; Aircel chief marketing officer Anupam Vasudev said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some analysts say the aggressive pricing by Reliance Jio has led to high competition in the Indian telecom industry, forcing existing players to come up with lower tariffs and lucrative schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full talk time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is also offering full talk time or FTT benefits on a recharge of Rs. 86. It is also offering 100MB of data with the download of its Aircel App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel&amp;rsquo;s app - Aircel App-Recharge &amp;amp; BillPay - is available on Google Play (for Android users) and App Store (for iPhone users).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app successfully caters to the growing customer base and increasing data consumption, offering benefits like data loan and main balance recharge options which are industry&amp;rsquo;s first features on the app, Aircel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have seen great success in the past with such products and we feel that these App exclusive products will suit the convenience of our customers and assist them to stay seamlessly connected,&amp;rdquo; Mr Vasudev added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aircel is a pan-India operator with 3G spectrum in 13 circles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That have Changed From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliance JioFi 3 vs JioFi 2</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/reliance-jiofi-3-vs-jiofi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Reliance Jio silently launched JioFi 3 in the Indian market just to replace its predecessor with some minor changes. We recently unboxed the device. The JioFi 3 now retails at Rs. 1,999 on official aJio website and is also available from Reliance Digital Xpress, Digital Xpress mini and other stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this device comes handy when your family and friends want to online On-the-go and also saves your phone’s battery life. With JioFi you can make voice and video calls even on a 2G/3G phone by installing Jio4GVoice (JioJoin previously) app and connecting it to the hotspot over WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared and jotted down the list of differences between the JioFi 3 and JioFi2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design of the box:&lt;/em&gt; The first thing you notice in the JioFi 3 is the circular box design compared to a rectangular box that JioFi 2 came in.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-03-768x609.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form Factor:&lt;/em&gt; Both the devices varies drastically when it comes to the build quality. While the JioFi 2 comes in a glossy plastic egg shaped body, its successor comes in a square-shaped body with a matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-10-768x494.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OLED display:&lt;/em&gt; One of the highlighted features in the JioFi3 is the addition of OLED display on the front top instead of just icons. The display provides information about the battery life, signal strength, and WiFi status, however it doesn’t have a separate indicator for WPS and data connectivity that were present in the JioFi 2.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-04-300x195.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Button placements and dimensions:&lt;/em&gt; Another minor difference is the placement of buttons on both the devices. In terms of dimensions, the JioFi 3 measures 96.6 x 65.2 x 15.2mm and JioFi 2 is slightly smaller measuring 85.0 x 55.0 x 16.0 mm&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-06-1024x582.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery:&lt;/em&gt; Another significant upgrade is in the battery division. The JioFi 3 has been bumped up to 2600mAh when compared to 2300mAh on JioFi 2. As per the company claims, the device promises up to 5 hours of usage and up to 260 hours of standby. Even though there is a 300mAh increase in battery,
the charging time is almost same for both the devices using the bundled AC charger.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/JioFi-3-vs-JioFi-2_fonearena-08-768x431.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SIM and microSD slots:&lt;/em&gt; You need to remove the battery in both the versions but JioFi 3 has a nano SIM slot, which is preferred by most and both the SIM and microSD slots have spring type method so the contacts don’t get damaged. The JioFi 2 has a full sized SIM slot and also came with a Micro to full SIM adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of connectivity, both the devices have WiFi 802.11 b/g/n (2.4GHz only) support and option to connect to up to 31 WiFi devices and 1 through USB tethering. Speed is almost same in both the devices through USB tethering and WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JioFi 3 is available for Rs. 1999 (MOP) same as the JioFi 2 and is a minor improvement when it comes to battery, addition of OLED display and a sturdy body with matte finish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: Amount Required, </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-amount-required-penalty-branches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the minimum balance required in my SBI savings account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has said its savings bank account holders in rural, semi-urban, urban and metro branches need to maintain an average balance of Rs 1,000, Rs 2,000, Rs 3,000 and Rs 5,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-metro-branches-650_650x400_51493954503.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, SBI last month merged its operations with five of its associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, joining &amp;ldquo;the coveted league of Global Top 50 banks&amp;rdquo;, it said in another Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI has revised its service charges across functions from April 4 this year, under which it levies a penalty - which is exclusive of service tax - on its savings account customers based on the quantum of shortfall between the monthly average balance and the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-service-charges-650_650x400_51493954227.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs. 333: BSNL&#39;s New Plan To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 333, Rs. 339, Rs. 349 and Rs. 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL or Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited has announced three new data plans priced from Rs 333, the latest offering from the telecom operator seen as aimed at Jio&amp;rsquo;s Dhan Dhana Dhan plans. BSNL is offering up to 270 GB of 3G mobile data along with unlimited voice calls for a period of 90 days. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs 333 includes 3 GB per day of unlimited data, beyond which the speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps, the operator said. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing is causing intense competition in Indian telecom industry, forcing incumbent operators to offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attractive mobile data and unlimited voice calls plans, according to analysts. BSNL has also revised its existing Rs 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of data per day, instead of 2 GB earlier, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s revised Rs 339 pack, valid for 28 days, also includes unlimited local and inter-circle BSNL-to-BSNL calls. Calls to other networks are allowed with a limit of 25 minutes per day, beyond which BSNL customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 349 and Rs 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL had earlier launched yearly packs starting from Rs 1,498 and going up to Rs 4,498, which include 18 GB and 80 GB of data for 365 days, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Notes Exchange: If Relief Granted, It Will Be For All</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/old-notes-exchange-if-relief-granted-it-will-be-for-all-says-top-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Supreme Court said that if it allows an extension then it has to be for all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court today said if it decides to grant relief for extension of the window for exchanging scrapped notes, it will be not in individual cases but for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If there has to be a window (extension for depositing demonetised notes) then all of you (petitioners and others) have to be considered,&amp;rdquo; a bench comprising Chief Justice J S Khehar and Justices D Y Chandrachud and S K Kaul said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hearing a batch of pleas including the one filed by Sudha Mishra challenging the Centre&amp;rsquo;s decision not to allow the public at large to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised by Prime Minister Narendra Modi and others as the window ended on December 30 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorney General (AG) Mukul Rohatgi, appearing for the Centre, referred to the recent affidavit filed by the government on the issue and said that &amp;ldquo;we have given the reasons as to why we do not want to open the window&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am bound by the court&amp;rsquo;s order&amp;hellip; There cannot be a separate window (to deposit notes) for individuals. If the court allows and grants the window (relief) then it has to be for all,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some lawyers, representing persons who wanted to deposit currency notes besides seeking other reliefs, started arguing their individual cases, the AG said, &amp;ldquo;Then, I will have to file separate counter affidavits on the facts of each case.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court then posted the petitions for hearing after the summer vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the Centre, in its affidavit, had told the apex court that it has taken a &amp;ldquo;conscious decision&amp;rdquo; not to extend the period beyond December 30 last year for exchanging demonetised currency notes unlike for the NRIs, and security personnel posted in remote areas, which ended on March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also said it was not legally bound to come out with a fresh notification to grant grace period or window for depositing scrapped currency notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The affidavit has given details about the raids and seizures made by the law-enforcing agencies during and after the demonetisation period claiming that undisclosed income of over Rs 5,400 crore was detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apex court had on March 6 issued notice to the Centre and the RBI on one of the pleas alleging that people were not being allowed to deposit demonetised currency notes till March 31 as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the petitions also referred to the speech of the prime minister on November 8, 2016 and subsequent notification of the RBI spelling out that people may deposit demonetised currency notes even after December 31, 2016 at specific RBI branches up to March 31, 2017 after complying with certain procedural requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has referred to the Specified Bank Notes Cessation of Liabilities Ordinance and said it had gone against the assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance had said that only those who were abroad, the armed forces personnel posted in remote areas or others who could give valid reasons for not being able to deposit the cancelled notes at banks, could deposit demonetised currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 till March 31 this year after the deadline expired on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Pension Scheme (NPS) Or Public Provident Fund (PPF): Which One To Pick?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-national-pension-scheme-nps-or-public-provident-fund-ppf-which-one-to-pick/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-national-pension-scheme-nps-or-public-provident-fund-ppf-which-one-to-pick/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although EPF is an option for salaried employees only, PPF is for all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public Provident Fund (PPF) and Provident Fund (PF) take centre stage whenever savings for retirement come to mind for most of us. Although EPF or Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund is for salaried employees only, PPF is for all. People have been investing in PPF - which provides secured return over the long term - for ages. However, the National Pension Scheme or NPS has been gaining lot of attention as a retirement savings product after the government provided additional tax deduction of Rs. 50,000 in Budget 2015-16. Under NPS, there are two types of accounts: Tier I and Tier II. While the Tier I account is non-withdrawable till the age of 60 except in specific situations, the Tier II account is a voluntary savings account. Subscribers to Tier II accounts can withdraw the money whenever they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the key differences between NPS and PPF:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-can-invest&#34;&gt;Who can invest?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PPF account can be opened by any Indian resident. One can also open a PPF account in the name of his or her minor children and can avail tax benefit on the contribution. However, an NPS account can be opened by Indian citizens above 18 years and less than 60 years of age. Non-resident Indians (NRIs) can also open an NPS account, but they cannot open a PPF account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;maturity&#34;&gt;Maturity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PPF account matures in 15 years. One can also extend this term after 15 years by a block of five years with or without making further contribution. However, in case of NPS, the maturity tenure is not fixed. You can contribute to the NPS account till the age of 60 years with an option to extend the investment to the age of 70 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;investment-limit&#34;&gt;Investment limit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One has to contribute a minimum Rs 500 to a PPF account annually with the maximum amount capped at Rs 1,50,000. A maximum 12 contributions per year are allowed in PPF accounts. However, in case of NPS, the minimum contribution required is Rs 6,000. There is no limit on contribution as long as it does not exceed 10 per cent of your salary, or 10 per cent of your gross total income in case of self-employed. But tax benefit will be available only on Rs 1.5 lakh under Section 80CCD(1) of the Income Tax Act, and an additional Rs 50,000 will be available under Section 80CCD(2) - a total tax benefit of up to Rs 2 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premature withdrawal/partial withdrawal: In case of PPF, partial withdrawals are allowed from the seventh year onwards with some limitation. One can also avail loan against his or her PPF account during the third and sixth financial years of opening the account with certain limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of NPS, after 10 years, subscribers become eligible for early, partial withdrawal under specific circumstance like children&amp;rsquo;s higher education or marriage, construction or purchase of house and treatment of critical illness (for self, spouse, children or dependant parents). But if you want to exit before retirement, you must use at least 80 per cent of the accumulated corpus to buy an annuity from a life insurance company including LIC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;investment-option&#34;&gt;Investment option&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of PPF, you do not have any discretion in deciding where to invest your money. However, in NPS, you can choose from a mix of three funds - equity funds, government securities fund and fixed income instruments other that government securities. A subscriber is allowed to invest up to 75 per cent in the equity fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;returns&#34;&gt;Returns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For PPF subscribers, interest rate is announced every quarter by the government. In case of NPS, returns are market-linked. &amp;ldquo;In our view, the potential of returns in a market-related investment like NPS is higher than of a guaranteed return instrument like PPF/PF. This is due to two reasons, one is the choice of equity exposure in NPS and secondly the component of professional fund management,&amp;rdquo; Manog Nagpal, CEO of Outlook Asia Capital, told NDTV Profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Mr Nagpal added: &amp;ldquo;PPF continues to be an attractive investment in itself, for those looking at zero volatility and a guarantee (in return). On a risk-adjusted basis, PPF returns though will be lower, will not be subject to the vagaries of the market.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tax-treatment&#34;&gt;Tax Treatment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PPF enjoys an EEE or &amp;lsquo;exempt, exempt, exempt&amp;rsquo; status, where the amount you contribute (up to Rs 1.5 lakh), the return you get and the maturity amount, all are tax exempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, NPS comes under an EET or &amp;lsquo;exempt, exempt, tax&amp;rsquo; tax structure. This means that contributions to NPS and the growth in corpus are not taxed but the lump sum withdrawn is partially taxed. Lump sum withdrawals above 40 per cent of the maturity amount are taxable in NPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;annuity&#34;&gt;Annuity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At maturity, you have to mandatorily purchase an annuity for at least 40 per cent of the accumulated wealth in case of NPS. But in case of a maturity amount less than Rs 2 lakh, you have the option of complete withdrawal. However, in case of PPF, you are not required to buy any annuity at the time of maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason NPS is purely a retirement savings scheme. You cannot use NPS for other purposes like children&amp;rsquo;s education, daughter&amp;rsquo;s marriage etc., which you can do with PPF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are certain limitations in NPS, it scores over PPF as a retirement savings scheme on various grounds, say financial planners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 30:you could buy a litre of petrol</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/in-5-years-you-could-buy-a-litre-of-petrol-for-rs-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/in-5-years-you-could-buy-a-litre-of-petrol-for-rs-30/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-s-true&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you remember the last time you paid Rs 30 for a litre of petrol? Well, that was 14 years go, July 2003 to be precise. Seems like petrol will go easy on pockets again. In coming five years, you could be paying as less than Rs 30 per litre for the fuel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;future-tech&#34;&gt;Future tech&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A futuristic technology will be decreasing gthe world&amp;rsquo;s dependence on petrol so much that its prices will crash, predicts Tony Seba, an American futurist famous for predicting a boom in solar power when the prices used to be around ten times of what they are today, which came true eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seba, a serial Silicon Valley entrepreneur, is also an instructor in Entrepreneurship, Disruption and Clean Energy at Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Continuing Studies Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;global-oil-demand-to-go-down&#34;&gt;Global oil demand to go down&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding his prediction, Seba says that it is the rise of self-drive cars that would bring down the global demand for oil, reducing the price of oil to $25 a barrel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oil demand will peak 2021-2020 and will go down 100 million barrels, to 70 million barrels within 10 years. And what that means, the new equilibrium price is going to be $25,&amp;rdquo; says Seba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;affordable-electric-cars&#34;&gt;Affordable electric cars&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though people would not stop using fuelled cars, they would start using self-drive electric vehicles more, which would be cheaper to buy as well as run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;india-to-go-all-electric-by-2030&#34;&gt;India to go all-electric by 2030&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Union power minister Piyush Goyal had also said that India was looking to have all-electric car fleet by 2030, meaning that not a single petrol or diesel car would be sold in the country after 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trai Releases An App Which Lets You Rate Call Quality</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-releases-an-app-which-lets-you-rate-call-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sector regulator Trai today said it will soon roll-out an app that enables subscribers to rate the service quality of a phone call. The &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app would be available by the end of this month, Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (Trai) chairman RS Sharma said at &amp;lsquo;Digital Broadcasting in India - Way Forward&amp;rsquo;, a seminar to commemorate the completion of 20 years of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We would like the consumers to assess the quality of calls, through &amp;lsquo;mycall&amp;rsquo; app, which will be rolled out by this month end,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, once downloaded, the new app would give the subscribers the choice of assessing the quality of all or a portion of calls. When the call is completed, the users will be able to rate it, and the data will thereafter be analysed by the regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The application will pop up a window and enquire about the quality of the call. The subscriber can give it one star to five stars. There will also be assessment parameters like whether the call was indoors or outside or while travelling,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government and the regulator have refused to lower their guard on the issue of call drops, and have kept a close watch on call quality through initiatives like drive tests and automated call system.
Last year, when instances of call drops spiked, the government and the regulator made a co-ordinated effort tackle the issue through deliberations with the industry. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system, which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops. The system is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trai through its analytics portal has also rolled out initiatives that measure data speeds and maps call drops in India, which is the world&amp;rsquo;s second largest telecom market with 1.12 billion mobile subscribers.
Sharma today said that Trai also plans to &amp;ldquo;strengthen&amp;rdquo; the &amp;lsquo;Do Not Disturb&amp;rsquo; or DND service aimed at blocking pesky calls by telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have already done a lot of work in this,&amp;rdquo; Sharma said, but refused to elaborate on the upcoming plans. At present, there is a framework for DND registry that allows telecom subscribers to block unwanted communication from telemarketers. Reaching out to such subscribers can result in a heavy fine for telemarketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source familiar with the initiative said that the regulator may look at building specific intelligence features into the system such that pesky messages with certain key words could automatically generate a prompt on whether the users wishes to report the message as a spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the occasion, Communications Minister Manoj Sinha said TRAI&amp;rsquo;s regulatory framework has provided a conducive environment for the sector&amp;rsquo;s growth. It has made the sector more competitive and enhanced accessibility of services at affordable tariffs, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awareness of the some of the main challenges faced by the sector and regulatory framework of today - ranging from convergence to the persisting issue of the digital divide - is therefore necessary to be better equipped to handle these challenges in future,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अनलिमिटेड कॉलिंग और 4G इंटरनेट:19 रुपए में</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-superday-plan-to-compete-jio-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-superday-plan-to-compete-jio-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मुकेश अंबानी की कंपनी रिलायंस जियो को टक्कर देने के लिए वोडाफोन इंडिया ने गुरुवार को अपने ग्राहकों के लिए 19 रुपए की शुरुआती कीमत वाले कुछ किफायती प्लान पेश किए हैं। इस प्लान में ग्राहकों को अनलिमिटेड वॉयस कॉलिंग के साथ इंटरनेट के लिए 4जी डेटा भी दिया जा रहा है। कंपनी ने इन प्लान को एक-दिन (Vodafone SuperDay) और एक-हफ्ते (Vodafone SuperWeek) वाली दो कैटगरी में बांटा है। इसमें लोकल और एसटीडी कॉलिंग के साथ सात दिन के लिए 250 एमबी तक का डेटा पा सकेंगे।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19 रुपए वाले शुरुआती पैक की वैलिडिटी 1 दिन की है। इसमें ग्राहकों को वोडाफोन से वोडाफोन अनलिमिटेड कॉलिंग (लोकल व एसटीडी) और 100 एमबी का 4जी डेटा मिलेगा। इससे बड़े पैक की कीमत 49 रुपए और वैधता 7 दिन की होगी। इसमें ग्राहकों को 7 दिन के लिए वोडाफोन से वोडाफोन अनलिमिटेड कॉलिंग (लोकल व एसटीडी) और 250 एमबी का 4जी डेटा मिलेगा। सबसे बड़े पैक की कीमत 89 रुपए है जिसकी वैधता भी 7 दिन है। हालांकि इसमें 49 रुपए वाले पैक की सुविधाओं के अलावा वोडाफोन से अन्य नेटवर्क पर (लोकल व एसटीडी) कॉलिंग के लिए 100 मिनट दी जाएंगी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ये सभी पैक्स कंपनी की वेबसाइट, माइ वोडाफोन ऐप और रिटेल स्टोर से लिए जा सकते हैं। ध्यान दें ये सभी पैक्स सिर्फ प्रीपेड यूजर्स के लिए ही है। बता दें कि इससे पहले कंपनी ने जियो की टक्कर पर प्रतिदिन एक जीबी डेटा वाला पैक पेश किया था। 352 रुपए वाले पैक के तहत ग्राहकों को प्रतिदिन एक जीबी डेटा 56 दिनों तक मिलता था। इसे वोडाफोन सुपर ऑफर के नाम से भी जाना जाता है। इस प्लान के तहत ग्राहकों को अनलिमिटेड लोकल और एसटीडी कॉलिंग की भी सुविधा दी गई थी। यह ऑफर न तो वोडाफोन की वेबसाइट पर मिलेगा और न ही ऐप पर। इस ऑफर का लाभ उठाने के लिए आपको वोडाफोन स्टोर या फिर किसी आउटलेट पर जाना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>करोड़पति शेयर: 14.3 लाख के निवेश पर तीन साल में 1 करोड़ रुपये का रिटर्न</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/crorepati-stock-rs-14-3-lakh-invested-in-this-stock-became-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/crorepati-stock-rs-14-3-lakh-invested-in-this-stock-became-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मोदी सरकार ने अपने कार्यकाल के तीन साल पूरे कर लिए। इस दौरान सरकार ने कई महत्वपूर्ण आर्थिक सुधारों को अंजाम दिया और यह प्रक्रिया जारी है। इधर, अर्थव्यवस्था के मौलिक मापदंडों में मजबूती देखी जा रही है। इनके अलावा, देश में राजनीतिक स्थिरता एवं सरकार के स्तर पर सक्रियता की वजह से शेयर बाजार नित नई ऊंचाइयां छू रहा है। इसी क्रम में पिछले तीन सालों में बॉम्बे स्टॉक एक्सचेंज (बीएसई) में लिस्टेड कंपनियों का मार्केट वैल्यू 40 लाख करोड़ रुपये बढ़ गया है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मार्केट वैल्यू में वृद्धि के मामले में मारुति सुजुकी, आईओसी, एचडीएफसी और रिलायंस इंडस्ट्रीज जैसी बड़ी कंपनियों ने नेतृत्वकारी प्रदर्शन किया। लेकिन, बेस्ट परफॉर्मर्स की टॉप 10 लिस्ट में जगह बनाने वाली एक नई कंपनी ने सबको चकित कर रखा है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जिन निवेशकों ने तीन साल पहले इस कंपनी के शेयर में 14.27 लाख रुपये निवेश किए होंगे, वह आज करोड़पति बन चुके हैं। पिछले तीन साल में यह शेयर 538 प्रतिशत उछला है और अब कंपनी दिग्गजों की सूची में शुमार हो चुकी है। यह कंपनी है बजाज फाइनैंस।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस स्टॉक का मार्केट कैप शुक्रवार को 71,000 करोड़ रुपये तक पहुंच गया जो महज तीन साल पहले 10,000 करोड़ रुपये था। आंकड़े बताते हैं कि कंपनी ने पिछले तीन साल से वित्त वर्ष 2016 तक 29.31 प्रतिशत की दर से ऐनुअल प्रॉफिट ग्रोथ दर्ज की है। इस अवधि में कंपनी की बिक्री में सालाना 33.64 प्रतिशत की वृद्धि हुई। विश्लेषक अब भी इस स्टॉक में निवेश की सलाह दे रहे हैं।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ब्रोकरेज फर्म शेयरखान ने बजाज फाइनैंस के शेयर की रेटिंग अपग्रेड कर दी और उसे होल्ड से बाय कैटिगरी में ला दिया। फर्म में इसका रिवाज्ड प्राइस टार्गेट 1,550 रुपये रखा है। सोमवार को बीएसई में यह स्टॉक 1,282 रुपये पर ट्रेड कर रहा था। मार्केट वैल्यू के लिहाज से शानदार प्रदर्शन करने वाली टॉप 10 कंपनियों ने पिछले तीन साल में बीएसई के मार्केट कैप में 9 लाख करोड़ रुपये का इजाफा किया है।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>