<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Lucky Grahak, Digi Dhan: Rs 1 Crore Jackpot For Person Making Rs 1,590 Digital Payment</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-1-crore-jackpot-for-person-making-rs-1-590-digital-payment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of the Digi Dhan scheme, three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were declared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Pranab Mukherjee picked six winners from a draw of lots under the government&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes, aimed at promoting digital transactions in the country. &amp;ldquo;In the consumer category, three mega Prizes of Rs 1 crore, Rs 50 lakh and Rs 25 lakh went to the Consumers using Rupay Debit Cards making digital payment of less than Rs.1,000,&amp;rdquo; an official release said. Three mega prizes for merchants worth Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 25 lakh and Rs. 12 lakh were also declared at the event on the final day of the 100-day scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction of Rs. 1,590 won a Central Bank of India customer a lucky draw of Rs. 1 crore under the consumer category, as part of the government&amp;rsquo;s promotional scheme to popularise digital payments. The President congratulated all the six winners - three consumers and three merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am happy today to be a part of the digital payment movement that India has embarked upon. I congratulate each one of you who has contributed in this mission to make India a less cash society,&amp;rdquo; the President said in his address on the occasion of mega draw of lots for the two schemes held at Rashtrapati Bhawan on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners will be felicitated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on April 14 at Nagpur on the occasion of Ambedkar Jayanti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his address, Mr Mukherjee asked citizens to extend their unstinted support to the mission of a less-cash India. &amp;ldquo;India has a long way to go to become a cash less society. The initiatives of the government are a good beginning and we need to sustain and nurture these with active participation from all segments of the society&amp;hellip;It is necessary to reduce cash in circulation and impart greater urgency to promoting secure digital payment methods to ensure greater transparency,&amp;rdquo; the President said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the consumer section, the second prize of Rs 50 lakh went to a Bank of Baroda customer while the third prize of Rs. 25 lakh was bagged by a customer of Punjab National Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the three customers had made the transactions using their RuPay debit cards. The names of three winners were not yet known as the draw only displayed their transaction numbers. These will be matched with card details to identify the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital transactions have gathered momentum giving a fillip to the less cash economy post demonetisation thanks to the initiatives taken by the government. NITI Aayog&amp;rsquo;s Lucky Grahak and Digidhan Vyapar schemes have played a catalytic role in making it a mass movement, the statement noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressing that India is on the cusp of a digital revolution, Mr Mukherjee noted that more than one billion Indians have a unique identity number with a biometric identifier which is unique in its own way. &amp;ldquo;Even countries which are technologically far more advanced than India with comparatively much smaller size population do not have such a system in place. The Aadhaar card initiative is a watershed event in the development story of India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation of Rs 500 and Rs. 1,000 notes on November 9 last year, the government took a slew of measures to promote digital payments in the country. It had launched the Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes on December 25 last year for consumers and merchants, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lucky Grahak and Digi Dhan Vyapar schemes are being implemented by the National Payment Corporation of India (NPCI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the scheme, daily, weekly and monthly rewards worth Rs. 256 crore have been disbursed to over 16 lakh citizens over the past 100 days for making and accepting small transactions digitally. Over the past 100 days, everyday 15,000 consumers have qualified for total prize money of Rs. 1.5 crore, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The draw has seen a positive impact from various age groups and occupations in adopting digital payments methods. We have seen a steady increase in the number of transactions made using all payment methods,&amp;rdquo; said A P Hota, MD and CEO of National Payment Corporation of India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.”  For telecom providers, the DoT is giving a one year time period to carry out this eKYC process; the order puts the final date at February 6, 2018. The DoT directive comes after the Supreme Court issued an order with this respect in February this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is Aadhaar-based eKYC and what does it require? For starters, the Aadhaar card becomes mandatory if you to hold onto your old mobile number or even get a new one. Aadhaar eKYC is a paperless form of Know Your Customer (KYC); the KYC guidelines ensure that the service provider, and this is not just restricted to mobile service providers, but includes banks, etc, need to have details of their customers like address, age, full name, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Aadhaar-based KYC  identity, address and other details are verified via the Aadhaar authentication online. A user will have to give his Aadhaar number, do the biometric verification, and the KYC is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how will you know when to get eKYC done with your mobile operator? No need to rush just yet, but this will come soon. Customers will start receiving SMS alerts, or see television and print ads from their telecom provider regarding the same as DoT has directed them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cellular operators’ association of India (COAI) had said that its members, which includes the majority of telecom providers in the country, will meet later this week to discuss the process. However COAI has pointed out the entire exercise will cost Rs 1,000 crore for infrastructure and training, which will have to be borne by the operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The issue of fake subscribers will go away. We will try our best to cover the entire base within the stipulated time frame of one year but in case we cannot, we may ask DoT for an extension,” COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said in a statement to PTI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will one eKYC be good enough to get another connection with the same operator? No, if you go by the DoT notification. According to a PTI report, “For issuing additional mobile connections to re-verified subscriber, the operator would have to follow a separate eKYC process.” So if you have a Vodafone or Airtel connection, and you get it re-verified, getting a second number will require another eKYC, which is tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are converting prepaid to postpaid or vice versa, then you won’t be requiring another eKYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for Aadhaar-based eKYC is that it will help deal with the issue of fake mobile subscribers in the country. But the catch is that it also means that anyone who doesn’t have an Aadhaar card won’t be able to continue with the mobile connection, which sounds extreme. India has over 1 billion plus mobile connections, and this Aadhaar eKYC will impact every single user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Still Get Reliance Jio&#39;s &#39;Summer Surprise Offer&#39;? Here Are The Details</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-you-still-get-jios-summer-surprise-offer-here-are-the-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/can-you-still-get-jios-summer-surprise-offer-here-are-the-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although, the offer can still be availed over the &amp;ldquo;next few days&amp;rdquo; and those who &amp;ldquo;subscribe before the discontinuation&amp;rdquo; will remain eligible for the complimentary plan,&amp;rdquo; Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s website stated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) asked Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Jio to withdraw the complimentary &amp;ldquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rdquo; plan as it did not fit into the &amp;ldquo;regulatory framework&amp;rdquo;. Reliance Jio has accepted the regulator&amp;rsquo;s decision and is in the process of &amp;ldquo;fully complying&amp;rdquo; with it. Jio &amp;lsquo;complimentary&amp;rsquo; offer included free data usage and calls for three months on a recharge of Rs 303 or higher. Although, the offer can still be availed over the &amp;ldquo;next few days&amp;rdquo; and those who &amp;ldquo;subscribe before the discontinuation&amp;rdquo; will remain eligible for the complimentary plan,&amp;rdquo; the company&amp;rsquo;s website stated.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/reliance-jio_650x400_61491559381.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We examined it and found that it was not in accordance with regulatory framework, so we advised them to stop it,&amp;rdquo; TRAI Chairman RS Sharma said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the regulator&amp;rsquo;s decision, Cellular Operators Association of India (COAI) said that the TRAI&amp;rsquo;s move to stop the three-month complimentary offer would reduce the deterioration in industry&amp;rsquo;s revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When the regulator establishes a level-playing-field, the market forces establish the right price points,&amp;rdquo; COAI Director General Rajan Mathews said, terming the withdrawal of the offer as a &amp;ldquo;relief&amp;rdquo; for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the data released by TRAI, the revenue of telecom sector from consumer services like mobile telephony and data dipped 10.5 per cent to Rs 37,284 crore in the October-December period over the previous three months. The revenue of the sector from the same set of services stood at Rs 41,681 crore in July-September last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incumbent telecom operators have blamed free services of new entrant Reliance Jio for the decline in their quarterly numbers. While Jio provided free 4G service during the period, other telecom operators struggled to compete with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31 March Last Day For Depositing Old Notes In RBI: Here&#39;s A Checklist</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-31-march-last-day-for-depositing-old-notes-in-rbi-heres-a-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-31-march-last-day-for-depositing-old-notes-in-rbi-heres-a-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the March 31 deadline looming for depositing demonetised currency, the Reserve Bank offices continued to witness long queues. There is confusion among people standing in the queues as ineligible ones are making it longer. &amp;ldquo;Several people who are ineligible queueing up at RBI counters making the queue longer,&amp;rdquo; Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal said in the Rajya Sabha. As tempers ran high outside the central bank branches, he added that &amp;ldquo;each application has to be checked at the counters for his/her absence from the country from passport stamp marks, it is taking considerable time for the counter staff.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a checklist before the opportunity ends on March 31:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Possession of more than 10 notes in junked currency after March 31 is illegal for Indian residents. Violation of this is punishable with a fine which may extend to Rs 10,000 or five times the amount of the face value of the notes, whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central bank allowed Indian residents who were abroad during November-December 2016 to exchange the scrapped notes up to March 31 but for non-resident Indians (NRIs) the deadline is June 30.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NRIs coming to India are required to come through &amp;lsquo;Red Channel&amp;rsquo; disclosing to the Customs authorities at the airport the amount of the defunct notes and secure a certificate to be tendered at RBI at the time of exchange. A one-page form has been worked out for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no monetary limit for exchange for the eligible resident Indians, but the limit for NRIs will be as per the relevant FEMA Regulations (Rs 25,000 per person).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indian citizens resident in Nepal, Bhutan, Pakistan and Bangladesh cannot avail this facility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The facility to exchange old notes is available at RBI offices in Mumbai, Delhi, Kolkata, Chennai and Nagpur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On fulfillment of the terms and conditions and the genuineness of the notes tendered, the amount will be credited to the person&amp;rsquo;s Know Your Customer (KYC) compliant bank account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case of refusal by the central bank, a person may appeal to the Central Board of the Reserve Bank within 14 days of the communication of such refusal to him. Such representations may be addressed to the Central Board, Reserve Bank of India, Secretary&amp;rsquo;s Department.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto, Health Insurance To Cost More As Regulator Okays Raise For Agents</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-auto-health-insurance-to-cost-more-as-regulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Car, motorcycle and health insurance will cost more from April 1 with regulator Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority (IRDAI) giving go-ahead to insurers for revision in commission for agents. The change in premium after modification will be limited to around 5 per cent of the existing rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increase will be in addition to the enhanced third party motor insurance rates, which too will come into affect from April. The IRDAI (Payment of Commission or Remuneration or Reward to Insurance Agents and Insurance Intermediaries) Regulations, 2016 comes into effect from April 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulations, the regulator said, bring about certain revisions in commission/ remuneration rates and also introduce the reward system. These may trigger insurers to revisit the pricing of their products in so far as the costing input relating to commission or remuneration is concerned, said IRDAI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the change in premium due to the new regulations should be &amp;ldquo;limited to +/- 5 per cent of the existing premium rates of products/add-ons&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, insurers will have to give a certificate that there is &amp;ldquo;no detrimental change&amp;rdquo; in premium rates or any other provision of policies already sold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Aadhaar-based payment modes work</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-based-payment-modes-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The government is planning to utilise the Aadhaar database to give shape to a digital future and utilise it for payments, and authentication of transactions is the key to its success. While Unified Payments Interface and BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) are processes for peer-to-peer transactions using smartphones, the government is promoting Aadhaar-enabled payment systems for the non-smartphone savvy. As per sources it is planning to launch Aadhaar Pay on April 14. ET looks into the different forms of Aadhaar payment modes being developed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems?
Payments that can be done with the help of au thentication and identi fication through the Aadhaar database is referred to as the Aadhaar Enabled Payment Systems (AEPS). This is the new form of pay ment that is being pro moted by the govern ment to push for digital payments instead of cash transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the major types of Aadhaar Enabled Payments?
The first type of payment is Aadhaar Bridge Payment System which is meant for direct bene fit transfer and subsidy payments from the gov ernment to the benefi ciaries. The second is AEPS which is used at the level of the business correspondent or `bank mitras’ where bank customers can use Aadhaar to access various services like cash withdrawal, account opening and fund transfer even without going to a bank branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is Aadhaar Pay wherein merchants can accept payments through Aadhaar identification of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we need Aadhaar Enabled payments?
These forms of payments are be ing promoted by the government specifically for the under privileged sections of the society and the rural poor who are not comfortable using cards or mobile wallets for payments.Instead of a mobile phone or a plastic card, in these forms of payments, the mode of authentication becomes the Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who runs the systems?
National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is the nodal authority for all Aadhaar-enabled payments in collaboration with banks. The payment company is trying to get as many banks to seed their customers’ accounts with their Aadhaar number so that payments can flow smoothly .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do the different forms of payments work?
Aahdaar Bridge Payment (ABPS):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant for recur ring payments done by the government to its customers for various subsidies as well as direct benefit transfer. Here the beneficiary is identified through an Aadhaar number, then NPCI manages an Aadhaar Mapper where the Aadhaar number is mapped to a specific bank account and the money flows to the connected bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-enabled-payment-aeps&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Enabled Payment (AEPS):&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the customer has to approach a business correspondent (BC), use his Aadhaar number and biometrics which the BC shares with NPCI, which checks the ID with UIDAI (Unique Identification Authority of India) to confirm the customer’s identity . It also checks the funds in the connected account and allows the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for merchant payments where the merchant will download the merchant payments app of his bank, authenticate the customer through his biometrics and Aadhaar number and initiate a pull transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotak Bank Launches 811 &#39;Zero Balance, Zero Charge&#39; Account. Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/kotak-bank-launches-811-zero-balance-zero-charge-account-details-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private sector lender Kotak Mahindra Bank (KMB) on Wednesday announced the launch of &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; savings account scheme, aimed at doubling its customer base over the next 18 months, primarily through digital account opening from the current 8 million. Executive vice-chairman Uday Kotak said it has been named &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;inspired by November 8, 2016, &amp;ldquo;the day that changed India&amp;rdquo; referring to Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s announcement of high value notes last year. The 811 scheme offers a &amp;ldquo;completely digital, paperless account opening experience&amp;rdquo; through Kotak Bank&amp;rsquo;s app in five minutes, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is inspired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s November 8 (demonetisation) move. The inspiration is from PM Modi&amp;rsquo;s vision of new India,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key things to know about Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 savings account scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &amp;ldquo;811&amp;rdquo; is part of Kotak&amp;rsquo;s existing banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Kotak&amp;rsquo;s 811 account will offer users an interest rate of up to 6 per cent on savings account balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) The 811 scheme offers &amp;ldquo;zero balance with zero charges&amp;rdquo; for all digital transactions, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Only Aadhaar and PAN numbers are required to open and operate it, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The 811 savings account scheme offers over 100 features including financial transactions management, online shopping, booking of movie tickets, flights and hotel rooms, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The app is also Unified Payment Interface or UPI-enabled which lets you send and receive money without adding any other bank information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kotak is the first bank to integrate the newly introduced Aadhaar-based OTP on mobile, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) It is a combination of a regular bank account, mobile account and a digital wallet which gives access to e-commerce, Mr Kotak said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Select Tax Department Offices To Be Open Till March 31 Midnight</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/select-tax-department-offices-to-be-open-till-march-31-midnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/select-tax-department-offices-to-be-open-till-march-31-midnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The last date for making declaration under the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana, 2016 is March, 31 2017.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CBDT on Thursday issued an order that all designated offices of the Income Tax department which can accept declarations under the black money window of PMGKY will remain open till midnight of March 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The last date for making declaration under the Pradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Yojana, 2016 is March, 31 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Therefore, in order to facilitate the filing of declarations even after the office hours on the last date, the CBDT, hereby directs that the designated offices for receiving the declarations under PMGKY shall remain open till the midnight of March 31, 2017 in all jurisdictions,&amp;rdquo; the CBDT order said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) is the policymaking body of the Income Tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A person or entity who opts for PMGKY will have to pay 49.9 per cent tax on the undisclosed income, whereas a person who does not opt for the scheme but offers his black income in his Income Tax Returns will face a tax and penalty rate of 77.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one who does not offer his stash funds under the scheme but is caught with undisclosed income in scrutiny assessment will face 83.25 per cent tax rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who do not declare their stash under the PMGKY and are raided will face 107.25 per cent tax and penalty if the undisclosed income is surrendered during the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who do not surrender such hidden income even during searches will stand to face the highest level of penalty and tax at 137.25 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre had come out with the PMGKY scheme after its decision to demonetise high value currency notes of Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quarter of the total sum will also have to be parked in a non-interest bearing deposit for four years under the said scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scheme had commenced on December 17 last year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Income Tax Rules That Will Change From April. See Details Here</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-income-tax-rules-that-will-change-from-april-see-details-here/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5-Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lok Sabha on Wednesday passed the Finance Bill, completing the budgetary exercise for 2017-18. Since the Finance Bill is a Money Bill, it needs only to be cleared by the Lok Sabha. Starting from April 1, 2017, some income tax laws will change. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had announced a number of income tax changes in Budget 2017. In addition, some amendments were also introduced in the Finance Bill that was passed by the Lok Sabha. Here are some of the changes that income tax payers should note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) The tax rate on income between Rs. 2.5 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh will get halved to 5 per cent from 10 per cent. However, rebate under Section 87A gets reduced from Rs. 5,000 to Rs. 2,500. And no rebate will be applicable for taxpayers having income above Rs. 3.5 lakh. This means tax savings of up to Rs. 7,700 for those with a taxable income between Rs. 3 lakh and Rs. 5 lakh. And for persons with taxable income between Rs. 5 lakh and Rs. 50 lakh, tax savings of Rs. 12,900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A 10 per cent surcharge will be applicable for individuals having income ranging from Rs. 50 lakh to Rs. 1 crore (existing surcharge of 15 per cent will remain the same for individuals having income above Rs. 1 crore.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: These 10 Transactions Will Get Reported To Income Tax Department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A simple one-page form will be introduced for filing tax return for individuals having a taxable income up to Rs. 5 lakh other than business income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) No deduction will be allowed for investment in Rajiv Gandhi Equity Saving Scheme from Assessment Year 2018-19. This tax-saving scheme, announced in the Union Budget for financial year 2012-13, was designed exclusively for the first-time individual investors in the securities market with gross total income below a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Income tax officials can reopen tax cases for up to 10 years if search operations reveal undisclosed income and assets of over Rs. 50 lakh. Currently, tax officers can go back up to six years to scrutinise the books of accounts of assessees. Taxpayers who do not file their returns on time will have to shell out a penalty of up to Rs. 10,000 from Assessment Year 2018-19. However, if the total income of the person does not exceed Rs. 5 lakh, the fee payable under this section shall not exceed Rs. 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) The holding period of a property for qualifying as long-term gains will be reduced to two years, from three years. This will help save tax if a property is sold within two years of buying. The profit from the transaction will be treated as short-term capital gains and will be taxed according to the slab rate applicable to him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) The government has cut down tax benefits borrowers enjoyed on properties let out on rent. As per current tax laws, for properties rented out, a borrower could deduct the entire interest paid on home loan after adjusting for the rental income. On the other hand, borrowers of self-occupied properties get a deduction of Rs. 2 lakh on interest repayment on home loan. But on rented properties, the borrower can only claim a deduction of up to Rs. 2 lakh per year after adjusting for the rental income. And the amount above Rs. 2 lakh can be carried forward for eight assessment years. Since the interest component of home loan repaid in initial years is higher, experts say that the borrower may not be able to fully adjust the interest paid as deduction even in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Individuals will be required to deduct a 5 per cent TDS (tax deducted at source) for rental payments above Rs. 50,000 per month. Tax experts say that the move will ensure that persons who get a large rental income come into the tax net. It will be effective from June 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Partial withdrawals from National Pension System (NPS) will not attract tax. According to the proposed changes, NPS subscribers can withdraw 25 per cent of their contribution to the corpus for emergencies before retirement. Remember that withdrawal of 40 per cent of the corpus is tax-free on retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Aadhaar number will be a must while applying for PAN as well as filing of income tax returns from July 1. To curb black money, the limit on cash transactions has been set at Rs. 2 lakh. The Finance Bill had originally proposed the cap at Rs. 3 lakh. If a person receives any sum in contravention of the tax law, he/she will be liable to pay, by way of penalty, a sum equal to the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Prepaid Users Can Get Up To 120GB Extra Data. Here Is How</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-prepaid-users-can-get-120gb-extra-data-here-is-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/article-jio-prepaid-users-can-get-120gb-extra-data-here-is-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier this week, a survey conducted by Bank of America Merrill Lynch said that around 84 per cent of the current Jio members are expected to subscribe for the Prime membership.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime offer, which opened for enrolment on March 1, entitles customers to &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; benefits till March 2018. To sweeten the Prime offer, Jio is offering additional benefits for subscribers who recharge their accounts before March 31, 2017. Those who recharge before March 31, will get up to 10 GB of extra data for one recharge cycle (under different prepaid plans). For example, If subscribers opt for the Rs. 149 prepaid plan (validity 28 days) before March 31, then they will get 1 GB of free data in addition to 2 GB of data originally on offer. Similarly under the Rs. 303 plan, Jio offers 5 GB of free data along with 28 GB of data subscribers are originally entitled for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Jio customer care executive confirmed that a Prime member can lock in the above benefits till March 2018. For example, if a Prime customer recharges his account with the Rs. 499 plan 12 times before March 31, 2017, then he would be entitled to get 120GB of extra data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/jio-prime-650_650x400_41490449016.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

Meanwhile, in the Rs. 999, Rs. 1999, Rs. 4,999 and Rs. 9,999 plans Jio is offering 10 GB of extra data per recharge cycle over and above the data originally on offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rs. 149, Rs. 303 and Rs. 499 plans of Reliance Jio have a validity of 28 days while the Rs. 999 plan offers a validity of 60 days. Meanwhile, the Rs. 1,999 and Rs. 4,999 plans have validity of 90 and 180 days respectively. The Rs. 9,999 plan of Jio comes with a validity of 360 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio, which started its operations in September 2016, has already crossed the 100 million subscribers mark. Earlier this week, a survey conducted by Bank of America Merrill Lynch said that around 84 per cent of the current Jio members are expected to subscribe for the Prime membership.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associate Bank Branches To Become SBI Branches From April 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/associate-bank-branches-to-become-sbi-branches-from-april-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branches of all five associate banks, which are merging with parent State Bank of India, will begin functioning as SBI branches from April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customers, including depositors of State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur, State Bank of Hyderabad, State Bank of Mysore, State Bank of Patiala and State Bank of Travancore will be treated as customers of State Bank of India with effect from April 1, 2017,&amp;rdquo; the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) said in a notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the merger of all the five associates, SBI is expected to become a lender of global proportions with an asset base of Rs 37 lakh crore or over $555 billion, 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs. It will have over 50 crore customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officers and employees, with the exception of the board of directors and executive trustees of the associate banks, will become employees of SBI following the merger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI alone has nearly 20,000 branches, including 191 foreign offices spread across 36 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the five subsidiary banks, only SBBJ, SBM and SBT are listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the government on Monday announced that Bharatiya Mahila Bank will also be merged with SBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Payments Corporation Says No Vulnerability In BHIM App</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-says-no-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/national-payments-corporation-says-no-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPCI significant downloads have been witnessed since the BHIM app was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;National Payments Corporation of India&lt;/em&gt; (NPCI) on Monday said there is no vulnerability or loopholes reported in the Bharat Interface for Money or BHIM application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI has done intensive testing, robust design of security controls and continuous monitoring of its Unified Payments Interface (UPI) infrastructure, the corporation said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The environment in which BHIM or UPI is run by NPCI is highly secure and certified with best global practices,&amp;rdquo; it said, adding that the packages have also been audited by reputed IT security firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NPCI has put in place adequate governance mechanism for banks to report any fraud or system issues and its redressal, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, it said that since BHIM was launched by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, significant downloads have been witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Out of the 19.16 million downloads, 5.1 million customers have been able to link their bank accounts. In many cases customers downloaded the application to see that they have not linked their mobile number to the bank account,&amp;rdquo; it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Banks are expected to reach out to all their customers by various means and ensure universal acceptance of mobile banking services at the earliest,&amp;rdquo; NPCI managing director and CEO A P Hota said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt tells RBI to work with stakeholders for PoS roll-out</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-tells-rbi-work-stakeholders-pos-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/govt-tells-rbi-work-stakeholders-pos-roll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The govt has asked RBI to fix responsibilities for stakeholders, including PoS manufactures, UIDAI that administers the 12-digit Aadhaar number, and the NPCI to launch the process&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance ministry has asked the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to bring together all stakeholders, including banks and back-end service providers, and establish a process for the roll-out of Aadhaar-based point of sales (PoS) machines to promote cashless transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his budget speech last month, finance minister Arun Jaitley said two million Aadhaar-based PoS machines will be rolled out by September-end. Banks have flagged the lack of an established back-end infrastructure as an impediment in implementing this mandate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has now asked RBI to fix responsibilities for stakeholders, including PoS manufactures, back-end service providers, banks, and the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) that administers the 12-digit Aadhaar number, and the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) to launch the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For Aadhaar-based PoS machines to be a reality, many systems and processes have to be put in place. The biometric data captured on these machines has to be encrypted and transmitted after which Aadhaar authentication has to be done. The payment then has to be processed. For this, all the stakeholders have to be brought together by RBI and the process established,” said a senior finance ministry official, who did not wish to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time that an Aadhaar-based authentication process has been proposed. RBI, in a notification in September 2016, made it mandatory for all banks to ensure that all new card acceptance infrastructure deployed from 1 January, 2017 is enabled for processing payment transactions using Aadhaar-based biometric authentication. After banks raised concerns about a mismatch between demand and supply of such Aadhaar-enabled devices, the central bank gave banks time till end-June to deploy this infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deepak Bhutra, chief executive officer, India Transact Services Ltd, a merchant payment solutions firm, said it is possible to shift to new age biometric payment systems. “This is not technically a difficult task but rather a very expensive one. Companies will have to invest in securing these biometric readers and assembling them in the currently available PoS machines,” he said in an email. “We do see faster acceptance of the PoS machines now with the push from the government, but a major challenge would be to educate the customer to pay through Aadhaar payment method as opposed to paying via the card route,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are a few things which banks will incrementally have to follow. Firstly, banks will need to get certified with NPCI for AEPS (Aadhaar- enabled payment system) switching capability which will have to be managed or outsourced by the bank. Secondly, deployment of a merchant app with low cost peripheral, to enable Aadhaar biometric authentication is needed. Lastly, banks would need to upgrade their existing EDC (electronic draft capture) PoS or mPoS terminals to support biometric capture which may work out to be more costly and much less scalable,” Deepak Sharma, chief digital officer, Kotak Mahindra Bank, said in response to emailed questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“From a consumer perspective, the Aadhaar-based payment methodology will work even in the absence of feature phones and high-end smart phones—which addresses a significant part of the population at the bottom of the pyramid,” added Sharma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An IDFC Bank official said the target is easily achievable if new age banks adopt this route. “The bank has an ambitious roll-out plan for both Aadhaar Pay as well as micro ATMs,” the official added on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay is a service for merchants that will enable them to receive payments from customers without any physical payment instrument. The app has to be downloaded by merchants on their phones and linked to an Aadhaar biometric reader. Once the merchant has this infrastructure in place, consumers can start transacting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPI, Aadhaar Pay, Bharat QR force Paytm, Mobikwik to step up their game</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/upi-aadhaar-pay-bharat-qr-force-paytm-mobikwik-step-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/upi-aadhaar-pay-bharat-qr-force-paytm-mobikwik-step-game/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the arrival of state-sponsored e-payment services, electronic payment firms have ratcheted up their efforts to lure customers in the cashless driven market&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic payment firms got a big boost when India abolished most of the country’s banknotes last year, but rival state-sponsored e-payment services are forcing them to raise their game to hang on to their new customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until November’s move, which scrapped 86% of all notes to foil counterfeiting and the black market, more than 90% of transactions in India were in cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic payments providers such as market leaders Paytm and MobiKwik, and smaller players FreeCharge, Citrus, ItzCash and Oxigen, seized the opportunity, snapping up millions of customers and merchants caught out by the sudden shortage of cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the government is rolling out three tools to facilitate rival cashless transactions, including a United Payments Interface (UPI) app that simplifies inter-bank fund transfers, and Aadhaar Pay, a bank-linked payment service that relies on the national identity card and can be used with just a fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also promoted Bharat QR, another bank-linked service that uses machine-readable labels as the base for a simple payment system, helped by Visa and MasterCard. It requires only a smartphone and is aiming to sign up 2 million merchants by September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UPI app was downloaded more than 17 million times within two months of launch, and transaction values jumped 18 times between November and January, albeit from a low base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So e-wallet providers such as Alibaba-backed Paytm, the largest, with more than 200 million clients, are adding services to stay a step ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paytm is betting that its licence to set up a niche bank so it can pay interest on deposits—and connect its systems with the UPI network—will help, and it knows it will need extra services to make the business profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The point is that e-wallets as a standalone business will be massively risky and not viable,” said Vijay Shekhar Sharma, founder and chief executive of Paytm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;freebies&#34;&gt;Freebies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early stages of their build-up, the companies haven’t even paid lipservice to viability—giving a free service to customers and merchants, while burning through their start-up funding. Their only source of income has been commissions on phone and utility bill payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paytm’s parent company has raised $675 million from Alibaba and more from others, and says its current valuation is about $5 billion, but it has lost about $230 million over the last financial year. MobiKwik, part-owned by American Express and Sequoia Capital, has raised about $80 million and is eyeing a $1 billion valuation as it holds talks with investors for more funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both have waived fees to enable free money transfers from wallets to bank accounts. Paytm says transfers within its wallets and accounts will be free forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they have been using cash discounts and freebies to lure customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mumbai-based management teacher Christina Sundaresan says she started using Paytm when the government pulled the plug on notes, and now uses it so frequently she gets a free movie ticket each weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My laptop repairer, the vegetable vendor and the medical store are all accepting Paytm, so it works well,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she says she would consider other payment options, including UPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That will make it difficult for Paytm to withdraw the freebies, but they can’t keep burning cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t have a business that says ‘pay a 500 bill and take 250 cash back’,” said Aditya Puri, head of third-biggest Indian lender HDFC Bank, which has its own payment app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MobiKwik, which started as a simple digital wallet, is looking to partner with mainstream banks to market a host of financial services on its platform, from mutual funds to loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It aims to triple its wallets user base to 150 million by end-2017, and raise the value of transactions five times to $10 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It thinks its head start and extra services will keep it on top of the competition, and that banks, latecomers to e-payment, will struggle to match the scale of its operations and vendor network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“UPI is a solution for bank transfers. UPI is not a payments ecosystem today, as there are no merchants on UPI,” said MobiKwik chief executive Bipin Preet Singh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dhruv Chopra, managing director at the Indian unit of South African payments solutions provider Net1, which has invested in MobiKwik, is also betting the start-ups will be too nimble for the banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with a large number of small players, many will not survive, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avnish Bajaj of venture capital firm Matrix Partners, which has investments in payments companies ItzCash, Mswipe, and ride hailing firm Ola, which has its own e-wallet, agrees there will be a clearout under competitive pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s going to be a bit of consolidation in the e-wallets space in the next two years,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar payments: All you need to know about the new Aadhar Pay app</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-payments-need-know-new-aadhar-pay-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-payments-need-know-new-aadhar-pay-app/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In a bid to promote Aadhaar-based payment system, Modi government has launched a new Android app for merchants to accept payments using their biometric data or the registered data under UIDAI’s Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar-based payment system is currently being used by 1,10,000 business correspondents for disbursing cash, and is also being utilised in Common Service Centres to pay for various services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is all you need to know about the newly launched Aadhaar Pay:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-the-new-app-will-work&#34;&gt;How the new app will work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After downloading the app, the user also needs to register with a valid ID. Then he/she needs to fill the required details to validate the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Merchants: After downloading the Aadhaar Pay app from Google Play Store, the user has to install a biometric scanner linked to the user’s smartphone. The user also needs to link his bank account to the phone so that the transaction can be completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Customers: Customers need their Aadhaar number which has to be linked to their bank account. They can use either a fingerprint or biometric data to complete the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages of doing a transaction through Aadhaar app is that no additional charges will be levied unlike debit and credit cards.
Also, the installing cost for a biometric scanner for Aadhaar Pay is much more less than a POS machine. A POS machine costs Rs 5,000 whereas the biometric scanner will cost around Rs 2,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;however-one-of-the-limitation-of-aadhaar-app-payments-is-that-they-can-only-take-place-if-the-internet-is-available&#34;&gt;However, one of the limitation of Aadhaar app payments is that they can only take place if the internet is available.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;meanwhile-here-are-other-related-points-about-the-newly-launched-aadhaar-pay&#34;&gt;Meanwhile, here are other related points about the newly launched Aadhaar Pay&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app has been jointly developed by UIDAI,NPCI and IDFC Bank. The Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is the nodal body responsible for rolling out the Aadhaar programme in the country. Transactions through the app would be made with the help of registered data under UIDAI’s          Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emphasizing upon the rural pockets of the country, UIDAI has favored “incentives” for merchants using the biometric mode for digital transactions, in line with commission given by banks to Business Correspondents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Ajay Bhushan Pandey, CEO of UIDAI told media, “If a merchant is using Aadhaar-enabled payment systems then he should be put at par with Business Correspondent and whatever facility and commission is available to the Business Correspondent, he should be paid on the same lines”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also added that incentivizing shopkeepers who adopt the biometric payment system would also “remove an extra layer” as consumers today approach banks, ATMs or business correspondents for withdrawal of money to purchase items such as ration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to an Economic Times report, the Government is mulling over an option of giving banks an incentive of up to Rs 10 for each transaction. Quoting a government official, the report stated that a suggestion to provide an incentive of 0.25% on the value of a transaction – capped at Rs 10 –     made on the biometric-based payment system Aadhaar Pay and UPI platform BHIM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The committee of secretaries had said that if they (banks) don’t have incentives, they may not go and acquire merchants, so let them have incentives, and merchant will not bear cost and it may be borne from the financial inclusion fund,” the official told ET.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digital payment channels like mobile wallets, USSD and RuPay have seen massive uptake and rise in transactions post demonetisation on November 8. Even in case of Aadhaar-enabled payment system, the volume of transactions have jumped 2.5 times post demonetisation from 6 lakh a day before November   to 15 lakh transactions per day at present.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>