<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things To Know About New iPhone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-launches-iphone-x-10-things-to-know-about-new-iphone-1749628/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-launches-iphone-x-10-things-to-know-about-new-iphone-1749628/</guid>
      <description>Apple Inc. on Tuesday launched the much-awaited iPhone X, the 10-year anniversary edition of Apple&amp;rsquo;s pioneering touch-screen mobile. Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone X, among the latest entrants in the iPhone series of smartphones, will be clad in glass and stainless steel and will come loaded with features including facial recognition unlocking. The iPhone X will also feature an edge-to-edge display termed as &amp;ldquo;the biggest leap forward since the original iPhone&amp;rdquo; by chief executive Tim Cook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>508 Km In 3 Hours: India&#39;s First Bullet Train Project In 10 Points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/508-km-in-3-hours-india-s-first-bullet-train-project-in-10-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/508-km-in-3-hours-india-s-first-bullet-train-project-in-10-points/</guid>
      <description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his Japanese counterpart Shinzo Abe laid the foundation stone for India’s first bullet train project in Ahmedabad on Thursday. The bullet train project touted to revolutionize railways technology in the country. The first line which will connect Ahmedabad to Mumbai can cover the 508 km distance in as little as two hours, the government said. The project will be executed as a joint venture between the Indian Railways and Japanese firm Shinkansen Technology at an estimated cost of Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar eKYC mandatory for mobile connections: Here’s how it applies to you</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-ekyc-mandatory-mobile-connections-heres-applies/</guid>
      <description>If you don’t have an Aadhaar card number, you’ll probably have to get one soon, since the government is making this mandatory across a range of services, and it looks like getting a mobile connection is next on the list. Last Friday, Department of Telecom (DoT) has issued an order asking telecom operators to start the process of re-verifying their subscribers with Aadhaar-based eKYC.
DoT’s order reads, “All licensees shall re-verify all existing mobile subscribers (prepaid and postpaid) through Aadhaar-based e-KYC process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All You Need To Know About New Rs 100 Coins That Are Coming Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-100-coins-to-be-issued-to-mark-mg-ramachandrans-birth-centenary-1749334/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rs-100-coins-to-be-issued-to-mark-mg-ramachandrans-birth-centenary-1749334/</guid>
      <description>The Rs 100 coins will be introduced to commemorate the occasion of Dr MG Ramachandran birth centenary. This was stated in a notification, dated September 11, from the Ministry of Finance. New Rs 5 coins will also be issued to mark the birth centenary of the late AIADMK founder, the notification added. The Rs 100 coin will be 44 millimeter in diameter with a metal composition of silver (50 per cent), copper (40 per cent), nickel (5 per cent) and zinc (5 per cent).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Wars: Jio Gets Competition As Airtel Launches VoLTE Services</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/data-wars-jio-gets-competition-as-airtel-launches-volte-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/data-wars-jio-gets-competition-as-airtel-launches-volte-services/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s entry into the telecom market triggered an extended price war last year which saw telecom companies slashing tariffs and data charges. Jio also offered a 4G Voice over Long-Term Evolution or VoLTE service, enabling users to make voice calls using data - a first in the telecom sector. On Monday, Bharti Airtel became the second operator to offer 4G VoLTE services as it launched its service in Mumbai. Bharti Airtel said that there will be no additional data charges for VoLTE and calls will be billed as per existing plans or packs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Aadhaar linking deadlines you should not miss</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/four-aadhaar-linking-deadlines-not-miss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/four-aadhaar-linking-deadlines-not-miss/</guid>
      <description>There are certain deadlines that you need to meet related to your Aadhaar in order to avoid pain in the coming year, 2018.
Here’s the list of various deadlines set by the government regarding Aadhaar.
 Aadhaar and PAN linking deadline is now December 31, 2017 The government had earlier notified that income tax returns (ITR) filed after July 1, 2017 would be accepted only after a tax assessee linked his/her PAN with Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to link Aadhaar Card with SIM card: What you need to do in this critical task; step by step guide</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-card-sim-card-need-critical-task-step-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-card-sim-card-need-critical-task-step-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>#How to link Aadhaar Card with SIM card?
Aadhaar card is now a crucial thing to have in India, especially with the way the government has made it mandatory in several sectors and even services. Having an Aadhaar number is not only necessary for establishing your identity to avail schemes but also in financial matters like bank accounts and filing taxes. Even mobile phone service users will now have to verify using Aadhaar numbers, as the telcos, in March, had been instructed to start the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Life To Launch First Billion Dollar IPO In Seven Years</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-life-to-launch-first-billion-dollar-ipo-in-seven-years-1749441/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-life-to-launch-first-billion-dollar-ipo-in-seven-years-1749441/</guid>
      <description>SBI Life Insurance Co Ltd will launch an initial public offering next week to raise as much as $1.3 billion, sources with direct knowledge told Reuters, in what will be the country&amp;rsquo;s first billion-dollar IPO in nearly seven years.
SBI Life, a subsidiary of top Indian lender State Bank of India, will open the IPO sale to the public on September 20 and close it on September 22, according to a filing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to replace your mobile with Google Pixel for free? Find out if you are eligible</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/google-pixel-xl-nexus-6p-pixel-2-pixel-xl-2-replace-warranty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/google-pixel-xl-nexus-6p-pixel-2-pixel-xl-2-replace-warranty/</guid>
      <description>Google has announced that it will replace defective Nexus 6P smartphones with the new Pixel devices. Users of the Nexus phones will have to get rid of the 2-year-old smartphone and accept the 2016’s Google Pixel XL. This is a part of the tech giant’s warranty policy. While most companies usually replace your problematic phones with new ones, Google is replacing the brand itself. According to latest reports, the Mountain View company will offer Nexus users to replace their phones with the Pixel XL handsets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things that are banned for you, from opening a bank account to processing of I-T returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</guid>
      <description>If you thought that filing an income tax return or opening a bank account are the only few things which require Aadhaar cards now, then think again. The fact is Aadhaar has now been made mandatory for so many things, including availing the benefits of various social and government schemes. While for some schemes it has already been made compulsory, for some others it will be made mandatory soon.
Here we are taking a look at 10 such things:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>