<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>270 GB Data For Rs. 333: BSNL&#39;s New Plan To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/270-gb-data-for-rs-333-bsnls-new-plan-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs. 333, Rs. 339, Rs. 349 and Rs. 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL or Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited has announced three new data plans priced from Rs 333, the latest offering from the telecom operator seen as aimed at Jio&amp;rsquo;s Dhan Dhana Dhan plans. BSNL is offering up to 270 GB of 3G mobile data along with unlimited voice calls for a period of 90 days. BSNL&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triple ACE STV or special tariff voucher priced at Rs 333 includes 3 GB per day of unlimited data, beyond which the speed will be reduced to 80 Kbps, the operator said. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive pricing is causing intense competition in Indian telecom industry, forcing incumbent operators to offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attractive mobile data and unlimited voice calls plans, according to analysts. BSNL has also revised its existing Rs 339 plan, which now includes 3 GB of data per day, instead of 2 GB earlier, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the other offerings by BSNL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 349&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dil Khol Ke Bol&amp;rdquo; special tariff voucher priced at Rs 349 comes with a validity of 28 days and includes 2 GB of data per day at 3G speed. Other benefits in the Rs 349 pack include unlimited local and STD calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rs 395&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nehle pe Dehla&amp;rdquo; pack includes with 2GB daily data at 3G speed for Rs. 395 for 71 days. The Rs 395 recharge pack also includes 3,000 minutes of calls on its network and 1,800 minutes of on other networks, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s revised Rs 339 pack, valid for 28 days, also includes unlimited local and inter-circle BSNL-to-BSNL calls. Calls to other networks are allowed with a limit of 25 minutes per day, beyond which BSNL customers will be charged at 25 paise per minute, BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unlimited data at high speed in all of BSNL&amp;rsquo;s Rs 333, Rs 339, Rs 349 and Rs 395 packs will be reduced to 80 Kbps per second under its fair usage policy, BSNL added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BSNL had earlier launched yearly packs starting from Rs 1,498 and going up to Rs 4,498, which include 18 GB and 80 GB of data for 365 days, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 GB Free Data: Vodafone&#39;s Latest Offer In Response To Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/9-gb-free-data-vodafones-latest-offer-in-response-to-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September, incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Vodafone is also currently offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone is giving &lt;em&gt;9 GB data&lt;/em&gt; free to customers in a special scheme, its latest offer to counter Reliance Jio which has come up with aggressive tariff plans. &amp;ldquo;Thank you for making us a 200 million strong family! As a token of appreciation, we are happy to delight you with free data on your Vodafone mobile,&amp;rdquo; Vodafone said. A Vodafone customer care executive said the 9 GB free data offer has been made to select customers. The 9 GB free data will be applicable &lt;em&gt;at 3 GB/month&lt;/em&gt; for three billing cycles. Vodafone said this 9GB offer is in addition to &amp;ldquo;existing data quota on your plan/pack at no extra cost&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s launch in September,&lt;/em&gt; incumbent operators have been coming up with aggressive plans to lure new customers. Currently, Vodafone is also offering 4 GB data in some circles on upgrade to 4G SIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New entrant Reliance Jio has kept the pressure on other operators to cut tariffs and make special offers to customers. Jio&amp;rsquo;s current &amp;ldquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rdquo; plans offer &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; data under recharge packs starting from Rs. 309.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Vodafone said that it will offer free incoming calls during international roaming on its network in 45 countries at a daily rental of Rs. 500 along with all international and local outgoing calls for Rs. 1 a minute. In the countries where Vodafone operates, the customer will get 1 megabyte of mobile internet for Rs. 1 which implies 1 GB of data will cost them Rs. 1,024. &amp;ldquo;Keeping in mind the requirements of international travelers, Vodafone had recently introduced the i-RoamFREE proposition offering free incoming calls, Re 1 for all international and local outgoing calls and data at Re 1 per MB in over 45 countries on a daily basis,&amp;rdquo; Vodafone said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price war for data subscribers has dented the bottom lines of wireless telecom service providers, yet none of them is likely to pull a punch, Crisil said in a report. If anything, competition will only heat up further given that market leadership is all-crucial to the business, it said. The proposed merger between Idea and Vodafone - which marks the biggest consolidation in the Indian telecom sector - is also part of this quest to strengthen market position, alongside lowering investment needs and costs, Crisil added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar based lic policies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-launches-two-aadhaar-based-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lic-launches-two-aadhaar-based-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life insurance behemoth LIC has introduced two endowment assurance plans for individuals having Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the _Aadhaar Shila _is a plan exclusively designed for women, the other scheme &lt;em&gt;Aadhaar Stambh&lt;/em&gt; is meant for men. Absolute amount assured on death under Aadhaar Stambh is 100%, whereas for Aadhaar Shila it is 110% of basic sum assured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These plans offer a combination of protection and savings and provide a lump-sum amount at the time of maturity for the surviving policyholder and financial support for the family in case of death of the policyholder, a Corporation statement said today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maturity benefit under both the plans will be the sum assured with loyalty additions if any, it added. Total basic sum assured under all policies issued to an individual under this plan shall not exceed Rs 3 lakh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This plan is available to standard healthy lives from age 8-55 years, without any medical examination. The maximum age of maturity is 70 years and the terms available are from 10 to 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of death during first five years, the sum assured on death shall be payable. However, in case of death after completion of five policy years but before the date of maturity, the sum assured on death and loyalty addition, if any, shall be payable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sum assured on death is defined as the highest of 10 times of annualised premium or the absolute amount assured to be paid on death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebate on tabular premium at 2% for year mode and 1% on half-yearly mode is available while quarterly, monthly (through NACH), salary deductions are other modes available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An optional benefit of accident benefit rider is available by payment of additional premium. Loyalty addition is payable on certain conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, these plans also take care of liquidity needs through auto cover as well as loan facility. PTI KD BEN NRB&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM-Aadhaar App Revamped. Here&#39;s What Is New</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-aadhaar-app-revamped-heres-what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the latest version of BHIM e-wallet app on Friday, as the government aggressively pursues a &amp;ldquo;less-cash&amp;rdquo; economy to combat the problem of black money and digitise the economy. Promoting the latest version BHIM 1.3, on the 126th birth anniversary of Dr Bhimrao R. Ambedkar, PM Modi said that the BHIM-Aadhaar platform would play the same role of empowering the common Indian as the Constitution of India, framed by Dr Ambedkar. To further incentivize Indians to make the switch to using the BHIM app for transacting business, PM Modi also launched two schemes - cash back for merchants and referral bonus for individual owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Are Some Of The Key Features Of BHIM:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BHIM, short for Bharat Interface for Money, enables its users to transfer money using their mobile phone. The app created a world record by registering 10 million downloads in just four months since its launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new cashback scheme, the merchants will get a cashback on every transaction using BHIM. For every successful referral, users can earn Rs. 10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;PM Modi declared on Friday that incentives totalling Rs. 495 crore will be given to merchants for accepting payments through BHIM and existing users for referring it to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 2 MB in size, the latest version of the app enables payments through a fingerprint scanner by authenticating biometric details of the user against the Aadhaar database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is available in 12 languages with three new languages (Marathi, Punjabi and Assamese) added in BHIM 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, now allows users to transfer money to contacts saved on the phone. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a cap of Rs. 10,000 for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present account holders of around 30 banks can transact on BHIM 1.3. The app will add Punjab And Maharashtra Co-Operative Bank Ltd, Punjab &amp;amp; Sind Bank and Jammu and Kashmir Bank soon, according to its Google Play Store page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the United Payments Interface (UPI), BHIM users do not need to download mobile applications of multiple banks to transact with different banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the government&amp;rsquo;s move on November 8 last year to demonetise Rs. 500 and Rs. 1,000 currency notes, the number of digital payment apps have logged a nearly 23-fold increase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed by National Payments Corporation of India, BHIM aims pave the way for making payments using fingerprints or iris scanners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Minimum Balance: How Much Fine You Have To Pay</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-minimum-balance-how-much-fine-you-have-to-pay/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;SBI or State Bank of India is charging a fine on savings bank account customers not meeting the average monthly balance requirement. The amount of penalty for non-compliance with monthly average balance or MAB requirement is based on customer location - such as metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was said by India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI on Twitter while specifying various ranges according to which it will levy the charges. Charges levied for not maintaining the minimum balance depend upon how much the average balance in the account is below the agreed minimum, said SBI, which has&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;introduced minimum balance requirement in savings accounts from April 1. SBI also unveiled a new identity after merging its operations with six other banks recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is minimum balance requirement?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI savings bank account customers need to maintain a monthly average balance or MAB, which is the average of daily balances in the account during the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When do SBI savings bank account customers pay this charge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing to maintain the monthly balance as specified by the bank will attract a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What to do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A regular review of your account will help you to ensure the average monthly balance is maintained and avoid the minimal charges,&amp;rdquo; State Bank of India (SBI) said in another tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much fine do I need to pay?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking behemoth SBI has divided its customers into four categories: metro, urban, semi-urban and rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For metro customers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI requires its savings bank account customers in metros to maintain a monthly average balance of Rs 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case the monthly average balance of an SBI savings bank account holder comes out to be between Rs 2,500 and Rs 5,000 - a shortfall of less than 50 per cent, a charge of Rs 50 plus service tax will be levied, SBI said. For those with a shortfall of between 50 and 75 per cent (MAB from Rs 1,250 to Rs 2,500), a fee of Rs 75 plus service tax will be charged, and Rs 100 plus service tax for those keeping an average less than Rs 749 (more than 75 per cent shortfall).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-semi-urban-customers&#34;&gt;For semi-urban customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-rural-customers&#34;&gt;For rural customers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Shortfall&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SBI charges plus service tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Over 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Till 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rs 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/sbi-minimum.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The charges have been permitted by the Reserve Bank of India and are being levied by banks across the industry &amp;ldquo;and help us in providing better services to the customers&amp;rdquo;, SBI added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides savings bank accounts, SBI offers some other accounts wherein customers are not required to maintain a minimum balance. SBI&amp;rsquo;s small savings bank account and basic savings account are two such products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After its merger with five associate banks and Bharatiya Mahila Bank, SBI has entered the league of top 50 global banks with a balance sheet size of Rs. 41 lakh crore, 2.77 lakh employees, 50 crore customers, over 22,500 branches and 58,000 ATMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your PAN card could become invalid from July 1: Here&#39;s why</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/invalid-pancard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/invalid-pancard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of applications submitted for correction of names in Permanent Account Number (PAN) cards have seen a significant jump in recent weeks. This is because the government has set a deadline of July 1, 2017, to link one&amp;rsquo;s PAN with his/her Aadhaar number. But people who do not have a consistent style of spelling their names are facing problems in linking their PAN cards with Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kamala Radhakrishnan, Vice President (Business Development) at CAMS, empanelled by the National Securities Depository Ltd (NSDL) for PAN applications, says, &amp;ldquo;We understand there is a significant increase in requests for correction of names in PAN cards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way out for such people is to either correct the details in their PAN cards or get the changes done in their Aadhaar cards. You can also apply for it online by uploading the requisite documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amit Maheshwari, Partner at Ashok Maheshwary &amp;amp; Associates LLP, says, &amp;ldquo;If the details in PAN are incorrect, the person is advised to submit a PAN correction form at the designated centres of NSDL with necessary evidences. Similarly, if the details in Aadhaar are to be corrected, the person should visit the designated centres with necessary evidences to get it rectified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-Resident Indians (NRIs), however, are exempted from quoting Aadhaar numbers while filing income-tax returns back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not link your PAN card with the Aadhaar card within the stipulated time, it may lead to invalidation of your PAN card. If that happens, you will not be able to file your return this year as quoting both PAN and Aadhaar numbers has been made mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar is a 12-digit number code, issued by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI). It is used to establish a person&amp;rsquo;s identity on the basis of demographic and biometric information. The Permanent Account Number or PAN is a 10-digit alphanumeric number issued by the Income-Tax Department for tracking your financial transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the latest data available, there are more than 24.37 crore PAN registered in the country while Aadhaar cards have been issued to 113 crore people. However, only 2.87 crore individuals filed income-tax returns in the assessment year 2012-2013, out of which 1.62 crore did not pay any tax, leaving the number of taxpayers at just one per cent of the country&amp;rsquo;s total population. Due to such a low number of tax payers in the country, the government intends to catch tax evaders with the linkage of PAN cards with Aadhaar cards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>70 GB 4G Data At Rs 244, Rs 399: Airtel&#39;s New Plans To Counter Jio &#39;Dhan Dhana Dhan&#39;</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-gb-4g-data-at-rs-244-rs-399-airtels-new-plans-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/70-gb-4g-data-at-rs-244-rs-399-airtels-new-plans-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After withdrawing the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, Jio has come up with Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plans offering unlimited data, SMS and voice calling for three months.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bharti-airtel-650_650x400_81492158840.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With the tariff war getting brutal in the telecom space, India&amp;rsquo;s biggest operator Airtel has come up with aggressive new prepaid plans to counter Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s latest &amp;lsquo;Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; offer. Under Rs 244 plan, Airtel is offering unlimited local and STD calls on Airtel network and 1 GB/day for 70 days. Under the Rs 399 plan, Airtel is offering free local and STD calls on any network as well as 1 GB/day data for 70 days. Under the Rs 345 plan, Airtel is offering unlimited call and 2GB data/day for 28 days. A check on Airtel&amp;rsquo;s website showed these new plans are available for subscription on prepaid numbers through online payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After withdrawing the &amp;lsquo;Summer Surprise&amp;rsquo; offer, Jio has come up with Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plans offering unlimited data, SMS and voice calling for three months. Starting Rs 309, &amp;lsquo;Jio Dhan Dhana Dhan&amp;rsquo; plan offers 1 GB data per day for a period of 84 days. Also, with a recharge of Rs 509, users will get 2 GB data per day for 84 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s aggressive entry into the telecom space has led to a drop in tariffs as the competition gets intense. The revenue of telecom sector from consumer services like mobile telephony and data dipped 10.5 per cent to Rs 37,284 crore in the October-December period over the previous three months, according to regulator Trai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aggressive offerings from telecom operators have led higher data usage. Two out of three consumers in India want to switch to a new phone within the next 12 months, a report by Counterpoint Research said. &amp;ldquo;As per the survey, two in three users plan to upgrade to a new mobile phone in the next 12 months. This is a departure from an average of 24-30 months to under 20 months upgrade cycle,&amp;rdquo; the report said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Accounts To Be Blocked If Not Self-Certified By April 30. What To Do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-accounts-to-be-blocked-if-not-self-certified-by-april-30-what-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank accounts opened between July 1, 2014 and August 31, 2015 need to submit self-certification by April 30 to comply with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) provisions, without which the accounts would be blocked, the income tax department said. &amp;ldquo;The account holders may be informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till April 30, 2017, the accounts would be blocked, which would mean that the financial institution would prohibit the account holder from effecting any transaction with respect to such accounts,&amp;rdquo; the Central Board of Direct Taxes or CBDT said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Account holders are informed that, in case self-certifications are not provided till 30.4.2017,A/Cs would be blocked : pic.twitter.com/YICvRHqfPm
— Income Tax India (@IncomeTaxIndia) April 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) FATCA allows automatic exchange of financial information between India and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) India had entered into an agreement with the United States for implementation of the Foreign Accounts Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) with effect from August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Investors are required to provide details such as country of tax residence, tax identification number from such country, country of birth, country of citizenship etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) If the accounts are blocked due to lack of self-certification, then transactions by the account holder in such blocked accounts will be permitted once the self-certification is obtained and due diligence is completed, the tax department said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Earlier, the financial institutions had to obtain self-certification from account holders by August 31, 2016, in respect of all individual and entity accounts opened from July 1, 2014-August 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Mutual funds and other financial institutions had also asked customers to comply with the new norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In view of the difficulties faced by stakeholders, the tax department had on August 31, 2016, extended the deadline for complying with self-certification norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) The financial institutions were advised to continue to work on completing the required due diligence, including obtaining self-certifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) The purpose of FATCA is aimed at ensuring that individuals pay tax on income generated from their wealth parked overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) FATCA obliges such banks and financial institutions to report such information about citizens having accounts with them. (With agency inputs)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Loan Or Credit Card Loan: Which One To Go For?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bank-loan-or-credit-card-loan-which-one-to-go-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a phone call and money gets credited to your account within 2-3 days. Yes, it is this simple today to get credit card loans. Though credit card loans are easier to get, they come at a higher cost than personal loans from banks. So you need to know clearly when to take a credit card loan or a personal loan. Even if the credit card company charges you the same rate of interest as that of personal loan, the cost for servicing credit card loan is higher. Along with processing fees and pre-closure charges, credit card companies also charge service tax on the interest you pay on your loan every month, which is 15 per cent currently (service tax@14%+ Swach Bharat Cess@ 0.5%+ Krishi Klyan Cess @ 0 .5%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if costs like interest rate, pre-closure charges and loan processing fees remain the same for credit card loan and bank personal loan, interest cost of credit card loan become 15 per cent more because of service tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you take a personal loan of Rs 1 lakh from a bank at 14 per cent interest for 24 months, then your first month instalment will be Rs 4,802, in which interest component will be Rs 1,166.66 and principal repayment will be Rs 3635.33. If you take the same loan on your credit card at the same interest rate, in the first month you have to pay Rs 4,976.99 which is Rs 175 more than what you pay on a bank loan. This is because of the service tax of Rs 175 on interest of Rs 1,166.66. This service tax is also applicable when you convert your purchases on credit card to equated monthly instalment (EMI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are some instances, where credit card loans are preferred over bank personal loans. If the amount you are opting for is less (less than Rs 50,000) and the tenure you want is less than 1 year, then credit card loans become more useful (even with higher cost) because banks generally do not offer personal loans below Rs 50,000 and for less than one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit cards even offer loans even for six months and for small amounts as low as Rs 10,000. If your requirement for funds is for a short term and you think you can repay it faster, then it is worth going for a credit card loan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Get Time Till June 30 To Obtain PAN From Account Holders</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-get-time-till-june-30-to-obtain-pan-from-account-holders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department has given banks three more months till June 30 to obtain permanent account number (PAN) or Form-60 from all account holders as it looks to tighten the noose around evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the deadline for getting the PAN or Form 60 (if PAN is not available) by banks ended on February 28, the tax department on April 5 notified the extension of the time till June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the notification, the Income Tax Department said that in Income-Tax Rules 114B, in the fourth proviso, &amp;ldquo;for the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;28th day of February&amp;rsquo; the figures, letters and words &amp;lsquo;30th day of June&amp;rsquo; shall be substituted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 114B lists various transactions for which quoting PAN is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax department had in January asked banks, post offices and cooperative banks to document PAN or declaration of Form 60 received from account holders and maintain all records for transactions under Rule 114B of I-T Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had said that persons who have not quoted PAN, or did not furnish Form 60 at the time of opening account, will have to provide the same by February 28. Form 60 is a declaration form filed by an individual without PAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the demonetisation move effective November 9, the tax department had asked banks and post offices to report to it all deposits above Rs 2.5 lakh in savings accounts and more than Rs 12.50 lakh in current accounts made between November 10 and December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, cash deposits exceeding Rs 50,000 in a single day had to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an estimated Rs 15 lakh crore in junked currency notes coming back into the banking system post demonetisation, the tax department has started analysing the bank deposit trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Rs 11 To Rs 509: Jio Recharges Explained</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/from-rs-11-to-rs-509-jio-recharges-explained/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, according to its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering a variety of recharge options to members of its paid Prime service. Jio, or Reliance Jio Infocomm, the telecom arm of billionaire Mukesh Ambani-led Reliance Industries, has also launched benefits like multi-fold data and validity under &amp;ldquo;all unlimited three months&amp;rdquo; schemes on first recharges of Rs 309 and Rs 509. Jio last week announced &amp;ldquo;all unlimited plans with special benefits&amp;rdquo; priced at Rs 309 and Rs 509, putting an end to complimentary service plans under its Summer Surprise offer on telecom regulator TRAI&amp;rsquo;s advice. Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime service offers &amp;ldquo;truly free&amp;rdquo; voice, &amp;ldquo;no charge towards voice or the data used to make 4G voice calls&amp;rdquo;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-s-what-you-get-under-various-jio-recharges-starting-from-rs-11&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you get under various Jio recharges, starting from Rs 11:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio is offering several add-on recharges, or &amp;ldquo;boosters&amp;rdquo;, that work on the base plan&amp;rsquo;s existing validity, in case you reach the maximum 4G data limit before expiry of your active 4G plan: Rs 11, Rs 51, Rs 91, Rs 201 and Rs 301. These packs enable a Jio customer to continue using data in high speed (4G) in case he or she reaches 4G data threshold before expiry of validity on the active plan. The smallest Rs 11 recharge under this category comes with 0.1 GB of 4G data, followed by Rs 51 (1 GB), Rs 91 (2 GB), Rs 201 (5 GB) and Rs 301 (10 GB), as per the Jio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-149-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 149 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides free calls - local, STD and roaming - to all networks, Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 149 plan includes 2GB of 4G data and comes with a validity of 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-309-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 309 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;most affordable&amp;rdquo; Rs 309 recharge, which comes with the first recharge benefit - wherein Jio users making their first recharge of Rs 309 get 1GB data per day for a period of 84 days, instead of 28 days. At subsequent recharges of Rs 309, Jio users get 1GB of 4G data per day for 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rs-509-recharge&#34;&gt;Rs 509 Recharge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio&amp;rsquo;s this recharge pack also offers the first recharge benefit. Prime members making their first Rs 509 recharge get 2GB of 4G data per day for 84 days. The 84-day validity is reduced to 28 days on subsequent Rs 509 recharges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much You Pay For Petrol, Diesel Could Change Every Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-you-pay-for-petrol-diesel-could-change-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-much-you-pay-for-petrol-diesel-could-change-every-day/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;State-run oil marketing companies, which control over 90 per cent of the retail fuel market in the country, are mulling a plan that would allow daily changes in the price of petrol and diesel, Economic Times reported on Friday. State-owned Indian Oil Corporation and its two smaller peers Bharat Petroleum and Hindustan Petroleum are considering ways to roll out the plan to review petrol and diesel prices daily, executives from the firms told the daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Petrol, diesel prices depend on global oil prices and rupee rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently, petrol and diesel prices are revised on a fortnightly basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This could change into daily revision of fuel prices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state-run companies declined to immediately comment. The daily price change - also called dynamic fuel pricing - essentially means the companies will not wait for a fortnight to adjust the price of petrol and diesel in tandem with crude price as they do now. Instead, they will change the price every day based on crude price movements. This will help India move to an international standard of fuel pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This will cushion the companies from any loss they face due to currency and crude movements over a 15-day period and will make their margins more predictable,&amp;rdquo; said Dhaval Joshi, analyst with Emkay Global Financial Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move would free private players - Essar Oil and Reliance Industries - which currently follow the price set by state-owned companies, to also shift to a dynamic model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost your Aadhaar card? Follow these simple steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar Card</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/lost-aadhaar-card-follow-simple-steps-get-duplicate-aadhaar-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes when their important documents are lost or misplaced. One such crucial document is the Aadhaar Card as the 12-digit unique identity number has become a matter of necessity for various purposes. The Narendra Modi government is completely committed to making Aadhaar the most potent identification instrument for Indian citizen. In a bid to make Aadhaar Card the single identity proof, the government has made all efforts to make sure that the Aadhaar number is linked to bank accounts and tax payments. Today, the Aadhaar card has become one of the vital documents to live in India, it has become a basic necessity and its need is increasing with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person can apply for a duplicate Aadhaar card if he/she has lost or misplaced it. In case you do not know or are unsure of your Aadhaar number, or if you have lost or misplaced your acknowledgement slip that you acquired at the time of registration, then you can download a duplicate copy of your Aadhaar card by visiting the UIDAI’s website www.uidai.gov.in . The UIDAI has made it possible for all residents to acquire a duplicate card through a simple procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the following steps to get a duplicate Aadhaar card if have misplaced your Aadhaar card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/uid-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&#34;&gt;https://resident.uidai.net.in/find-uid-eid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate option, ‘Aadhaar No (UID)’ OR ‘Enrolment No (EID)’, under ‘You want to receive your lost’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your full name, your email address and your registered Mobile Number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the security code as displayed and click on “Get OTP” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After this, One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the box below, enter the OTP you just received on your mobile and/or email address and then click on “Verify OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person will receive a message on your mobile with your Aadhaar card number or Enrollment Id as you selected in Step 2 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&#34;&gt;https://eaadhaar.uidai.gov.in/&lt;/a&gt; and select appropriate option, “Enrollment Id” OR “Aadhaar”, under “I have:”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your AADHAR card number or Enrollment Id, full name, Pin Code, security text and mobile number and then click on “Get OTP”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Time Password (OTP) will be delivered to your mobile and/or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the OTP you just received on your mobile in the “Enter OTP” box and click on “Validate and Download”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you have downloaded your e-Aadhar card. Enter your Pin Code as the password when you open the PDF document and there you have your e-AADHAR card, which you can print out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the procedure is over, you can now download E-Aadhaar card which will serve as the duplicate Aadhaar card which will be equally helpful. Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley recently said in the Lok Sabha said that efforts are being made to make Aadhaar the only card required to identify a person, replacing Voter ID and PAN. “The unique identification number Aadhaar may become the single identity card in future”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No card? Aadhaar, fingerprints will do</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-card-aadhaar-fingerprints-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitisation, the most common word in circulation these days after demonetisation, is what Arun Jaitley is betting on to drive the triad of transparency, tax compliance and ease of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finance minister also sought to turbo-charge the government’s objective of maximising cashless transactions with institutional support that included waiving all duties on point-of-sale (PoS) machines and biometric readers, improving rural digital infrastructure, tax breaks, cash incentives and easier loans based on digital transactions history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring about structural reforms, a Payments Regulatory Board will be created in the Reserve Bank of India. The governor and deputy governor of RBI will be on this Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sops have been lined up too. The government has announced a ‘referral bonus scheme’ for individuals and a cashback scheme for merchants who use the Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the tax front, the Budget encourages small businesses (with turnover up to Rs 2 crore) by reducing presumptive income tax to 6% on non-cash receipts against 8% at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of digital transaction is on rural and semi-urban areas through post offices, fair price shops and banking correspondents. Petrol pumps, fertilizer depots, municipalities, block offices, road transport offices, universities, colleges, hospitals and other institutions will also be encouraged, and possibly rule-bound at some point of time, to have facilities for digital payments. “A proposal to mandate all government receipts through digital means, beyond a prescribed limit, is under consideration,” Jaitley said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small Industries Development Bank of India (SIDBI) will be encouraged to refinance credit institutions that provide unsecured loans, at reasonable interest rates, to borrowers based on their electronic payment transaction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In my opinion, initiatives like cutting excise duty on manufacturing of payment devices and a Payment Regulatory Board will further boost India’s digital economy,” said Sanjay Rishi, regional president, American Express.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Himanshu Pujara, managing director, Euronet Services India said the measures would allow people in rural areas, those “beyond the 15% data-enabled smartphone users and mobile subscribers across the country” to become a part of the digital payments ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, You Can Get A PAN Or TAN Within A Day</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-you-can-get-a-pan-or-tan-within-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax department today said it has issued Permanent Account Number (PAN) within a day to 19,704 newly incorporated companies till March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to physical PAN card, CBDT has introduced the Electronic PAN (e-PAN) card, which is sent by email to all applicants, including individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Applicant would be benefited by having a digitally signed E-PAN card which they can submit as proof of identity to other agency electronically directly or by storing in the Digital Locker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;https://digilocker.gov.in),&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; CBDT, the apex policy making body of the Income Tax department, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said that newly incorporated companies have also been issued Tax Deduction Account Number (TAN) simultaneously with PAN as the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) has tied up with the Ministry of Corporate Affairs (MCA) under which companies can submit a common application form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicant companies submit a common application form SPICe (INC 32) on MCA portal and once the data of incorporation is sent to CBDT by the MCA, PAN and TAN are issued immediately without any further intervention of the applicant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Certificate of Incorporation (COI) of newly incorporated companies includes the PAN in addition to the Corporate Identity Number (CIN). TAN is also allotted simultaneously and communicated to the company,&amp;rdquo; the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till March 31, 2017, 19,704 newly incorporated companies were allotted PAN in this manner. During March 2017, of the 10,894 newly incorporated companies, PAN was allotted within 4 hours in 95.63 per cent cases and within one day in all cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, TAN was allotted to all such companies within 4 hrs in 94.7 per cent cases and within 1 day in 99.73 per cent cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;CBDT&amp;rsquo;s initiative in starting of a business is expected to significantly improve the ranking of India in the Ease of Doing Business Study conducted by World Bank by reducing the number of processes of registration before various authorities under law, reducing the time taken for allotment of the registration number (CIN, PAN, TAN) and making the entire registration process for new companies much simpler,&amp;rdquo; it said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>