<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Payment on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Payment on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/digital-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things that are banned for you, from opening a bank account to processing of I-T returns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-aadhaar-card-here-are-10-things-that-are-banned-for-you-from-opening-a-bank-account-to-processing-of-i-t-returns/</guid>
      <description>If you thought that filing an income tax return or opening a bank account are the only few things which require Aadhaar cards now, then think again. The fact is Aadhaar has now been made mandatory for so many things, including availing the benefits of various social and government schemes. While for some schemes it has already been made compulsory, for some others it will be made mandatory soon.
Here we are taking a look at 10 such things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Link Your Mobile Number (SIM) With Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-mobile-number-sim-with-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-your-mobile-number-sim-with-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The government has made it mandatory to link your Aadhaar number to your bank account and your PAN card. The 12-digit biometric ID is now not only necessary to avail schemes but also in financial matters like bank accounts and filing taxes. Even mobile phone service users will now have to verify using Aadhaar numbers. According to the news agency Press Trust of India (PTI), the government is moving ahead with linking Aadhaar with mobile SIM cards and all unlinked phones will be deactivated after February 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Numbers Not Linked To Aadhaar To Be Deactivated After February: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sim-cards-not-linked-to-aadhaar-to-be-deactivated-after-february-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sim-cards-not-linked-to-aadhaar-to-be-deactivated-after-february-report/</guid>
      <description>The government is moving ahead with linking Aadhaar with mobile SIM cards and all unlinked phones will be deactivated after February 2018, said informed sources. Sources told news agency IANS that linking of Aadhaar with mobile is being done as per the orders of Supreme Court passed in February this year in Lokniti foundation case and all SIM cards have to be verified with Aadhaar within a year from the date of judgement, with all unlinked phones to be deactivated after February next year, so criminals, fraudsters and terrorists cannot use the issued SIMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only 5 Free ATM Transactions From October, Punjab National Bank Says</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-free-atm-transactions-from-october-punjab-national-bank-says/</guid>
      <description>PNB customers will have to shell out money beginning October if they carry out more than five transactions a month from the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs. At present, account holders of the country&amp;rsquo;s second largest public sector bank can make any number of transactions in a month, financial or non-financial, at the bank&amp;rsquo;s ATMs without attracting any charge.
&amp;ldquo;The number of free transactions and the charges beyond these free transactions for PNB customers on PNB ATMs have been revised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>link your Aadhaar number with your bank account</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-aadhaar-bank-account-linking-last-date-check-it-in-3-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-link-aadhaar-bank-account-linking-last-date-check-it-in-3-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Have you recently got a message from your bank asking you to link your Aadhaar number with your bank account? This is most likely in cases where someone has still not linked one’s Aadhaar number to one’s bank account or the bank has failed to do so for some reasons.
For instance, the message from a leading bank says, “Dear Customer, as per a Government of India mandate (under Prevention of Money Laundering Rules, 2005), all bank accounts must be linked with Aadhaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>link your SBI account to Aadhaar via ATMs and SMS: Here’s how to do it in easy steps</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-link-aadhaar-card-online-via-atm-sms-state-bank-of-india-heres-how-to-do-it-in-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-account-link-aadhaar-card-online-via-atm-sms-state-bank-of-india-heres-how-to-do-it-in-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Are you a State Bank of India customer and want to link your Aadhaar number to your SBI account? Or have got a message from the bank to do so? Here’s some good news for you. SBI allows its customers to link their bank accounts to their Aadhaar number in various ways, including their ATM channel and through SMS. You can also get it done by visiting any of their branches or through Internet banking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar data hack: IIT Kharagpur graduate arrested, earns Rs 40 lakh a year at Ola</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-data-hack-iit-kharagpur-graduate-arrested-earns/</guid>
      <description>An IIT Kharagpur graduate, Abhinav Srivastava, who allegedly hacked Aadhaar data has been arrested by Bengaluru Police. According to investigation, Srivastava had gained access to the repository of the Unique Identification Development Authority of India’s (UIDAI) Aadhaar project through the Digital India e-hospital portal. The 31-year-old hails from Uttar Pradesh and was arrested in connection with a complaint filed by the UIDAI on July 26, according to Indian Express.
Police said the complaint against Srivastava stated that he accessed UIDAI data without authorisation between January 1 and July 26 for an app called ‘eKYC Verification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 smart tips which can help you save more &amp; become rich</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/7-smart-tips-which-can-help-you-save-more-become-rich/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t want to become rich? However, getting wealthy isn’t that easy. It begins with determined consciousness to get wealthy. We all know that to become rich you need to spend less than what you earn. That is because the less you spend, the more you will be able to save. You should save and invest what you have into investments (assets) that appreciate over time. Apart from these, here we are taking a look at a few really easy and ‘anyone can do it’ strategies or DIY tips that can make you a crorepati:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt makes Aadhaar mandatory for students</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-mandatory-students/</guid>
      <description>The move is aimed at checking the drop-out rate and ensuring quality education
The Yogi Adityanath government in Uttar Pradesh has made Aadhaar Card mandatory for students from Class 1 to 8 in government schools. The Basic Education department has been entrusted with this task involving over 1.75 crore students.
The Basic Education Minister Anupama Jaiswal said that directions have been issued in this regard. “The main aim of the government is to link their Aadhaar Card number with different welfare schemes, including mid-day meal, run by the state for the welfare of primary students,” she said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar with PAN using SMS: I-T department</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-with-pan-using-sms/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department today urged taxpayers to link their Aadhaar with their PAN, using an SMS-based facility.
The department issued advertisements in leading national dailies and described how both the unique identity numbers of an individual can be linked by sending an SMS to either 567678 or 56161.
It said people can also visit the official efiling website of the department to link the two identities, in both the cases&amp;ndash; identical names in the two databases or in case where there is a minor mismatch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>