<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/e-kyc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/e-kyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar e-verification raises security concerns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-e-verification-raises-security-concerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-e-verification-raises-security-concerns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than 111 crore users have registered for Aadhaar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aadhaar e-KYC or e-verification for commercial purposes is a cause of worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar has been hitting headlines more often than before. With more services making Aadhaar mandatory, e-KYC or e-verification has been raising several questions. the most important one – is our Aadhaar data safe? This becomes worrisome as the government plans to introduce Aadhaar Pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several companies now require your Aadhaar details as mandatory documents for issuing services. For instance, Reliance Jio users had to submit their Aadhaar card copy to get their hands on the SIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When issuing Aadhaar cards, the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) had assured that the private data collected from citizens will not be used for any commercial purposes. However, a report in Deccan Chronicle points out that a few MNCs have started using the data for e-KYC verification aka e-verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such user told the news site that when purchasing a SIM card, he was asked to give Aadhaar card details for e-verification. He soon received an email that said his Aadhaar number was used successfully for authentication using the ‘fingerprint. This is a cause of worry as many users have linked their bank accounts and almost all financial dealings with the Aadhaar card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has raised questions about the security of the data that the Central government has collected, which includes fingerprints and iris scans. There is no clarity over why it is being used for commercial purpose and who will be responsible if it is misused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Several start-ups, MNCs and telecom operators are using the Aadhaar database in the city for various purposes. There is no clarity on who will be responsible if any one misuses the data,” an officer told the news site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently saw how Aadhaar Pay comes with its fair share of problems.For instance, there is no clarity over the legal status over if a person/organisation can store someone’s biometric data without their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With biometric failure, cyber security concerns and so on, the data could be further vulnerable if used for commercial purposes by telecom operators and other companies. The digital push, Aadhaar and biometrics are a way forward, but we need clearly stated rules to ensure the data isn’t misused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI recommends Aadhaar-based e-KYC for existing mobile subscribers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-recommends-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-existing-mobile-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-recommends-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-existing-mobile-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aiming to reduce instances of SIM cards being issued against fake documents, the Indian telecom regulator has submitted its recommendations to the Department of Telecom (DoT), an official said on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“DoT may work with the TSPs (telecom service providers), to evolve a framework to verify the existing mobile subscribers through Aadhaar based e-KYC (know your customer) services in a phased manner and within a defined timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this process should be optional to the service providers as well as mobile subscribers,” the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) said in a statement here. “The subscribers may have to be given some sops in terms of free talk-time or data to encourage them to undergo the e-KYC process,” it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TRAI has received several cases from state police (crime branch) wherein it has been found that hundreds of SIM cards have been obtained on fake documents. The existence of such SIM cards poses a real security challenge, the TRAI said, adding that it is essential that not only the new subscribers are enrolled through e-KYC process. Further it also recommended the DoT that: “Aadhaar based e-KYC should be permitted for outstation customers also at any place within the service area.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI Registration Must For All Aadhaar Authentication Devices; TRAI Proposes Aadhaar e-KYC For Existing &amp; New Mobile Users</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-registration-must-aadhaar-authentication-devices-trai-proposes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-registration-must-aadhaar-authentication-devices-trai-proposes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two big news surfaced regarding the usage and implementation of Aadhaar based authentication. While one of them concerns protecting the privacy of all Aadhaar users, the second is related with Aadhaar based KYC process, for all mobile users. Existing and new, both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UIDAI Registration Now Must For All Aadhaar Authentication Devices&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The devices which use Aadhaar based authentication has access to literally millions of datasets, stored under the Aadhaar database. If any one of the devices is hacked, then it means sensitive data of millions of Indians are compromised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding this threat, Govt. of India has made UIDAI registration a must for all Aadhaar authentication devices – this includes mobile phones and other hardware devices as well, which are used for authenticating Aadhaar based data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ajay Bhushan Pandey, CEO of UIDAI said, “We are going to say that in India only registered devices will work (for Aadhaar authentication). If you want to use Aadhaar authentication then your devices will have to be registered with us,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A formal announcement would be soon made, and the process will take approximately 4-5 months. This decision will add another layer of protection to the devices which access Aadhaar data. Right now, only STQC (Standardisation Testing and Quality Certification) is required for such devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the question, how will it be done? As per reports, Govt. will make it mandatory to embed the Aadhaar encryption key right into the device when it is being manufactured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRAI Proposes Aadhaar e-KYC For All Mobile Users&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) has proposed to make Aadhaar based e-KYC (Know Your Customer) for all mobile users, whether they are new or existing. This means, Govt. now wants Aadhaar linked telecom users, after making the same mandatory for all bank customers last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports, TRAI is proposing some incentive based Aadhaar push, like offering free talk time for linking their Aadhaar cards with the telecom service provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a statement, TRAI has justified this move by saying that existing KYC process is not robust, and scamsters are taking advantage of the same. TRAI said, “The existing paper-based KYC is not robust enough and the possibility of a significant number of working SIMs, which may have been acquired on fake/forged identity, cannot be fully ruled out. The owner of such fake identity would not even be aware that SIMs are working in his/her name..”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their statement, TRAI has emphasized the fact such Aadhaar based e-KYC should be optional, and not mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>