<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>E Kyc on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/e-kyc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in E Kyc on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/e-kyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UIDAI Registration Must For All Aadhaar Authentication Devices; TRAI Proposes Aadhaar e-KYC For Existing &amp; New Mobile Users</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-registration-must-aadhaar-authentication-devices-trai-proposes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/uidai-registration-must-aadhaar-authentication-devices-trai-proposes/</guid>
      <description>Two big news surfaced regarding the usage and implementation of Aadhaar based authentication. While one of them concerns protecting the privacy of all Aadhaar users, the second is related with Aadhaar based KYC process, for all mobile users. Existing and new, both.
UIDAI Registration Now Must For All Aadhaar Authentication Devices
The devices which use Aadhaar based authentication has access to literally millions of datasets, stored under the Aadhaar database. If any one of the devices is hacked, then it means sensitive data of millions of Indians are compromised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar e-verification raises security concerns</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-e-verification-raises-security-concerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-e-verification-raises-security-concerns/</guid>
      <description>More than 111 crore users have registered for Aadhaar.
 Aadhaar e-KYC or e-verification for commercial purposes is a cause of worry.  Aadhaar has been hitting headlines more often than before. With more services making Aadhaar mandatory, e-KYC or e-verification has been raising several questions. the most important one – is our Aadhaar data safe? This becomes worrisome as the government plans to introduce Aadhaar Pay.
Several companies now require your Aadhaar details as mandatory documents for issuing services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI recommends Aadhaar-based e-KYC for existing mobile subscribers</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-recommends-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-existing-mobile-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/trai-recommends-aadhaar-based-e-kyc-existing-mobile-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>Aiming to reduce instances of SIM cards being issued against fake documents, the Indian telecom regulator has submitted its recommendations to the Department of Telecom (DoT), an official said on Monday.
“DoT may work with the TSPs (telecom service providers), to evolve a framework to verify the existing mobile subscribers through Aadhaar based e-KYC (know your customer) services in a phased manner and within a defined timeframe.
However, this process should be optional to the service providers as well as mobile subscribers,” the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) said in a statement here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>