<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/id-verification/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/id-verification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fingerprint-enabled Aadhaar Pay may soon become a reality in rural areas</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fingerprint-enabled-aadhaar-pay-may-soon-become-reality-rural-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/fingerprint-enabled-aadhaar-pay-may-soon-become-reality-rural-areas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make poor and illiterate in the rural areas adopt to digital payments, the government is now giving Aadhaar Pay a push as it will ensure financial transactions by just using fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aadhaar Pay is a merchant version of Aadhaar-enabled payment system(AEPS) and the government hopes that it will be an alternative for all online and card transactions which require password and PIN. It will facilitate merchants to take cashless payments from a customer as it will only require Aadhaar number, name of the bank (from where the money is to be deducted) and finger print for authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) CEO AB Pandey said Aadhaar Pay works on any android-based phone, even a low cost one, with an attached finger biometric device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This ensures digital transactions which are cardless, PINless … There is no need of smartphone for the customers,” he told ET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a move to make Aadhaar Pay popular, the government has asked banks to enrol 30-40 merchants per branch so that they are able to take cashless payments from customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present five banks – &lt;em&gt;Andhra Bank&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;IDFC Bank&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;IndusInd Bank&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;State Bank of India and Syndicate Bank&lt;/em&gt; – have gone live over Aadhaar Pay and several banks are in the process of launching pilots on the app.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ‘Aadhaar’ of survival in India, even if SC states otherwise</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-survival-india-even-sc-states-otherwise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-survival-india-even-sc-states-otherwise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court says the decision to sign up for an Aadhaar card is entirely up to citizens. But the reality is that the Aadhaar card has been pushed by the Centre and the Delhi government to such an extent that it is impossible to avail services without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disregarding the apex court order, the Centre over the past year has made it must for people to have an Aadhaar card to get LPG subsidy and for several other benefits and schemes. From toddlers to senior citizens, no one can do without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while elderly people can’t get concessions on railway tickets without the card, kids can’t hope to get admission in nursery. The Delhi government has made it mandatory for parents from Economic Weaker Section (EWS) to furnish Aadhaar card number and enrolment number in order to get admission.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Not Valid Proof of Citizenship</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-valid-proof-citizenship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-not-valid-proof-citizenship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;##FACTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Court was considering a bail plea of a person who was booked under Section 14F of the Indian Foreigners Act. The person claimed that she is an Indian Citizen that the issuance of the Aadhaar card was in view of long residence of the petitioner in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ISSUES BEFORE THE COURT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;new passport rules which were announced by Minister of State for External Affairs VK Singh on December 23 where Aadhaar and E-Aadhaar with Date of Birth will now be considered as a valid identity proof.( Aadhaar not valid proof of citizenship or domicile; News 18/ December 26 2016)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether a mere holding of an Aadhaar card grants citizenship to any person&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HELD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court contended Section 9 of the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and other subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act 2016, state that- “9. The Aadhaar number or the authentication thereof shall not, by itself, confer any right of, or be proof of, citizenship or domicile in respect of an Aadhaar number holder.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from this the petitioner also placed reliance of his claim of his citizenship on the residence certificate issued by a representative of a local body. The Court also did away with this claim by holding the letter issued by the representative of the local body as to the residence of the petitioner also does not, ipso facto, confer citizenship on the petitioner.( High Court denies Aadhaar as proof of citizenship/ Blog.scconline/Dec 28, 2016)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;LEARNING OUTCOME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New passport rules have been announced by the Minster of State for External Affairs, where Aadhaar and E-Aadhaar with date of birth is to be considered as a valid identity proof.Aadhaar has been made compulsory for various transaction post demonetization. Aadhaar has been made compulsory for Tirupati devotees who go to Tirumala hills on foot. Aadhaar is now also mandatory for patients at the Outpatient Department (OPD) at Civil hospital in Gurugram. (Aadhaar Card not valid proof of citizenship, rules Calcutta High Court; India.com/ Dec26, 2016) At the same time it has been made clear by the High Court of Calcutta that Aadhaar card shall not confer any right of or be proof of citizenship or domicile thereto while rejecting the claim of an accused who claimed to be an Indian citizen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre, States Reach Consensus On Control Over Tax Payers: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-states-reach-consensus-on-control-over-tax-payers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/centre-states-reach-consensus-on-control-over-tax-payers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The consensus was reached after the Centre agreed to the demand of states to go in for horizontal split with regard to tax payers based on annual turnover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a major breakthrough, the Centre and states today reached a consensus on sharing powers for control over tax payers under GST but the new indirect tax regime will now be rolled out from July 1 instead of previously planned April 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consensus was reached after the Centre agreed to the demand of states to go in for horizontal split with regard to tax payers based on annual turnover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the decision reached at the 9th meeting of all-powerful GST Council, states will have powers to assess and administer 90 per cent of the tax payers under Rs 1.5 crore annual turnover while the remaining would be controlled by the Centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For tax payers with more than Rs 1.5 crore turnover, states and the Centre will control and administer them in 50:50 ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, briefing reporters about the decisions taken at the meeting, said states would also have the powers to levy tax on economic activity within 12 nautical miles of territorial waters even though such rights Constitutionally vest with the Centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the power to levy and collect Integrated-GST, a tax on inter-state movement of goods and services, will lie with Centre but by special provisions in law, states will also be cross-empowered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Council will meet on February 18 to approve of the drafts of IGST law and other supporting legislations needs for subsuming central and state levies like excise duty and service tax and VAT, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GST, he said, now looks realistically possible from July 1 instead of April 1 previously planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister said each assess will be assessed by only one authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;West Bengal Finance Minister Amit Mitra said he dissented at the Council meeting as his state government wanted 100 per cent of the tax payers up to Rs 1.5 crore turnover to be with states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He termed 90 per cent of the assessees being with states as a victory to protect small traders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, Kerala Finance Minister T M Thomas Isaac said there was no agreement on the issue of administration of GST, with states continuing to seek sole control over tax payers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delta ID rolls out Iris Scanning Technology for in-Car Biometrics and Secure Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/delta-id-rolls-iris-scanning-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/delta-id-rolls-iris-scanning-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Delta ID launched its iris scanning technology for automotive at CES 2017. Delta ID collaborated with Gentex Corporation to demonstrate the use of iris scanning as a secure, reliable and convenient way to identify and authenticate the driver in a car, and as a way to elevate the security of automobiles during the driving experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID and Gentex demonstrated a rearview mirror that scans the iris of the driver upon entering the vehicle and gets ready to drive. Only if authorized, the driver is able to start and drive the vehicle. In India, this rearview mirror can also be configured for Aadhaar authentication of the driver to ensure only an authorized driver is indeed driving the taxi or an Uber, or Ola car. Additionally, in private vehicles the same feature can be used for in-cabin personalization and other use cases such as payments at petrol pumps and other drive-through stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID and Gentex have entered into a strategic partnership to bring iris scanning technology to automotive. Gentex’s rearview mirrors will integrate Delta ID’s Active IRIS technology. Both companies believe the iris is the right modality for in-car biometric identification and authentication, and rearview mirrors are the right place to integrate iris.  The integrated solution provides a high level of security along with convenience and reliability of use. The companies envision their joint offerings to enable novel use cases in the cars of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Downing, Senior Vice President at Gentex Corporation, said, “We believe driver identification will play a critical role in car sharing, in-car payment and the autonomous driving space. Delta ID ‘s proven iris scanning technology combined with Gentex’s display-integrated rearview mirrors will bring fast, reliable and secure iris scanning to the cars of the future.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delta ID’s ActiveIRIS technology combines its patented hardware design and advanced software algorithm to bring iris scanning and recognition to consumer devices that is fast and easy to use. Delta ID was the first company to bring iris scanning and recognition technology to smartphones in May 2015. Since then the company has launched its ActiveIRIS technology in multiple devices from various OEMs, and maintains its leadership position in the industry with respect to speed, usability and reliability of iris scanning for mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salil Prabhakar, President and CEO of Delta ID, said, “We believe iris scanner integrated rearview mirrors will elevate the safety of riders and security of autos to a new level. Gentex has been leading the advancements in rearview mirrors in the industry. It has been a privilege to work with Gentex in designing and developing this novel solution that may end up changing the way we interact with our cars forever.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>