<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bhim App on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/bhim-app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bhim App on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/bhim-app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM will now allow you to make payments via Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app will now allow users to send and receive money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number.
This comes shortly after the government announced the Aadhaar Pay which would allow any person with their Aadhaar number linked to a bank account, can make and receive payment electronically.
At the time, IT minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said that BHIM would be able to make Aadhar Payments any biometric authentication, as indicated by this Economic Times report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.
 The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aadhaar With Your PAN Card Just by Uploading a Scanned Proof</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/link-aadhaar-pan-card-just-uploading-scanned-proof/</guid>
      <description>Individuals struggling to link their Permanent Account Number with Aadhaar because of differently spelt names can now simply upload a scanned copy of PAN to get the work done.
Besides, the tax department is planning to introduce an option on the e-filing portal through which taxpayers can choose to link the Aadhaar without changing the name by opting for a One-Time Password (OTP), provided that the year of birth of the person matches in both documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar card linking has mitigated 65L bogus ration card holders: Harsh Gupta</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-mitigated-65l-bogus-ration-card-holders-harsh-gupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-mitigated-65l-bogus-ration-card-holders-harsh-gupta/</guid>
      <description>The linking of Aadhaar card numbers with the ration cards has helped the Department of Food and Civil Supplies to weed out 65 lakh bogus ration cards across the state, said Secretary to the department, Harsh Gupta.
Addressing media persons after chairing a progress review meeting here in the city on Sunday, he said, “Aadhaar linking process has been completed, out of the 4.10 crore ration card holders, 3.40 crore had been linked to Aadhaar numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Public Sector Banks to join BHIM by end of this month: NPCI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/public-sector-banks-join-bhim-end-month-npci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/public-sector-banks-join-bhim-end-month-npci/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India expects all Public Sector Banks (PSBs) to join Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) by the end of this month. BHIM is the common platform across the nation for making simple, easy and quick payment transactions using Unified Payments Interface (UPI).
As on date 37 banks are a part of the BHIM platform including PSBs like State Bank of India, Bank of India, Bank of Baroda and Union Bank of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is BHIM different from mobile wallets?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-different-mobile-wallets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-different-mobile-wallets/</guid>
      <description>With BHIM, the government is fortifying its focus on digital India. We tell you how the app fares compared with other digital payment solutions
The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) mobile app, launched on December 30, 2016, in a bid to make digital financial services available to all, has emerged as one of the fastest growing apps. Within 10 days of launch, it has seen one crore downloads, and over 20 lakh transactions across the UPI (unified payments interface) and USSD (unstructured supplementary service data) platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPCI expects all state-run banks to join BHIM by month end</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-expects-state-run-banks-join-bhim-month-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-expects-state-run-banks-join-bhim-month-end/</guid>
      <description>BHIM is the common platform across the nation for making simple, easy and quick payment transactions using Unified Payments Interface (UPI).
“Since the customer base of PSBs is very large, their participation in BHIM is of crucial importance for the success of this app. We are confident that once all PSBs are a part of BHIM, the user base will jump multiple times,” NPCI’s managing director and CEO A P Hota said in a statement here today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget 2017: Two New Schemes Announced To Boost BHIM App</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/union-budget-2017-two-new-schemes-announced-to-boost-bhim-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/union-budget-2017-two-new-schemes-announced-to-boost-bhim-app/</guid>
      <description>Mr Jaitley said a mission will be set up with a target of over 2,500 crore digital transactions for 2017-18 through the United Payments Interface, Aadhaar Pay, Immediate Payment Service and debit cards.
Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today announced two new schemes to boost the government&amp;rsquo;s BHIM or Bharat Interface for Money digital payment app. Digital economy will clean up the system, and weed out corruption and black money, Mr Jaitley said in his Budget speech, announcing an Aadhaar-based payment system to promote digital transactions for people living in remote areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biometric Aadhaar Payments to usher in Tech Revolution, says President</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-aadhaar-payments-usher-tech-revolution-says-president/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-aadhaar-payments-usher-tech-revolution-says-president/</guid>
      <description>BHIM has become one of the most popular mobile payment apps within days of launch, President Pranab Mukherjee said Tuesday, exuding confidence that soon-to-be unveiled biometric Aadhaar payment system will usher in a “technological revolution” in India.
“The launch of mobile app BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) is a tribute to the vision of Dr. Bhimrao Ambedkar who sought economic empowerment of the poorest. Within a few days it has become one of the most popular mobile app based payment mechanisms in the country,” Mukherjee said addressing the joint sitting of Parliament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM app users can now send money using Aadhaar card number</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-users-can-now-send-money-using-aadhaar-card-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-users-can-now-send-money-using-aadhaar-card-number/</guid>
      <description>BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) ll now be able to send money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number at places where Aadhaar is listed as a payment option. The Unified Payments Interface (UPI)-based app will get biometric-based Aadhaar Pay option as well. The feature is expected to roll out in the coming weeks. In our case, we were able to make payments using our verified Aadhaar card number. Apart from Aadhaar-based payment option, users can pay using Mobile/Payment Address and Account +IFSC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp&#39;s latest update will let you track your friends&#39; locations</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/whatsapps-latest-update-will-let-you-track-your-friends-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/whatsapps-latest-update-will-let-you-track-your-friends-locations/</guid>
      <description>Instant messaging app WhatsApp is working on a feature that will track the live location of members, allowing users to track the whereabouts of their friends in real time.
According to the WABetaInfo account on Twitter which is known for leaking information related to WhatsApp updates, the feature will work on WhatsApp beta version 2.17.3.28 for iOS, 2.16.399+ on Android and will be disabled by default.
&amp;ldquo;The tracking can be kept on for 1 minute, 2 minutes, 5 minutes, or indefinitely.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>