<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/bhim-app/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/bhim-app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs. 1299 First look at Reliance Jio 4G VoLTE feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/exclusive-first-look-at-reliance-jio-4g-volte-feature-phone-priced-at-rs-1299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know that Reliance Jio is all set to launch feature phones with VoLTE support soon. We managed to get hold of the first image of the feature phone that is launching soon for Rs. 1299. As you can see from the image, the phone has shortcut keys for MyJio, Jio Live TV, Jio video and Jio Music below the display.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/Reliance-Jio-VoLTE-feature-phone.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The phone has T9 keypad and D-pad in the middle, just like any other feature phone and doesn’t have a touchscreen. It also has a dedicated button for torchlight. Maker of this feature phone is not known yet. Currently we don’t have any specifications of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to recent reports, Jio will launch these VoLTE-enabled feature phones starting at Rs. 999 that will run on Android operating system. Earlier reports said that capability to make VoLTE calls in these feature phones will be enabled by Spreadtrum chips, and Jio is in talks with Qualcomm and MediaTek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Jio plans start as low as Rs. 149 per month offering unlimited calls, this will be useful for those who make a lot of calls and need a cheap phone with a keypad. We should know more details about more upcoming VoLTE-enabled feature phones from Jio soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Public Sector Banks to join BHIM by end of this month: NPCI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/public-sector-banks-join-bhim-end-month-npci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/public-sector-banks-join-bhim-end-month-npci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Payments Corporation of India expects all Public Sector Banks (PSBs) to join Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) by the end of this month. BHIM is the common platform across the nation for making simple, easy and quick payment transactions using Unified Payments Interface (UPI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As on date 37 banks are a part of the BHIM platform including PSBs like State Bank of India, Bank of India, Bank of Baroda and Union Bank of India. The PSBs which will go live very soon on the platform are Corporation Bank, Punjab and Sindh Bank and five associates of State Bank of India. NPCI is working with these seven banks to ensure that all of them are a part of the platform by the end of this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Since the customer base of PSBs is very large, their participation in BHIM is of crucial importance for the success of this app. We are confident that once all PSBs are a part of BHIM, the user base will jump multiple times,” said Mr. A. P. Hota, MD &amp;amp; CEO, NPCI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM was launched on December 30, 2016 by the Hon’ble Prime Minister Shri Narendra Modi. The response has been very positive and till January 31, 2017, 13.8 million customers downloaded the app out of which 3.6 million customers have linked the app to their bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gap in the number of app downloads and the number of customers linking the app to their bank account has been because it is observed that most of these customers have downloaded BHIM without checking if their bank is active on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month a new version 1.2 was launched with additional features like pay to Aadhaar number’, SPAM report, improvised customer redressal mechanism with drop down menu. The new version also has seven new languages apart from English and Hindi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About BHIM / UPI: Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) / Unified Payments Interface (UPI) is a smart mobile phone based app that allows simple, easy and quick payment transactions using UPI. One can easily make direct bank to bank payments instantly and collect money using Mobile number or Payment address. It is a unique payment solution which empowers an individual with immediate send and collect request. It uses an email like Virtual Payment Address (VPA)/ Mobile Number@upi /Account number &amp;amp; IFSC Code/Aadhaar Number as payment identifier for sending or collecting money instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is BHIM different from mobile wallets?</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-different-mobile-wallets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-different-mobile-wallets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With BHIM, the government is fortifying its focus on digital India. We tell you how the app fares compared with other digital payment solutions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) mobile app, launched on December 30, 2016, in a bid to make digital financial services available to all, has emerged as one of the fastest growing apps. Within 10 days of launch, it has seen one crore downloads, and over 20 lakh transactions across the UPI (unified payments interface) and USSD (unstructured supplementary service data) platforms. While it is a big step towards digital inclusion, how different is it really from the existing digital payments systems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One for All&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM is a digital payments solution app, for easy and quick transactions, based on the Unified Payments Interface (UPI) from the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI). Those who have signed up for UPI-based payments on their bank accounts, which are also linked to mobile phone numbers, will be able to use the BHIM app to carry out digital transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can easily make direct bank-to-bank payments instantly, and collect money using just a mobile number or payment address. It allows person-to-person money transfers, scheduled money collection, and transactions to be done through a smartphone. Payments can be made across all participating banks (35 in total). To make transactions using UPI, one does not require an account number, or bank details, all transactions can be done using the VPA (virtual payment address) created within the banking app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of the BHIM app is that all the UPI transactions are combined into a single app – people need not download different UPI-linked banking apps to make transactions. Other than sending, receiving, and requesting for money, one can also check their account balance and switch between accounts in case they have multiple bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money can also be sent to non-UPI supported banks using IFSC code and account number. It supports only Hindi and English languages as of now unlike other mobile wallets that support regional languages, too. BHIM is available only on Android via Google Play. Those without access to data services, can use BHIM by dialing *99# (USSD-based mobile banking service) on their phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPI-linked apps such as PhonePe and Trupay enable transfer of money without sharing any details, using only the mobile number, provided the receiver also has the same app. People can pay their utility bills, purchase gift cards, and share expenses among friends using these apps. But when sending money using the BHIM app, the amount will go directly into the receiver’s bank account irrespective of whether the receiver has the BHIM app or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“BHIM is a skeleton of what UPI does, which is sending and receiving payments. Trupay starts where BHIM stops; it provides value-added services over and above what BHIM does,” says Vivek Lohcheb, Co-founder of Trupay.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/bhim-moss2_020817115110.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BHIM vs. Mobile Wallets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Level of authentication: Wallets mostly rely on a phone’s locking system as their security system. Even while making a payment, wallets often don’t ask for any kind of pin or password. So if the phone is stolen, anyone can make transfers using the wallet by merely unlocking the screen. The BHIM app, on the other hand, has its own app password. One needs to enter the password to access the app, to proceed with a transaction, and also to check balance. The payment gateway is blocked after three wrong tries. However, with BHIM allowing just the name or mobile number as payment address, anyone can request for money. The NPCI has cautioned people about unknown payment requests one may get. There have been a few updates and ‘bug fixes’, but it is not known if the issue has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charges and limits for transferring money: To use wallets for making payments and transfers, one needs to fill them with money first. The amount sent and received stays in the wallet account itself. To make transfers from a wallet to a bank account, a processing fee of 1-4 per cent per transaction is charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With BHIM, one can directly send, receive, and request for money to and from their bank accounts. There is no need to fill up any wallet to proceed with a transaction. For those using *99#, Rs. 0.50 is charged per transaction. It is the bank’s discretion to levy charges on the customer for using BHIM; from NPCI, there are no charges levied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With wallets there is a maximum transaction limit of Rs 1 lakh per month. Transaction limit using BHIM is Rs. 20,000 per user, per day, and Rs. 10,000 per transaction. The limit for USSD has currently been set at Rs. 5,000 per day. It has come as a huge advantage for merchants who can now accept payments directly into their bank accounts, and pay no transaction charges, unlike on wallets. Bank transactions and transfers through BHIM happen 24X7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perks: Offers, discounts, and cashbacks are what draw users towards mobile wallets. In keeping with this trend, NPCI has come up with its own lucky draw schemes – Lucky Grahak Yojna for consumers and Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojna for merchants. Lucky Grahak Yojna will give out Rs. 1,000 daily for 15,000 customers, and a weekly prize of Rs. 5,000, Rs. 10,000, and Rs. 1 lakh. Digi-Dhan Vyapar Yojna will give away a weekly prize of Rs. 2,500, Rs. 5,000 and Rs. 50,000 for merchants. Users of RuPay Card, USSD, BHIM/UPI and Aadhaar-enabled payment services are eligible for these daily and weekly lucky draw prizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mobile Wallets at a Loss?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM app is not a mobile wallet; it is an open platform which links directly to any bank account and proves to be much more useful than mobile wallets. “UPI being a more efficient platform from a user or merchant point of view, it will overtake wallets in no time now. Wallets will exist till they keep giving cashbacks. In the long run, wallets will not exist in India,” Lohcheb says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wallets have a few shortcomings. Only a fixed amount of money can stay in a wallet app, unlike BHIM. Wallets do not allow users to send or receive money from different mobile wallets; whereas there is no such restriction within the BHIM app as it uses UPI. Bipin Preet Singh, Co-founder of MobiKwik, says, “We hope that provisions will be made for registering e-wallets on UPI, thereby enabling people to pay through bank accounts or e-wallets using the BHIM app.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPCI expects all state-run banks to join BHIM by month end</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-expects-state-run-banks-join-bhim-month-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/npci-expects-state-run-banks-join-bhim-month-end/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BHIM is the common platform across the nation for making simple, easy and quick payment transactions using Unified Payments Interface (UPI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Since the customer base of PSBs is very large, their participation in BHIM is of crucial importance for the success of this app. We are confident that once all PSBs are a part of BHIM, the user base will jump multiple times,” NPCI’s managing director and CEO A P Hota said in a statement here today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As on date 37 banks including State Bank of India, Bank of India, Bank of Baroda and Union Bank of India, are on the BHIM platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PSBs which will go live very soon on the platform are Corporation Bank, Punjab and Sindh Bank and five associates of State Bank of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BHIM was launched on December 30, 2016 by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till January 31, 13.8 million customers have downloaded the app out of which 3.6 million customers have linked the app to their bank account.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget 2017: Two New Schemes Announced To Boost BHIM App</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/union-budget-2017-two-new-schemes-announced-to-boost-bhim-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/union-budget-2017-two-new-schemes-announced-to-boost-bhim-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr Jaitley said a mission will be set up with a target of over 2,500 crore digital transactions for 2017-18 through the United Payments Interface, Aadhaar Pay, Immediate Payment Service and debit cards.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today announced two new schemes to boost the government&amp;rsquo;s BHIM or Bharat Interface for Money digital payment app. Digital economy will clean up the system, and weed out corruption and black money, Mr Jaitley said in his Budget speech, announcing an Aadhaar-based payment system to promote digital transactions for people living in remote areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A merchant enabled Aadhaar payment system will be launched shortly. This will specially be beneficial to those who do not have debit cards, mobile wallets or mobile phones,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jaitley said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He spoke about the BHIM app, launched on December 30 by Prime Minister Narendra Modi as a big push towards digital India after the November notes ban.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nearly 125 lakh people have adopted the BHIM app. Government will launch two new schemes - a referral bonus and a cash back scheme for merchants - to promote the use of BHIM,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jaitley said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BHIM app, based on Unified Payments Interface (UPI), is available on Google&amp;rsquo;s Play Store. It has been upgraded twice since its launch to include seven new languages besides English and Hindi. The new version has enhanced security features and an improvised customer care mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley said a mission will be set up with a target of over 2,500 crore digital transactions for 2017-18 through the United Payments Interface, Aadhaar Pay, Immediate Payment Service and debit cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stating that the government wanted to promote digital economy as an integral part of the government&amp;rsquo;s strategy, the Finance Minister said it would have a transformational impact on the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This, in turn, is expected to energise private investment in the country through lower cost of credit. India is now at the cusp of a massive digital revolution. A shift to digital platform has huge benefits to the common man,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BHIM app, said the finance minister, will unleash the power of mobile phones for making digital payments and financial inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM will now allow you to make payments via Aadhaar</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-will-now-allow-make-payments-via-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM) app will now allow users to send and receive money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes shortly after the government announced the Aadhaar Pay which would allow any person with their Aadhaar number linked to a bank account, can make and receive payment electronically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, IT minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said that BHIM would be able to make Aadhar Payments any biometric authentication, as indicated by this Economic Times report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the government has 14 banks onboard to facilitate payments via Aadhaar Pay, with more to join soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The updated BHIM app now has options where it will allow users to pay with Aadhar number in addition to virtual payment addresses (VPA) and bank account and IFSC codes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biometric Aadhaar Payments to usher in Tech Revolution, says President</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-aadhaar-payments-usher-tech-revolution-says-president/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/biometric-aadhaar-payments-usher-tech-revolution-says-president/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BHIM has become one of the most popular mobile payment apps within days of launch, President Pranab Mukherjee said Tuesday, exuding confidence that soon-to-be unveiled biometric Aadhaar payment system will usher in a “technological revolution” in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The launch of mobile app BHIM (Bharat Interface for Money) is a tribute to the vision of Dr. Bhimrao Ambedkar who sought economic empowerment of the poorest. Within a few days it has become one of the most popular mobile app based payment mechanisms in the country,” Mukherjee said addressing the joint sitting of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The indigenously-developed BHIM was launched on December 30 by Prime Minister Narendra Modi to enable fast and secure cashless transactions using mobile phones. It has already seen over 1.1 crore downloads by mid-January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The biometric Aadhaar payment system to be launched soon will usher a technological revolution in India,” Mukherjee said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many as 14 banks have already come on board for Aadhaar Pay, which will enable people to make and receive payments using their Aadhaar number and biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, Digidhan Abhiyaan and two lakh Common Service Centres are providing employment to over five lakh youth, and spreading digital literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take banking system to the doorstep of the poor, and the unbanked, Indian Postal Payment Bank has been started, he pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The postal network with wider reach and deep penetration of over 1.5 lakh post offices will also function as postal banks. Besides, the over 1 lakh bank-mitras appointed by banks, over 2.5 lakh Gram-Dak Sewaks will also function as banking correspondents,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, through the Stand-Up India initiative, plans to empower over 2.5 lakh Scheduled Castes, Schedule Tribes and women entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For promoting entrepreneurship, the National SC/ST Hub has been launched with an initial allocation of Rs. 490 crores,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The President further said that the BharatNet project, optical fibre cable now cover over 75,700 gram panchayats, up from only 59 in May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said coal block and spectrum auctions illustrate the highest standards of transparency set by the Government in allocation of natural resources. To carry this forward, Government procurements have been brought under a single platform – Government eMarket Place (GeM), he observed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, he said, has approved North East BPO promotion scheme in the digital India programme for creation of employment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar card linking has mitigated 65L bogus ration card holders: Harsh Gupta</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-mitigated-65l-bogus-ration-card-holders-harsh-gupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-linking-mitigated-65l-bogus-ration-card-holders-harsh-gupta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The linking of Aadhaar card numbers with the ration cards has helped the Department of Food and Civil Supplies to weed out 65 lakh bogus ration cards across the state, said Secretary to the department, Harsh Gupta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing media persons after chairing a progress review meeting here in the city on Sunday, he said, “Aadhaar linking process has been completed, out of the 4.10 crore ration card holders, 3.40 crore had been linked to Aadhaar numbers. Several measures initiated by the department to check pilferage in the public distribution system have helped in saving 35 metric tonnes of food grains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Though there had been an increase in the number of LPG connections, around 90 lakh families were still getting kerosene under the earlier scheme and many had not disclosed their LPG connections,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the data available with oil marketing companies, 99 % of the households in Mysuru district have LPG connection, while majority of the houses in Bengaluru Urban and Rural have gas connections. In order to prevent pilferage, subsidised kerosene (blue) was not being sold at the shops selling non-subsidised kerosene (white),” Gupta added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, “The department has listed out the names of 210 people who have no gas connection to bring them under the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana (PMUJ), launched with the objective of providing LPG connections to families below the poverty line. While the Centre gives free LPG connection, the state government will provide them gas stove with two burners.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deputy Commissioner D Randeep, Deputy Director for Food and Civil Supplies K Rameshwarappa were present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHIM app users can now send money using Aadhaar card number</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-users-can-now-send-money-using-aadhaar-card-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/bhim-app-users-can-now-send-money-using-aadhaar-card-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BHIM &lt;em&gt;(Bharat Interface for Money)&lt;/em&gt; ll now be able to send money using their 12-digit Aadhaar number at places where Aadhaar is listed as a payment option. The Unified Payments Interface (UPI)-based app will get biometric-based Aadhaar Pay option as well. The feature is expected to roll out in the coming weeks. In our case, we were able to make payments using our verified Aadhaar card number. Apart from Aadhaar-based payment option, users can pay using Mobile/Payment Address and Account +IFSC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the government has 14 banks on-board to facilitate payments via Aadhaar Pay, with more to join soon. According to a report, 1.11 billion people in India have already registered with Aadhaar, and close to 390 million bank accounts are linked to Aadhaar number. With the launch of biometric-based Aadhaar Pay, payment via BHIM app will become simpler as it only requires verifying your biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, two PINs are required for a successful BHIM transaction. One is the app PIN which is stored locally on the phone and is required every time a person starts BHIM. The other is the UPI PIN with which you set up an UPI account or a VPA, which is required only when a transaction is taking place or you request to see your account balance on the BHIM app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced the digital payments app BHIM from National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) on December 30 last year. The digital payments app topped Google Play Store free apps chart in just three days. Within a month, it was downloaded more than 5 million times on Android. Aadhaar Pay option was anticipated since the app was launched. BHIM is different to mobile wallets such as Paytm and MobiKwik as it also allows sending money to people who don’t have the app. The UPI integration to USSD payments can work on feature phones and offline as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp&#39;s latest update will let you track your friends&#39; locations</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/whatsapps-latest-update-will-let-you-track-your-friends-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/whatsapps-latest-update-will-let-you-track-your-friends-locations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instant messaging app WhatsApp is working on a feature that will track the live location of members, allowing users to track the whereabouts of their friends in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the WABetaInfo account on Twitter which is known for leaking information related to WhatsApp updates, the feature will work on WhatsApp beta version 2.17.3.28 for iOS, 2.16.399+ on Android and will be disabled by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The tracking can be kept on for 1 minute, 2 minutes, 5 minutes, or indefinitely. This comes in handy if you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to meet the gang at a certain location and time, and you want to see how far away from the destination every one in the group is,&amp;rdquo; phonearena.com reported on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The live streaming can also be disabled so that your group members can&amp;rsquo;t learn where you are at any given moment, it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Live Location Tracking&amp;rdquo; is disabled by default, which means that WhatsApp needs to activate it when it is ready to be launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December last year, WhatsApp added the features to revoke and edit the sent messages in a beta version testing. The feature is currently available in WhatsApp beta for the iOS 2.17.1.869 platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp recently launched a video calling feature from India which was rolled out globally to other countries. The feature is available on all platforms &amp;ndash; Android, iOS and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 160 million users in India, WhatsApp is available in more than 50 different languages around the world and in 10 Indian languages. Nearly 100 million calls are being made on the platform daily worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>