<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar essential for getting fellowships, scholarships from UGC, AICTE</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-essential-getting-fellowships-scholarships-ugc-aicte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-essential-getting-fellowships-scholarships-ugc-aicte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to an order issued by the Human Resource Development (HRD) ministry on Wednesday, students seeking government scholarships and fellowships will need to declare Aadhaar numbers by the end of June, putting yet another of its benefits programme behind the Unique Identity project wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The order covers fellowship schemes implemented by the University Grants Commission and the All India Council for Technical Education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The use of Aadhaar as identity document for delivery of services or benefits or subsidies simplifies the government delivery processes, brings in transparency and efficiency, and enables beneficiaries to get their entitlements directly in a convenient and seamless manner and Aadhaar obviates the need for producing multiple documents to prove one’s identity,” the government stated in its notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students have till June 30 to declare their Aadhaar numbers, or apply for one and declare the enrolment number, to their respective colleges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification came into effect from Wednesday, covering all states excluding Assam, Meghalaya and Jammu and Kashmir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, activists have criticised the government’s move to make the Aadhaar programme – the enrolment to a national database with biometric information such as fingerprints and iris scans – must for those drawing state benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The criticism has centred around a Supreme Court order in September last year, when it said that people without UID numbers must not be denied assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NITI&#39;s vision: Houses, vehicles, ACs for all by 2032</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-vision-houses-vehicles-acs-for-all-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-vision-houses-vehicles-acs-for-all-by/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government think tank NITI Aayog has envisaged a new India in which all citizens in 15 years will have houses with toilets, two-wheelers or cars, power, air conditioners and digital connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a glimpse of Vision 2031-32 presented by the NITI Aayog Vice-Chairman Arvind Panagariya to the body&amp;rsquo;s Governing Council, chaired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, at a meeting held yesterday in the presence of chief ministers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The India 2031-32: Vision, Strategy and Action Agenda also visualises a fully literate society with universal access to health care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also calls for having a much larger and modern network of roads, railways, waterways and air connectivity and a clean India where citizens would have access to quality air and water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is envisions that per capita income would increase three fold to Rs 3.14 lakh in 2031-32 from Rs 1.06 lakh in 2015-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, it states that the country&amp;rsquo;s gross domestic product or economy would rise to Rs 469 lakh crore in 2031-32 from Rs 137 lakh crore level in 2015-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vision says that the central and state expenditure will rise by Rs 92 lakh crore in 2031-32 to Rs 130 lakh crore from Rs 38 lakh crore in 2015-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work on the Fifteen Year Vision and Seven Year Strategy document spanning 2017-18 to 2031-32 is in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Three Year Action Agenda covering 2017-18 to 2019-20 was circulated to the Governing Council Members yesterday and would be finalised shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the vision presentation, all efforts had to be made to realise the Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s vision of a vibrant India by 2031-32.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We must transform India into a prosperous, healthy, secure, corruption-free, energy abundant, environmentally clean and globally influential nation,&amp;rdquo; the presentation added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF Withdrawal Easier For Education, Hospital Bills: 10 Facts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-documents-just-self-declaration-for-provident-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-documents-just-self-declaration-for-provident-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EFPO subscribers can seek withdrawal from their employee provident fund (EPF) account on various grounds by using a composite form along with a self-declaration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO or Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation has made partial withdrawal easier from provident fund for medical and other purposes like purchase of house, education and marriage of children. The subscriber is no longer required to submit various certificates or documents. EFPO subscribers can seek withdrawal from their employee provident fund (EPF) account on various grounds by using a composite form along with a self-declaration. The submission of composite claim form signed by the EPF subscriber shall be construed as &amp;lsquo;self-certification&amp;rsquo; for partial withdrawals, according to the retirement fund body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) EPFO&amp;rsquo;s latest move to ease the withdrawal process will benefit nearly 4 crore subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) The subscribers can seek advance from the fund for treatment of illness in certain cases including hospitalisation lasting for one month or more, or major surgical operation in a hospital, or in case they are suffering from TB, leprosy, paralysis, cancer, mental derangement or heart ailment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Earlier, the members were required to submit a certificate from a doctor of the hospital that the member or his dependent has been hospitalised or requires hospitalisation for one month or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Now after change in employee provident fund laws, a member would no longer be required to submit any medical certificate or document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) For medical purpose, an EPFO subscriber can withdraw up to six months of salary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) EPPO has been taking a number of steps to ease withdrawal rules. Recently, it allowed subscribers to withdraw up to 90 per cent of their funds for home/land purchase. It also allowed payment of home loan EMIs by using the provident fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Partial provident fund withdrawal is also allowed for post-matriculation education of children and marriage purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For various withdrawal purposes, the subscriber is now only required to submit a self-declaration, which is included in a claim form, to avail advance from the provident fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Subscribers who have seeded their Universal Account Number (UAN) with Aadhaar and bank account details can submit claim forms directly to EPFO without the attestation of employers. A universal account number allows provident fund number portability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) However, in cases where Aadhaar has not been seeded, the attestation of employers is required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how your petrol pump might be cheating you right in front of your eyes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-your-petrol-pump-might-be-cheating-you-in-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-your-petrol-pump-might-be-cheating-you-in-front/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A series of raids by Uttar Pradesh Special Task Force (STF) in Lucknow yesterday have revealed how petrol pumps are cheating consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most consumers only check the display of the fuel dispensing machine for the amount and the quantity of the fuel filled but the raids show that the pumps were using a remote-controlled electronic chip to dupe consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is how petrol pumps are cheating you:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Petrol pumps install a chip inside the fuel dispensing machine, which is designed to reduce the fuel output by nearly five to ten per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The chip is attached to a wire, which sets the limit through a remote control. So, if you are buying one-litre of petrol, the machine will release only 940 ml.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such chips cost around Rs 3,000 a piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The STF suspects that the chips have been sold to a large number of pumps. As per STF estimate, a petrol pump using this chip earns an undue profit of around Rs 14 lakh per month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Check If Your Employer Has Deposited Your Income Tax</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26as-how-to-check-your-income-tax-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26as-how-to-check-your-income-tax-credit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In case there is a mismatch in TDS figures in Form 16 and Form 26AS, one should approach his/her employer or respective entity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax return filing season has started from April 1. Usually, for many salaried employees, the first thing that comes to mind is Form 16 that is issued by employers. But another document - Form 26AS - is also a crucial document that a salaried individual should access before filing tax returns. Form 16 is a document from your employer, certifying that TDS or tax deducted at source has been deducted on your salary. Form 26AS is basically your tax credit statement which shows all taxes received by the Income Tax Department. You can access Form 26AS from the tax department&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is extremely important to go through the Form 26AS to ensure that all due credits for TDS deducted from a person&amp;rsquo;s salary, FD interest, etc. are duly accounted for,&amp;rdquo; said Sandeep Sehgal, director of tax and regulatory at Ashok Maheshwary &amp;amp; Associates LLP. &amp;ldquo;Any shortfall of TDS reflected in Form 26AS than what is actually claimable in the income tax return will result in automatic generation of demand by Centralized Processing Centre of Income Tax Department subsequent to filing of income tax return.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, it could also be problematic for the tax payer when excess TDS is reflected in Form 26AS. &amp;ldquo;Income Tax Department may question the person for the corresponding income which the person may not have shown in his/her income tax return. Hence, to avoid such hassles, it is necessary to tally the due TDS credit with Form 26AS,&amp;rdquo; adds Mr Sehgal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case there is a mismatch in TDS figures in Form 16 and Form 26AS, Mr Sehgal says the &amp;ldquo;person should approach the his/her employer or respective entity which has deducted TDS on any of his income and tell them to get their TDS return rectified to adjust.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The taxpayer can also see the refund received by him/her for previous assessment year in Form 26AS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-access-your-form-26as&#34;&gt;How to access your Form 26AS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the income tax department&amp;rsquo;s website for tax filing (incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in) and log into your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &amp;lsquo;My Account&amp;rsquo; tab and select Form 26AS from the drop down menu; After confirmation, the taxpayer will be directed to TDS Reconciliation Analysis and Correction Enabling System (TRACES) website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The taxpayer can then select the assessment year and format in which he/she would like to view Form 26AS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Password for Form 26AS PDF/text file is Date of Birth as printed on PAN card. Enter date in ddmmyyyy format to open file (e.g., for 10-Oct-2012, enter as 10102012).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxpayers can also view Form 26AS through net banking facility. Select banks offer this facility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory For Subsidy: Indian Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to curb corruption in the Public Distribution System (PDS), the Indian government had made the Aadhar Card mandatory for availing foodgrain subsidy at PDS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has already made Aadhar Card mandatory for the cooking gas LPG subsidy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has declared Rs 1.4 lakh crore subsidy under the food security law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A timeline till June 30 is given for the common people who avail subsidy to apply for Aadhar Card, the government categorically stated in the notification in this regard that no subsidised foodgrains with Aadhaar after June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since November 2016, the Government of India, under the National Food Security Law (NFSA), has been providing 5 kg of foodgrains per person per month at Rs 1-3/kg to over 80 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification has been applicable from February 8 in all States and Union Territories (UTs) except Assam, Meghalaya and Jammu and Kashmir. This move indicates Government’s serious intetion of digitisation to curb the corruption in PDS as well as a move towards a simplifies delivery process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Proposal To Withdraw New 2,000 Rupee Notes: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday said there is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 notes that were introduced post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 denomination banknote,&amp;rdquo; the minister said in a written reply in the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley further said the Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes returned to currency chests of the RBI amounted to Rs 12.44 lakh crore (as on December 10, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data obtained in this regard would need to be reconciled with the physical cash balances to eliminate counterfeit notes, accounting errors and possible double counts after which only the final figures will be arrived at, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added that as on March 3, 2017 the currency in circulation was Rs 12 lakh crore and as on January 27, it was Rs 9.921 lakh crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley said the cash recall seeks to create a new &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; wherein the GDP will be bigger, cleaner and real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This exercise is part of the government&amp;rsquo;s resolve to eliminate corruption, blackmoney, counterfeit currency and terror funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This exercise has resulted in an increase in deposits with banks. This will facilitate reduction of interest rates and provide more headroom to banks to expand their credit base,&amp;rdquo; the minister said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation, several restrictions were imposed on withdrawal from banks as well as ATMs. The restrictions have been gradually removed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BSNL Is Planning To Counter Reliance Jio, Airtel, Others</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new plan gives 2GB of 3G data per day at Rs 339&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlimited calling within its network is also applicable under the plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-run &lt;em&gt;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited&lt;/em&gt; (BSNL) announced a new plan which offers 2GB of 3G data per day with unlimited calling within its network for Rs 339. In an effort to take on the service providers like Reliance Jio, Airtel and others, BSNL will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks and after that the users will be charged 25 paise per minute. The company further said that the data of 2GB per day is one of the best in the industry. The limited offer for prepaid services comes with a validity of 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are committed to providing affordable and efficient services to all segment of our loyal mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL Director for Consumer Mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data and unlimited calling to all network till March 31. From April 1, users opting for Jio Prime service will get unlimited data and calls till March 31, 2018, for one time registration fee of Rs 99 and Rs 303 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharti Airtel has also introduced its &amp;lsquo;Surprise offer&amp;rsquo; which will give free 30GB data for three months, starting March 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers from Airtel or other operators comes in wake of the telecom war started by the new entrant Reliance Jio in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea To Sell 1GB 2G, 3G, 4G Mobile Data At Same Price From March End</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present, Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision in the wake of stiff competition in the market&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with a month validity for Rs 170&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular will start selling 1GB and above mobile data plans across its 2G, 3G and 4G network at same price by the end of this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Idea has now announced that it will allow open market data recharges of 1GB and above to work on Idea&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G or 4G network without any differential prices and this will be rolled out nationally by March 31, 2017,&amp;rdquo; Idea said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates. Due to stiff competition in the market from Reliance Jio, the 4G mobile data service of Idea is significantly cheaper than 2G service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the high speed data plans were priced higher based on their download speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customer can choose the recharge price basis usage and volume available in pack, without having to worry about the platform the customer&amp;rsquo;s device is logged in,&amp;rdquo; Idea Cellular Chief Marketing Officer Sashi Shankar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea will bring all data product categories like sachets, freedom packs to unified pricing and will be rolled out nationally in phases by May 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Idea&amp;rsquo;s pan India broadband coverage continues to expand and reduces gap with existing 2G coverage which covers 4 lakh towns and villages, customers can now seamlessly migrate services between technology &amp;amp; platform without worrying about differential costs,&amp;rdquo; Shankar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data limit in high speed internet plans gets exhausted in less time compared to that on slow speed network like 2G.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plastic Rs 10 Note Could Be A Reality Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plastic-rs10-note-could-be-a-reality-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plastic-rs10-note-could-be-a-reality-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has been authorised to conduct field trials for printing plastic Rs 10 denomination notes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has been authorised to conduct field trials for printing plastic Rs 10 denomination notes which will have a longer life span, Parliament was informed on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Approval for procurement of plastic substrate and printing of bank notes of Rs 10 denomination on plastic banknote substrates has been conveyed to the RBI,&amp;rdquo; Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal told the Lok Sabha in a written reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Substrate denotes the underlying substance or layer on which currency is printed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister said the government had decided to conduct field trials at five locations of the country with plastic banknotes, which are expected to last longer than cotton substrate-based banknotes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जल्द मिलेगा होम लोन कवर के साथ कम रेट का फायदा!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/profit-of-low-rate-with-home-loan-cover-home-loan-to-be-available-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/profit-of-low-rate-with-home-loan-cover-home-loan-to-be-available-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कंपनियों का रेग्युलेटर नैशनल हाउजिंग बैंक (NHB) इंश्योरेंस इंस्टीट्यूट ऑफ इंडिया के साथ मिलकर एक ऐसा व्यापक फ्रेमवर्क बनाने पर काम कर रहा है, जिसमें होम लोन का रेट आधा पर्सेंटेज पॉइंट तक घटेगा, बशर्ते लोन लेने वाले इंश्योरेंस कवर लें। मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले सूत्रों ने बताया कि इसका मकसद डिफॉल्ट रिस्क घटाना भी है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NHB के नैशनल डायरेक्टर और चीफ एग्जिक्युटिव ऑफिसर श्रीराम कल्याणरमन ने ईटी से बातचीत में इस खबर को सही बताया। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम आपदा (संपत्ति) बीमा की संभावनाओं का पता लगाने के लिए इंश्योरेंस इंस्टीट्यूट ऑफ इंडिया के साथ मिलकर एक सर्वे कर रहे हैं। हम यह पता लगा रहे हैं कि क्या होम लोन लेते वक्त इंश्योरेंस कवर भी लेने पर कम लेंडिंग रेट ऑफर किया जा सकता है?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कल्याणरमन ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;इंश्योरेंस कवर से रिस्क प्रीमियम घटना चाहिए। इसका फायदा लेंडर्स कंज्यूमर्स को दे सकते हैं। यह प्रक्रिया पूरी होने पर आने वाले समय में हम एक व्यापक फ्रेमवर्क जारी करेंगे।&amp;rsquo; हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कंपनियों के बीच होम लोन बॉरोअर्स को प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस ऑफर करने का चलन बना है। मिसाल के लिए देश की सबसे बड़ी होम लोन प्रोवाइडर फर्म हाउजिंग डिवेलपमेंट फाइनैंस कॉर्पोरेशन (HDFC) प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस सहित नॉन-लाइफ इंश्योरेंस के लिए HDFC एर्गो प्रॉडक्ट्स ऑफर कर रही है। इसी तरह दीवान हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कॉर्पोरेशन (DHFL) अपनी शाखाओं के जरिए चोलामंडलम एमएस जनरल इंश्योरेंस प्रॉडक्ट्स बेचती है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ग्राहक ज्यादा कवरेज पर सस्ते प्रीमियम को तरजीह देते हैं। प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस आमतौर पर भूकंप, बाढ़, आतंकी घटनाओं, आगजनी से हुए नुकसान के अलावा साइक्लोन, आसमानी बिजली गिरने, तोड़फोड़ के चलते होने वाले वित्तीय घाटे से सुरक्षित करता है। फाइनैंशल इंस्टीट्यूशंस और बैंक की तरफ से कई मौकों पर कस्टमर्स को प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस लेने पर मजबूर किए जाने का आरोप लगता रहता है। बिहार, जम्मू कश्मीर, उत्तर प्रदेश, उत्तराखंड, गुजरात में हालिया प्राकृतिक आपदाओं ने स्टेकहोल्डर्स का घाटा घटाने के उपाय के तौर पर प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस की अहमियत बढ़ा दी है। मामले से जुड़े एग्जिक्युटिव ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;आधी कवायद हो चुकी है। हालांकि यह पूरी नहीं हुई है लेकिन इससे कम-से-कम आधा पर्सेंटेज पॉइंट का फायदा हो सकता है।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस मामले को एक उदाहरण से समझने की कोशिश करते हैं। अभी एक रिटेल होम लोन बॉरोअर 20 साल के लिए 8.6% के रेट से 1 लाख रुपये के होम लोन पर 874 रुपये का ईएमआई चुकाता है। अब इस लोन का रेट 50 बेसिस पॉइंट घटा दिया जाता है तो होम लोन कस्टमर का ईएमआई घटकर 842 रुपये रह जाएगा। यह एस्टीमेट क्रेडिट रेटिंग कंपनी इकरा ने दिया है। इकरा के सीनियर वीपी कार्तिक श्रीनिवासन ने कहा, &amp;lsquo;ऐसे उपाय को अगर अंतिम रूप दे दिया जाता है तो बॉरोअर्स को बहुत मदद मिलेगी। इससे उनको अपना रिस्क प्रोफाइल बेहतर बनाने में तो मदद मिलेगी ही, उनकी लोन लेने की क्षमता भी बढ़ेगी। उनको कम रेट या ज्यादा लोन मिल सकता है। इंश्योरेंस कवर की लागत बॉरोअर्स को उठानी होगी, फिर भी उनको फायदा होगा क्योंकि ऊंचे इंट्रेस्ट रेट के नजरिए से प्रीमियम मामूली होगा।&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;एनएचबी का कहना है कि प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस के लिए पारदर्शी और सहज ट्रांजैक्शन सिस्टम होने से कंज्यूमर्स, बैंक, हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कंपनियों जैसे लेंडिंग इंस्टीट्यूशंस और इंश्योरेंस कंपनियों का कॉन्फिडेंस बढ़ेगा और इससे कंज्यूमर्स को प्रॉपर्टी इंश्योरेंस के लिए खुद आगे आने के लिए बढ़ावा मिलेगा।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funds Transferred From Provident Fund To NPS Not Taxable: Regulator</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/funds-transferred-from-provident-fund-to-nps-not-taxable-regulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/funds-transferred-from-provident-fund-to-nps-not-taxable-regulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The transferred recognised provident fund or superannuation fund will not be treated as contribution of the current year by employee/employer and the subscriber would not be required to claim tax deduction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority (PFRDA) on Tuesday said funds transferred from a provident fund account to a National Pension System (NPS) account will not attract any tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The amount so transferred from recognised Provident Fund/Superannuation Fund to NPS is not treated as income of the current year and hence not taxable,&amp;rdquo; it said while specifying procedure for effecting transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the transferred recognised provident fund or superannuation fund will not be treated as contribution of the current year by employee/employer and the subscriber would not be required to claim tax deduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016-17 Budget, the government had announced that the subscribers from recognised Provident Funds and Superannuation Funds would be able to transfer their corpus from these funds to National Pension System (NPS) without any tax implication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A subscriber planning to transfer his PF funds will have to approach the Provident Fund/Superannuation Fund Trust through the current employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulator said the NPS is gaining momentum in comparison to other retirement products and it was receiving a number of queries related to transfer of amounts to NPS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI&#39;s Move To Impose Minimum Balance Penalty Faces Government Hurdle</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-move-to-impose-minimum-balance-penalty-faces-government-hurdle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-move-to-impose-minimum-balance-penalty-faces-government-hurdle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s biggest public sector bank, State Bank of India (SBI), announced that come April its savings bank account customers will have to maintain a higher monthly average balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s biggest public sector bank, State Bank of India (SBI), announced that come April its savings bank account customers will have to maintain a higher monthly average balance, a move which is seen as hitting 31 crore depositors. Otherwise the account holders of the SBI will have to pay a penalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Press Trust of India citing sources said that the government has asked SBI to reconsider its decision to levy penalty on non-maintenance of minimum balance. SBI has announced imposing penalty ranging from Rs. 20-100 on non-maintenance of Minimum Average Balance (MAB) in savings bank accounts from April 1. The penalty is as high as Rs. 500 in case of current accounts. The penalty for breach of minimum average balance is being reintroduced after a gap of five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs. 5,000 for branches in six metros. Savings bank account holders of SBI and its five associates - which will merge with it soon - will have to maintain the monthly balance. Else, they will have to pay a penalty ranging from Rs. 20 (in rural branches) to Rs. 100 (in metro cities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press Trust of India, also citing sources, said that SBI has been asked to reconsider charges it proposes to levy on cash transactions at branches over specified limits. Some private banks have started charging a minimum amount of Rs. 150 per transaction for cash deposits and withdrawals beyond four free transactions in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 GB Data For Rs 345: Airtel&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer offers comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tariff battle in the Indian telecom sector has further intensified with Bharti Airtel launching an aggressive mobile data plan to counter Reliance Jio. Market leader Bharti Airtel has announced a plan for select customers wherein its subscribers will be offered 28 GBs of  data along with free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;local and STD calls for a period of 28 days under a pack priced at Rs 345. Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer, though it will charge for its services from April 1. Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Prime plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;continues the benefits that the telecom arm of Reliance Industries had offered under its Happy New Year scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s Rs 303 Prime offer, for example, gives Jio subscribers free voice calls and a daily cap of 1 GB of internet data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel has also placed a limit on internet usage at 1 GB per day. Airtel customers can use 500 MBs of data during day and the remaining 500 MB data can be consumed between 12 am and 6 am, said a customer care executive of Bharti Airtel. Recently, Bharti Airtel chairman Sunil Mittal said that the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new tariff announced by Reliance Jio is very aggressive and unsustainable, and the industry will respond to it with more competitive plans and additional data offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tariffs that they (Jio) have announced are still very aggressive, which means you got to respond. You got to do more packages&amp;hellip; you have to throw in more data. All those things need to be done,&amp;rdquo; he had said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airtel had on February 27, 2017 waived domestic roaming charges to compete with free voice calls and roaming offered by Jio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jio has promised to match the best mobile data usage plan in the market and also add 20 per cent more data to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPhone 6 32GB Variant Offered At Discount On Amazon India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon India is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://aadhaarcardnews.in/images/iphone-6-32-gb-amazon-in-650-400_650x400_61488796030.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Apple iPhone 6 32GB variant in Space Grey option is being sold for Rs 28,999, instead of Rs 30,700, under a limited period scheme on Amazon India&amp;rsquo;s website. The iPhone 6 32GB variant scheme is open till March 7, 2017, Amazon India said. Amazon India, the Indian operations of American e-commerce giant Amazon, is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-few-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Here are few things to know:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 32GB variant of iPhone 6 is being offered by third-party retailers, not by Apple Inc itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers will be able to save Rs 1,701 or 6 per cent (inclusive of all taxes) under the scheme, the Amazon India website noted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the exchange option, customers can avail up to Rs 8,550 off for delivery to select locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orders can be placed via credit/debit cards and net banking. However cash on delivery or COD option is not available, as per the Amazon India website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;lsquo;One-Day Delivery&amp;rsquo; option is also available under the scheme, which guarantees delivery under one working day in select cities for items Fulfilled by Amazon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to analysts, sale of the 32GB variant is likely to attract good demand for Cupertino, California-based Apple Inc, which had launched iPhone 6 only in 16GB, 64GB and 128GB storage variants initially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers can also avail EMI options. &amp;ldquo;EMI available on HDFC Bank, Citibank, ICICI Bank, SBI Card, Standard Chartered Bank, Kotak Mahindra Bank, Axis Bank and HSBC credit cards&amp;hellip;Banks may charge you pre-closure and interest charges when you cancel/return an EMI order,&amp;rdquo; the Amazon India website     added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 32GB variant of iPhone 6 comes with a one-year manufacturer warranty for device and 6-month manufacturer warranty for in-box accessories including batteries from the date of purchase, it added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>