<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savings Account on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Savings Account on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>26 Chartered Accountants Under Watch In Crackdown On Shell Companies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26-chartered-accountants-under-watch-in-crackdown-on-shell-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26-chartered-accountants-under-watch-in-crackdown-on-shell-companies/</guid>
      <description>At least 26 chartered accountants have come under the scanner of the ICAI for allegedly helping shell companies, a senior official said. The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (ICAI) is the regulator for accountancy professionals and can initiate disciplinary action against erring members.
&amp;ldquo;The role of (around) 26 chartered accountants with respect to their alleged links with shell companies are being looked into by the institute,&amp;rdquo; ICAI President Nilesh Shivji Vikamsey told PTI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.27 Lakh Assessees Respond To Income Tax Query On Cash Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-27-lakh-assessees-respond-to-income-tax-query-on-cash-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-27-lakh-assessees-respond-to-income-tax-query-on-cash-deposits/</guid>
      <description>Responding to the SMS/email queries under &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo;, the assessees have disclosed additional 25,000 bank accounts in which cash was deposited.
The I-T Department on Monday said 5.27 lakh assessees, out of 18 lakh who were sent SMS/emails for making suspicious deposits post demonetisation, have submitted their response and warned others of &amp;lsquo;enforcement action&amp;rsquo; if they fail to respond by February 15.
It further said that 99.5 per cent of the 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar must to get government co-contribution for availing Atal Pension Yojana</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</guid>
      <description>The finance ministry on Monday said their subscribers of the Atal Pension Yojana (APY) will have to link their Aadhaar to their accounts for availing up to Rs 1,000 government’s co-contribution.
Any individual who is eligible to receive benefits under the APY will have to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo enrolment under Aadhaar authentication, the ministry said in a statement.
Pension regulator PFRDA has identified nearly 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</guid>
      <description>Both Apps uses Unified Payments Interface (UPI) technology to transfer money between any two individuals and between an individual and a merchant.
Navneet Dubey Moneycontrol News
Are you considering using one of the mobile payment apps launched by the government recently? If so, you may be confused on whether you should use the Aadhaar Payment App or Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM)?
Well, there are specific features of each of these apps which differentiate them which you should be aware of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Rush To Buy Cyber Security Cover As Digi Payments Rise</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-rush-to-buy-cyber-security-cover-as-digi-payments-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-rush-to-buy-cyber-security-cover-as-digi-payments-rise/</guid>
      <description>The government may cut back some of the plethora of socio-economic schemes that have outlived their utility as it uses outcome budgeting to assess the impact of central sector schemes, a top official said.
In a bid to improve quality of public expenditure, the finance ministry has asked every ministry to prepare outcome budget statement linking outlays against each scheme with deliverables achieved and their impact on economy and citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Call Drop Problem: No More Tricks, Telecom Minister Warns Operators</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</guid>
      <description>Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement
Refusing to lower his guard on the issue of call drops, Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement, which leaves no room for any manipulation. &amp;ldquo;We are looking at every aspect of call drop. No trick will work in this case,&amp;rdquo; Sinha told Press Trust of India in an interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.
“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.
He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI To Use Aadhaar For Verification In Recruitment Process</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-to-use-aadhaar-for-verification-in-recruitment-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-to-use-aadhaar-for-verification-in-recruitment-process/</guid>
      <description>State Bank of India or SBI plans to introduce Aadhaar to verify the identity of candidates across its recruitment processes effective July 1.
State Bank of India or SBI plans to introduce Aadhaar to verify the identity of candidates across its recruitment processes effective July 1. India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI, in a notice dated June 2, said: &amp;ldquo;Ascertaining the identities of candidates is critical for fair conduct of recruitment process and prevention of impersonation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Of Rs 200 Note To Fill The Missing Middle, Says SBI Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launch-of-rs-200-note-to-fill-the-missing-middle-says-sbi-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launch-of-rs-200-note-to-fill-the-missing-middle-says-sbi-report/</guid>
      <description>Introduction of Rs 200 note will fill in the &amp;ldquo;missing middle&amp;rdquo; even as the new currency in circulation (CIC) has already reached 84 per cent of the pre demonetisation level, says a report. Cash with banks, a CIC component, has however witnessed a decline over November 2016 level, said the State Bank of India Ecowrap report.
The data for June 23, 2017 shows cash in hand with banks declining to 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOVT plans app to rival Ola, Uber</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/driverless-cars-wont-be-allowed-in-india-nitin-gadkari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/driverless-cars-wont-be-allowed-in-india-nitin-gadkari/</guid>
      <description>India will not see driverless cars plying on its roads as Union minister for roads and transport Nitin Gadkari feels that his government would rather protect the jobs of millions of drivers here than see a technological marvel on the streets.
Bolstering his case, the minister said the technology in its present form wasn’t suited for the Indian market and will also render millions of Indian drivers jobless. Gadkari said the government was planning to launch a taxi booking app on the lines of Ola and Uber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Considering To Change Financial Year To January-December</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-considering-to-change-financial-year-to-january-december-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-considering-to-change-financial-year-to-january-december-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday told lawmakers that the government is considering to change the country&amp;rsquo;s financial year to January-December from April-March.
&amp;ldquo;The matter of changing financial year is under consideration,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jaitley told lawmakers in a written reply to the lower house of Parliament.
He declined to elaborate whether the budget presentation would be advanced to November or December from February 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government: Digital Transactions In All Co-Operative Banks By 2018</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-transactions-in-all-co-operative-banks-by-2018-says-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-transactions-in-all-co-operative-banks-by-2018-says-government/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) on Monday said all co-operative banks in the country would be part of digital transactions by March 2018.
&amp;ldquo;The Unified Payments Interface (UPI) ecosystem now covers all public sector undertakings and major private banks. We are in the process of extending the service for co-operative bank. All co-operative banks, which computerised their operation, would be part of digital transactions,&amp;rdquo; said NPCI Managing Director and CEO A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s what you should do if your smartphone gets stolen</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-you-should-do-if-your-smartphone-gets-stolen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-you-should-do-if-your-smartphone-gets-stolen/</guid>
      <description>All it takes is a moment of carelessness, an open handbag or an opportunist pickpocket and your smartphone can disappear from right under your nose. Here are some of the things you should do if your smartphone gets stolen this summer.
_Act quickly _
It&amp;rsquo;s highly likely that your smartphone was stolen while it was switched on and ready to use. Quickly call your mobile operator to get your line blocked before the thief has the time to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to pick the right insurance company: Here are 4 brief points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-pick-the-right-insurance-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-pick-the-right-insurance-company/</guid>
      <description>Having chosen a life partner and settling down to a secure job, one would normally be enjoying a happy and contented life. Soon a new life between the two may propel them ahead with a wonderful bonding. However, often in solitude or even in the midst of celebrations he may start worrying about how to protect the future of his loved ones from any unforeseen event. Quite naturally, the bread earner starts looking for some kind of financial protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Phone: 5 things every buyer wants to know before buying the Reliance Jio 4G feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-5-things-every-buyer-wants-to-know-before-buying-the-reliance-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-5-things-every-buyer-wants-to-know-before-buying-the-reliance-jio/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio Phone was unveiled by Mukesh Ambani recently, and this is a really unique feature phone, mainly because of the 4G VoLTE connectivity, ability to play Jio apps like JioTV and JioMusic. However, there is some confusion on the specs and features of the Reliance Jio 4G feature phone.
Reliance Jio Phone was unveiled by Mukesh Ambani recently, and this is a really unique feature phone, mainly because of the 4G VoLTE connectivity, ability to play Jio apps like JioTV and JioMusic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Pension Scheme Offers &#39;Respectable&#39; Returns To Elders: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-pension-scheme-offers-respectable-returns-to-elders-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-pension-scheme-offers-respectable-returns-to-elders-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today said the Pradhan Mantri Vaya Vandana Yojana (PMVVY) will provide a &amp;ldquo;respectable&amp;rdquo; rate of return to senior citizens at a time when interest rates are falling globally.
PMVVY is a pension scheme exclusively for senior citizens (aged 60 years and above) which is available from May 4, 2017 to May 3, 2018.
It provides an assured return of 8 per cent per annum payable monthly (equivalent to 8.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>