<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Department Identifies 18 Lakh People With Suspicious Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-18-lakh-people-with-suspicious-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-18-lakh-people-with-suspicious-deposits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These people will have to reply within 10 days to avoid any notice from the tax department or further enforcement action.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax department has identified 18 lakh people who have made &amp;lsquo;suspicious&amp;rsquo; cash deposits post demonetisation, including those having deposited over Rs 5 lakh, and will send emails and SMSes seeking explanation about their source of funds. These people will have to reply within 10 days to avoid any notice from the tax department or further enforcement action. The department on Tuesday launched &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo; project under which CBDT, with data analysis and profiling of assessees, will send e-communications to people whose cash deposits post November 8 note ban do not match their income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Operation Clean Money/Swachh Dhan Abhiyan is a programming software which will be used to get answers on all the deposits made and after preliminary answers from the people. Then only, if need be, we would take legal action against those people,&amp;rdquo; Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) Chairman Sushil Chandra said 10 days&amp;rsquo; time would be given to people to reply to the e-communication and replies can be filed by logging on to the e-filing portal of the Income Tax department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the initial phase, we are putting data of those persons who have deposited Rs 5 lakh or more and deposits between Rs 3 lakh and Rs 5 lakh of suspicious nature and who have poor tax compliance after November 8,&amp;rdquo; Chandra said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, this will cover 18 lakh tax payers whose data will be uploaded on e-filing portal. These people while filing reply have to explain to tax department the sources of deposit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandra said that tax department has compiled huge data which shows that there are over 1 crore accounts where above Rs 2 lakh money have been deposited and involves unique PAN of 70 lakh persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have compared these vast data with the income profile, turnover and the various other particulars of income available in the income tax data bank. In the first phase where the deposits in account are not matching with our data, we are putting the same on our e-filing portal seeking explanation of source of income,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandra said the intention of the scheme is to avoid any harassment to the tax payer, they need not come to office and online verification would be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Swachh Dhan Abhiyan is a continuous exercise to widen and deepen the tax base. All the accounts in which money has been deposited will be tracked and we have hired the data analytics and we will identify the ultimate beneficiaries even in layered accounts,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Pay Arrears Immediately&#39;: Income Tax Department Names Five Defaulters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pay-arrears-immediately-income-tax-department-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pay-arrears-immediately-income-tax-department-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The taxman has begun this exercise of naming and shaming tax defaulters for the last few years and had named at least 96 such entities which have huge tax liabilities on them and have either gone non-traceable or have shown no assets for recovery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Income Tax Department on Thursday published names of five entities owing over Rs 10 crore in taxes, as part of its strategy to name and shame big defaulters. In an advertisement issued in leading national dailies, the department brought out the list of defaulters of income tax and corporate tax even as it advised them to pay their &amp;ldquo;tax arrears immediately&amp;rdquo;. The Income Tax Department has begun this exercise of naming and shaming tax defaulters for the last few years and had named at least 96 such entities which have huge tax liabilities on them and have either gone non-traceable or have shown no assets for recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest list has names of five such alleged defaulters, based in Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior official said the public list, with details of the individual or entity like their PAN card number (in certain cases), last known address and assessment range and defaulted amount of tax, is also aimed to make aware the people at large so that they can inform the department in case they have some inputs against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The entries in the list are specific to the tax arrears and assessment year mentioned. The tax defaulter&amp;rsquo;s address, business, shareholding and management may have changed,&amp;rdquo; the notice issued by the Principal Chief Commissioner of Income Tax (New Delhi) said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total taxes due by these five defaulters is Rs 10.27 crore, the notice said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT), the policy-making body of the Income Tax Department, had few years back adopted the strategy of bringing out the names of chronic defaulters in public domain and had also begun posting these names on its official website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Income Tax Department recently launched an online facility to correct errors in names and other details in permanent account number (PAN) and Aadhaar documents. Alongside the facility to link biometric identifier Aadhaar with PAN, the department also put two separate hyperlinks on its e-filing website - one to update changes in existing PAN data or for application of new PAN by an Indian or a foreign citizen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICICI, Axis, SBI Gain, RBI To Get Power To Act Against Loan Defaulters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Union Cabinet cleared an ordinance empowering the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to act against wilful defaulters. The ordinance has been sent to the president for approval. The ordinance is aimed at empowering RBI to deal more effectively with stressed assets than earlier. A senior finance ministry official said &amp;ldquo;It is part of a broader plan to resolve bad loans with banks&amp;rsquo; issue that has been a major hurdle in the economy from achieving its full potential.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking sub-index on the NSE Nifty Bank index rose to its record high following this development. The index advanced as much as 2 per cent to hit record high of 22,743.70. Sub-index of the public-sector banks Nifty PSU index also rallied over 3 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinance may enable RBI to direct banks on how to deal with stressed assets. Moving an amendment to the banking regulation act may take time as the next session of parliament starts sometime after second week of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amended law will also empower RBI to set up oversight panels that will shield bankers from later action by probe agencies looking into loan recasts as a lot of discretion will be involved in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By December 2016, non-performing assets (NPAs) or bad loans with Indian banks rose to Rs. 6.07 lakh crore, of which the share of Public sector banks was Rs. 5.02 lakh crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysts say the ordinance is a positive step towards banks recovering their dues from the defaulters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kishor Ostwal of CNI Research, says &amp;ldquo;Because of this ordinance there will be more and more recovery of bad loans and wilful defaulters which have money will come out and repay their debts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the individual banking shares, ICICI Bank was the top gainer, rose 9.18 per cent to Rs 297.8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canara Bank, Bank of Baroda, State Bank of India, IDFC Bank, Punjab National Bank and Axis Bank were also among the other gainer in the banking sun-index rising between 1-3.5 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the state-run lenders, Union Bank, Andhra Bank, IDBI Bank and  Allahabad Bank also rallied up to 4 per cent each.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Call Drop Problem: No More Tricks, Telecom Minister Warns Operators</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refusing to lower his guard on the issue of call drops, Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement, which leaves no room for any manipulation. &amp;ldquo;We are looking at every aspect of call drop. No trick will work in this case,&amp;rdquo; Sinha told Press Trust of India in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent report from the Department of Telecom (DoT) had said call drops had come down by seven per cent in three months between December 2016 to March 2017. The minister was responding to a query on whether the DoT has taken into account the prolonged use of &amp;lsquo;radio link timeout&amp;rsquo;, a technology that prevents disconnection of calls even if there is no or weak signal. Usually, in such cases, the customer ends up disconnecting the call without it showing up as a call drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not only the DoT report, but even Trai releases official report every quarter&amp;hellip; they clearly show that there is a significant reduction in call drop. However, it is a matter of continuous monitoring. Also, the manner in which BTS (Base Transceiver Stations) have been installed in last 8-9 months is a record,&amp;rdquo; Sinha noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telecom operators had informed the government that they installed more than 1.60 lakh additional BTS or mobile sites across the country between June 15 and December 31, 2016 and another 1.1 lakh additional mobile sites were committed by March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per a report of the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India, all operators have met call drop standard norms in the three months ended June and September. In October-December 2016, Trai found performance of Aircel below par for call drops in most circles. The DoT has set up an IVRS or automated call system which makes random calls to subscribers to check status of call drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinha said the IVRS is helping the government in identifying blind spots in areas that do not receive mobile signals or get weak ones. &amp;ldquo;The IVRS system makes an average 2600-2700 calls everyday. It is helping us in identifying those blind spots where there are regular call drops and telecom service providers are informed about it. They (telecom operators) are trying to sort it out,&amp;rdquo; Sinha added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister emphasised that the government is boosting telecom connectivity across the country, including optical fibre rollout in village panchayats, the North-East and even in Left wing extremism-affected areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have been successful in connecting 91,000 panchayats. In coming 15-20 days, we will meet our target of connecting one lakh panchayats. There was problem of equipment. It was an indigenous technology developed by (state-owned company) C-DOT. Vendors were not available. It took a lot of time in testing,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 50 thousand such equipment have been supplied by Tejas Networks, ITI Ltd and L&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I feel that from next week onwards (optical fibre) in as many as 300 villages per day will be lit. Thereafter, the pace will increase to 400 villages per day. Right now, it is around 100 villages,&amp;rdquo; Sinha said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prasad also said 4.47 crore bank accounts have been opened with Aadhaar eKYC as compared to only one lakh accounts opened as of May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the government has linked the BHIM app with Aadhaar so that transactions through the app happens in a transparent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Check If Your Employer Has Deposited Your Income Tax</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26as-how-to-check-your-income-tax-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26as-how-to-check-your-income-tax-credit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In case there is a mismatch in TDS figures in Form 16 and Form 26AS, one should approach his/her employer or respective entity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax return filing season has started from April 1. Usually, for many salaried employees, the first thing that comes to mind is Form 16 that is issued by employers. But another document - Form 26AS - is also a crucial document that a salaried individual should access before filing tax returns. Form 16 is a document from your employer, certifying that TDS or tax deducted at source has been deducted on your salary. Form 26AS is basically your tax credit statement which shows all taxes received by the Income Tax Department. You can access Form 26AS from the tax department&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is extremely important to go through the Form 26AS to ensure that all due credits for TDS deducted from a person&amp;rsquo;s salary, FD interest, etc. are duly accounted for,&amp;rdquo; said Sandeep Sehgal, director of tax and regulatory at Ashok Maheshwary &amp;amp; Associates LLP. &amp;ldquo;Any shortfall of TDS reflected in Form 26AS than what is actually claimable in the income tax return will result in automatic generation of demand by Centralized Processing Centre of Income Tax Department subsequent to filing of income tax return.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, it could also be problematic for the tax payer when excess TDS is reflected in Form 26AS. &amp;ldquo;Income Tax Department may question the person for the corresponding income which the person may not have shown in his/her income tax return. Hence, to avoid such hassles, it is necessary to tally the due TDS credit with Form 26AS,&amp;rdquo; adds Mr Sehgal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case there is a mismatch in TDS figures in Form 16 and Form 26AS, Mr Sehgal says the &amp;ldquo;person should approach the his/her employer or respective entity which has deducted TDS on any of his income and tell them to get their TDS return rectified to adjust.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The taxpayer can also see the refund received by him/her for previous assessment year in Form 26AS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-access-your-form-26as&#34;&gt;How to access your Form 26AS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the income tax department&amp;rsquo;s website for tax filing (incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in) and log into your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &amp;lsquo;My Account&amp;rsquo; tab and select Form 26AS from the drop down menu; After confirmation, the taxpayer will be directed to TDS Reconciliation Analysis and Correction Enabling System (TRACES) website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The taxpayer can then select the assessment year and format in which he/she would like to view Form 26AS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Password for Form 26AS PDF/text file is Date of Birth as printed on PAN card. Enter date in ddmmyyyy format to open file (e.g., for 10-Oct-2012, enter as 10102012).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxpayers can also view Form 26AS through net banking facility. Select banks offer this facility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar essential for getting fellowships, scholarships from UGC, AICTE</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-essential-getting-fellowships-scholarships-ugc-aicte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-essential-getting-fellowships-scholarships-ugc-aicte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to an order issued by the Human Resource Development (HRD) ministry on Wednesday, students seeking government scholarships and fellowships will need to declare Aadhaar numbers by the end of June, putting yet another of its benefits programme behind the Unique Identity project wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The order covers fellowship schemes implemented by the University Grants Commission and the All India Council for Technical Education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The use of Aadhaar as identity document for delivery of services or benefits or subsidies simplifies the government delivery processes, brings in transparency and efficiency, and enables beneficiaries to get their entitlements directly in a convenient and seamless manner and Aadhaar obviates the need for producing multiple documents to prove one’s identity,” the government stated in its notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students have till June 30 to declare their Aadhaar numbers, or apply for one and declare the enrolment number, to their respective colleges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification came into effect from Wednesday, covering all states excluding Assam, Meghalaya and Jammu and Kashmir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, activists have criticised the government’s move to make the Aadhaar programme – the enrolment to a national database with biometric information such as fingerprints and iris scans – must for those drawing state benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The criticism has centred around a Supreme Court order in September last year, when it said that people without UID numbers must not be denied assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NITI&#39;s vision: Houses, vehicles, ACs for all by 2032</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-vision-houses-vehicles-acs-for-all-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-vision-houses-vehicles-acs-for-all-by/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government think tank NITI Aayog has envisaged a new India in which all citizens in 15 years will have houses with toilets, two-wheelers or cars, power, air conditioners and digital connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a glimpse of Vision 2031-32 presented by the NITI Aayog Vice-Chairman Arvind Panagariya to the body&amp;rsquo;s Governing Council, chaired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, at a meeting held yesterday in the presence of chief ministers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The India 2031-32: Vision, Strategy and Action Agenda also visualises a fully literate society with universal access to health care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also calls for having a much larger and modern network of roads, railways, waterways and air connectivity and a clean India where citizens would have access to quality air and water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is envisions that per capita income would increase three fold to Rs 3.14 lakh in 2031-32 from Rs 1.06 lakh in 2015-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, it states that the country&amp;rsquo;s gross domestic product or economy would rise to Rs 469 lakh crore in 2031-32 from Rs 137 lakh crore level in 2015-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vision says that the central and state expenditure will rise by Rs 92 lakh crore in 2031-32 to Rs 130 lakh crore from Rs 38 lakh crore in 2015-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work on the Fifteen Year Vision and Seven Year Strategy document spanning 2017-18 to 2031-32 is in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Three Year Action Agenda covering 2017-18 to 2019-20 was circulated to the Governing Council Members yesterday and would be finalised shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the vision presentation, all efforts had to be made to realise the Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s vision of a vibrant India by 2031-32.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We must transform India into a prosperous, healthy, secure, corruption-free, energy abundant, environmentally clean and globally influential nation,&amp;rdquo; the presentation added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF Withdrawal Easier For Education, Hospital Bills: 10 Facts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-documents-just-self-declaration-for-provident-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-documents-just-self-declaration-for-provident-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EFPO subscribers can seek withdrawal from their employee provident fund (EPF) account on various grounds by using a composite form along with a self-declaration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO or Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation has made partial withdrawal easier from provident fund for medical and other purposes like purchase of house, education and marriage of children. The subscriber is no longer required to submit various certificates or documents. EFPO subscribers can seek withdrawal from their employee provident fund (EPF) account on various grounds by using a composite form along with a self-declaration. The submission of composite claim form signed by the EPF subscriber shall be construed as &amp;lsquo;self-certification&amp;rsquo; for partial withdrawals, according to the retirement fund body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are 10 things to know:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) EPFO&amp;rsquo;s latest move to ease the withdrawal process will benefit nearly 4 crore subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) The subscribers can seek advance from the fund for treatment of illness in certain cases including hospitalisation lasting for one month or more, or major surgical operation in a hospital, or in case they are suffering from TB, leprosy, paralysis, cancer, mental derangement or heart ailment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Earlier, the members were required to submit a certificate from a doctor of the hospital that the member or his dependent has been hospitalised or requires hospitalisation for one month or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Now after change in employee provident fund laws, a member would no longer be required to submit any medical certificate or document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) For medical purpose, an EPFO subscriber can withdraw up to six months of salary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) EPPO has been taking a number of steps to ease withdrawal rules. Recently, it allowed subscribers to withdraw up to 90 per cent of their funds for home/land purchase. It also allowed payment of home loan EMIs by using the provident fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Partial provident fund withdrawal is also allowed for post-matriculation education of children and marriage purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) For various withdrawal purposes, the subscriber is now only required to submit a self-declaration, which is included in a claim form, to avail advance from the provident fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Subscribers who have seeded their Universal Account Number (UAN) with Aadhaar and bank account details can submit claim forms directly to EPFO without the attestation of employers. A universal account number allows provident fund number portability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) However, in cases where Aadhaar has not been seeded, the attestation of employers is required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how your petrol pump might be cheating you right in front of your eyes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-your-petrol-pump-might-be-cheating-you-in-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-your-petrol-pump-might-be-cheating-you-in-front/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A series of raids by Uttar Pradesh Special Task Force (STF) in Lucknow yesterday have revealed how petrol pumps are cheating consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most consumers only check the display of the fuel dispensing machine for the amount and the quantity of the fuel filled but the raids show that the pumps were using a remote-controlled electronic chip to dupe consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is how petrol pumps are cheating you:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Petrol pumps install a chip inside the fuel dispensing machine, which is designed to reduce the fuel output by nearly five to ten per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The chip is attached to a wire, which sets the limit through a remote control. So, if you are buying one-litre of petrol, the machine will release only 940 ml.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such chips cost around Rs 3,000 a piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The STF suspects that the chips have been sold to a large number of pumps. As per STF estimate, a petrol pump using this chip earns an undue profit of around Rs 14 lakh per month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory For Subsidy: Indian Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a bid to curb corruption in the Public Distribution System (PDS), the Indian government had made the Aadhar Card mandatory for availing foodgrain subsidy at PDS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has already made Aadhar Card mandatory for the cooking gas LPG subsidy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has declared Rs 1.4 lakh crore subsidy under the food security law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A timeline till June 30 is given for the common people who avail subsidy to apply for Aadhar Card, the government categorically stated in the notification in this regard that no subsidised foodgrains with Aadhaar after June 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since November 2016, the Government of India, under the National Food Security Law (NFSA), has been providing 5 kg of foodgrains per person per month at Rs 1-3/kg to over 80 crore people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification has been applicable from February 8 in all States and Union Territories (UTs) except Assam, Meghalaya and Jammu and Kashmir. This move indicates Government’s serious intetion of digitisation to curb the corruption in PDS as well as a move towards a simplifies delivery process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Proposal To Withdraw New 2,000 Rupee Notes: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday said there is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 notes that were introduced post demonetisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 denomination banknote,&amp;rdquo; the minister said in a written reply in the Lok Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley further said the Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes returned to currency chests of the RBI amounted to Rs 12.44 lakh crore (as on December 10, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data obtained in this regard would need to be reconciled with the physical cash balances to eliminate counterfeit notes, accounting errors and possible double counts after which only the final figures will be arrived at, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added that as on March 3, 2017 the currency in circulation was Rs 12 lakh crore and as on January 27, it was Rs 9.921 lakh crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley said the cash recall seeks to create a new &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; wherein the GDP will be bigger, cleaner and real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This exercise is part of the government&amp;rsquo;s resolve to eliminate corruption, blackmoney, counterfeit currency and terror funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This exercise has resulted in an increase in deposits with banks. This will facilitate reduction of interest rates and provide more headroom to banks to expand their credit base,&amp;rdquo; the minister said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following demonetisation, several restrictions were imposed on withdrawal from banks as well as ATMs. The restrictions have been gradually removed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BSNL Is Planning To Counter Reliance Jio, Airtel, Others</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new plan gives 2GB of 3G data per day at Rs 339&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlimited calling within its network is also applicable under the plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-run &lt;em&gt;Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited&lt;/em&gt; (BSNL) announced a new plan which offers 2GB of 3G data per day with unlimited calling within its network for Rs 339. In an effort to take on the service providers like Reliance Jio, Airtel and others, BSNL will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks and after that the users will be charged 25 paise per minute. The company further said that the data of 2GB per day is one of the best in the industry. The limited offer for prepaid services comes with a validity of 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are committed to providing affordable and efficient services to all segment of our loyal mobile customers. We offer best prices to our customers considering present trend of Indian telecom industry,&amp;rdquo; BSNL Director for Consumer Mobility RK Mittal said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance Jio is offering 1GB of 4G data and unlimited calling to all network till March 31. From April 1, users opting for Jio Prime service will get unlimited data and calls till March 31, 2018, for one time registration fee of Rs 99 and Rs 303 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharti Airtel has also introduced its &amp;lsquo;Surprise offer&amp;rsquo; which will give free 30GB data for three months, starting March 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offers from Airtel or other operators comes in wake of the telecom war started by the new entrant Reliance Jio in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea To Sell 1GB 2G, 3G, 4G Mobile Data At Same Price From March End</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present, Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision in the wake of stiff competition in the market&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with a month validity for Rs 170&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telecom operator Idea Cellular will start selling 1GB and above mobile data plans across its 2G, 3G and 4G network at same price by the end of this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Idea has now announced that it will allow open market data recharges of 1GB and above to work on Idea&amp;rsquo;s 2G, 3G or 4G network without any differential prices and this will be rolled out nationally by March 31, 2017,&amp;rdquo; Idea said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates. Due to stiff competition in the market from Reliance Jio, the 4G mobile data service of Idea is significantly cheaper than 2G service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the high speed data plans were priced higher based on their download speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Customer can choose the recharge price basis usage and volume available in pack, without having to worry about the platform the customer&amp;rsquo;s device is logged in,&amp;rdquo; Idea Cellular Chief Marketing Officer Sashi Shankar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea will bring all data product categories like sachets, freedom packs to unified pricing and will be rolled out nationally in phases by May 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Idea&amp;rsquo;s pan India broadband coverage continues to expand and reduces gap with existing 2G coverage which covers 4 lakh towns and villages, customers can now seamlessly migrate services between technology &amp;amp; platform without worrying about differential costs,&amp;rdquo; Shankar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data limit in high speed internet plans gets exhausted in less time compared to that on slow speed network like 2G.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plastic Rs 10 Note Could Be A Reality Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plastic-rs10-note-could-be-a-reality-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plastic-rs10-note-could-be-a-reality-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has been authorised to conduct field trials for printing plastic Rs 10 denomination notes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has been authorised to conduct field trials for printing plastic Rs 10 denomination notes which will have a longer life span, Parliament was informed on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Approval for procurement of plastic substrate and printing of bank notes of Rs 10 denomination on plastic banknote substrates has been conveyed to the RBI,&amp;rdquo; Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal told the Lok Sabha in a written reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Substrate denotes the underlying substance or layer on which currency is printed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister said the government had decided to conduct field trials at five locations of the country with plastic banknotes, which are expected to last longer than cotton substrate-based banknotes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>