<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savings Account on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Savings Account on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</guid>
      <description>Both Apps uses Unified Payments Interface (UPI) technology to transfer money between any two individuals and between an individual and a merchant.
Navneet Dubey Moneycontrol News
Are you considering using one of the mobile payment apps launched by the government recently? If so, you may be confused on whether you should use the Aadhaar Payment App or Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM)?
Well, there are specific features of each of these apps which differentiate them which you should be aware of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI To Use Aadhaar For Verification In Recruitment Process</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-to-use-aadhaar-for-verification-in-recruitment-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-to-use-aadhaar-for-verification-in-recruitment-process/</guid>
      <description>State Bank of India or SBI plans to introduce Aadhaar to verify the identity of candidates across its recruitment processes effective July 1.
State Bank of India or SBI plans to introduce Aadhaar to verify the identity of candidates across its recruitment processes effective July 1. India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI, in a notice dated June 2, said: &amp;ldquo;Ascertaining the identities of candidates is critical for fair conduct of recruitment process and prevention of impersonation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar must to get government co-contribution for availing Atal Pension Yojana</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</guid>
      <description>The finance ministry on Monday said their subscribers of the Atal Pension Yojana (APY) will have to link their Aadhaar to their accounts for availing up to Rs 1,000 government’s co-contribution.
Any individual who is eligible to receive benefits under the APY will have to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo enrolment under Aadhaar authentication, the ministry said in a statement.
Pension regulator PFRDA has identified nearly 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s next President:10 things about Draupdi Murmu, the woman who could be India&#39;s next President</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-things-about-draupdi-murmu-the-woman-who-could-be-indias-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-things-about-draupdi-murmu-the-woman-who-could-be-indias-next/</guid>
      <description>With the new president of India set to be elected next month, several names are doing the rounds including those of BJP veteran Najma Heptullah and Mahatma Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s writer grandson Rajmohan Gandhi. Many say Prime Minister Narendra Modi has decided Jharkhand Governor and BJP leader Draupdi Murmu to be the party candidate.
Very few people know about Murmu outside eastern states. Here are 10 things to know about the woman who can be the next president of the country:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI new Rs 500 currency. Here&#39;s what is different in new notes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</guid>
      <description>The Reserve Banks of India (RBI) today announced introduction of new Rs 500 currency notes.
The new version will have few different aspects. The one noticeable aspect of the new currency notes is the inclusion of an inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;.
Besides, in the new notes the signature of the RBI Governor will be on the reverse side.
  &amp;ldquo;In continuation of issuing of Rs 500 denomination banknotes in Mahatma Gandhi (new) series from time to time which are currently legal tender, a new batch of banknotes with inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; in both the number panels bearing the signature of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 12. Vodafone Announces New Ramzan Plans.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-announces-new-ramzan-plans-starting-at-rs-12-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-announces-new-ramzan-plans-starting-at-rs-12-details/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone also said it will offer unlimited voice calling, unlimited national roaming and 1GB data per day in plans priced at Rs 342 and Rs 442.
Telecom operator Vodafone India announced new Ramzan offers for its prepaid users. The new plans, called &amp;ldquo;Ramzan 342 and 442&amp;rdquo;, are valid for users in Karnataka, Vodafone India said in a release. Under the offer, users can avail of unlimited 2G data at Rs 5 per hour and unlimited 3G/4G data at Rs 19 per hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mVisa can be use for booking Railway Tickets</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/travellers-can-now-book-railway-tickets-using-mvisa-payment-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/travellers-can-now-book-railway-tickets-using-mvisa-payment-solution/</guid>
      <description>Rail travellers can now book tickets by mVisa payment method which allows them to scan a quick response (QR) code and pay through smartphones.
Users can securely link their visa debit, credit or prepaid account to the mVisa application on their smartphones and make their travel bookings by simply scanning their mVisa QR code on the Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation website.
IRCTC, a subsidiary of the Indian Railways, is offering a promotion offer until September 4 that will give Rs 50 cashback to consumers booking their tickets through mVisa scan and pay on the IRCTC website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-aadhaar-is-being-challenged/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-aadhaar-is-being-challenged/</guid>
      <description>Six articles that explain why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court
•Aadhaar is vulnerable to identity theft because of its design and the way it is used: A centralised database, dual use as identifier and authenticator, and lack of sound legal framework are its main weaknesses.
•Amid the debate about privacy, the more pressing issue of exclusion has been forgotten: Exclusion due to authentication errors and deactivation have an immediate impact on millions of people across India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks To Start Charging For Person To Person Payments On UPI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</guid>
      <description>SBI is charging Rs 5 per transaction of up to Rs 1 lakh, Rs 15 for transactions between Rs 1-2 lakh and Rs 25 for those between Rs 2 lakh and Rs 5 lakh, while HDFC Bank is proposing Rs 3 for transactions of up to Rs 25,000 and Rs 5 for those between Rs 25,000 and Rs 1 lakh.
Nearly two years after operationalisation of the Unified Payment Interface (UPI), banks have started moving to charge for peer-to-peer payments on the new platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Fine If Your SBI Account Has No Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.
State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest lender, has decided to increase manifold the minimum balance required for maintaining savings account from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.
The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Department Identifies 18 Lakh People With Suspicious Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-18-lakh-people-with-suspicious-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-18-lakh-people-with-suspicious-deposits/</guid>
      <description>These people will have to reply within 10 days to avoid any notice from the tax department or further enforcement action.
The Income Tax department has identified 18 lakh people who have made &amp;lsquo;suspicious&amp;rsquo; cash deposits post demonetisation, including those having deposited over Rs 5 lakh, and will send emails and SMSes seeking explanation about their source of funds. These people will have to reply within 10 days to avoid any notice from the tax department or further enforcement action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Call Drop Problem: No More Tricks, Telecom Minister Warns Operators</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</guid>
      <description>Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement
Refusing to lower his guard on the issue of call drops, Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement, which leaves no room for any manipulation. &amp;ldquo;We are looking at every aspect of call drop. No trick will work in this case,&amp;rdquo; Sinha told Press Trust of India in an interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICICI, Axis, SBI Gain, RBI To Get Power To Act Against Loan Defaulters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</guid>
      <description>The Union Cabinet cleared an ordinance empowering the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to act against wilful defaulters. The ordinance has been sent to the president for approval. The ordinance is aimed at empowering RBI to deal more effectively with stressed assets than earlier. A senior finance ministry official said &amp;ldquo;It is part of a broader plan to resolve bad loans with banks&amp;rsquo; issue that has been a major hurdle in the economy from achieving its full potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.
“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.
He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST To Lower Tax Burden On Medical Devices, Smartphones: Finance Ministry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-lower-tax-burden-on-medical-devices-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-lower-tax-burden-on-medical-devices-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>The Goods and Services Tax (GST) will lead to lower tax burden in several commodities, including packaged cement, medicaments, smartphones and medical devices, the Finance Ministry said on Tuesday.
&amp;ldquo;Packaged cement attracts central excise duty of 12.5 per cent plus Rs 125 PMT (per metric tonne) and standard VAT (value-added tax) rate of 14.5 per cent. At these rates, the present total tax incidence works out to more than 29 per cent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST To Smoothen Taxation, Bring In Transparency: Experts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-smoothen-taxation-bring-in-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-smoothen-taxation-bring-in-transparency/</guid>
      <description>At an interactive awareness programme for start-ups, the experts said the government is expected to resolve the queries of entrepreneurs regarding GST.
GST will not only ease the process of taxation, but bring in transparency, say experts.
At an interactive awareness programme for start-ups here, the experts said the government is expected to resolve the queries of entrepreneurs regarding GST.
&amp;ldquo;GST will not only ease the process, but also bring transparency as all the invoices needed to be uploaded by sellers are visible to the buyer every month,&amp;rdquo; said Manish Ojha, Development Head of KDK Softwares Pvt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Plan Of Affordable Housing For All By 2022</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-real-estate-act-will-boost-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-real-estate-act-will-boost-housing/</guid>
      <description>The government has backed its Housing for All by 2022 promise with a slew of reforms for buyers and developers alike.
The Indian real estate sector has seen a resurgence of interest in 2017 after a slowdown over the past 2-3 years, buoyed by the affordable housing segment, which includes residential units below Rs 50 lakh. Legislations the like Real Estate (Regulation and Development) Act, 2016, (RERA) and Goods and Services Tax (GST) have signalled that the government is ready to walk the talk for its &amp;lsquo;Housing for All&amp;rsquo; by 2022 promise and many developers and institutional players have flocked to the affordable housing market, a report by Colliers International India, the Indian wing of a global commercial real estate company said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modi government is firming up a plan to create India&#39;s own Harvard</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/hrd-ministry-seeks-cabinet-nod-for-20-world-class-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/hrd-ministry-seeks-cabinet-nod-for-20-world-class-institutions/</guid>
      <description>India has taken a firm step towards building 20 world-class educational institutions, which will be termed Institutions of Eminence, with the human resource development ministry moving the proposal to the Union Cabinet for approval. Firmly bearing the stamp of the Prime Minister’s Office, this is a new framework to catapult Indian institutions to global recognition by freeing the best of them from the University Grants Commission’s restrictive regulatory regime and ushering in an unprecedented level of institutional autonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Pay Arrears Immediately&#39;: Income Tax Department Names Five Defaulters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pay-arrears-immediately-income-tax-department-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pay-arrears-immediately-income-tax-department-names/</guid>
      <description>The taxman has begun this exercise of naming and shaming tax defaulters for the last few years and had named at least 96 such entities which have huge tax liabilities on them and have either gone non-traceable or have shown no assets for recovery.
The Income Tax Department on Thursday published names of five entities owing over Rs 10 crore in taxes, as part of its strategy to name and shame big defaulters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Check If Your Employer Has Deposited Your Income Tax</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26as-how-to-check-your-income-tax-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26as-how-to-check-your-income-tax-credit/</guid>
      <description>In case there is a mismatch in TDS figures in Form 16 and Form 26AS, one should approach his/her employer or respective entity.
The tax return filing season has started from April 1. Usually, for many salaried employees, the first thing that comes to mind is Form 16 that is issued by employers. But another document - Form 26AS - is also a crucial document that a salaried individual should access before filing tax returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar essential for getting fellowships, scholarships from UGC, AICTE</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-essential-getting-fellowships-scholarships-ugc-aicte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-essential-getting-fellowships-scholarships-ugc-aicte/</guid>
      <description>According to an order issued by the Human Resource Development (HRD) ministry on Wednesday, students seeking government scholarships and fellowships will need to declare Aadhaar numbers by the end of June, putting yet another of its benefits programme behind the Unique Identity project wall.
The order covers fellowship schemes implemented by the University Grants Commission and the All India Council for Technical Education.
“The use of Aadhaar as identity document for delivery of services or benefits or subsidies simplifies the government delivery processes, brings in transparency and efficiency, and enables beneficiaries to get their entitlements directly in a convenient and seamless manner and Aadhaar obviates the need for producing multiple documents to prove one’s identity,” the government stated in its notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NITI&#39;s vision: Houses, vehicles, ACs for all by 2032</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-vision-houses-vehicles-acs-for-all-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-vision-houses-vehicles-acs-for-all-by/</guid>
      <description>Government think tank NITI Aayog has envisaged a new India in which all citizens in 15 years will have houses with toilets, two-wheelers or cars, power, air conditioners and digital connectivity.
This is a glimpse of Vision 2031-32 presented by the NITI Aayog Vice-Chairman Arvind Panagariya to the body&amp;rsquo;s Governing Council, chaired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, at a meeting held yesterday in the presence of chief ministers.
The India 2031-32: Vision, Strategy and Action Agenda also visualises a fully literate society with universal access to health care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF Withdrawal Easier For Education, Hospital Bills: 10 Facts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-documents-just-self-declaration-for-provident-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-documents-just-self-declaration-for-provident-fund/</guid>
      <description>EFPO subscribers can seek withdrawal from their employee provident fund (EPF) account on various grounds by using a composite form along with a self-declaration.
EPFO or Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation has made partial withdrawal easier from provident fund for medical and other purposes like purchase of house, education and marriage of children. The subscriber is no longer required to submit various certificates or documents. EFPO subscribers can seek withdrawal from their employee provident fund (EPF) account on various grounds by using a composite form along with a self-declaration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how your petrol pump might be cheating you right in front of your eyes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-your-petrol-pump-might-be-cheating-you-in-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-your-petrol-pump-might-be-cheating-you-in-front/</guid>
      <description>A series of raids by Uttar Pradesh Special Task Force (STF) in Lucknow yesterday have revealed how petrol pumps are cheating consumers.
Most consumers only check the display of the fuel dispensing machine for the amount and the quantity of the fuel filled but the raids show that the pumps were using a remote-controlled electronic chip to dupe consumers.
This is how petrol pumps are cheating you:
 Petrol pumps install a chip inside the fuel dispensing machine, which is designed to reduce the fuel output by nearly five to ten per cent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory For Subsidy: Indian Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to curb corruption in the Public Distribution System (PDS), the Indian government had made the Aadhar Card mandatory for availing foodgrain subsidy at PDS.
The government has already made Aadhar Card mandatory for the cooking gas LPG subsidy.
The government has declared Rs 1.4 lakh crore subsidy under the food security law.
A timeline till June 30 is given for the common people who avail subsidy to apply for Aadhar Card, the government categorically stated in the notification in this regard that no subsidised foodgrains with Aadhaar after June 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Proposal To Withdraw New 2,000 Rupee Notes: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.
Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday said there is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 notes that were introduced post demonetisation.
The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BSNL Is Planning To Counter Reliance Jio, Airtel, Others</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.
HIGHLIGHTS  BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new plan gives 2GB of 3G data per day at Rs 339
 It will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea To Sell 1GB 2G, 3G, 4G Mobile Data At Same Price From March End</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</guid>
      <description>Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.
HIGHLIGHTS  At present, Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates
 The decision in the wake of stiff competition in the market
 Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with a month validity for Rs 170
  Telecom operator Idea Cellular will start selling 1GB and above mobile data plans across its 2G, 3G and 4G network at same price by the end of this month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plastic Rs 10 Note Could Be A Reality Soon</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plastic-rs10-note-could-be-a-reality-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/plastic-rs10-note-could-be-a-reality-soon/</guid>
      <description>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has been authorised to conduct field trials for printing plastic Rs 10 denomination notes.
The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has been authorised to conduct field trials for printing plastic Rs 10 denomination notes which will have a longer life span, Parliament was informed on Friday.
&amp;ldquo;Approval for procurement of plastic substrate and printing of bank notes of Rs 10 denomination on plastic banknote substrates has been conveyed to the RBI,&amp;rdquo; Minister of State for Finance Arjun Ram Meghwal told the Lok Sabha in a written reply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जल्द मिलेगा होम लोन कवर के साथ कम रेट का फायदा!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/profit-of-low-rate-with-home-loan-cover-home-loan-to-be-available-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/profit-of-low-rate-with-home-loan-cover-home-loan-to-be-available-soon/</guid>
      <description>हाउजिंग फाइनैंस कंपनियों का रेग्युलेटर नैशनल हाउजिंग बैंक (NHB) इंश्योरेंस इंस्टीट्यूट ऑफ इंडिया के साथ मिलकर एक ऐसा व्यापक फ्रेमवर्क बनाने पर काम कर रहा है, जिसमें होम लोन का रेट आधा पर्सेंटेज पॉइंट तक घटेगा, बशर्ते लोन लेने वाले इंश्योरेंस कवर लें। मामले की जानकारी रखने वाले सूत्रों ने बताया कि इसका मकसद डिफॉल्ट रिस्क घटाना भी है।
NHB के नैशनल डायरेक्टर और चीफ एग्जिक्युटिव ऑफिसर श्रीराम कल्याणरमन ने ईटी से बातचीत में इस खबर को सही बताया। उन्होंने कहा, &amp;lsquo;हम आपदा (संपत्ति) बीमा की संभावनाओं का पता लगाने के लिए इंश्योरेंस इंस्टीट्यूट ऑफ इंडिया के साथ मिलकर एक सर्वे कर रहे हैं। हम यह पता लगा रहे हैं कि क्या होम लोन लेते वक्त इंश्योरेंस कवर भी लेने पर कम लेंडिंग रेट ऑफर किया जा सकता है?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funds Transferred From Provident Fund To NPS Not Taxable: Regulator</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/funds-transferred-from-provident-fund-to-nps-not-taxable-regulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/funds-transferred-from-provident-fund-to-nps-not-taxable-regulator/</guid>
      <description>The transferred recognised provident fund or superannuation fund will not be treated as contribution of the current year by employee/employer and the subscriber would not be required to claim tax deduction.
The Pension Fund Regulatory and Development Authority (PFRDA) on Tuesday said funds transferred from a provident fund account to a National Pension System (NPS) account will not attract any tax.
&amp;ldquo;The amount so transferred from recognised Provident Fund/Superannuation Fund to NPS is not treated as income of the current year and hence not taxable,&amp;rdquo; it said while specifying procedure for effecting transfers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI&#39;s Move To Impose Minimum Balance Penalty Faces Government Hurdle</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-move-to-impose-minimum-balance-penalty-faces-government-hurdle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbis-move-to-impose-minimum-balance-penalty-faces-government-hurdle/</guid>
      <description>India&amp;rsquo;s biggest public sector bank, State Bank of India (SBI), announced that come April its savings bank account customers will have to maintain a higher monthly average balance.
India&amp;rsquo;s biggest public sector bank, State Bank of India (SBI), announced that come April its savings bank account customers will have to maintain a higher monthly average balance, a move which is seen as hitting 31 crore depositors. Otherwise the account holders of the SBI will have to pay a penalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 GB Data For Rs 345: Airtel&#39;s Latest Offer To Counter Jio</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/28-gb-data-for-rs-345-airtels-latest-offer-to-counter-jio/</guid>
      <description>Airtel&amp;rsquo;s Rs 345 offer offers comes days after billionaire investor Mukesh Ambani-controlled Reliance Jio announced a new &amp;lsquo;Prime&amp;rsquo; membership offer.
The tariff battle in the Indian telecom sector has further intensified with Bharti Airtel launching an aggressive mobile data plan to counter Reliance Jio. Market leader Bharti Airtel has announced a plan for select customers wherein its subscribers will be offered 28 GBs of data along with free
local and STD calls for a period of 28 days under a pack priced at Rs 345.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPhone 6 32GB Variant Offered At Discount On Amazon India</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/apple-iphone-6-32gb-variant-offered-at-discount-on-amazon-india/</guid>
      <description>Amazon India is also offering exchange option for purchase of the iPhone 6 32GB smartphone in Space Grey colour at select locations, as per its website.
 The Apple iPhone 6 32GB variant in Space Grey option is being sold for Rs 28,999, instead of Rs 30,700, under a limited period scheme on Amazon India&amp;rsquo;s website. The iPhone 6 32GB variant scheme is open till March 7, 2017, Amazon India said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Average Download Speed Doubles In January, Says Telecom Regulator</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-average-download-speed-doubles-in-january-says-telecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-average-download-speed-doubles-in-january-says-telecom/</guid>
      <description>TRAI collects and computes speed of mobile data from subscribers across the country with the help of the MySpeed application on a real time basis.
Average peak download speed on Reliance Jio&amp;rsquo;s network more than doubled to 17.42 megabit per second at the end of January, according to data by the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI).
The monthly average mobile broadband speed published by the telecom regulator showed that the download speed on Jio network reached 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Asked To Reconsider Penalty For Not Keeping Minimum Balance: Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-asked-to-reconsider-penalty-for-not-keeping-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-asked-to-reconsider-penalty-for-not-keeping-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>State Bank of India, according to a source, has also been asked to reconsider charges it proposes to levy on cash transactions and ATM withdrawals over specified limits.
The government on Monday asked State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s largest lender, to reconsider its decision to levy penalty on non-maintenance of minimum balance, which the bank plans to hike manifold from April 1 impacting over 31 crore savings bank account holders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All banks must enable mobile banking by March 31: Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-banks-must-enable-mobile-banking-by-march-31-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/all-banks-must-enable-mobile-banking-by-march-31-government/</guid>
      <description>The government on Friday said it has asked banks to provide mobile banking facility to all customers by the end of the current fiscal on March 31.
In a move to promote digital transactions post-demonetisation, the government on Friday said it has asked banks to provide mobile banking facility to all customers by the end of the current fiscal on March 31. “Ministry issues advisory to banks to enable mobile seeding, Aadhaar seeding of bank</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI Announces Penalty For Not Keeping Minimum Balance In Accounts </title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-penalty-for-non-maintenance-of-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-announces-penalty-for-non-maintenance-of-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>Making maintenance of Rs 5,000 mandatory for accounts in metropolitan areas, Rs 3,000 in urban areas, Rs 2,000 in semi-urban areas and Rs 1,000 in rural areas, the SBI listed out the charges to be effective from April 1.
Making it compulsory for account-holders to maintain a minimum balance, the State Bank of India (SBI) on Thursday said it will be charging defaulters a penalty from April 1 onwards.
Making maintenance of Rs 5,000 mandatory for accounts in metropolitan areas, Rs 3,000 in urban areas, Rs 2,000 in semi-urban areas and Rs 1,000 in rural areas, the SBI listed out the charges to be effective from April 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Takes Issue Of Defaulters Very Seriously: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-takes-issue-of-defaulters-very-seriously-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/india-takes-issue-of-defaulters-very-seriously-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>The Union Minister for Finance and Corporate Affairs is set to meet UK Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson later today, when the issue may come up.
Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Monday said the Indian government takes the issue of defaulters very seriously and indicated that he may raise the issue of defaulters based in Britain with the UK government, in an apparent reference to liquor baron Vijay Mallya.
&amp;ldquo;Certainly, when the opportunity does come, I do take that opportunity to mention it (issue of defaulters based in Britain) to my counterparts here,&amp;rdquo; he told reporters here when asked if the issue of defaulters based in the UK will feature on the agenda of his discussions with British ministers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senior Citizen Savings Scheme: 10 Things You Should Know Before Investing</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/senior-citizen-savings-scheme-10-things-you-should-know-before-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/senior-citizen-savings-scheme-10-things-you-should-know-before-investing/</guid>
      <description>Due to the benefits offered under the Senior Citizen Savings Scheme like higher returns, less risk factor and tax savings option, it is becoming a popular choice among the retirees.
To invest wisely is the main responsibility after retirement. Choosing an investment plan which offers fair returns and security is very important. The Senior Citizen Savings Scheme (SCSS) under the Post Office Savings Schemes is preferably the most effective way for that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>