<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savings Account on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Savings Account on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Of Rs 200 Note To Fill The Missing Middle, Says SBI Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launch-of-rs-200-note-to-fill-the-missing-middle-says-sbi-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launch-of-rs-200-note-to-fill-the-missing-middle-says-sbi-report/</guid>
      <description>Introduction of Rs 200 note will fill in the &amp;ldquo;missing middle&amp;rdquo; even as the new currency in circulation (CIC) has already reached 84 per cent of the pre demonetisation level, says a report. Cash with banks, a CIC component, has however witnessed a decline over November 2016 level, said the State Bank of India Ecowrap report.
The data for June 23, 2017 shows cash in hand with banks declining to 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26 Chartered Accountants Under Watch In Crackdown On Shell Companies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26-chartered-accountants-under-watch-in-crackdown-on-shell-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26-chartered-accountants-under-watch-in-crackdown-on-shell-companies/</guid>
      <description>At least 26 chartered accountants have come under the scanner of the ICAI for allegedly helping shell companies, a senior official said. The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (ICAI) is the regulator for accountancy professionals and can initiate disciplinary action against erring members.
&amp;ldquo;The role of (around) 26 chartered accountants with respect to their alleged links with shell companies are being looked into by the institute,&amp;rdquo; ICAI President Nilesh Shivji Vikamsey told PTI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOVT plans app to rival Ola, Uber</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/driverless-cars-wont-be-allowed-in-india-nitin-gadkari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/driverless-cars-wont-be-allowed-in-india-nitin-gadkari/</guid>
      <description>India will not see driverless cars plying on its roads as Union minister for roads and transport Nitin Gadkari feels that his government would rather protect the jobs of millions of drivers here than see a technological marvel on the streets.
Bolstering his case, the minister said the technology in its present form wasn’t suited for the Indian market and will also render millions of Indian drivers jobless. Gadkari said the government was planning to launch a taxi booking app on the lines of Ola and Uber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Considering To Change Financial Year To January-December</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-considering-to-change-financial-year-to-january-december-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-considering-to-change-financial-year-to-january-december-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday told lawmakers that the government is considering to change the country&amp;rsquo;s financial year to January-December from April-March.
&amp;ldquo;The matter of changing financial year is under consideration,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jaitley told lawmakers in a written reply to the lower house of Parliament.
He declined to elaborate whether the budget presentation would be advanced to November or December from February 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government: Digital Transactions In All Co-Operative Banks By 2018</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-transactions-in-all-co-operative-banks-by-2018-says-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-transactions-in-all-co-operative-banks-by-2018-says-government/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) on Monday said all co-operative banks in the country would be part of digital transactions by March 2018.
&amp;ldquo;The Unified Payments Interface (UPI) ecosystem now covers all public sector undertakings and major private banks. We are in the process of extending the service for co-operative bank. All co-operative banks, which computerised their operation, would be part of digital transactions,&amp;rdquo; said NPCI Managing Director and CEO A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s what you should do if your smartphone gets stolen</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-you-should-do-if-your-smartphone-gets-stolen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-you-should-do-if-your-smartphone-gets-stolen/</guid>
      <description>All it takes is a moment of carelessness, an open handbag or an opportunist pickpocket and your smartphone can disappear from right under your nose. Here are some of the things you should do if your smartphone gets stolen this summer.
_Act quickly _
It&amp;rsquo;s highly likely that your smartphone was stolen while it was switched on and ready to use. Quickly call your mobile operator to get your line blocked before the thief has the time to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to pick the right insurance company: Here are 4 brief points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-pick-the-right-insurance-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-pick-the-right-insurance-company/</guid>
      <description>Having chosen a life partner and settling down to a secure job, one would normally be enjoying a happy and contented life. Soon a new life between the two may propel them ahead with a wonderful bonding. However, often in solitude or even in the midst of celebrations he may start worrying about how to protect the future of his loved ones from any unforeseen event. Quite naturally, the bread earner starts looking for some kind of financial protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Phone: 5 things every buyer wants to know before buying the Reliance Jio 4G feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-5-things-every-buyer-wants-to-know-before-buying-the-reliance-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-5-things-every-buyer-wants-to-know-before-buying-the-reliance-jio/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio Phone was unveiled by Mukesh Ambani recently, and this is a really unique feature phone, mainly because of the 4G VoLTE connectivity, ability to play Jio apps like JioTV and JioMusic. However, there is some confusion on the specs and features of the Reliance Jio 4G feature phone.
Reliance Jio Phone was unveiled by Mukesh Ambani recently, and this is a really unique feature phone, mainly because of the 4G VoLTE connectivity, ability to play Jio apps like JioTV and JioMusic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Pension Scheme Offers &#39;Respectable&#39; Returns To Elders: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-pension-scheme-offers-respectable-returns-to-elders-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-pension-scheme-offers-respectable-returns-to-elders-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today said the Pradhan Mantri Vaya Vandana Yojana (PMVVY) will provide a &amp;ldquo;respectable&amp;rdquo; rate of return to senior citizens at a time when interest rates are falling globally.
PMVVY is a pension scheme exclusively for senior citizens (aged 60 years and above) which is available from May 4, 2017 to May 3, 2018.
It provides an assured return of 8 per cent per annum payable monthly (equivalent to 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI new Rs 500 currency. Here&#39;s what is different in new notes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</guid>
      <description>The Reserve Banks of India (RBI) today announced introduction of new Rs 500 currency notes.
The new version will have few different aspects. The one noticeable aspect of the new currency notes is the inclusion of an inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;.
Besides, in the new notes the signature of the RBI Governor will be on the reverse side.
  &amp;ldquo;In continuation of issuing of Rs 500 denomination banknotes in Mahatma Gandhi (new) series from time to time which are currently legal tender, a new batch of banknotes with inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; in both the number panels bearing the signature of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 153 Unlimited Plan; Idea, Airtel Shares Slump</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jiophone-launched-with-rs-153-unlimited-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jiophone-launched-with-rs-153-unlimited-plan/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani today launched JioPhone, meant for feature phone users with a Rs 153 unlimited monthly tariff plan. This announcement led to a sharp fall in Bharti Airtel and Idea Cellular share prices. JioPhone will be available from September, effectively free for Jio users. Jio will charge Rs 1,500 towards security deposit for the JioPhone, refundable after three years. On the JioPhone, voice will always be free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon, you can charge your smartphone just by waving or walking!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-you-can-charge-your-smartphone-just-by-waving-or-walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-you-can-charge-your-smartphone-just-by-waving-or-walking/</guid>
      <description>Scientists, including one of Indian origin, have developed an ultra-thin device that can power your smartphone, fitness tracker and other gadgets using human movements such as walking and waving.
Based on battery technology and made from layers of black phosphorus that are only a few atoms thick, the energy harvesting system generates small amounts of electricity when it is bent or pressed even at the extremely low frequencies characteristic of human motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonetisation again? There are signs of another currency ban coming</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-again-there-are-signs-of-another-currency-ban-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-again-there-are-signs-of-another-currency-ban-coming/</guid>
      <description>Is the Central government quietly planning another round of demonetisation? A large number of people believe the Rs 2,000 note will be scrapped. Now the talk has reached Parliament too.
The Opposition in Rajya Sabha today asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley to clarify whether the government has decided to scrap the newly launched Rs 2,000 note. However, Jaitley did not respond even as many Opposition members insisted for clarification from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have You Filed Your Income Tax Return? Key Changes To Know This Year</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/have-you-filed-your-income-tax-return-key-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/have-you-filed-your-income-tax-return-key-changes/</guid>
      <description>Filing of income tax return (ITR) has changed this year with regard to the forms to be used. The Income Tax Department has prescribed new forms for filing tax returns. Listed below are some major changes in the ITR forms due to which you will have to fill these forms differently this year.
1) Simplified one-page ITR form for salaried class taxpayers
Changes in ITR 1 Sahaj form
Now the government has notified a simplified one-page form, called &amp;lsquo;ITR-1 Sahaj&amp;rsquo;, for individuals earning income from salary, pension, one house property and income from other sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistakes in filing income tax returns that may get you a tax notice</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mistakes-in-filing-income-tax-returns-that-may-get-you-a-tax-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mistakes-in-filing-income-tax-returns-that-may-get-you-a-tax-notice/</guid>
      <description>Some common mistakes that taxpayers often make while filing income tax returns are listed below. These errors could result in problems or a tax notice for the tax payers later on. Consequently, it is best to avoid them.
Here are some of the mistakes that are often made by the taxpayers.
 Filing ITR using the wrong form As per tax laws, an individual is required to report all sources of income and file the income tax return using the correct form applicable to him.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>