<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savings Account on Latest news </title>
    <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Savings Account on Latest news </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tags/savings-account/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar must to get government co-contribution for availing Atal Pension Yojana</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-must-get-government-co-contribution-availing-atal-pension-yojana/</guid>
      <description>The finance ministry on Monday said their subscribers of the Atal Pension Yojana (APY) will have to link their Aadhaar to their accounts for availing up to Rs 1,000 government’s co-contribution.
Any individual who is eligible to receive benefits under the APY will have to furnish proof of possession of Aadhaar number or undergo enrolment under Aadhaar authentication, the ministry said in a statement.
Pension regulator PFRDA has identified nearly 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Without Aadhaar Enrolment Centres To Face Fine From October</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-without-aadhaar-enrolment-centres-to-face-fine-from-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-without-aadhaar-enrolment-centres-to-face-fine-from-october/</guid>
      <description>The UIDAI has given banks one more month to open Aadhaar enrolment centres in a stipulated 10 per cent of branches and will impose Rs. 20,000 as fine per uncovered branch after September 30, CEO Ajay Bhushan Pandey said today.
The Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), in July, had asked private as well as public banks to open Aadhaar enrolment and updation facility in one out of 10 branches by August-end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government: Digital Transactions In All Co-Operative Banks By 2018</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-transactions-in-all-co-operative-banks-by-2018-says-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/digital-transactions-in-all-co-operative-banks-by-2018-says-government/</guid>
      <description>The National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) on Monday said all co-operative banks in the country would be part of digital transactions by March 2018.
&amp;ldquo;The Unified Payments Interface (UPI) ecosystem now covers all public sector undertakings and major private banks. We are in the process of extending the service for co-operative bank. All co-operative banks, which computerised their operation, would be part of digital transactions,&amp;rdquo; said NPCI Managing Director and CEO A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>119 banks connected with Aadhaar-enabled payment system: Minister</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/119-banks-connected-aadhaar-enabled-payment-system-minister/</guid>
      <description>The government on Friday said 119 banks are connected with the Aadhaar-enabled payment system and 33.87 crore transactions have taken place through Aadhaar-enabled payment systems.
“There are 111 crore Aadhaar enrolments done so far out of the total population of 125 crore in India. Aadhaar is becoming a powerful instrument to bridge the digital divide,” Ravi Shankar Prasad, Minister of Information Technology, said here.
He said ₹36,000 crore has been saved in the last two years due to the linking of Aadhaar with the public distribution system including household LPG supply and MGNREGA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.27 Lakh Assessees Respond To Income Tax Query On Cash Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-27-lakh-assessees-respond-to-income-tax-query-on-cash-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/5-27-lakh-assessees-respond-to-income-tax-query-on-cash-deposits/</guid>
      <description>Responding to the SMS/email queries under &amp;lsquo;Operation Clean Money&amp;rsquo;, the assessees have disclosed additional 25,000 bank accounts in which cash was deposited.
The I-T Department on Monday said 5.27 lakh assessees, out of 18 lakh who were sent SMS/emails for making suspicious deposits post demonetisation, have submitted their response and warned others of &amp;lsquo;enforcement action&amp;rsquo; if they fail to respond by February 15.
It further said that 99.5 per cent of the 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26 Chartered Accountants Under Watch In Crackdown On Shell Companies</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26-chartered-accountants-under-watch-in-crackdown-on-shell-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26-chartered-accountants-under-watch-in-crackdown-on-shell-companies/</guid>
      <description>At least 26 chartered accountants have come under the scanner of the ICAI for allegedly helping shell companies, a senior official said. The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (ICAI) is the regulator for accountancy professionals and can initiate disciplinary action against erring members.
&amp;ldquo;The role of (around) 26 chartered accountants with respect to their alleged links with shell companies are being looked into by the institute,&amp;rdquo; ICAI President Nilesh Shivji Vikamsey told PTI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Of Rs 200 Note To Fill The Missing Middle, Says SBI Report</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launch-of-rs-200-note-to-fill-the-missing-middle-says-sbi-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/launch-of-rs-200-note-to-fill-the-missing-middle-says-sbi-report/</guid>
      <description>Introduction of Rs 200 note will fill in the &amp;ldquo;missing middle&amp;rdquo; even as the new currency in circulation (CIC) has already reached 84 per cent of the pre demonetisation level, says a report. Cash with banks, a CIC component, has however witnessed a decline over November 2016 level, said the State Bank of India Ecowrap report.
The data for June 23, 2017 shows cash in hand with banks declining to 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Rush To Buy Cyber Security Cover As Digi Payments Rise</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-rush-to-buy-cyber-security-cover-as-digi-payments-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-rush-to-buy-cyber-security-cover-as-digi-payments-rise/</guid>
      <description>The government may cut back some of the plethora of socio-economic schemes that have outlived their utility as it uses outcome budgeting to assess the impact of central sector schemes, a top official said.
In a bid to improve quality of public expenditure, the finance ministry has asked every ministry to prepare outcome budget statement linking outlays against each scheme with deliverables achieved and their impact on economy and citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-pay-vs-bhim-app-suits-making-payments/</guid>
      <description>Both Apps uses Unified Payments Interface (UPI) technology to transfer money between any two individuals and between an individual and a merchant.
Navneet Dubey Moneycontrol News
Are you considering using one of the mobile payment apps launched by the government recently? If so, you may be confused on whether you should use the Aadhaar Payment App or Bharat Interface for Money (BHIM)?
Well, there are specific features of each of these apps which differentiate them which you should be aware of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Call Drop Problem: No More Tricks, Telecom Minister Warns Operators</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indias-call-drop-problem-no-more-tricks-telecom-ministe/</guid>
      <description>Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement
Refusing to lower his guard on the issue of call drops, Telecom Minister Manoj Sinha today said his ministry is keeping a watchful eye on all factors of call drop measurement, which leaves no room for any manipulation. &amp;ldquo;We are looking at every aspect of call drop. No trick will work in this case,&amp;rdquo; Sinha told Press Trust of India in an interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBI To Use Aadhaar For Verification In Recruitment Process</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-to-use-aadhaar-for-verification-in-recruitment-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/sbi-to-use-aadhaar-for-verification-in-recruitment-process/</guid>
      <description>State Bank of India or SBI plans to introduce Aadhaar to verify the identity of candidates across its recruitment processes effective July 1.
State Bank of India or SBI plans to introduce Aadhaar to verify the identity of candidates across its recruitment processes effective July 1. India&amp;rsquo;s largest bank SBI, in a notice dated June 2, said: &amp;ldquo;Ascertaining the identities of candidates is critical for fair conduct of recruitment process and prevention of impersonation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOVT plans app to rival Ola, Uber</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/driverless-cars-wont-be-allowed-in-india-nitin-gadkari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/driverless-cars-wont-be-allowed-in-india-nitin-gadkari/</guid>
      <description>India will not see driverless cars plying on its roads as Union minister for roads and transport Nitin Gadkari feels that his government would rather protect the jobs of millions of drivers here than see a technological marvel on the streets.
Bolstering his case, the minister said the technology in its present form wasn’t suited for the Indian market and will also render millions of Indian drivers jobless. Gadkari said the government was planning to launch a taxi booking app on the lines of Ola and Uber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Considering To Change Financial Year To January-December</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-considering-to-change-financial-year-to-january-december-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/government-considering-to-change-financial-year-to-january-december-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday told lawmakers that the government is considering to change the country&amp;rsquo;s financial year to January-December from April-March.
&amp;ldquo;The matter of changing financial year is under consideration,&amp;rdquo; Mr Jaitley told lawmakers in a written reply to the lower house of Parliament.
He declined to elaborate whether the budget presentation would be advanced to November or December from February 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s what you should do if your smartphone gets stolen</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-you-should-do-if-your-smartphone-gets-stolen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/what-you-should-do-if-your-smartphone-gets-stolen/</guid>
      <description>All it takes is a moment of carelessness, an open handbag or an opportunist pickpocket and your smartphone can disappear from right under your nose. Here are some of the things you should do if your smartphone gets stolen this summer.
_Act quickly _
It&amp;rsquo;s highly likely that your smartphone was stolen while it was switched on and ready to use. Quickly call your mobile operator to get your line blocked before the thief has the time to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to pick the right insurance company: Here are 4 brief points</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-pick-the-right-insurance-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-to-pick-the-right-insurance-company/</guid>
      <description>Having chosen a life partner and settling down to a secure job, one would normally be enjoying a happy and contented life. Soon a new life between the two may propel them ahead with a wonderful bonding. However, often in solitude or even in the midst of celebrations he may start worrying about how to protect the future of his loved ones from any unforeseen event. Quite naturally, the bread earner starts looking for some kind of financial protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jio Phone: 5 things every buyer wants to know before buying the Reliance Jio 4G feature phone</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-5-things-every-buyer-wants-to-know-before-buying-the-reliance-jio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jio-phone-5-things-every-buyer-wants-to-know-before-buying-the-reliance-jio/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Jio Phone was unveiled by Mukesh Ambani recently, and this is a really unique feature phone, mainly because of the 4G VoLTE connectivity, ability to play Jio apps like JioTV and JioMusic. However, there is some confusion on the specs and features of the Reliance Jio 4G feature phone.
Reliance Jio Phone was unveiled by Mukesh Ambani recently, and this is a really unique feature phone, mainly because of the 4G VoLTE connectivity, ability to play Jio apps like JioTV and JioMusic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Pension Scheme Offers &#39;Respectable&#39; Returns To Elders: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-pension-scheme-offers-respectable-returns-to-elders-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/new-pension-scheme-offers-respectable-returns-to-elders-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today said the Pradhan Mantri Vaya Vandana Yojana (PMVVY) will provide a &amp;ldquo;respectable&amp;rdquo; rate of return to senior citizens at a time when interest rates are falling globally.
PMVVY is a pension scheme exclusively for senior citizens (aged 60 years and above) which is available from May 4, 2017 to May 3, 2018.
It provides an assured return of 8 per cent per annum payable monthly (equivalent to 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBI new Rs 500 currency. Here&#39;s what is different in new notes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/rbi-introduces-new-rs-500-currency-heres-whats-different-in-new-notes/</guid>
      <description>The Reserve Banks of India (RBI) today announced introduction of new Rs 500 currency notes.
The new version will have few different aspects. The one noticeable aspect of the new currency notes is the inclusion of an inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;.
Besides, in the new notes the signature of the RBI Governor will be on the reverse side.
  &amp;ldquo;In continuation of issuing of Rs 500 denomination banknotes in Mahatma Gandhi (new) series from time to time which are currently legal tender, a new batch of banknotes with inset letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; in both the number panels bearing the signature of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 153 Unlimited Plan; Idea, Airtel Shares Slump</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jiophone-launched-with-rs-153-unlimited-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/jiophone-launched-with-rs-153-unlimited-plan/</guid>
      <description>Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani today launched JioPhone, meant for feature phone users with a Rs 153 unlimited monthly tariff plan. This announcement led to a sharp fall in Bharti Airtel and Idea Cellular share prices. JioPhone will be available from September, effectively free for Jio users. Jio will charge Rs 1,500 towards security deposit for the JioPhone, refundable after three years. On the JioPhone, voice will always be free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon, you can charge your smartphone just by waving or walking!</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-you-can-charge-your-smartphone-just-by-waving-or-walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/soon-you-can-charge-your-smartphone-just-by-waving-or-walking/</guid>
      <description>Scientists, including one of Indian origin, have developed an ultra-thin device that can power your smartphone, fitness tracker and other gadgets using human movements such as walking and waving.
Based on battery technology and made from layers of black phosphorus that are only a few atoms thick, the energy harvesting system generates small amounts of electricity when it is bent or pressed even at the extremely low frequencies characteristic of human motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonetisation again? There are signs of another currency ban coming</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-again-there-are-signs-of-another-currency-ban-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/demonetisation-again-there-are-signs-of-another-currency-ban-coming/</guid>
      <description>Is the Central government quietly planning another round of demonetisation? A large number of people believe the Rs 2,000 note will be scrapped. Now the talk has reached Parliament too.
The Opposition in Rajya Sabha today asked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley to clarify whether the government has decided to scrap the newly launched Rs 2,000 note. However, Jaitley did not respond even as many Opposition members insisted for clarification from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have You Filed Your Income Tax Return? Key Changes To Know This Year</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/have-you-filed-your-income-tax-return-key-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/have-you-filed-your-income-tax-return-key-changes/</guid>
      <description>Filing of income tax return (ITR) has changed this year with regard to the forms to be used. The Income Tax Department has prescribed new forms for filing tax returns. Listed below are some major changes in the ITR forms due to which you will have to fill these forms differently this year.
1) Simplified one-page ITR form for salaried class taxpayers
Changes in ITR 1 Sahaj form
Now the government has notified a simplified one-page form, called &amp;lsquo;ITR-1 Sahaj&amp;rsquo;, for individuals earning income from salary, pension, one house property and income from other sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistakes in filing income tax returns that may get you a tax notice</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mistakes-in-filing-income-tax-returns-that-may-get-you-a-tax-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/mistakes-in-filing-income-tax-returns-that-may-get-you-a-tax-notice/</guid>
      <description>Some common mistakes that taxpayers often make while filing income tax returns are listed below. These errors could result in problems or a tax notice for the tax payers later on. Consequently, it is best to avoid them.
Here are some of the mistakes that are often made by the taxpayers.
 Filing ITR using the wrong form As per tax laws, an individual is required to report all sources of income and file the income tax return using the correct form applicable to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modi&#39;s war on bad debt: Why you might not see more Vijay Mallyas in future</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modis-war-on-bad-debt-why-you-might-not-see-more-vijay-mallyas-in-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/modis-war-on-bad-debt-why-you-might-not-see-more-vijay-mallyas-in-future/</guid>
      <description>Just two years ago, when Prime Minister Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s government was planning to clean up the bad debt of state banks, it seemed a messy and arduous task. But slowly, the government has tightened its grip on the problem.
After the Centre brought in the Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code, 2016 and backed it up with several other measures, the message for India Inc is loud and clear &amp;ndash; Default is a dangerous situation to be in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No penalty for late ITR this year but here are 4 important reasons to file it in time</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-penalty-for-late-itr-this-year-but-here-are-4-important-reasons-to-file-it-in-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-penalty-for-late-itr-this-year-but-here-are-4-important-reasons-to-file-it-in-time/</guid>
      <description>The due date for filing income tax return for individuals - July 31 - is fast approaching but several people think that if one has paid all one&amp;rsquo;s taxes there is no adverse consequence even if one misses the tax return filing deadline. This is more so because the proposed penalty for delayed filing of income tax return kicks in from next year and is not applicable for returns filed for FY16-17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxman Probing 30,000 Cases Where ITRs Revised Post-Notes Ban</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/taxman-probing-30-000-cases-where-itrs-revised-post-notes-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/taxman-probing-30-000-cases-where-itrs-revised-post-notes-ban/</guid>
      <description>The Income Tax Department is probing over 30,000 cases of alleged tax evasion wherein the income tax returns (ITRs) were revised by assessees post-demonetisation, Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) chief Sushil Chandra said on Monday. The ITRs filed after November 8 last year were scrutinised against their earlier tax compliance following which these cases were detected, he said. &amp;ldquo;We are taking action in these instances,&amp;rdquo; Mr Chandra told reporters on the sidelines of an event to mark the 157th Income Tax day here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks To Start Charging For Person To Person Payments On UPI</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/indian-railways-to-cut-shatabdi-short-run-train-fares/</guid>
      <description>SBI is charging Rs 5 per transaction of up to Rs 1 lakh, Rs 15 for transactions between Rs 1-2 lakh and Rs 25 for those between Rs 2 lakh and Rs 5 lakh, while HDFC Bank is proposing Rs 3 for transactions of up to Rs 25,000 and Rs 5 for those between Rs 25,000 and Rs 1 lakh.
Nearly two years after operationalisation of the Unified Payment Interface (UPI), banks have started moving to charge for peer-to-peer payments on the new platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GST will change your online shopping experience from July 1</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-change-your-online-shopping-experience-from-july-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-will-change-your-online-shopping-experience-from-july-1/</guid>
      <description>Tax collected at source Currently, e-commerce websites do not collect tax in any form. Under the GST, they will collect tax at a fixed rate of 1 per cent while paying to the sellers listed on their websites. This is likely to impact prices and make your online shopping more expensive. Though, the move has been deferred, it is likely to come in force at a later date.
Faster delivery Under the GST, your goods will reach you faster as the retailers will not have to file a separate paperwork for each state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Plan Of Affordable Housing For All By 2022</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-real-estate-act-will-boost-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-gst-real-estate-act-will-boost-housing/</guid>
      <description>The government has backed its Housing for All by 2022 promise with a slew of reforms for buyers and developers alike.
The Indian real estate sector has seen a resurgence of interest in 2017 after a slowdown over the past 2-3 years, buoyed by the affordable housing segment, which includes residential units below Rs 50 lakh. Legislations the like Real Estate (Regulation and Development) Act, 2016, (RERA) and Goods and Services Tax (GST) have signalled that the government is ready to walk the talk for its &amp;lsquo;Housing for All&amp;rsquo; by 2022 promise and many developers and institutional players have flocked to the affordable housing market, a report by Colliers International India, the Indian wing of a global commercial real estate company said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks Not Responsible For Theft From Lockers, Says Reserve Bank</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-have-no-liability-for-loss-of-valuables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/banks-have-no-liability-for-loss-of-valuables/</guid>
      <description>Some banks, in their locker hiring agreements, have made it clear that any item stored in the locker is at the customer&amp;rsquo;s own risk and he or she may, in their own interest, insure the valuables.
Do not expect any compensation for theft or burglary of valuables in safe deposit boxes of public sector banks as the locker hiring agreement absolves them of all liability.
This bitter truth was disclosed in an RTI response by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and 19 PSU banks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s next President:10 things about Draupdi Murmu, the woman who could be India&#39;s next President</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-things-about-draupdi-murmu-the-woman-who-could-be-indias-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/10-things-about-draupdi-murmu-the-woman-who-could-be-indias-next/</guid>
      <description>With the new president of India set to be elected next month, several names are doing the rounds including those of BJP veteran Najma Heptullah and Mahatma Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s writer grandson Rajmohan Gandhi. Many say Prime Minister Narendra Modi has decided Jharkhand Governor and BJP leader Draupdi Murmu to be the party candidate.
Very few people know about Murmu outside eastern states. Here are 10 things to know about the woman who can be the next president of the country:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rs 12. Vodafone Announces New Ramzan Plans.</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-announces-new-ramzan-plans-starting-at-rs-12-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/vodafone-announces-new-ramzan-plans-starting-at-rs-12-details/</guid>
      <description>Vodafone also said it will offer unlimited voice calling, unlimited national roaming and 1GB data per day in plans priced at Rs 342 and Rs 442.
Telecom operator Vodafone India announced new Ramzan offers for its prepaid users. The new plans, called &amp;ldquo;Ramzan 342 and 442&amp;rdquo;, are valid for users in Karnataka, Vodafone India said in a release. Under the offer, users can avail of unlimited 2G data at Rs 5 per hour and unlimited 3G/4G data at Rs 19 per hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mVisa can be use for booking Railway Tickets</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/travellers-can-now-book-railway-tickets-using-mvisa-payment-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/travellers-can-now-book-railway-tickets-using-mvisa-payment-solution/</guid>
      <description>Rail travellers can now book tickets by mVisa payment method which allows them to scan a quick response (QR) code and pay through smartphones.
Users can securely link their visa debit, credit or prepaid account to the mVisa application on their smartphones and make their travel bookings by simply scanning their mVisa QR code on the Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation website.
IRCTC, a subsidiary of the Indian Railways, is offering a promotion offer until September 4 that will give Rs 50 cashback to consumers booking their tickets through mVisa scan and pay on the IRCTC website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-aadhaar-is-being-challenged/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/why-aadhaar-is-being-challenged/</guid>
      <description>Six articles that explain why Aadhaar is being challenged in the Supreme Court
•Aadhaar is vulnerable to identity theft because of its design and the way it is used: A centralised database, dual use as identifier and authenticator, and lack of sound legal framework are its main weaknesses.
•Amid the debate about privacy, the more pressing issue of exclusion has been forgotten: Exclusion due to authentication errors and deactivation have an immediate impact on millions of people across India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, Pay Fine If Your SBI Account Has No Minimum Balance</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/now-pay-fine-if-your-sbi-account-has-no-minimum-balance/</guid>
      <description>The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.
State Bank of India, the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest lender, has decided to increase manifold the minimum balance required for maintaining savings account from April 1, hitting 31 crore depositors including pensioners and students.
The monthly average balance (MAB) requirement has been increased to as high as Rs 5,000 for branches in six metros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Department Identifies 18 Lakh People With Suspicious Deposits</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-18-lakh-people-with-suspicious-deposits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/tax-department-identifies-18-lakh-people-with-suspicious-deposits/</guid>
      <description>These people will have to reply within 10 days to avoid any notice from the tax department or further enforcement action.
The Income Tax department has identified 18 lakh people who have made &amp;lsquo;suspicious&amp;rsquo; cash deposits post demonetisation, including those having deposited over Rs 5 lakh, and will send emails and SMSes seeking explanation about their source of funds. These people will have to reply within 10 days to avoid any notice from the tax department or further enforcement action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICICI, Axis, SBI Gain, RBI To Get Power To Act Against Loan Defaulters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/icici-axis-sbi-gain-rbi-to-get-power-to-act-against-loan-defaulters/</guid>
      <description>The Union Cabinet cleared an ordinance empowering the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to act against wilful defaulters. The ordinance has been sent to the president for approval. The ordinance is aimed at empowering RBI to deal more effectively with stressed assets than earlier. A senior finance ministry official said &amp;ldquo;It is part of a broader plan to resolve bad loans with banks&amp;rsquo; issue that has been a major hurdle in the economy from achieving its full potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST To Lower Tax Burden On Medical Devices, Smartphones: Finance Ministry</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-lower-tax-burden-on-medical-devices-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-lower-tax-burden-on-medical-devices-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>The Goods and Services Tax (GST) will lead to lower tax burden in several commodities, including packaged cement, medicaments, smartphones and medical devices, the Finance Ministry said on Tuesday.
&amp;ldquo;Packaged cement attracts central excise duty of 12.5 per cent plus Rs 125 PMT (per metric tonne) and standard VAT (value-added tax) rate of 14.5 per cent. At these rates, the present total tax incidence works out to more than 29 per cent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GST To Smoothen Taxation, Bring In Transparency: Experts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-smoothen-taxation-bring-in-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/gst-to-smoothen-taxation-bring-in-transparency/</guid>
      <description>At an interactive awareness programme for start-ups, the experts said the government is expected to resolve the queries of entrepreneurs regarding GST.
GST will not only ease the process of taxation, but bring in transparency, say experts.
At an interactive awareness programme for start-ups here, the experts said the government is expected to resolve the queries of entrepreneurs regarding GST.
&amp;ldquo;GST will not only ease the process, but also bring transparency as all the invoices needed to be uploaded by sellers are visible to the buyer every month,&amp;rdquo; said Manish Ojha, Development Head of KDK Softwares Pvt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modi government is firming up a plan to create India&#39;s own Harvard</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/hrd-ministry-seeks-cabinet-nod-for-20-world-class-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/hrd-ministry-seeks-cabinet-nod-for-20-world-class-institutions/</guid>
      <description>India has taken a firm step towards building 20 world-class educational institutions, which will be termed Institutions of Eminence, with the human resource development ministry moving the proposal to the Union Cabinet for approval. Firmly bearing the stamp of the Prime Minister’s Office, this is a new framework to catapult Indian institutions to global recognition by freeing the best of them from the University Grants Commission’s restrictive regulatory regime and ushering in an unprecedented level of institutional autonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Pay Arrears Immediately&#39;: Income Tax Department Names Five Defaulters</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pay-arrears-immediately-income-tax-department-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/pay-arrears-immediately-income-tax-department-names/</guid>
      <description>The taxman has begun this exercise of naming and shaming tax defaulters for the last few years and had named at least 96 such entities which have huge tax liabilities on them and have either gone non-traceable or have shown no assets for recovery.
The Income Tax Department on Thursday published names of five entities owing over Rs 10 crore in taxes, as part of its strategy to name and shame big defaulters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Check If Your Employer Has Deposited Your Income Tax</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26as-how-to-check-your-income-tax-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/26as-how-to-check-your-income-tax-credit/</guid>
      <description>In case there is a mismatch in TDS figures in Form 16 and Form 26AS, one should approach his/her employer or respective entity.
The tax return filing season has started from April 1. Usually, for many salaried employees, the first thing that comes to mind is Form 16 that is issued by employers. But another document - Form 26AS - is also a crucial document that a salaried individual should access before filing tax returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar essential for getting fellowships, scholarships from UGC, AICTE</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-essential-getting-fellowships-scholarships-ugc-aicte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-essential-getting-fellowships-scholarships-ugc-aicte/</guid>
      <description>According to an order issued by the Human Resource Development (HRD) ministry on Wednesday, students seeking government scholarships and fellowships will need to declare Aadhaar numbers by the end of June, putting yet another of its benefits programme behind the Unique Identity project wall.
The order covers fellowship schemes implemented by the University Grants Commission and the All India Council for Technical Education.
“The use of Aadhaar as identity document for delivery of services or benefits or subsidies simplifies the government delivery processes, brings in transparency and efficiency, and enables beneficiaries to get their entitlements directly in a convenient and seamless manner and Aadhaar obviates the need for producing multiple documents to prove one’s identity,” the government stated in its notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NITI&#39;s vision: Houses, vehicles, ACs for all by 2032</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-vision-houses-vehicles-acs-for-all-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/nitis-vision-houses-vehicles-acs-for-all-by/</guid>
      <description>Government think tank NITI Aayog has envisaged a new India in which all citizens in 15 years will have houses with toilets, two-wheelers or cars, power, air conditioners and digital connectivity.
This is a glimpse of Vision 2031-32 presented by the NITI Aayog Vice-Chairman Arvind Panagariya to the body&amp;rsquo;s Governing Council, chaired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, at a meeting held yesterday in the presence of chief ministers.
The India 2031-32: Vision, Strategy and Action Agenda also visualises a fully literate society with universal access to health care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PF Withdrawal Easier For Education, Hospital Bills: 10 Facts</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-documents-just-self-declaration-for-provident-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-documents-just-self-declaration-for-provident-fund/</guid>
      <description>EFPO subscribers can seek withdrawal from their employee provident fund (EPF) account on various grounds by using a composite form along with a self-declaration.
EPFO or Employees&amp;rsquo; Provident Fund Organisation has made partial withdrawal easier from provident fund for medical and other purposes like purchase of house, education and marriage of children. The subscriber is no longer required to submit various certificates or documents. EFPO subscribers can seek withdrawal from their employee provident fund (EPF) account on various grounds by using a composite form along with a self-declaration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how your petrol pump might be cheating you right in front of your eyes</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-your-petrol-pump-might-be-cheating-you-in-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-your-petrol-pump-might-be-cheating-you-in-front/</guid>
      <description>A series of raids by Uttar Pradesh Special Task Force (STF) in Lucknow yesterday have revealed how petrol pumps are cheating consumers.
Most consumers only check the display of the fuel dispensing machine for the amount and the quantity of the fuel filled but the raids show that the pumps were using a remote-controlled electronic chip to dupe consumers.
This is how petrol pumps are cheating you:
 Petrol pumps install a chip inside the fuel dispensing machine, which is designed to reduce the fuel output by nearly five to ten per cent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aadhaar Card Mandatory For Subsidy: Indian Government</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/aadhaar-card-mandatory-subsidy-indian-government/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to curb corruption in the Public Distribution System (PDS), the Indian government had made the Aadhar Card mandatory for availing foodgrain subsidy at PDS.
The government has already made Aadhar Card mandatory for the cooking gas LPG subsidy.
The government has declared Rs 1.4 lakh crore subsidy under the food security law.
A timeline till June 30 is given for the common people who avail subsidy to apply for Aadhar Card, the government categorically stated in the notification in this regard that no subsidised foodgrains with Aadhaar after June 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Proposal To Withdraw New 2,000 Rupee Notes: Arun Jaitley</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/no-proposal-to-withdraw-new-2-000-rupee-notes-arun-jaitley/</guid>
      <description>The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.
Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Friday said there is no proposal to withdraw the Rs 2,000 notes that were introduced post demonetisation.
The Rs 2,000 banknotes were introduced along with new Rs 500 currency following the withdrawal of old Rs 500 and Rs 1,000 notes from November 9, 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BSNL Is Planning To Counter Reliance Jio, Airtel, Others</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/how-bsnl-is-planning-to-counter-reliance-jio-airtel-others/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The benefits customer will get under the Combo STV (special tariff voucher) of Rs 339 are unlimited calls in BSNL network and unlimited data with fair use policy of 2 GB per day with validity of 28 days,&amp;rdquo; BSNL said.
HIGHLIGHTS  BSNL&amp;rsquo;s new plan gives 2GB of 3G data per day at Rs 339
 It will also provide 25 minutes of free calls per day to other networks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea To Sell 1GB 2G, 3G, 4G Mobile Data At Same Price From March End</title>
      <link>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aadhaarcardnews.in/idea-to-sell-1gb-2g-3g-4g-mobile-data-at-same-price-from-march/</guid>
      <description>Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with about a month validity for around Rs 170 and 4G is priced around Rs 123.
HIGHLIGHTS  At present, Idea mobile internet plans are priced at different rates
 The decision in the wake of stiff competition in the market
 Idea sells 1GB of 2G service with a month validity for Rs 170
  Telecom operator Idea Cellular will start selling 1GB and above mobile data plans across its 2G, 3G and 4G network at same price by the end of this month.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>